Okay! Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha the Movie 1st.
Hello to everyone who's watching from a disc!
This is Disaster Prevention Leader Subaru Nakajima, 19 years old,
with the Time-Space Administrative Bureau's
Midchilda Harbor Safety Force.
Similarly, I'm Enforcer Teana Lanster, age 20,
with the Time-Space Administrative Bureau's Main Office.
So the four of us from the StrikerS team plus one,
as well as two special guests
will be providing audio commentary!
That's what's happening.
First up is the two of us talking about all sorts of things
in the background of the actual movie.
It's sort of nerve-wracking,
but I'll do my best!
We'll be in your care!
Hey, isn't this when the title comes up?
Ah, wait. I asked one of our special guests
to do something for this scene.
Really?
So... 3... 2...
Go ahead!
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha the Movie 1st
will now begin.
Oooh! Just like old times!
If it's the series opening,
then it's gotta be this.
Now then, in the video, the incident has already begun, but...
A black shadow's appeared, huh?
We sort of came out and did our introductions just then,
but there's probably some people who are going,
"Eh? Who're they?" so here's a little explanation.
Right. The incident happening in this movie, beginning right now in the video, is the Jewel Seed Incident.
By Midchilda's calendar, it would have occurred
during N.C. 0065, right?
Yep.
And exactly ten years after this incident, we met Nanoha
through various coincidences and circumstances.
We're recording right now in N.C. 0079,
fourteen years after this incident.
In summary, we're from fourteen years after this event
and know Nanoha and Fate as adults.
That's why we've been allowed to do this commentary.
So with that, we'd be happy if you could enjoy this
as though we're watching it alongside you.
Really happy!
So, that one line in the opening sequence
sort of spoiled the secret about the special guests.
That's right! Even though I told you
to leave it a mystery until they showed up!
Yeah, but didn't you wanna hear that line for the opening?
Yeah, that was a super good job, Tia.
Right?
Eh... from about chapter 12 onward,
our two special guests and the protagonists of this work,
Nanoha and Fate, will be joining us.
Oh, and Vivio's coming too!
Yep, we're going to have fun with everyone, so please enjoy.
Please enjoy!
Okay, let's take a look at the actual movie.
Right. Looks like Chief Yuuno is down...
Oh my...
Okay, this is where the real thing starts!
This is the city of Uminari in Japan.
Good morning, Nanoha.
It's time to get up! Please wake up!
Good morning!
Hey, I've been wondering since I first saw this,
but did she go to bed with her ribbons on?
Oh, now that you mention it...
Well, I do that sometimes, too.
On screen right now is everyone
from the Takamachi family.
They really haven't changed much since then, huh?
Really.
And Nanoha is just a normal third-grader, huh?
Pretty normal. And also...
Alisa and Suzuka sure are small, too!
Alisa had such long hair back then!
She sure did!
The three of them together make for such a cute scene.
Yeah!
Oh, and in this scene, Alisa's doodles are really good!
That's right!
Say, Tia, when you were in third grade,
did you have things like dreams for the future?
Hmm... I don't remember.
I was thinking stuff like "If I was a baker,
I'd be able to eat cake every day!"
That's quite generic...
So I had dreams like owning a bakery or a burger joint.
So you were a kid with an appetite...
Oh yeah, about what we were talking about earlier...
Earlier?
When we were talking about hair,
you said that you leave it tied up when you sleep.
Ah, only once in a while.
Like when I'm not really paying attention at home.
Hmm...
Speaking of which, your hair's short,
but have you ever grown it out longer?
Well, never long enough to tie it up.
It just doesn't feel like it'd fit me, you know.
I don't really think that's true.
Well, leaving that aside for now,
it's about time for Chief Yuuno...
Ah, Chief Yuuno's in ferret mode, and he...
This is where Nanoha
receives a telepathic message, right?
Seems so. He probably set it to only broadcast
to people with latent magical powers.
Ah, I see.
So, Nanoha is running forward!
Do your best!
Do your best! Do your best!
So...
Here it comes! Here it comes!
Ferret discovered! And...
Getting closer...
There! Chief Yuuno and Nanoha's first meeting.
Raising Heart's shimmering too.
So this is how Chief Yuuno and Nanoha met.
Meeting here was Nanoha's first step as a mage.
But really, if Nanoha had never met Chief Yuuno,
lots of things would never have even begun.
That's true. As a really close example, how about you?
Oh right! During the airport fire, I might have died!
No way! What's with that?! So scary! It's terrifying!
Well, we don't know if you would've died or not...
Next time, I'll have to take Vivio and go thank him.
Chief Yuuno is, indirectly, my savior!
Don't do that! You'll just bother him.
Eh, why?
Oh, pay attention to the screen just after this part.
Eh? What is it? What happens?
Nanoha's amazingly fast at texting!
Wow, you're right.
I thought that was amazing with such a tiny keypad.
It is! it is! I still can't get used to pressing the keys.
Even for typing, I always end up using speech-to-text.
No way! I think that's harder.
If you have a proper keyboard,
wouldn't it be faster to just type it up?
Well, I've got a really great partner, right? Even if I talk really fast, Mach Caliber will fix it all up for me.
Ah, that's so unfair.
It's not unfair! It's the power of our bond.
Now then, in the video,
we see Nanoha trying her best again.
Makihara Veterinary
Aren't Nanoha's casual clothes
just so bright and cute?
I'm a little curious about what the words
written on the front actually say.
So now, Nanoha is trapped inside the barrier.
The black shadow attacks! Chief Yuuno is being chased!
Will Nanoha be able to save him?!
Oh!
Nanoha takes off!
The Chief Librarian goes flying!
He's been sent flying!
The two see each other!
Raising Heart shines!
Nanoha reaches out!
And then?!
Nanoha catches!
Right, catch!
But Nanoha falls over.
Oh yeah, this scene...
Huh?
See how Chief Yuuno talks and Nanoha is shocked?
Yeah.
I didn't understand this at first.
I thought, "Eh? Is that supposed to be surprising?"
Oh, right. For people from Mid,
it's not really strange for animals to talk.
I thought it was normal for animals
to be able to talk using telepathy.
But now that I think about it,
Earth doesn't have anything like familiars or telepathy.
That'd make it twenty times as shocking!
Oh, and Tia, just in case you don't know,
Chief Yuuno isn't a familiar.
I know that! How rude!
Rude to me and Chief Yuuno!
Heheh, sorry!
Ah, it's about time for Nanoha's setup scene.
Isn't that a bit later?
And Tia, it's not a "setup". It's a transformation!
Even though her body's not changing?
For magical girls, even just changing clothes is a transformation. That's just how it is!
Is that so? Really, I don't even
understand the concept of magical girls.
Girls who use magic, fly, jump around, sparkle,
and protect people's hearts and peace are magical girls.
Well, she does fly and jump in the following scene.
And the light from her magic does shine brightly...
And she totally protects people's hearts and the peace!
Therefore Nanoha is a super magical girl!
Well, I'll just accept it.
Ah, here's the setup! "Raising Heart, set up!"
Oh, she's already shining—or rather, sparkling...
A pink light that pierces the sky!
No wonder Chief Yuuno is so surprised.
Isn't the way the rings appear here so pretty?
The ones all around Nanoha, right?
Oh, the first time Raising Heart speaks!
Nanoha's "Nice to meet you." is so cute.
Oh! Time for the transformation scene!
Here it comes!
I just can't get used to calling it a "transformation".
Now then, standby, ready!
Nanoha's transformation, here we go!
Yep!
The magic circle goes fweeeeng!
And her clothes go plink!
Whoa, no matter how many times I see it,
that's quite a strip...
Or rather, it's an interesting order
for deconstructing her garments.
Of course!
If they aren't deconstructed from top to bottom,
the reconstruction might be off when she switches back.
Well, our setups are probably like this, too.
But you don't get to see someone's
setup process very often, huh?
That's true.
Raising Heart is also steadily completing.
So this is the very first build.
She uses Mid's standard mage staff style
as the basis with a classical arrangement.
I see.
Oh, Nanoha's finally in the equipping stage.
Jacket equipped!
This movie version Jacket
sure has quite a few hard-shell parts, huh?
Her wrists are hard-shell parts too, right?
Yeah! In this second version!
It looks like it'd have really tough defense.
There's barely any skin showing,
so it looks pretty safe.
Right? Ah, the setup—or, uh,
the transformation's about done.
Yep! Transformation complete!
She's so cool even at nine years old.
After gaining her transformation,
Nanoha stands in the sky!
Chief Yuuno seems pretty happy about the success, too.
Hey, hey! The way Nanoha says "Wha?"
and "Huuuuuh?!" in this scene is just so cute!
I thought so too!
And after this she also goes "Whaaaaaa!"
Yeah! Yeah!
She's so cute but can already fly perfectly, huh?
Well, at this stage, she's basically just floating.
But this is where she breaks out
the flying support magic.
See? And after that, it's a lot more like aerial maneuvers.
Still, doesn't it seem kind of dangerous?
She lands straight away, after all.
But to be able to fly right away like that sure is amazing.
Yeah. Normally, the thought of flying at all would be scary.
And here, the charging enemy...
...gets completely blocked by Raising Heart's barrier!
To destroy the side that was attacking
takes some crazy defense.
Nanoha has solid mana reserves, after all.
Ah, this part. Those maneuvers are pretty cool.
Apparently the controls were on autopilot here,
but it still looks really scary.
And the way she sort of floats
around haphazardly is cute too.
It makes me smile to think that
even Nanoha used to be like this.
Time does some amazing things!
It sure does.
Oh, I think it's time for the first Buster.
Eh? Wasn't it a Barret rather than a Buster?
Right after this part, the shadow goes to attack Chief Yuuno...
Oh, right, right. The way she defends him
is quite standard and by the book.
Right down to the way she jumps in,
and even the size of her barrier, huh?
Oh, here comes Shoot Barret!
When Nanoha executes her first ever ranged spell.
Shoot Barret
When she executes it like this,
is it even a ranged spell anymore?
The power's amazing too!
She sent that black shadow flying!
I wonder if those shadows are going,
"No way! We can't beat her!" before running away.
Probably something like that.
Those things might be looking to absorb energy
from dormant mages or something, right?
Ah, I see.
Now, with those black shadows running away,
it's the moment we've been waiting for...
Here comes Nanoha's long-range bombardment!
This bombardment spell was amazing too.
Three straight shots in a row, and they're all clean hits.
And to top it off, they're all sealed in one hit.
Nanoha's got good sense and skill, but the accuracy of
her long-range shots must be because of her great Device.
Yeah. This is the first time we see Cannon Mode, right?
Ah, this Cannon Mode has a trigger unit, right?
I saw it and thought, "Oh, I bet that'd be easy to use!"
I know what you mean! It looks really steady.
She's steadying it with her whole body,
and her balance looks good, too.
And she's got a clear shot.
You're right.
Now she's locking on and steadying her aim...
Nanoha isn't going to be shouting it, so the two of us will.
Divine...
...Buster
Uh, you don't have to do the sound effects, too.
Ahaha, it was just so cool that I couldn't help it.
Now then, they've been sealed with some nice shots.
The dangerous situation's over for now, huh?
Uh, we're currently on chapter 7.
So by movie standards, this would be roll 1.
This is where they'd change the film roll.
Yep.
It'll be about eighteen minutes in when this chapter ends,
up to the equivalent of episode 3 in the TV series.
Eh, going by the files, the events of episodes 1 and 3
were combined to speed up the beginning's pacing.
You're right. Time-wise, it was over really fast.
And the meeting with Fate after this has things
from episodes 2, 4, and 5 of the TV series mixed in too.
Yeah. In the TV series, we spend
more time on Nanoha's daily life.
Yep.
The movie version isn't as episodic as the TV version.
Right?
Oh, speaking of which, do you know
how Earth's cinematography works?
No.
When you go to the theater, about 15­–20 minutes in,
the footage on the screen gets a bit shaky.
Do you know why that is?
It's a roll swap, right?
They change the film.
How come you know?
I was curious about it too, so I asked.
At first I thought, "Eh, noise?
Is the film shaking or something?"
It seems like that, huh?
Oh, of course, on this DVD or Blu-ray,
you won't see that.
How are you supposed to read that anyway?
Blu-ray or Blue-ray?
Eh, I wonder.
I think the commercials on Earth say "BLU-RAY!"
But the disc is blue, right?
So wouldn't it be Blue-ray?
Uh... I'm not sure.
Eh, if you know the correct one, please write to
the Midchilda Harbor Safety Force with the answer!
For
Your
Ferret
Caring
Stop that! Making everyone else do all the work...
Oh, our special guest—er, well, Nanoha sent us a message...
"It isn't called Blu-ray because of the color of the disc.
It's the color of the light used to read it."
Oh, sorry about that. Excuse us.
By the way, which spelling is right?
"I don't know. It might vary depending on the maker."
Earth's home electronics culture is surprisingly complex.
And with that, this chapter is over.
Once Nanoha's and Chief Yuuno's introductions are over,
the commentary group will also grow by two!
We'll be going on without even a commercial break!
Right, so from here on we'll have
two more members doing commentary.
Go ahead with your introductions!
Hello! Erio Mondial, currently 14, with the Frontier Nature Conservation Corps!
I'm Caro Ru Lushe, also 14, with the same position.
Seishō University Magnet Elementary School
Yep! Welcome!
These two are this work's other protagonist's, Fate's...
Fate's...
Fate's?
When I talk about you two to other people,
I'm never sure what to do. What should I call you?
We're still Fate's wards as always.
Fate is our legal guardian, after all.
Yeah, if you just say "children who Fate holds dear",
then it's easy to understand.
Right!
She's really important to the two of us.
Right.
So from now on, we'll be switching with the two of you
for commentary and sometimes talking as a whole group.
How many times have you two seen this movie?
Seishō University Magnet Elementary School
Quite a few times! We had the disc sent over, so we watched it with everyone at the Conservation Corps camp.
I watched it by myself, but I also had to run an errand
to Lu's house, so we watched it together.
Ah, then the commentary should be easy.
Um... leaving aside whether it's easy or not...
We'll all do our best!
Okay then! After the next chapter,
it'll be focused on Fate for a while, so...
...we'll be going away.
Right!
We'll be listening from over there,
so you two do your best!
Okay!
All right, Erio!
Subaru and Tia have gone to the back,
so now it's up to us to handle the commentary!
Yeah! Let's do it!
Oh, this is where the cat beast comes out.
Right! Fate makes her appearance.
And right after this is the long-awaited
transformation scene, Erio!
Oh, um, for the transformation scene,
it's really hard for me to give commentary...
Fate, set up!
Okay, the ribbons are coming off.
Th-The lights are spinning...
She spins around, and there go her clothes!
Oh, uh... ah! B-Bardiche's construction is cool, isn't it?
Yeah! The parts are all coming together.
This is the new movie version model, Axe Form!
And right after is Fate's gallant
equipping of her Jacket's undersuit!
Waah! I probably shouldn't be watching this!
And you obviously haven't
watched this frame-by-frame, right?
Of course I haven't!
I-I-Isn't that obvious!?
And now her cape is also finished.
Fate's and Bardiche's setup...
Complete!
But you know, Fate's transformation scene
is shorter than Nanoha's.
Oh, really?
Fate's is just short of 40 seconds,
while Nanoha's is about a minute and 20 seconds.
Is that so? Maybe it's because it was Nanoha's
very first transformation, so it took longer?
That could be it. But anyways, Erio...
Hm?
After examining both of their transformations closely,
which one catches your heart more?
Hmmm, let's see.
After examining them really closely, I think—
Hey, wait!
I haven't examined them closely!
And they didn't make me go thump thump
or heart-catch or anything like that!
Huh?
You did this in the commercials, too.
Please stop it! Geez...
Oh, we got a message from Subaru and Tia...
"Erio, playing the straight man?"
Caro's been playing the wise guy a lot lately,
so if I don't do that, the conversation won't move on.
While we were talking about that,
Fate has been in combat with the cat beast.
The wing she cut off turned into snakes.
Fate hasn't done anything yet, though.
Yeah. Oh, it's around here that...
Nanoha charges in! And a direct hit!
You can really see the future Nanoha's
fortress-like aggressive cannon style in that attack.
Definitely. It's sort of a shame that
it didn't finish it off in one hit, though.
The cat beast is escaping. Fate chases it,
and with a great slash from her beloved Bardiche...
...it's been spectacularly sealed!
As expected of the Lightning Ace.
And here's their first encounter.
This is a story of their meeting,
and this is the first time they meet, huh?
Well, they do start off as enemies, though.
It feels really tense.
Even now, Nanoha and Fate
sometimes have arguments,
but it's never as tense as this.
That's true. Even we can just go in and say,
"Um... there, there" to stop those.
Then if you were there during this battle, do you think
that you'd have the courage to try to break them up?
I do!
Oh! What would you say?
"Stop it, you two!" or something?
Eh? Um, I'm not sure...
"This is the Bureau! Please stop fighting!" or something?
Would that stop them?
Those are some serious sparks going off.
That's true.
Well, I'd probably end up having to stop it by force.
Admiral Chrono... oh, he would have been an Enforcer around this time...
It'd be safer if you could stop them
with binds like Enforcer Chrono.
If I charged in carelessly and got stuck between
an Arc Saber and a Protection, I might just die...
Then you'd get blown up by an Explode and shot with Lancer.
And get taken down with Nanoha...
Wait, then there's no point to me charging in.
Fate would probably think,
"Who was that boy who came out of nowhere?"
But I'm sure she'd say "I'm sorry", too!
I wouldn't be too happy about that.
Ah, look!
While we were talking, Nanoha got shot down!
Yeah. It was a direct hit but didn't seem to do
much damage thanks to her heavy Barrier Jacket, huh?
It looked like her auto-guard activated
right before she was hit, so that might've helped.
Right.
And here's Fate's demand for her to
"Give up on the Jewel Seeds."
Ah, by the way, this scene has a mix of events
from the 2nd and 4th episodes of the TV series.
I see.
And with that, the worried Chief Yuuno
and bewildered Nanoha reunite.
They seem relieved that the kitten is safe.
The couple's first meeting and battle ends here.
So then, Subaru and Tia
will now be joining us again.
Hey there!
We're back!
And on top of that, more members
are joining our commentary group.
Right! When it comes to commentary about the 1st movie,
there's no one better than the two protagonists.
Hello, Nanoha Takamachi, 23 years old, and...
Hello, Fate Testarossa-Harlaown, 23.
And one more special commentator,
Nanoha's daughter and magic academy fourth-grader...
Hello, I'm Vivio Takamachi.
With that, the commentary members are all here.
Nanoha, Fate, we're happy to have you!
Yep, us too.
We're happy to be here.
Vivio as well, of course.
Yeah!
But if we talk with all of us here,
it'll probably be hard to keep up so...
From here, we'll be switching up
the members between chapters as we go on.
Right.
So the Nanoha on screen right now is at the point
where she resolves to learn magic seriously, right?
Do you remember this particular time?
But of course.
I even remember the order I learned spells in.
That's amazing!
And Fate, do you remember
the first time you went to Earth?
I do. It's an unforgettable, precious memory, after all.
How wonderful!
But, um, Fate...?
For you, isn't this movie also the story of your sad past?
This scene is kind of heartwrenching, too.
So we feel a little bad about being so excited over here...
No, it's fine.
Really?
How should I put this?
It's hard to put into words, but my memories of
Presea and Alicia are still warm and precious to me.
Right.
A lot has happened ever since
the Jewel Seed Incident, after all.
Yeah, so I'm fine.
We don't get to do commentaries, often so let's have fun.
Right! Thank you very much!
Starting with the next chapter,
we'll be following the footage again.
Studying in progress!
Okay, this chapter is from Nanoha's training.
The chapter's title is even "Training". Just like that.
This chapter will be done by the famous,
training-loving, former Stars team—
Eh? Famous?
We are! We are! The three of us
from Stars will be doing the chapter.
Yep!
So, about your basic training...
Nanoha, what was your initial magical training like?
There was a lot to remember,
and there were some difficulties,
but I really enjoyed it.
You enjoyed it?
This was when I decided to help
Yuuno collect the Jewel Seeds
and when I became interested in Fate.
Right.
Having things that you're concerned or worried about,
but not being able to do anything
about them is painful, isn't it?
Ah, right, right!
I get it.
So being told that I might be able to
do something if I tried made me happy.
I think that encouraged me.
It encouraged you?
I realized that I wasn't just a child who couldn't do anything.
So that's how you felt, huh?
That must be why you even multitasked
so you could train during class.
Uh, about that... it's not something to be proud of.
Now, I regret it a little.
Ma'am, I'm sorry for not paying attention during your lesson!
There. The apology fourteen years later, recorded.
Okay, what are we doing for this chapter?
We've switched up since the last one.
This will have the former Lightning Team, plus one.
Seishō University Magnet Elementary School
Here!
I'm the plus one.
Oh, right, Vivio...
For people who have only seen this movie,
hearing about you would be a pretty big surprise, huh?
Oh, since I'm Mama Nanoha's daughter?
Yeah, that. You're ten years old now, right?
They must be thinking
"Nanoha's still so young but already has such a big kid!"
Oh. Eh, the reason we're so close in age
is because Mama Nanoha adopted me.
A lot happened between Nanoha and Vivio, too.
Yeah, a lot. And with Mama Fate, too.
Ever since Vivio was a tiny child, we've played together,
and I adopted Vivio together with Nanoha.
So I've always thought,
"Wow, I've got two mamas. I'm so blessed."
I remember that feeling.
So even now, I still call her Mama Fate.
I'm happy for you to call me that.
It doesn't seem like that all happened too long ago,
but it's already been four years, huh?
Eh? To me, it feels like it's been a really long time.
To me, it still feels quite recent, but a lot has happened, so it also feels like it's been some time. A bit of both.
Ah, me too.
Right?
So, this chapter will be delivered by these members.
Between Fate's magic projectiles and the bombardment
spells used by both of them, it's a scene with a lot to see.
It's Divine Buster versus Spark Smasher.
And it's the first appearance of Glaive Form!
So far, Fate's been gathering Jewel Seeds
pretty desperately. Is that because...?
Yeah, I wanted to bring the Jewel Seeds
back to my mother, Presea, as quickly as possible.
So you were worried about Presea back then?
I was worried, and I missed her.
At this time, I still couldn't tell the difference
between Alicia's memories and my own.
Presea was a really kind
and gentle mother to Alicia, after all.
Right. She was kind, a bit shy and awkward,
and always so happy while watching over Alicia.
So that's how it was.
Your memories from before...
Are they completely separate now?
Yeah, they've always been clearly split
between the time before and after the accident,
so the memories as Alicia and those fewer
memories that were mine were slowly sorted out.
Right.
H-Huh?
Um... everyone, don't get so serious.
Ah, okay...
Um...
Look, the seal's already finished.
And Chief Yuuno gets attacked by Arf.
It makes you think,
"Arf, don't be so rough with such a tiny ferret", right?
It really does.
It's amazing that he fends it off though.
After Arf's transformation,
we'll return to continue with commentary!
Right, so this is the second battle
between myself and Nanoha.
The chapter title is "The Lights of Battle Dance and Spread".
It's the same as the song title, right?
So, going back to earlier...
Ah, yes?
There were many painful things back then, but
it was because my mother and Alicia were
such a happy family that I was able to be born.
Considering all that, I don't want to think of the past—my past, at least—as something that's sad or unfortunate.
Right.
The me right now is a child of the Harlaown family,
Erio and Caro's legal guardian, and Vivio's adopted mother,
but I was born as a child of the Testarossa family.
Even if there were sad things in the past
or if I wasn't loved like I wished to be,
I don't want to deny my birth and that part of my past.
And that's why Mama Fate's full name is
Fate Testarossa-Harlaown.
Right.
Presea is the one who gave birth to me,
and Alicia is my older sister.
That's what I still think, so that's how it is.
It is, huh?
Oh, look! The dogfight's started!
It's a battle between buildings, huh?
Looking at this battle, Nanoha's improvement
since the last skirmish is amazing, isn't it?
Yeah, the way she dodges is impressive.
Even when I'm shooting from the best angle, she avoids it.
And she even charges me while I'm shooting.
She's guiding her Shooters now, too.
This one is hard to dodge.
But the way Mama Fate dodges is really pretty!
I practiced a lot, after all.
Though I had to block that last one.
That was a close-range shot, right?
Was it a Smasher?
It seemed stronger than a Smasher,
so maybe it was a Short Buster?
Nanoha's Smasher is intended for close-range use, right?
That's right.
Is this when you were thinking that
you could finish it with a dogfight?
I was thinking that when I charged in,
but Nanoha was a surprisingly tough opponent.
The Jewel Seed was right there,
so that would've been distracting, too.
That might've also been part of it. I didn't know
anything about Yuuno's abilities back then either.
Oh, and if they'd had any other allies...
Right, the sealed Jewel Seed would get taken away.
So that's why you tried to quickly snatch it, huh?
Right, I wanted to fly over and quickly pick it up,
but Nanoha's acceleration was surprisingly fast.
Even back then, Nanoha's short-distance acceleration was impressive, huh?
And while I was trying to retrieve it,
things somehow turned really bad.
A small-scale dimensional tremor, right?
Now that I think about it,
that really was dangerous.
Fate, we're really glad you're okay!
At the time, I didn't understand the dangers
and now regret my ignorance.
Mama Nanoha was surprised too.
Oh, I was too.
Nanoha and I were both completely blown away.
It's a relief that there weren't any casualties.
It really is...
Oh, a message from Nanoha...
Uh...
"I'd fallen down onto the ground
and couldn't get back up. Sorry!"
Oh, um... okay.
It's fine, Mama Fate.
I've also smashed Mama Nanoha
into a wall before in the Cradle.
Oh, that's true now that I think about it.
Eh? Um, is that what we were talking about?
I'm not sure, but on-screen,
Fate is attempting a dangerous forced sealing.
Fate, dash!
Mama Fate, don't do it!
Arf is worried too!
Sorry. I knew it was dangerous, but...
But it's great that you managed to seal it.
I did my best. Well, trying my best for something
this risky isn't really something to be proud of...
Thinking about how Arf would feel while
watching this kinda makes my chest ache.
Yeah, I really worried Arf back then.
After all this, most things don't
seem to bother Arf much now.
Oh, I've heard that too.
She said she was really scared at the time.
You really worried people, huh, Mama Fate?
Right. Back then, Arf and Nanoha didn't get along.
Arf really gave her a death glare!
And Nanoha was left with that painful parting.
But now, Mama Nanoha and Arf get along fine.
So I guess that everything turned out okay!
Yeah, I think so.
Now then, from here, the plot
will start moving more quickly.
Right.
So we're passing the commentary
back to Nanoha's team.
The Stars Team will be continuing from here.
While we're being shown Fate
and Arf's secret home, switch places!
Mama Fate, that's a really cool room!
Arf found it for us.
She said it had a good view.
Good job, Arf!
And now, over in a lovely little abode in the city of Uminari,
we begin from the Takamachi residence.
We're back.
This is Stars Team.
I really like this part.
The scene of Nanoha's resolve.
This was the first time you expressed
your interest in Fate out loud, right?
That's right.
I think that I was interested
ever since we first met though.
Really?
Yep. When I first saw her,
I thought, "Ah, what a pretty girl!"
Right, right...
And I wanted to know why
such a kind-looking person seemed so sad.
Something must've clicked.
Yes, definitely.
Ah, this song is the instrumental version of "Innocent Starter", the TV series' opening theme.
There are arrangements of other vocal songs in the movie as well.
Like "Little Wish" and "Flying High".
They're quite nostalgic songs
for those who've seen the TV series.
If any more show up, we'll be sure to point them out.
Yep.
And now, the Bureau's L-class cruiser, the Arthra, appears.
We've been on it too, but for Nanoha,
Time-Space Administrative Bureau
L-Class Dimensional Cruiser
Arthra
it's a ship with many more memories, right?
Yeah, I've been stationed on it
and have visited it even after that.
Commodore Lindy really hasn't changed at all since then, huh?
Her hairstyle is different now, though.
The two in the operator seats are Allex and Landy.
The one with the glasses is Allex,
and the one with the harsh voice is Landy.
Seeing Amy like this, she looks so young.
Arthra Chief of Staff/Assistant Enforcer
Amy Limietta
She was sixteen at the time, right?
Yep, and Chrono was fourteen.
Commodore, Time-Space Administrative Bureau
Captain of the Arthra
Lindy Harlaown
At first, I thought Chrono was about my age,
but I really should've been calling him "Enforcer Chrono".
Enforcer, Time-Space Administrative Bureau
Chrono Harlaown
Oh, it's because the first time I called him "Chrono",
he responded normally like nothing was wrong.
Well, you were a civilian collaborator at the time, Nanoha.
Even as his subordinate,
Amy just calls him "Chrono".
Well, calling him that got passed to Hayate,
which is why we both still call him "Chrono".
But after this, he got much taller.
He looks a lot more mature now, doesn't he?
Right? About a year after these events,
he had a huge growth spurt.
He just kept growing and growing!
Hey, wait, isn't this chapter really short?
It's almost time for the next one.
Ah, Presea and Fate are on screen...
It's a really painful scene.
I feel like Erio, Caro, and Vivio
shouldn't be watching this.
Ah! The cake!
The cake that Fate picked out and bought for her...
The cake that would've make Erio or Caro jump for joy...
I don't think that Erio and Caro would be able
to be happy when the situation is so tense.
Eh? But when Fate buys a cake
for Vivio and me, we get tense.
We get so happy that we skip around the house!
Fate is nodding, but Vivio's trying to laugh it off.
Right?
But Nanoha, about Presea... Presea...
What's wrong?
It's nothing. Um...
I was just wondering if it's fine to just call her by her first name since she's Fate's mother, after all.
Oh, I see.
I don't know what to call her.
They say so in the movie too, but Mrs. Lindy and
Chrono both refer to her as "Ms. Presea".
Oh, that's a safe choice.
So, what were you saying?
Ah, right. Nanoha, you didn't ever
meet Ms. Presea face-to-face, right?
Nope, not even once.
I never spoke to her via video or telepathy either.
Hypothetically, if you had been able to contact her,
what do you think you would've talked about?
That's tough.
Nanoha is wavering.
When I think about what I'd talk about or what
I could talk about, there really isn't anything.
I guess that's to be expected.
Presea experienced a tragic loss in her life
and spent a long time considering her response.
For someone like that,
no matter what a simple child had to say...
...nothing would get through, huh?
No matter how right what you say is, to someone who's
made up their mind, words alone won't reach them.
Right.
It's too bad that all our thoughts and feelings
can't be conveyed through just meeting and talking.
Yeah.
So then, it looks like another battle between
myself and Fate is beginning here, but...
But one doesn't start, right?
Chrono shows up straight away, after all.
Nanoha, this is the first time that you
call Fate by her name, isn't it?
Right, she hadn't told me her name,
but I overheard Arf calling to her so I knew it.
Oh, that makes sense.
I'll only admit this now, but
back then, I was really worried that her name might've
actually been totally different from what I'd heard!
I see, so that's why you were a bit hesitant.
I went with "Fa..." then checked her reaction to see
if I'd gotten it wrong, then finished it with "...te".
I do that too.
Right? But I think getting through that little bit of worry
to call them by their name is important.
I haven't really thought about that before.
But don't you only ever call people by their names?
It just feels more natural.
"Hey you" or "you there"
just doesn't seem right to me.
Yeah, I actually feel the same way.
So if I don't refer to them by name,
the conversation feels really awkward.
Yeah, I'm like "Hey!" or "Wait!" or something.
I'm the type that's perfectly okay not using names.
Caro doesn't do that, but I think Erio does.
They're both nodding.
Fate's the type to only call those close to her by name.
Alisa's the same way.
Hm? Oh, Chrono definitely doesn't
call people by their names.
Now that you mention it, he even calls
Fate and Amy "you" or stuff like that.
I wonder why.
Is it to sound authoritative?
I've never really thought about it.
Oh, right. This is the part of the movie where
Arf attacks Chrono, and then Chrono shoots at Fate.
Yeah, it's a tense scene, isn't it?
When Enforcer Chrono protected Nanoha,
I thought that was so like him.
Yeah, I thought that too, but apparently
Chrono was thinking stuff like
"Why are you spacing out? Where's your defense?"
and had to put up a shield in a hurry.
But if you aren't experienced,
it's hard to react in those situations.
Fate was too focused on the Jewel Seed and got hit too.
Chrono's Stinger is really fast.
If you're watching from up close,
you really can't see it.
I know, right?
I really don't want to get caught in Enforcer Chrono's range.
Huh? Teana, have you ever had
a mock battle with Chrono?
Once or twice when I was working under Fate.
I bet you got hit with lots of binds.
I was totally tied up.
And it looks like the Nanoha on screen is also all tied up.
I was flabbergasted!
Okay, now we're on the Arthra,
and Nanoha's group has taken off for a bit.
From here until roll 3, we'll be continuing
with just the four Forwards.
Right. Nanoha, Vivio, and Fate are off on a break.
They sure are.
Now then, this is when we find out about Chief Yuuno's
true form along with some other events, right?
There's Nanoha taking her Jacket off.
I really like this part!
Nanoha points her finger
at Chief Yuuno and goes "Ahhh! Ahhh!".
It is really cute.
Ah, here's the scene.
Chief Yuuno, transformation disengaged!
Going back to normal boy mode!
Chief Yuuno had overused his mana, right?
I wonder what that feels like.
I get that sometimes too.
When you're training or on a mission on an unfamiliar world and use too much mana, it's like "Ahhh, I feel sick."
I've had that too.
It's sort of like getting motion sickness.
Ah, that sounds tough!
You don't like riding in vehicles, huh, Caro?
And yet you don't mind riding Fried.
I'm especially bad with cars. Fate's car is okay though,
so it's probably because of the smell or something.
Ah! It's time for Commodore Lindy's appearance.
I've been wondering about all those
props and things she had in that room.
When we were on the Arthra,
they weren't there, were they?
Uh, it's written in the booklet too, but
it was prepared to create an environment where
the locals would feel comfortable if they made contact.
Nanoha actually looks a bit shocked instead.
Maybe they got something wrong about the culture?
Oh, according to Nanoha,
there's nothing wrong with the room,
but the difference between it
and the rest of the ship was jarring.
Well, the walls of the room still look like the Arthra's.
But you can feel that it's a welcoming atmosphere.
That's what's important.
That's true.
Ah, we're getting to the explanation about Lost Logia.
I feel like we sort of have a weird
connection with Lost Logia.
Nanoha and Fate have had
quite a few encounters with them, huh?
Both the Jewel Seeds and the Book of Darkness...
Riot Force 6 was a Lost Logia task force, too.
Oh, this part when Commodore Lindy drinks her tea...
Ah, and she puts in milk and sugar?
I like green tea and all,
but I'm not sure about driking it with milk and sugar.
It tastes good with matcha, though.
Apparently it's sold on Earth in an already sweetened state.
Like matcha-flavored chocolate and ice cream.
It's that tea that's made from powder, right?
Yes, grown tea leaves are ground into powder.
In Japan, it's quite a formal drink.
But in Japan, you normally don't put in milk or sugar.
In a tea ceremony-esque atmosphere like that,
it's probably even more jarring for Nanoha.
I see. Thanks for explaining Earth's customs
to our Midchildan audience.
And here comes Commodore Lindy's
"You two, stay out of this situation, okay?"
Nanoha and Chief Yuuno would probably be shocked by that, but we're from the Bureau ourselves, so...
There's no choice in that case.
But Chief Yuuno feels responsible for losing the Jewel Seeds,
and Nanoha is interested in Fate...
They can't help but worry.
And now we're changing locations to Fate's hideout.
A wounded Fate and Arf,
who's trying to persuade her...
I really don't like this part.
It just seems so tragic!
And personally knowing Arf and Fate
makes it even harder...
Right? Fate is working so hard for her mother,
and Arf is so worried about Fate...
Even when her family situation was deteriorating,
Fate was always kind to Arf, huh?
Yes, Arf's often told us about how she was raised with a lot of love.
Fate from back when she lived in Artesaim,
and Arf being so tiny...
If you only looked at them, they'd seem happy.
When they're running together, they really do look
just like an ordinary little master and her perky familiar.
That's what makes this part so hard to watch.
Everyone's trying so hard,
but their feelings don't reach each other. It's so sad.
Yeah...
And even here, as Fate's saying
"I'm sorry", she won't reconsider.
But she can't help it. She wants to help her mother, and she wants her kind mother from before to come back, too.
Yeah...
Oh, Fate is watching from the other side of the glass.
She looks really embarrassed.
Um... "I'm sorry that I was so stubborn back then."
Who's she apologizing to?
I assume Arf?
Um... "To lots of different people", is what she wrote.
Oh, on screen, Chief Yuuno is requesting
permission to aid with the search.
It's pretty rare for civilian collaborators
to work on cases involving Lost Logia.
That's probably why Enforcer Chrono got so flustered.
But since Nanoha had potential as an ally,
and it was Commodore Lindy's decision...
Well, in the end, it turned out to be the best choice.
That's how it turned out.
But if Nanoha or Chief Yuuno hadn't requested permission,
or if Lindy had turned them down...
...then Nanoha and Fate might
have never seen each other again, huh?
Isn't that a bad ending?
That would've been terrible.
Nanoha and Fate are going
"No way!" on the other side of the glass.
And for some reason, Vivio is too.
I don't want to think about it either! No, no, no!
Oh, even Caro's doing the "No, no" dance.
There, there. Their request ended up getting accepted,
and they were allowed on the Arthra, so it's okay.
By the way, Nanoha did get permission from her parents
and has taken leave from school to be on the Arthra.
Fate and Arf are hard at work collecting
Jewel Seeds while avoiding the Arthra's crew.
Both sides are slowly continuing their search.
Ah, sorry, this has nothing to do with the story, but
the cookies that Nanoha and Chief Yuuno
eat a little later look really good!
Ah! I thought so too!
Eh? Do they really look that good?
They do! So good that I wanna pause
to check them out really carefully.
That much...?
I think it's around here. Ah, a little more!
Um... uh...
There they are!
Did you see them?!
Did I ever!
The emergency alarm is going off...
Okay, we've entered roll 4 of the film.
And have switched members to the
Takamachi family and...
The Stars pair is also here.
This scene is the climax of the first half, the sea battle.
Mama Fate is about to do a lot of reckless things.
Uh, I'm a Belkan-style user, so I can't use big, flashy spells
like this, but it's really strenuous, right?
I wasn't nearly as good at stuff like that back then,
so I'm sure it was tough.
Vivio, do you get taught ritual spells at school?
We do ritual spell processing,
but we don't do anything this big.
Well, it'd be bad if the weather
changed during a lesson or something.
Or lightning bolts coming down.
What exactly is this thing that comes out?
Is the body made of water?
Right, water.
So the Jewel Seeds are using magic to control the water?
Something like that. I think they sensed
a nearby magic source and locked onto it.
But their search ability is sort of weak, though.
They don't react until you get really close, huh?
Right.
If you can run away and don't move much,
they probably won't attack.
But if you get close, they'll attack relentlessly. And even if
you hit their bodies, you won't inflict any real damage.
Right.
So Vivio, if you had to fight
something like this, what would you do?
It'd be good if I could freeze them with cold spells,
but then recovering the Jewel Seeds would be tough.
And with huge volumes like this,
it'd have to be a really big spell.
Or you could pinpoint the location
of each Jewel Seed and snipe them,
but that would be hard too.
They might get away before you got them all.
So it comes down to using one huge spell
to seal them all at once.
Ah, and here we finally have Nanoha's sortie.
The scene where I disobey orders...
You guys can't do that, okay?
Right, I'm still scared from the one time that I did.
Ditto.
Everyone messes up once,
gets scolded, and matures from it.
Well, lots happened when we were young.
This is where Chief Yuuno sends you
directly into the barrier, right?
Yep, that's right.
It's the perfect chance for a barrier mage to shine.
Chief Yuuno is so amazing!
He is my teacher, after all.
When you introduce Chief Yuuno to people, don't you say
"This is my childhood friend and
the person who taught me magic", right?
Yeah, I do.
Nanoha, when you say that to people who
have heard of you, they get terrified.
Eh? Why's that?
Well, Subaru and I felt like that, too.
After all, you're our teacher so...
"The person who taught the ace of aces
must be someone really amazing!"
Mama, people who don't know you two
might think of Chief Yuuno
as some sort of legendary figure who fires off huge Busters or Breakers
and says things like "Were you surprised?
Because that was only 20% of my full power!"
Eh?! So that... you mean...
Have I been causing trouble
for Yuuno without knowing it?
Well, I don't think it's troublesome or anything.
As a barrier mage and as the Chief Librarian of the
Infinity Library, he actually is an amazing person.
Hmm, I'd better still text him later.
This is where Chief Yuuno gets to have a bit of the spotlight.
His Shield and Chain Bind both really helped.
Coming to provide support for Nanoha while leading
in this situation, the Chief Librarian is really taking charge.
That Chain Bind is stretching out really far!
And here, Mama Nanoha and Mama Fate meet face-to-face!
Fate is getting shaky from her low mana reserves.
And what does Nanoha do after charging in?
Yup, "divide energy!"
The lights come out with a ping ping!
And get absorbed with a cling cling!
And then...!
Scythe blade, revived!
Subaru and Vivio are synchronizing as usual.
I'm happy you two are getting along so well.
And when Chief Yuuno's in trouble, Arf comes to the rescue
with a Chain Bind! What an exciting turn!
It's sort of funny that Mama used to talk about Arf
like she's her superior or something.
It's because she looked like she was older.
And this is where the two of you go
"One, two!" and seal all of them in one hit, right?
Fate didn't talk at all in this scene, did she?
I was so focused on the situation at the time
that I didn't really notice, but you're right.
Ah, Fate writes, "I wasn't sure what to say."
Well, I did start talking to her out of the blue.
And now we see Nanoha reconfirming her own feelings.
The things she wants to convey and discuss...
You wanted to be able to share your feelings with her, right?
Yeah, I wanted to share our loneliness and sadness.
And here's Bardiche silently helping.
He changes into Glaive Form
as if he's trying to support her.
As expected of Lynith's legacy,
Fate's beloved Device.
Mama Nanoha's also getting ready
for Divine Buster, Full Power!
The way Raising Heart says "of course"
really shows her personality.
Raising Heart still acts like this.
She's sort of like a home tutor to me.
She teaches you stuff like mana processing, right?
Yep!
Oh, the Buster's charging up. It's almost ready.
Mama Fate's executing Thunder Rage, too!
Nanoha charges up in a funny way, doesn't she?
Like the way she waves the barrel around?
It's closer to a wide-area spell than a direct-fire spell.
You know, like how Hayate and Rein
hold their spells above their head before releasing them.
Oh, you're right.
The aim can be adjusted before firing, so when charging,
it's best to do it however is easiest to gather mana.
So as a result, it takes less time to finish charging and fire.
I get the logic, but I always end up
pointing the barrel where I want to shoot.
It might be easier for you to hold it that way, Teana.
Well, while our Center Guard was
chatting about bombardment spells...
...we've gotten to this super important part!
It's the scene where Mama Nanoha conveys
her unrequited feelings to Mama Fate.
Back then, it really was just unrequited,
but I was desperate.
On the other side of the glass,
Fate is trying to hide behind Erio and Caro.
She's getting embarrassed. Why's that?
Oh, here comes the famous line.
Here it comes!
Ready, set...
"I want to be... friends!"
No, no, no, I didn't say it like that!
Sorry, we just...
And watching the two are Chief Yuuno and Arf.
Oh, looks like there's another alert.
It's an attack from Ms. Presea.
Stuff like dimensional interference and
transdimensional attacks are pretty impressive.
Yes, definitely.
She sure is showing her strength as a conditional SS rank.
Still, that attack was quite reckless.
You're right. She probably fired that attack
knowing it would affect her health.
Being shot at was probably scary for Mama Fate,
but it must've also been tough to think that
her mother was hurting herself because she'd failed.
You're probably right.
Really?
Ah, Fate's gone into her worried pose.
And here's the skirmish between Arf and Enforcer Chrono.
The barrier was already down,
so he could get there straight away.
So Admiral Chrono was able to snatch four Jewel Seeds
but couldn't grab all of them.
There's no reason to leave them there, after all.
Chrono came to the scene with the intention
of capturing both Arf and the Jewel Seeds.
I guess you're right.
But Arf did her best!
Right.
Chrono says that not considering Arf's ability to escape
despite having lost her once already was a mistake.
It's really hard to catch someone
trained in teleportation magic.
It would've been easier if I'd managed to help him.
Nanoha was more concerned with Fate, after all.
Ah, Mama and Chief Yuuno are getting scolded.
We sure are.
I'm sort of starting to feel bad, too.
Commodore Lindy's words really do pierce your heart...
Let's take this opportunity for the Stars Team
to reflect on our mistakes!
Reflecting!
Um... there's some sort of strange
group reflection happening...
Well, it's only the middle of the chapter,
but we'll be swapping out some members.
It's because this chapter is quite long.
So Erio, swap with me!
Right!
And I'm swapping with Caro.
Excuse me.
And I'll be joining as an extra.
Yep! Welcome!
We wanted to ask Mama Fate
about the Testarossa family, too.
Yeah.
Ah, this is actually right when they talk about my mother.
The Presea that we see in these photos are
from when she was quite young, aren't they?
Yeah, it's data from Alectrosha, the company where she worked, so this would be back when Alicia was still alive.
Presea looked like such a normal, nice person back then.
That's what makes the next scene even harder to watch.
It's too painful to watch.
Oh yeah, this is where the really sad scene starts.
Oh... um... I'm sorry.
Presea's being so cruel!
Um... I hadn't considered it at the time, but...
Ah, yes?
It's true that my mother was really angry here,
but I think if she really only hated me,
then she would've done even more horrible things.
More horrible things?
Like maybe inflicting more serious wounds.
Do you think she might've been holding back
just so you could keep gathering the Jewel Seeds for her?
That might have been part of it.
After all, she never gave me any wounds
that couldn't be healed with basic magic.
That's true.
Of course, hitting me like that is still abuse,
so I'm not saying that she didn't do anything wrong.
Yeah.
Ah, this is the part where Arf goes to confront Presea.
I really don't like this part either.
Presea is coughing up blood.
Her illness must be getting really bad, huh?
That transdimensional attack she fired earlier
probably had an effect on her, too.
Ah, here comes Arf.
She looks really scary.
She's completely enraged.
But I can understand how Arf's feeling here. Like, "Why would you do that to a child who tries so hard for you?"
Yeah, me too.
Even now, Arf always praises us when we give something
our all, like "You sure did great!" and "Good job!"
I know, right? Erio, Caro,
have you ever seen Arf this angry before?
No, never like this.
We have been scolded before,
but she's never been scary.
Well, she's small now.
That's true.
Oh, have you two ever seen Arf in her big form at all?
I've only seen it in pictures.
I've seen it in person a few times.
When she has something to do,
she sometimes turns big again.
But normally, she says that staying small
is more comfortable and convenient.
Her clothes are mostly small now, too.
Ah, and now a shaken Arf is retreating.
I'm surprised she managed to escape from there.
I'm glad Arf's safe...
Well, I guess you can't really say she's safe,
but I'm glad she escaped alive.
Yeah, me too.
But Fate and Presea...
Ah, Arf's cape is still there.
Yeah, Fate's truly alone now.
But even then, you still wanted to help your mother, right?
Yes, that's probably what I was thinking,
but by this time, I was really hesitating.
Right...
Seishō University Magnet Elementary School
We've changed scenes again
to the school that my mamas went to.
Seishō University Magnet Elementary School
Vivio, you sometimes go to Uminari, right?
I do! We go back to play at Mama's house on Earth,
or at Alisa's or Suzuka's places!
Have you seen what their school is like?
Yeah, I've passed by it before.
After we graduated from junior high...
...we went with Hayate to see our teachers
and look around the school again.
Did it take you back?
Yeah, when we went back to our third-grade classroom,
the seats and desks were so small.
To think that we were really sitting
in those tiny things and studying on them.
I bet.
Oh right, the one who saved Arf
after she escaped was Alisa, right?
Right, it was really a coincidence,
and then she started taking care of her.
She took her to a vet right away to get treated.
Thanks to that, she recovered quickly.
Oh, so that's why, even now,
Arf thinks of Alisa as her savior.
Yep. Though for a dog lover like Alisa,
saving a wounded dog was something she'd do anyway.
Come to think of it, what happened when Arf left?
Didn't Alisa get worried when Arf just disappeared?
Oh, about that...
Someone from the Arthra staff...
Uh, who was it again?
It was Sierra.
Right, Sierra pretended to be her owner.
She was like, "That's my dog!
Thank you so much for saving her!"
Oh, I see.
We didn't know that either.
To think that there was an operation like that...
I heard about it from Arf afterwards.
There really were so many people I was indebted to.
Oh, a message from Subaru...
"After this part, the song that plays when Mama Nanoha
Hero takes 28 points of damage.
says that she wants to save Fate
is Sound Stage 01's arrangement of 'Flying High'."
Yep.
Arf is determined to assist,
and Nanoha commits to helping.
Fate, Nanoha's coming to save you soon!
Yeah.
Um... what was I doing during this time?
After I left the Garden, I went to check if Arf was okay
and to say "I'm sorry. Please wait for me."
And after that, you went back to rest, right?
Right, because I thought I'd probably
end up fighting with Nanoha.
Did you rest at your hideout condo?
Yes, that one.
What did you do after this, Nanoha?
I played with Alisa and Suzuka, went home, and
did some light training with Raising Heart, then went to bed.
Huh? You didn't arrange a time or place for the battle?
No, of course not.
No, we didn't.
Even though it looked like you were planning to meet there?
It just sort of happened.
Yep, it just happened.
Really?
Really, really.
And now this chapter is over, too.
We'll continue this discussion in the next chapter.
Eh, right. We're continuing that conversation from before.
This chapter is the last of roll 4, right before the duel.
So how did you two manage to meet up at the same
time and place without talking about it beforehand?
Well, I couldn't collect any more
Jewel Seeds without fighting Nanoha, right?
Right...
But I wasn't in a position to go searching for her to get them,
so I waited and did my best to prepare.
And I asked for a place to fight to be made for us,
since I thought that if I went there alone,
then Fate would definitely come.
Yeah, I went out thinking that I needed to be careful
about the location where we fought,
but I found her waiting for me at a really good place.
I barely had to wait since Fate arrived right after
preparations were finished, so I was actually surprised.
I-I see.
So that's how it happened.
My mamas' coincidences are sort of amazing.
I think so too.
And now, we're at the "our first and last real fight" scene.
The battle between the two will be brought
to you live by the four Forwards plus one!
No, it won't be live!
It's a commentary! A commentary!
So then, let's start the next chapter
with our serious commentary!
Hip, hip, hurrah!
E-Everyone's really into it...
Even Subaru and Teana!
Right, we're on roll 5 now.
The duel has finally begun!
The chapter title is simply "Duel".
Oh, this chapter title is also the same as the song title.
The song title was made to match what was happening
in the movie, so that's probably why.
By the way, in this footage, Amy has bed hair.
In the TV series, there's also
a slightly funny scene about that.
Right?
So why is the commentary
for this final duel being done by us?
Well, if we had Nanoha and Fate in here,
they'd be able to explain about their techniques and tactics...
...but we thought that it might not be as much fun
as our passionate commentary style.
And if we really need to find something out... Vivio?
Right! Mama Nanoha and Mama Fate
in the analysis corner, can you hear us?
Yep, this is the analysis corner.
We hear you!
We got kicked out of the room just for that?
Yep, just for that.
When necessary, please help us
with stuff like magic analysis.
Got it.
Um, please go easy on us.
Okay!
And with that, here goes
our really enthusiastic commentary!
Yeah!
And there, Nanoha cuts through the water!
She's trying to get a good angle to shoot,
but Fate doesn't let her get away!
Fate sets up her Lancers!
A shot from above and 7 o'clock behind her,
the best position for an instant down!
Nanoha dodges, dodges, dodges, and avoids it in midair!
She dodged them all!
And she does a half-loop to turn around!
She maneuvers behind Fate...
Here it comes! Divine Shooter!
The projectiles chase Fate!
She gets away from the bullets that surrounded her...
Then... with one slash, she takes out the Shooters!
Nanoha releases her last shot, but Fate dodges!
Maneuvering while accelerating and dodging a shot with
changing velocities like that is really hard, right, Teana?
And it's one coming from the front, too.
This is Fate's superior maneuverability.
But Nanoha's Shooter is...!
It's coming back! But Fate is also...!
She fires! And dodges!
Lots of action from the very start!
Nanoha crashes into a building
and passes straight through and into the sea!
I don't think she's down from just that, but...
Fate in analysis, what was that
Thunder Bullet spell you just fired?
Uh, it's a shield-breaking, high-speed projectile.
Oh! There's a light in front of Fate!
Cannon fire!
An unbelievable counterattack!
Nanoha in analysis, you took advantage of
the smokescreen to fire off a preemptive Short Buster, right?
Right, that was the plan.
It was a blind shot that relied on a lock-on marker.
If the shot had been any faster,
I might not have been able to dodge it.
Thank you very much!
Great! My mamas are into it, too!
While battling with wisdom and tactics,
Nanoha shares her feelings with her precious Device.
From here the battle gets even more fierce!
Okay, now it's time for the two from Lightning Team!
Right! Lightning commentators here!
The battle between the two has reached
its second stage, a fierce dogfight!
This time, Fate is being chased.
She skirts the buildings and the windows shatter!
Nanoha looks like she's cornering Fate,
even though she's faster. Fate, why is that?
Yes, Nanoha's very good at using space.
She'll fire in a way that makes me slow down
or force me into the center of her field of view.
I see. Now the two rise into the sky
and move into a high-altitude battle.
And here...!
Air Brake!
She overshoots and then immediately rains down
a storm of shots from the best angle!
Then a close-range attack!
Their maneuvers get tangled up and...
Clash!
And clash again!
I wonder if Nanoha has taken any damage.
Fate is catching her breath, too.
Oh, we've gone into a flashback.
This is Presea from the past, right?
Her grieving mother and fond memories of her childhood...
Those are why Fate just can't turn back.
Yes, I'm sure that's it.
Subaru and Tia from Stars,
what do you think about these memories?
A mother who thinks only of her child
and a daughter who loves her gentle mother...
It's tragic.
I can't take it either. It's awful.
Ms. Presea, after seeing the picture of
her precious daughter, seems to be reliving her past.
And now we start to see Ms. Presea's past.
That's right. Presea's flashback starts here.
It's of the most important little girl in all the worlds
to Presea and those feelings she had for her.
And those misfortunes which befell her,
or possibly her own failure.
It's that sort of flashback.
This is the Midchildan civilian power company, Alectrosha.
Presea was the Director of R&D there.
Her job keeps her busy, but with her trustworthy team,
she continues her development of a new reactor.
However, a harsh schedule change was forced on Presea
for a very unstable prototype reactor.
Presea objects...
But still, Alectrosha is her employer,
and the orders come from the top.
Even as the Director of R&D, she has to comply.
Corporate staff hijacked the research
under the pretense of "adding members to the team".
To meet the schedule, corporate staff
even took over safety regulation from Presea's team.
"To protect the company's reputation,
we need to hurry for the new reactor's test."
Because of that, the team's time ran out fast.
Presea was only able to go home late at night every day.
It seems she had a nanny come in
to look after her daughter and cat while she was out.
The only child of the family was always lonely.
The only time they had together
was right before bed and right before work.
It seems Presea was always thinking,
"Maybe it'd be better if I just quit my job."
But even so, because of her committed team
and her sense of responsibility towards the research
she'd begun, she couldn't abandon her job.
Ah, Lightning Team! Sorry to interrupt!
Yes?
The flashback's ending and we've returned to the battle!
The two mages soar through the sadness of the past!
Breaking off from the scissor, and then...!
A slash!
And another!
Fate's got some room so she reverses
direction and accelerates! Glaive Form!
Nanoha defends!
Break through!
Oh, we're going into another flashback.
Lightning Team, back to you.
Right.
Roger.
The memories of the past that sleep within Fate...
She was at home all by herself, gazing out at her
beloved mother's workplace when the accident occurred.
It shone in the distance, a bright golden flash.
It was the light from the accident at the reactor.
She awoke to a long-awaited reunion between
parent and child... or at least, it should've been.
At this time, neither mother nor daughter
knew what to expect.
They would both discover a sad reality.
A parent, child, and pet cat
with a new room and a new life...
A time they'd seen in their dreams.
But by then, the tragedy had already begun.
The mother was older and more frail
than the daughter remembered.
The young girl's speech was more cautious
and detached than in the mother's memories.
And so the mother discovers that
her dearest wish still hasn't been granted.
The girl also remembers the painful truth...
...that the name she'd been called in her memories
was different from the one that she has now.
The girl's name is Fate,
but her mother calls out for Alicia.
And we're back to the battle!
Because Fate got distracted,
she lost her grip on the shield.
It's understandable.
And Nanoha looks like she's realized
something's wrong with Fate.
Yeah, she does.
Oh, Fate executes her spell to shake off her hesitation!
Nanoha in analysis, what is this?
She's setting up Lightning Bind and Phalanx Shift.
The spears of Photon Lancer are
spreading out as if to surround her!
Nanoha tries to launch a counterattack, but...
Uh oh!
It's a bind! Nanoha's hands have been tied up!
There's no moving with that.
Chief Yuuno is surprised, too!
But Nanoha doesn't waver at all!
Oh, something happened just now!
It looks like she executed some sort of spell!
And then Fate swings Bardiche...
Ah! There was something at her feet!
Phalanx...!
Fire!
There they go!
A rain of compressed magic projectiles!
Nanoha's in trouble!
But Fate looks really serious!
Fate, the surrounding buildings are getting wrecked!
I-I went a little overboard.
Then she gathers the remaining magic
to complete the last part of Phalanx Shift...
Spark End...
Fire!
The Lancer that just left Fate's hands
flies straight on target! It hits! And then...!
Explode!
Wah, what's left of the buildings are...
W-Well, it is a finishing move after all.
Bardiche is taking a breather by letting out
some exhaust before going back to Axe Form.
Fate in analysis, all of Phalanx's shots were on target,
but how were you feeling after it?
I thought "That should've finished it. It's over, right?".
But still standing as if to dash those thoughts away is...
...a fluttering jacket and ribbon...
...a shining pink magic circle...
Nanoha is safe!
Raising Heart is fine, too!
She switches to Cannon Mode and lines up her aim!
Fate is stunned! She's speechless!
She tries to charge towards her but...
She gets stopped!
Nanoha executes Restrict Lock!
Fate's been trapped in the air!
Setting up the bind has made sure of that!
And what faces Fate is...
...a fully-charged Divine Buster!
Bombarding an opponent locked down by a bind,
the winning strategy of a long-range mage!
She takes her time to charge and target, then...
Buster!
Fate can't move!
This could be bad!
A direct hit! It's gonna be tough!
Fate in analysis, what was going on?
I was desperate to defend against it somehow.
But the cannon fire wears away
at her defenses and mana reserves!
Nanoha shoots, and Fate defends!
Keeping up such a long barrage is pretty tough, too!
The struggle between their attack and defense continues!
So who will come out on top?
Oh! Nanoha's barrage has stopped.
And her cape falls into the ocean.
Fate takes a breath of relief,
but all around her, there are tiny pinpricks of light...
Those tiny dots of light,
a countless number of them, float up towards the sky...
And what shines back down is a pink light.
Fate, Enforcer Chrono, and Amy
all stare on and gaze up at...
...a single shining star in the sky!
The wisdom and tactics prepared by Nanoha
and Raising Heart! The ace up their sleeve!
She's gathering the mana that's been scattered across
the battlefield for a bombardment spell, Starlight Breaker!
The small pink comets combine
and become a single giant star!
Fate has an expression of despair!
And now we enter the firing standby sequence!
The starlight gathers and focuses...
It's getting bigger! And bigger and bigger!
Nanoha swings Raising Heart above her head
and goes, "This attack is me at my full strength!"
"In this hand is the power to shoot through anything!
Tears, pain, destiny, and now...!"
Starlight...
...Breaker
Fire!
Ka-BOOM!
This is just crazy! The whole screen is going pink!
Could Fate possibly withstand this huge blast?!
Fate is holding on!
The perfectly fired short-range Breaker is busting through!
The shields won't hold!
Can she withstand it?!
She couldn't!
The Breaker destroys whole buildings!
Fate's been completely blown away!
It's a horrific scene for the buildings!
It's like an apocalyptic war!
This turned pretty crazy...
Mama Fate, it looks like you
fainted the instant that it hit you.
Anyone would get knocked out by something like that.
I lost consciousness as soon as it touched me.
Ah, I know that feeling.
You just can't withstand it any more.
Oh, that's right. You've both
experienced getting hit by Breakers.
We've also been hit a few times
while training with Riot Force 6.
But we've never taken a direct hit
from such close range though.
Well, with this, it's completely finished.
Nanoha heads to rescue Fate.
Fate's completely lost consciousness,
so this is a bit dangerous.
But she catches her and goes straight to...
...a safe place!
The fierce battle without a single break ends here.
How was it, Subaru?
Whoa, it was a great fight!
They sure busted out all of their biggest moves.
Teana?
As a fellow mage, I could learn
a lot of techniques and skills from it.
And you two from Lightning?
It's a shame Fate lost,
but it really was a great match.
I want to give them a heartfelt applause
for fighting with everything they had.
Thank you very much!
So then, this special sea-top battle commentary was brought to you by the four Forwards from Riot Force 6...
...and Vivio Takamachi!
Goodbye!
Uh... right...
In other words, we'll be ending
the battle commentary style.
From here, we'll continue on the way we were before.
This chapter is the beginning of roll 6.
But everyone was getting really into it.
We did, didn't we?
When Subaru and Vivio get together,
it's easy to get swept away with them.
Right?
Yeah, I know what you mean.
Subaru and Vivio are posing together
on the other side of the glass.
And Tia has suddenly gotten embarrassed
after finishing that commentary.
Nanoha is grinning as usual.
Now something dreadful is happening on-screen again.
It's my mother's attack.
A transdimensional Thunder Rage.
Being able to make an attack reach across dimensions
seems like a truly incredible skill.
To think that's actually possible...
But she could do it.
A conditional SS rank mage
with external power sources available...
Presea was an incredible mage, too.
Ever since she was a student,
she'd been interested in energy development,
so she studied a variety of related things.
I see.
But it's sad to think about the magic that she
learned for academics being used in such a way.
Yeah, it is.
Presea's location has been discovered,
and the sortie order from Commodore Lindy has gone out.
The Arthra's insertion team is deploying.
They all get teleported in there.
In the Garden, the alert system
is going off because of the intruders.
Ah, Presea is coughing up blood.
She looks like she's in a lot of pain.
Yes...
By this point, I think her sickness
had gotten much worse.
And right after this, the truth about
Presea and Fate is finally revealed.
Okay, and the teams are at the gate to the Garden.
The insertion team members are flooding in.
Commodore Lindy is watching over them, but then...
Ah, it's the captured Fate with Nanoha.
Fate looks like she's in pain.
She's holding the cracked Bardiche in her hands.
The insertion team has gotten to Presea.
Normally, she would've been arrested here, but instead...
They seemed confident that they could take her.
Ms. Presea had no actual experience
as a combat mage, after all.
Yeah, but she has access to the energy from the reactor,
so even if they tried to suppress her,
she could fight back. And sure enough...
She can take them all out in an instant, right?
Right, and that's what really happens.
And now we finally see Alicia appear.
That's Alicia's body, right?
It looks like she's just sleeping.
Yeah. Whoa, Ms. Presea is getting really mad!
Throwing such a large man with a single arm...
Was that done with physical enhancement magic?
Probably.
But if you use body enhancement carelessly,
the strain afterwards is really bad.
By this point, she probably wasn't even thinking
about what might happen later.
And now, we learn the secret
of Fate's creation from Presea.
I didn't think that she even needed
to bring it up at a time like this.
Yeah, but maybe she thought that this
would be the last time they could talk.
That's exactly why!
If that's going to be their last conversation,
then at least carry on the lie she told until the very end.
And even if that wasn't possible,
she could've been more vague.
The lie she told?
About being Fate's mother.
Well, about that...
This is just what I think, okay?
Okay...
If I was deceived, I'd rather be completely cut off like this.
It'd be better if I was able to think of the person
who hated me as a horrible person and hate them back.
It's such a difficult thing.
Oh, this is footage of the actual incident
from when the reactor overloaded.
I feel sorry for Ms. Presea and for poor Alicia, too.
But that doesn't make it okay for her
to do horrible things to other people.
Yeah.
When you look at Alicia like this, she's really small, huh?
Her cat, Lynith, was always with her, too.
It's so painful.
Not just this. When Ms. Presea tells Fate
to be like Alicia and act a little more selfish,
and Fate really wants to,
but she's been holding back for her all this time.
It's heartbreaking.
It is. If things had gone even a bit differently,
they might've had a better connection.
Oh, a message from Fate...
"Don't turn the conversation too serious.
Let's have fun with the commentary."
Ah, sorry.
We're sorry! We just...
But even after this, the heavy themes
just keep going in the movie.
Yeah...
But okay. Even though it's a serious topic,
we'll try to address it in a positive way!
Positive thinking!
Okay, let's cover something exclusive for this.
Fate, your magic is a pretty golden color,
but what color was Alicia's magic?
Uh... "It's a lot like Subaru's, a sky-blue color."
Ah, is that so?
Oh yeah! A while ago, there was that thing about
the color of your magic being based on your personality.
Well, there wasn't any scientific basis for it.
But y'know...
Huh? Vivio seems to be really interested in this subject.
Well, then we'll continue this in the next chapter.
Right, we're in the next chapter now.
We're already on chapter 35! Wasn't that fast?
It was.
Yep. Now then, please tell us about what the color
of your magic says about your personality.
You really don't know?
Nope!
Oh, it was popular quite a while ago
so you wouldn't know.
What about Erio and Caro?
Ah, looks like they know a little.
Nanoha's group would've been just the right age, right?
Eh? Oh wait, they spent a lot of time living on Earth.
But they say that they've heard about it.
Well then, let's get into it.
I don't really remember much about it...
I'm excited!
Uh... the light blue and sky blue of Alicia's and
my magic means we're positive and optimistic.
Eh? But I think Enforcer Chrono's magic
is also that sort of blue.
Um, Enforcer Chrono's color
is more of a normal sort of blue.
Hmm... really? What does that say about him then?
Blue means serious and straight-laced.
That seems right.
Isn't Ginga blue as well?
Ginny has more of an indigo color,
so between blue and purple, I guess.
Purples have a strong sense of responsibility
and affection for their loved ones.
Ms. Presea is another purple and...
Oh, Nanoha says Reinforce was too.
Eh? Doesn't Rein have white magic?
Not Zwei, the first one.
Oh, I see. It looked sort of black, but it was purple.
I've heard that reds are passionate and direct.
It does seem that way.
Right! Like with Lt. Vita.
Lt. Signum is a sort of purply-red,
so she's both passionate and responsible.
If mixed colors are allowed, then anything goes, huh?
Oh, Caro and Fate look like they're enjoying this.
Fate's golden color is quite rare so I'm not really sure,
but yellow is kind and well-mannered.
That matches Mama Fate and Erio pretty well.
What about Caro's and Mama Nanoha's pink?
Uh... Nanoha's and Caro's pink color is...
Um... what was it again?
Wasn't it something like "virtuous and focused"?
Ah, right, right!
Nanoha and Caro are virtuous and focused!
Nanoha's color is a little more red,
so would she also be passionate and straightforward?
It's right on!
Then what about Tia and Arf's orange color?
Um... empathetic and deeply emotional.
That might be right for Arf,
but it's a bit off for me.
Eh? But Tia, you're empathetic!
And it's a mix of red and yellow so you're kind and
passionate and come off as a bit of an angry person.
Right, you're just bending the rules however you want.
And what about my rainbow color?
What would Kaiserfarbe be?
Eh? R-Rainbow means... u-um...
A bright and happy little girl!
You just made that up.
Yeah, I did.
Looks like we've used up a whole chapter
for the magic-color-personality topic.
The two of us from Lightning will be taking over here.
By the way, some colors we didn't talk about last chapter were black and gray,
which mean knowledgeable and intelligent.
It seems that white means talented at leading
while being a little clumsy, and green is compassionate.
Does any of that match you at home?
Oh, and by the way, it's not shown in the movie,
but Lynith's magic is pale yellow.
It's fun just to think about what sort of colors
make up what personalities, huh?
Yep. And this is when Lynith and Fate actually meet.
Right.
By this point, she's already identifying as "Fate".
I think this is after Presea edited the memories
that were transferred into Fate.
I see. So that's why she was in a place
that looked like a hospital room.
Yeah.
Presea still looks quite normal in these scenes.
She does. And she's still talking normally to Lynith, too.
And she wasn't doing any horrible things
to Fate back then.
Arf says Lynith definitely
wouldn't have let that sort of thing happen.
There wasn't any reason for her to get mad.
Ah, puppy Arf! She's so cute! So is little Fate!
Yeah, really!
But Presea's health was
already getting quite bad by then.
Looks like it was a respiratory illness.
Lynith got really worried and tried to
make her go to the hospital many times.
But she never went.
Oh, and here's the part...
...right after Bardiche was born!
The Device that Lynith made just for Fate.
"He's an axe, he's a glaive, he's even a glowing scythe
who can slice through anything."
Ever since they met,
he's been Fate's beloved Device.
He's still with her here today.
Looks like Bardiche couldn't talk back then.
I'm not sure.
Bardiche doesn't really say much now, either.
Looks like Presea is doing poorly.
Coughing up blood like that is a really bad sign.
Yeah...
And on that winter day...
This chapter's title is "Love".
It's simple and maybe a little ironic.
If you look at the title to chapter 30, "My Mother",
and think about it while watching, it's quite heartbreaking.
That's true.
Ah, Presea has collapsed on screen,
and Lynith has discovered Alicia.
This is where Lynith finally discovers the truth.
Lynith sure is composed.
She's accepting all those things
and trying to sway her master.
Yeah.
Lynith is trying to persuade her
by saying that they can still turn back.
This was probably the very last chance
for Presea to turn back.
Probably.
Presea could've still had the things
she'd wished for all this time,
a calm period uninterrupted by work, and a peaceful life
with a lonely girl who loves her mother.
Yeah.
Oh, Caro, don't you think it would
have been nice to meet Lynith?
Yeah, I do!
If Lynith were here with us,
what do you think she would be like?
Hmm... it's actually hard to imagine how Lynith
would interact with Fate as an adult.
Fate, what do you think?
Oh, we're getting audio too.
I think that in front of Erio and Caro,
she'd let me play the part of the adult.
But if I did something wrong,
she'd wait until we were both alone and tell me,
"You shouldn't do that.
You should be more like this or like that."
Probably something like that.
I can really see that happening.
I can easily imagine that!
Thank you very much!
But I really want everyone to be safe
and live together happily.
Sad things will still happen, but let's make sure
to walk down the right path in those times.
Yeah, I'll give it my best too.
Okay, the flashback ends around here,
and we move on to the Garden assault.
And we finally see that scene!
We're back with the whole Forward team again.
We're finally at the assault on the Garden.
This chapter is really short.
It's only about a minute.
But it's got Chrono's big scene in it.
Right, right!
Now, Nanoha faces her target with swelling determination
and prepares for the assault!
While the emergency alarm is going off, the staff of
the Arthra, Amy, and Commodore Lindy are growing tense!
Nanoha's group arrives in a corridor of the Garden
dotted with holes of imaginary number space!
They're rushing to the scene.
The holes of imaginary number space were caused
by the dimensional tremor, right?
I think so.
Normally, you would never see them that closely.
You sometimes find them on uninhabited worlds.
The whole area around them becomes a crater.
Oh, I've seen that! It's really terrifying
if you don't know about them.
Yeah.
Ah! They busted down the door!
Was that Enforcer Chrono's Blaze Cannon?
Probably.
There are a whole bunch of golems!
But Enforcer Chrono's group faces them without wavering!
They split up here.
Enforcer Chrono heads toward Presea,
and Nanoha's group goes to stop the reactor.
Will Nanoha's group be able to get there safely?
And hopefully Enforcer Chrono
doesn't get wounded too badly!
And now, we've changed locations
back to where Fate is.
Even with Arf worrying right in front of her,
Fate is still heartbroken and in total shock.
This is also really painful.
But after all that, of course she'd be like this.
Everything she'd done up till then,
after working so hard, has been for nothing.
Even though all Fate wanted
was an ordinary life with Presea,
it should've been so simple to achieve.
It's so sad how all she has is
an incomplete set of Alicia's memories.
Not being able to convey your feelings is heartbreaking.
Not being able to reach someone no matter
how hard you try or how much you care is so sad.
Fate is thinking something sad again.
Like, "Maybe I should've never been born."
But this is when she thinks of Arf,
who's always been by her side,
and about Nanoha.
Yeah, there they are meeting.
I can't take this scene. It makes me cry!
The way Fate looks as she remembers Nanoha...
Nanoha and Fate, even while fighting each other and only clashing briefly, still managed to form a connection.
Yeah. They couldn't see eye-to-eye until now,
but nothing's ended yet, and nothing's begun so...
So Fate...
Don't give up!
Don't waver!
Right!
Yeah.
And then the one who gives Fate the strength
to stand up once again is her beloved Device, Bardiche.
Bardiche is so brave and reliable here.
Bardiche is quiet but really nice.
I think his silence is one of the great things about him.
He speaks through his actions instead of words
and protects his master as her weapon at all times.
This scene is exactly that!
He's all beat up, but he shows that
he can still do it! He can still fight!
The only thing he says is the single line, "Get set."
He's such a nice guy!
After seeing Bardiche like that,
there's no way Fate wouldn't be moved.
The bond between master and servant along with
the hopes that Lynith passed onto Bardiche...
I'm sure it was a mix of all those feelings
that made Fate stand up again.
A lot of tragic things have happened, but Fate
has realized that there are still people who love her!
Fate's eyes are clear again!
And by channeling her magic into her Device once more...
...she restores the broken parts to the way they were!
Recovery!
And the insert song is starting, too!
Then here we go! Close commentary mode!
Vivio, come on!
Yes, sir!
Fate's fully prepared!
She's heading out to begin anew as her true self!
All right, here we go with our passionate commentary!
Now we're in the Garden of Time
at the spiral staircase before the reactor!
The aerial golems are attacking Nanoha's group!
With power that can almost match them one-on-one
and a number advantage, it's a bad situation!
Arf is doing her best, too.
She took down a golem with a barrier break punch!
Chief Yuuno is holding down four of them with his binds!
But it looks really tough!
And then one of them escapes!
The golem aims for Nanoha. Watch out!
Nanoha is done for!
But over there...!
A flash of lightning! Golden lights spread all over!
It's been stopped! The thrown weapon
was stopped in the air by a Lock-On Bind!
And now for the finish...
Thunder Rage
A brilliant flash!
Not even a single scrap of the golems
are left under the falling lightning!
She takes all of them out in an instant!
When they look up, they see the princely Fate!
And of course, her partner Bardiche is with her, too!
And for the first time, Fate faces Nanoha by choice!
Their eyes meet, but then...
A huge roar! They turn around and see a giant golem!
The golem goes for them!
Just from its incredible size and armaments,
you can tell it's gonna be tough!
And to top it off, it's a bombardment type!
Fate says it quietly, but clearly...
"But if we work together..."
Those words bring a smile to Nanoha's face.
The cannon fire from the golem
could take them out in one shot!
But they dodge, dodge, and magnificently dodge!
Skill, speed, and bravery!
This is the pinnacle of high-speed flight!
The golem can't catch them!
Nanoha and Fate are readying their attacks!
And here it is: Arc Saber!
The flying arc gains speed...
And hits!
And Nanoha's Divine Shooter fires!
They hit and explode!
The golem loses its main arms and starts to fall!
But it's not done yet!
It's charging its cannons!
Fate switches Bardiche to Axe Form!
And Nanoha switches Raising Heart to Cannon Mode!
Their magic circles come up, and then...!
Thunder Smasher
It hits! And then...!
Divine...
...Buster
Direct hit! Getting ready...!
"And... now!"
There they go! It's incredible!
Not a single bit of the golem gets left behind!
Ka-BOOM!
The two stand together,
their Devices aligned and venting in unison.
Just how long have we waited for this moment?
Nanoha looks at Fate,
who returns her glance with a smile.
Arf eagerly flies to meet them, too!
That sure was a wonderful battle,
wasn't it, Nanoha in analysis?
Well, um... we didn't get a chance
to analyze anything, but okay.
Thank you for the very passionate commentary.
Well, let's stop with all the ruckus now.
This is where a certain tragedy befalls Fate.
It's a very sad event...
Ah! This chapter of the commentary
will be done by the Stars pair plus one!
Presea and Fate didn't manage
to connect even in the end.
But what does everyone else remember about their mother?
It's quite recent for you, Vivio,
so you have lots of memories, right?
Yep.
What was your mother like, Tia?
Why don't you tell everyone.
Eh? Um, I'm not sure...
I hear a lot about her from people who knew her, but...
Right...
They say that I'm a lot like her.
So she was a passionate and caring mother, huh?
Oh! So fast.
Well, it seems we had the same
color of hair, eyes, and even magic.
That seems so nice.
I'm always told that I'm not very similar to my mamas.
Um... yeah, I think you already know why,
so I won't say anything.
But sometimes I get told that we're really similar!
Oh? Like how?
Our personalities.
Ah, I can see that.
Oh, Fate's just arrived on screen.
It's the confrontation between parent and child.
It's a truly sad confrontation
between Ms. Presea and Fate.
Even though it must've been so painful for Fate, she still goes to face Ms. Presea.
This scene is sad in a lot of ways.
Yeah.
Even in the end, they couldn't reach each other, so...
Just a little bit ago, Presea said that she failed to
give Alicia affection, that she couldn't show her love.
Yeah...
But I don't think that's true.
Being busy with work may have made her lonely,
but in her memories, Alicia looked so happy.
She did.
I think Alicia really loved her mama.
So even after she was gone, I think that Alicia would want
her mother to cope with her grief and start smiling again.
Maybe if they meet in heaven, that's what she'll say.
Yeah.
Maybe it would've been enough if she could've just
said one last "sorry" to Alicia and left it all behind her.
But even that could be hard.
You think so?
For some people, it's more painful to forget
their own mistakes and grief than suffer alone.
They can't leave the past behind
and let themselves be happy again.
Some people can't live any other way.
That might be it...
Maybe she could have gotten better with time,
but Ms. Presea didn't have any left.
Right.
Ah, there's a message from Erio and Caro...
"What do you think she means when
she says that she didn't notice until it was too late?"
Hmm... I'm not really sure.
Subaru, what do you think?
Well, this is just my opinion, okay?
Okay.
Yeah.
It wasn't about anything self-destructive
like trying to bring Alicia back to life...
Look, this memory of Alicia.
Ah, when she says that she wants a little sister?
Alicia's really cute here, isn't she?
Presea is too!
Yeah.
She'd managed to keep her promise to Alicia
but didn't realize it until the end.
Um, can you explain it a bit more?
Um, I'm sorry about this, Fate,
but I'm interpreting Ms. Presea's words here...
Fate isn't a "failed" Alicia
or impersonation or anything like that.
Fate's a different individual with a different personality,
but still connected to both Presea and Alicia,
like Alicia's little sister.
She actually managed to fulfill that promise to Alicia.
I see.
Ah! Sorry, Fate! I think I said too much.
Mama Fate is laughing and saying "It's okay".
But you might be right.
If Presea had just told Fate that she had
an older sister who was lost in a sad accident,
and that she was born thanks to
her older sister, then Fate...
Fate would've definitely done her best to support
her sad mother so that her sister in heaven could be proud.
Erio and Caro are both nodding furiously.
Ms. Presea and Fate...
Lynith and Arf...
When you think about how the four of them
could've been happy together...
It's really sad.
Yeah...
Ah, but while we were talking about that,
they've returned to the Arthra.
It's the scene where Fate
can't be with Nanoha yet.
We'll be handing the next chapter off to
Erio, Caro, Fate, and Nanoha.
Vivio, we'll leave it to you.
Okay!
We're counting on you!
Okay, this is chapter 43, the end of the incident.
Yep.
Fate and Arf have been imprisoned.
This is one of the Arthra's holding cells, right?
Right.
Ah, Commodore Lindy's come to see you.
Yeah.
Hey, Mama Fate, how were you feeling back then?
Well, um...
I was thinking that I'd probably get thrown in jail
and was afraid that I might be executed.
No, no, no...
An Enforcer who knows how the law works
shouldn't be thinking such scary things!
Yeah, but back then, I didn't know anything
about the legal system since I was only nine.
Haha, that's true.
Mrs. Lindy told you all about how the trial would go, right?
What did she tell you?
Well, she told me that, no matter what happened,
to remember that what I did was wrong,
but to explain all the reasons and
circumstances involved at the trial.
I see.
Mrs. Lindy was being quite casual with you.
Maybe it was so she wouldn't worry you, Fate.
Yeah, I'm sure that's it.
Ah, Mama Fate, what sort of memories
do you have of the Arthra?
They gave me the chance to obtain all sorts of qualifications,
like the mage rank test and the part-time mage certification.
The trial was still going on, but it was fun to study
different things with the crew of the Arthra.
I see.
Oh, and Mama Nanoha's gone back home to Uminari.
Yeah.
Chrono said they wouldn't need
any more help with the incident.
Oh...
But were you worried about Mama Fate?
Of course.
I worried about whether she might be crying
or that we might never meet again.
And after just a single night of such worries...
Yeah. My phone started ringing,
and I wondered what it could be about.
And when Mama looked at the little screen...
SMS
Time-Space Administrative Bureau
It was from the Bureau.
The first time I saw this, I wondered if you'd
just added them to your contact list, Mama.
No, before returning from the Arthra, Amy said...
"I'll make it so that we can communicate
through that terminal, okay?"
But I didn't think that the number display
would show it as just a normal call.
And it wasn't even a number,
but the organization's name.
Right? Apparently that was Amy's little prank.
I see!
Oh, it's almost time for the final climax scene.
Let's get everyone else in here for it.
Okay!
Excuse us.
And Mama Fate and Erio and Caro too!
It's the beginning of the last scene.
Wow! The blue sky's so pretty!
This is Uminari Seaside Park, right?
Yes, it is.
Mama Fate's waiting for you,
along with Arf and Enforcer Chrono.
And rushing to meet Fate...
...is an overjoyed Nanoha...
...with a huge smile!
Mama Fate meets her while smiling back.
Oh, I almost forgot.
This is roll 8. There's only a little bit left.
And there's only two commentary chapters left.
Yep.
Oh, by the way, the title of this chapter is...
"When I Want to See You".
It's another song name.
Their eyes meet...
Aren't they so cute?
And above that sparkling water,
the two finally get to talk with each other.
The awkward conversation is really cute
and sort of makes tears come to your eye.
Let's enjoy it.
I think we might get in the way here,
so the two of us from Lightning will go watch outside.
Ah, then I should too.
Eh?!
Fate's already getting out of her seat!
Ah! Why? Fate, wait up! Wait! Wait!
But... it's just... so embarrassing.
But we'd still like to get some commentary
from you at a few points, Fate.
Well, okay.
Hey, is there anything special about the ribbons
that you two were wearing?
Ah, mine were just a set that I bought myself.
Back then, they were my favorite pair,
so I wore them for important events.
So they were your battle ribbons, huh?
Something like that.
What about Fate's?
Well, we didn't really have much from when we left Mid,
so they were something I took from my room on the Garden.
So they were from Lynith?
Yeah, I think Lynith bought them for me.
They were so pretty that it seems like a waste
to wear them, so I never really used them.
Oh, I see.
I also use the ones I got from Nanoha very sparingly.
I still have them now.
Me too.
Ah, it's time for that line from Nanoha.
It's the title of this chapter and the title of the song too, "Call My Name".
We've talked about it in the other chapters too,
but calling someone's name is an important beginning.
Yeah, that's what I think.
Yeah, me too.
It shows that they're not just some stranger.
Like, I call Vivio by her name.
Yep.
And the same for Subaru.
It's a way of saying "I know who you are,
and I want to talk to you."
A lot has happened,
but the two girls who were finally able
to call each other's names and become friends
are still so close fourteen years later.
It's such a nice story!
On screen, Nanoha is so happy that
Fate called her name that she's crying.
Well, I was really happy.
Fate's hand was so warm,
and so was the way she smiled and called my name.
Fate's wiping away Nanoha's tears.
She's so sweet!
She's so cool!
Ah, Nanoha's hugging her!
I was so happy that she reciprocated.
I still remember that warmth from when she embraced me.
Ah, Mama Fate's getting embarrassed over there,
even though it's nothing to blush over!
Lots of things had happened,
but it's great that Nanoha and Fate
were able to connect and become friends!
It was. I was the happiest of all.
Ah, through her embarrassment,
Fate is signalling "Me too."
That's right. Mama Nanoha and Mama Fate meeting
was the beginning of a lot of things after all.
Yeah, it really was.
And there are also observers present.
Arf is really crying a lot.
There's no such thing as too many tears of happiness.
Anyways, the next chapter is the last one for the commentary.
So stick with us for a bit longer!
So then, Nanoha and Fate
were able to reach a heartfelt understanding.
But it's already time for their farewell.
And this long commentary that we've joined in for
will be heading into its finale as well.
Yep.
But it went so quickly! Has it been two hours?
Did we talk that much?
Well, we had changeovers, too.
Everyone did their part.
Yeah. So then, Tia...?
The final ending theme,
the last piece before the main theme of the movie...
"Make a Little Wish!"
We'll be finishing at that song.
Then Erio, Caro, come back!
Fate, you too!
We'll do the last farewell with all of the members.
Erio, Caro, go ahead.
Okay, the instrumental version of the TV series'
ending theme has started playing.
The movie version's commentary will be ending here.
The song playing is
"Little Wish ~Lyrical Step~ Instrumental and Strings Mix".
"Because you were there for me,
I'm able to smile and doing well."
It's a song with the sentiments of a brief parting in it.
After finishing that two hour commentary,
how are our main commentators doing?
I feel like we really went overboard.
I thought it was fun! What about you, Caro?
I thought so too! It was a really valuable experience.
It sure was!
What about our three guests? Vivio, how was it?
Commentating was really fun!
Right?
And Fate?
Being able to talk about it so much and remembering
how I felt back then has been really refreshing.
Thank you so much.
Nanoha!
I'm feeling really nostalgic and really happy.
Thank you very much.
Okay, then can we have the signal from you two?
Right. So then, everyone...
I hope we'll be able to meet again.
One, two...
See you later!