A sudden incident has befallen me,
Nanoha Takamachi,
a girl who was supposed to be an ordinary third-grader.
I accepted the courage within my heart,
and I gained magical powers.
Feelings that miss each other, words that don't link together...
Is fighting the only thing that I can do to link them together?
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha
will now begin.
Cradling my knees in a corner of my room
I always shivered from uncertainty
I was scared of learning the truth,
so I closed the door
I found my own place within a kind lie and I fled inside my dreams
I dye a sea of loneliness that nobody knows of into a deep blue
An intense feeling to hide the loneliness
Is continually injuring your heart
The secret hidden deep within the eyes
To the truth behind the smile that draws me in
I will deliver a love so soft
Right now, a warmth that might break upon touching it
Parts itself from the past, and overflows
I'll be by your side forever
Do not be lured into the somber shadows
I'm sure it all started from one coincidence.
But many coincidences overlap each other.
I was choosing my path,
taking care to not make mistakes.
I think that's how everyone spends their days.
The current days of my life may have begun just by coincidence.
That's why I want to keep moving ahead,
without making any mistakes.
By my own will,
according to my own feelings.
Episode 5
This is a Town of Hot Water,
Uminari Hot Springs!
Okay!
It's vacation season all over Japan!
Café Midoriya is always open, but during vacation season,
sometimes we entrust the café to the employees
and go off on small family vacations.
This time, we're on a trip with all of my friends.
My big brother, his girlfriend
Shinobu Tsukimura,
and the maids from the Tsukimura family,
are with us as well.
For two nights we'll be soaking in hot springs, close to home.
The usual Takamachi vacation plan,
to ease the fatigue of everyday life.
Look, look, so much green!
You're so right!
It's just like the gardens in my house!
Nanoha!
You have to unwind during a vacation,
if nowhere else!
I know that.
It's okay!
I've been thinking too much about
that mage in black who I met last week
and not having been able to find any Jewel Seeds since,
so Yuuno recommended that I should take time off and rest a bit.
So big!
At least for the next two days,
I'm going to act like all the other kids my age.
I'm planning to play as much as I can!
Ladies' Bath
Sorry to keep you waiting!
Shall we go?
Have you ever soaked in a hot spring, Yuuno?
Uh... well... I've been to
a public bath before, but...
Hot springs are wonderful!
Really?
Nanoha!
I think, after all...
Er... I think I'll go to the men's bath
with Kyōya and Shirō.
It's okay! Let's go in together!
Fantastic!
Amazing! It's so spacious!
It is amazing!
Really!
Sis, let me wash your back!
Thank you, Suzuka.
Then I will too!
Thanks.
Then I'll give you a wash!
No need to worry!
I'm really good at washing things!
Holidays like this are so nice.
Yeah, you're right.
Now that we can let the youngsters
tend to the café for a bit...
And our kids are all so full of energy.
And you too.
Yes, I guess I am.
It took quite a while.
I'm sure I won't be worrying you or our kids anymore, Momoko.
Right, from now on,
Midoriya's owner is what I'll always be.
Yes. Thank you, honey.
Here you go.
Thanks.
But Noel, you're not on duty today,
so you can relax, you know?
Right, I am relaxing right now!
Then, Miyuki, Shinobu,
we're going to go on ahead!
Okay!
I'm going to go roam around the inn
a bit with Nanoha and Alisa!
Okay. See you later.
Now, let's go, Yuuno!
That really felt good!
Since we've washed off the sweat
shall we play some ping-pong?
Ping-pong?
Oh, I wanted to go see what souvenirs they had.
What should we do?
Which should we do first?
Why not play rock-paper-scissors to decide?
Hi, kiddies!
Are you the one who did the you-know-what to my girl?
You don't look too smart or strong.
You look like an ordinary kid.
Nanoha, do you know her?
No.
It seems she doesn't know you.
Who are you?!
Uh-huh...
Sorry, sorry!
I guess I was thinking of the wrong person.
You really look like a girl I know.
Oh, I see, that's what it was.
That's such a cute ferret!
Yes!
There, there! Pet, pet!
For now, I'm just going to say hello.
Let me warn you.
Kids should behave themselves
and play at home!
If you're being a bad girl,
you'll get bitten, got that?
Well then, I think I'll go take another bath!
Nanoha...
Yeah.
Yeah?
What was that?
Well... that was a really strange person.
Is she drunk this early in the day?!
She's creepy!
Alisa...
Now, now, this is a place to relax,
so there's all sorts of people here!
But you should know how to be modest!
Modest, I say!
Oh, hello, Fate?
This is Arf.
I went and took a look at that girl in white.
I see. How was she?
Well, she's not much of anything.
She's no match for you, Fate.
I see. I've gotten a small lead too.
I've determined the general location of the next Jewel Seed.
I think we'll be able to capture it tonight.
Nice going, Fate!
Nothing less from my mistress!
Thanks, Arf.
Let's meet up again tonight.
Sure!
Relax, relax!
Whoops.
Oh, no!
You think this will be fine?
And they lived happily ever after.
Oh, Falin. Are all the kids asleep already?
Yes, Mrs. Momoko.
They're sound asleep.
Thank you, Falin.
No, it's something I'm doing because I want to.
Yuuno, are you awake?
Yeah.
Does that woman from earlier have something
to do with that girl from the other day?
Probably.
Are things going to end up
like the other day?
Probably...
Nanoha, you know,
I've thought about it since that day.
And I think, after all, I should...
Stop!
If you finish that sentence,
I'll get mad!
You were going to say,
"I should do the rest from here by myself."
"I can't get you involved in this any further, Nanoha," right?
Yeah.
Collecting the Jewel Seeds...
At first I was just helping you out, Yuuno.
But now it's different.
It's something that I'm doing because I want to do it.
If you tell me you want to leave me behind and do it by yourself,
I'll get mad at you.
Okay.
Let's get some sleep.
There might be something
going on again tonight.
Yeah...
Bingo!
I've found it, Fate!
Nanoha...
It's all right! Let's hurry, Yuuno!
Raising Heart, please!
Standby, ready. Set up.
Wow, this is an amazing one!
Is this what you call the power of Lost Logia?
Though its condition is
very incomplete and unstable, yes.
Why does your mom want something like that, anyway?
Who knows?
I have no idea,
but the reason doesn't matter.
My mother wants them,
so I need to obtain them.
Bardiche, wake up.
Yes, sir.
Sealing Form, set up.
I'm going to seal it. Arf, back me up.
Sure thing.
That's...
That's two.
Oh, my, my, my!
Didn't I tell you that kids should behave?
What are you going to do with that Jewel Seed?!
It's a dangerous item!
Who knows?
I don't see any reason to answer that.
Besides, I was nice and told you, right?
That if you didn't behave,
you'd get bitten!
Just as I thought!
She's that girl's familiar!
A familiar?
That's right,
I'm a magical lifeform this girl uplifted.
In return for living on through my creator's magical powers,
I use my life and all my power to protect her!
Go home ahead of me.
I'll catch up to you soon.
Don't be reckless.
Okay!
Nanoha, please go after the girl!
As if I'd let you!
I'll make sure it happens!
Teleportation magic?! Not good!
A barrier and a translocation spell...
You have a good familiar with you.
Yuuno isn't what you call a familiar!
He's a dear friend of mine!
Well, what are you going to do?
Isn't there a way that we can somehow talk this out?
I must collect these shards of
Lost Logia, the Jewel Seeds.
And if you have the same goal as I do,
then we are enemies, who must fight over the Jewel Seeds as a prize.
That's why!
So that we don't quickly jump to that conclusion,
I think we need to talk everything out first!
Just talking it out...
I'm sure mere words won't change anything.
You wouldn't get it!
Flier Fin
But that doesn't mean that...
Let's make a bet.
We'll each stake one Jewel Seed.
Photon Lancer, get set.
Don't just scurry and sneak away!
What is a mage powerful enough
to make a familiar doing in this world?!
And what does she know about these
Lost Logia... the Jewel Seeds?!
Stop babbling!
Thunder Smasher
Divine Buster
Raising Heart, please!
All right.
Nanoha is powerful!
But she's too soft.
Scythe Slash
Nanoha!
Put out.
Raising Heart, what are you doing?!
I'm sure she's a good one who cares greatly for her mistress.
Let's go home, Arf.
Nothing less from my mistress!
See you later, kiddo!
Wait!
If it's at all possible,
never appear before us again.
If there's a next time,
I might not be able to stop myself.
Your name...
What is your name?
Fate.
Fate Testarossa.
Um... I'm...
Bye-bye!
Make a little wish
Even though at times
I'll trip or get lost
Because you're with me, I can continue to smile and be energetic
Ah, going over the sea of cellophane and over the forests
Passing through the silver wind
I was looking for something neither of us had
Ah, I was just crying inside a diorama of a city
Until I met that warm hand that reached out to me that day
Among the swaying days,
I felt a strong gaze
Hey, I finally, finally found the secret key
Make a little wish
Collecting the lemon-colored drops from the moon
I want to keep a light shining on the road that you travel down
Make a little wish
I wonder if there is something I can do even though I'm so little
Because you're with me, I can continue to smile and be energetic
Next Episode Preview
Nanoha is hiding something from us.
We can't do anything about that.
There are things that you can't tell even your friends about.
The events of the past are coming to light.
What are the destinies of the two magical girls
who meet one another once again?!
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha:
Episode 6
Feelings That Can't Be Understood?
Episode 6: Feelings That Can't Be Understood?
Lyrical, magical, hoping I can reach her...