A sudden incident has befallen me,
Nanoha Takamachi,
a girl who was supposed to be an ordinary third-grader.
I was handed a red gem, and with it
I was given magical powers.
Coincidences led by new meetings start to move in silence.
So that I don't look down on the days where one stands up and fights...
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha
will now begin.
Cradling my knees in a corner of my room
I always shivered from uncertainty
I was scared of learning the truth,
so I closed the door
I found my own place within a kind lie and I fled inside my dreams
I dye a sea of loneliness that nobody knows of into a deep blue
An intense feeling to hide the loneliness
Is continually injuring your heart
The secret hidden deep within the eyes
To the truth behind the smile that draws me in
I will deliver a love so soft
Right now, a warmth that might break upon touching it
Parts itself from the past, and overflows
I'll be by your side forever
Do not be lured into the somber shadows
Good evening, this is
Nanoha Takamachi!
I'm usually an ordinary third-grader, but lately,
all sorts of things have been going on.
Standby, ready.
Lyrical, magical...
Jewel Seed, Serial XX...
Seal!
Sealing
Nanoha, thanks for the hard work.
Well, I'm now working as what you'd call a magical girl.
Nanoha, are you all right?
I'm all right, but I'm a bit tired.
Nanoha! Nanoha, are you all right?
Episode 3
The City's in a Lot of Danger?
Nanoha, it's morning.
You should get up soon.
Today's Sunday, so let me sleep in just a bit more.
Nanoha!
I'm Nanoha Takamachi, a third-grader.
Thanks to an introduction and a series of coincidences,
I met Yuuno, who is a mage from another world.
During the day,
I'm an ordinary schoolgirl,
and at night, I'm a magical girl,
searching for the Jewel Seeds, which Yuuno is looking for.
Confirmation.
It's been one week since I met Yuuno.
We've collected a total of five Jewel Seeds.
I seem to be getting the hang of this magical girl thing, but...
Nanoha, for today, you should take care and rest up.
But...
We're taking a break today.
You already found five for me,
so you need some rest, or you won't last.
Besides, you have a promise to keep today, right?
You're right.
Then today we'll take a break from the search for Jewel Seeds.
Yeah.
Today, the soccer team that my father, Shirō Takamachi,
owns and coaches—Midoriya JFC—has a game.
Alisa, Suzuka, and I promised that we'd all
go to the game to cheer the players on.
Now that a lot of the stands are getting full,
would you like to start the game?
Shall we?
Go for it! Everyone, do your best!
This is one of the sports on this world, right?
Yeah, that's right. It's called soccer.
You kick the ball with your feet,
and you score a point when you get it into the opponent's goal.
Only the one in front of the goal is allowed to use his hands.
I see... it looks like fun.
Amazing goalie!
Really!
Get upfield, get upfield!
Are there sports like this on the world where you come from, Yuuno?
There are, but I was so engrossed in research and excavation
that I didn't play much of anything.
Just like me! I'm not too good at sports.
Midoriya
Sakuradai
Game set! Midoriya JFC wins, 2-0!
Awright!
Alright, all of you did a great job!
That was a great game, just like in practice!
Yes, sir!
Then, to celebrate this victory, let's have a feast!
You know, upon a second look,
don't you think this guy's a bit different from a ferret?
Come to think of it, maybe you're right?
The vet also said that he was slightly different from usual.
Well, I'm sure he's just a slightly different ferret.
Here, Yuuno, shake!
How cute!
He's so smart!
So cute!
Isn't he great?!
I'm sorry, Yuuno.
Good boy!
I'm fine...
Thanks for the meal!
Thank you so much!
Everyone, today you did a fantastic job!
Let's practice hard again next week,
and win the next tournament just like we did today!
Yes, sir!
Then that's it for today! All of you, be careful on your way home!
Thank you very much!
Good job, guys!
Good job today!
You too.
Was that my imagination, or...?
Oh, that was amusing!
Here, Nanoha!
Huh?
Now, I guess that's it for us today as well?
Yes, I think so.
That's right. We all have things to do this afternoon.
I'm going out with my sister.
I'm going shopping with Papa!
That's great! Tell me all about it on Monday.
Oh, you guys are calling it a day as well?
Oh, Dad!
Thank you so much for inviting us today!
The game was really cool!
Thanks to both of you, Suzuka and Alisa, for cheering us on.
If you're going home, would you like me to drive you?
Oh no, I'm getting picked up.
Same here!
I see. What about you, Nanoha?
I'll go home and relax!
I see.
Dear old dad's getting a quick bath at home, then it's back to work.
Would you like to come home with me?
Sure!
See ya later!
See you tomorrow!
Nanoha, did you grow taller again?
Dad, you asked me that just the other day!
I don't grow that quickly!
I see...
Nanoha, if you're going to bed, at least change out of your clothes.
You should get some rest too, Yuuno.
I'm going to take a nap until dinner.
Using magic when you're not used to it must be very tiring after all.
If only I were a bit more reliable...
You were amazing today too.
No, that's not true.
See, we always have good defense.
But you were really cool!
Oh, that's right!
Here.
It's pretty!
I think it's just a normal stone, but since it was so pretty...
Nanoha?!
Did you feel that?
What's up, Nanoha?
Want to come in with me?
Sorry, Dad, maybe next time!
I'm gonna go out for a bit!
Is that so? See you later...
Raising Heart, please!
Standby, ready. Set up.
How terrible...
A human probably activated it.
When someone with a strong will
activates it by wishing hard into it,
the Jewel Seed displays the strongest amount of power.
So it really was that boy that had it!
I had noticed it, too!
I might have been able to stop all of this before it happened.
Nanoha...
Nanoha?
Yuuno, what should I do at a time like this?
Yuuno!
Right.
You have to get close to it in order to seal it.
First, you have to find the root area for all of this.
But when it spreads out to such a large area,
how do you search for it?
So I just have to get to the root of it all, right?
What?
Area Search
Lyrical, magical...
Search for the root of the misfortune!
I found it!
Really?!
I'll seal it right away!
It's impossible from here!
You have to get closer!
I can do it! It's all right!
Right, Raising Heart?
Shooting Mode
Set up.
Go and catch it!
Standby, ready.
Lyrical, magical...
Jewel Seed, Serial X...
Seal!
Sealing
Receipt No. X
Mode release.
Thank you, Raising Heart.
Goodbye.
Long-range magic even I couldn't use...
Just how much magical talent does this girl have?
We troubled all sorts of people this time.
What?
What are you talking about?
Nanoha, you're doing a fine job!
I'd noticed that he had it.
But I thought it was just my imagination.
Nanoha!
Please, don't look so sad!
In the first place, it's all my fault,
and you're just helping me out, Nanoha!
Nanoha?!
You're doing a fine job, Nanoha!
Nanoha...
My first failure since I became a mage...
It's really tough for someone to be troubled because of you.
That's what I thought when
I decided I would help Yuuno out.
Not just with my best, but with everything I have...
I decided to collect the
Jewel Seeds of my own will,
and not just to help Yuuno out.
So that something like this never happens again.
Make a little wish
Even though at times
I'll trip or get lost
Because you're with me, I can continue to smile and be energetic
Ah, going over the sea of cellophane and over the forests
Passing through the silver wind
I was looking for something neither of us had
Ah, I was just crying inside a diorama of a city
Until I met that warm hand that reached out to me that day
Among the swaying days,
I felt a strong gaze
Hey, I finally, finally found the secret key
Make a little wish
Collecting the lemon-colored drops from the moon
I want to keep a light shining on the road that you travel down
Make a little wish
I wonder if there is something I can do even though I'm so little
Because you're with me, I can continue to smile and be energetic
We all visited Suzuka's house.
She has an older sister, a maid,
and lots of cats and kittens!
But one of the kittens seems to be involved in some trouble?!
And a second mage appears!
What is her motive?
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha:
Episode 4
A Rival!? Another Magical Girl!
Episode 4: A Rival!? Another Magical Girl!
Lyrical, magical, I'll do my best!