A sudden incident has befallen me,
Nanoha Takamachi,
a girl who was supposed to be an ordinary third-grader.
I was handed a red gem, and with it
I was given magical powers.
Coincidences led by new meetings now emit light, and begin to move.
Feelings that intertwine, and the story that begins...
The start of the days where magic and ordinary life are in parallel.
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha will now begin.
Cradling my knees in a corner of my room
I always shivered from uncertainty
I was scared of learning the truth,
so I closed the door
I found my own place within a kind lie and I fled inside my dreams
I dye a sea of loneliness that nobody knows of into a deep blue
An intense feeling to hide the loneliness
Is continually injuring your heart
The secret hidden deep within the eyes
To the truth behind the smile that draws me in
I will deliver a love so soft
Right now, a warmth that might break upon touching it
Parts itself from the past, and overflows
I'll be by your side forever
Do not be lured into the somber shadows
You're kidding. What is this?!
What?!
Episode 2
My Magical Incantation is Lyrical?
What is this?
It's coming!
Protection
Our powers, called programs, are magical equations
that are embedded into executors.
The caster's mental energy is needed to execute those equations.
And that is a thought entity, created under an ominous power.
To stop its activity, you need to seal it with that staff,
and turn it back into its original form.
I don't really get it.
What should I do?
Just like what you did earlier, basic maneuvers
such as attacking and defending will happen just by wishing for them.
However, to use magic that requires a higher level of power,
you need an incantation.
An incantation?
Open your heart.
Your own incantation should come to mind within your heart.
Protection
Lyrical, magical...
What needs to be sealed away is the ominous container,
the Jewel Seed!
Seal the Jewel Seed!
Sealing Mode, set up.
Standby, ready.
Lyrical, magical...
Jewel Seed, Serial 21...
Seal!
Sealing
This is a Jewel Seed.
Touch it to Raising Heart.
Receipt No. XXI
Hey...
Is it over?
Yes, all thanks to you.
Thank you so much.
Hold on! Are you all right?! Hey!
Maybe...
It's not such a good idea for me to stay here?
For now...
I'm sorry!
I'm sorry.
Did I wake you up?
Sorry for being so rough.
Are you hurt?
My wounds are fine. They've almost completely healed already.
No kidding. Most of the wounds are gone.
That's amazing.
Because you came to help me,
I was able to use my remaining magic power to heal.
I don't really get it, but okay.
Hey, can I introduce myself?
Sure.
Ahem.
I'm Nanoha Takamachi.
I'm in third grade.
My family and my close friends all call me Nanoha!
I'm Yuuno Scrya.
Scrya is my clan name, so Yuuno would be my name.
Yuuno? That's a cute name.
I'm sorry, I got you...
Nanoha.
I got you, Nanoha, involved in all of this.
Well, that's...
Well, I think I'm okay!
Oh, that's right!
Since you're hurt, Yuuno, you can't relax here.
For now, let's go to my house.
We'll figure out the rest there, okay?
Welcome back.
Kyōya...
Where did you wander off to, so late?
Um, well, um, uh...
My, it's so cute!
Miyuki?!
Oh, it doesn't seem to be so cheerful.
Nanoha, did you go visit there because you were worried about it?
Well, um...
I understand how you feel.
But you still can't run off without telling anyone.
Come on, it's all right.
She made it back safe and sound.
Besides, Nanoha, you're a good girl,
so you won't do anything like this again, right?
Well, um... Kyōya...
I'm sorry I made you worry by leaving the house without telling anyone.
Right.
Okay, that settles everything!
This is a very cute little animal!
Wouldn't Mom roll around in panic because it's so cute?
I won't deny that possibility.
Morning, Yuuno.
Er... good morning.
Well, for starters, kudos on the hard work last night.
Likewise.
Last night, when I showed Yuuno to Dad and Mom...
It's so cute!
He's adorable! He's just too adorable!
Mom, take it easy!
This is a rather wise-looking weasel.
It's a ferret, Dad.
Can it do any tricks?
Here, shake.
It's really intelligent!
And so, the family was in a frenzy.
Afterwards, we were running around deciding on things like Yuuno's food,
so I didn't get to talk to him much last night.
Are you used to calling me by my name now?
Right, Nanoha.
The only conversation I got in was to tell him to call me by my name,
and talk to me like a friend.
Okay, I have to go to school now.
But I'd like to hear more when I get home.
That's all right. We can have a conversation even if we're apart.
Nanoha, you're already a mage.
It's like when you called for me.
Right.
Keep Raising Heart with you, and talk to me within your heart.
Let's see...
Like this?
Right. Isn't it easy?
You're right!
I'll talk to you when you have free time.
About me, about magic, about the Jewel Seeds...
Lyrical Nanoha
Good morning!
Nanoha! Did you hear about what happened last night?
Last night?
Apparently there was a car accident
at the veterinary clinic that we went to yesterday,
and one of the walls got destroyed.
I'm worried about whether that ferret is still okay.
Yeah...
Well, about that...
I see! So he's fine, and at Nanoha's house now.
But that was some coincidence.
Coming across him in the streets after he ran away from the clinic!
Right?
I'm not lying, I'm not lying!
I just fudged the truth a tiny bit.
Oh, and it seems like that ferret wasn't anyone's pet,
so we'll be taking care of him for a while.
I see!
We've gotta give him a name.
Did you already decide on one?
Yeah, he's named Yuuno.
Yuuno?
Yeah, Yuuno.
I see.
As I said in a previous lesson,
a kanji is made up of a foundation and an annex.
By combining the two parts together,
a kanji can have different meanings,
even though it is only one character.
That is because a foundation has its own meaning,
and the annex has its own meaning as well.
Examples of foundations are: the ninben which represents a human,
the sanzui which represents water, and the kihen which stands for a tree.
Now, here's a little quiz.
The Jewel Seeds are ancient artifacts in our world.
They originally were magical stones that granted wishes for their holders,
but their execution of power is unstable.
Just like last night, they go out of control on their own.
They can harm their environment in their search for a valid user.
Sometimes they go out of control using the powers
of mistaken executions by people or animals that randomly find them.
Why are such dangerous things sitting around in my neighborhood?
It's all my fault.
Back where I came from, my job is to excavate ancient ruins.
And one day, I found them in an ancient monument.
I had asked the research group to hold onto them.
However, the time-space transporter carrying them
met either an accident or some kind of artificial tragedy.
Twenty-one Jewel Seeds were dispersed all over this world.
So far, I've been able to find only two.
So there's nineteen more?
Rise!
Isn't the balsam getting much bigger now?
How many centimeters tall is it?
Wait? Hold on a second.
Listening to that story,
the Jewel Seeds getting dispersed wasn't really your fault at all, Yuuno.
But I was the one that found them,
so I have to find them all,
and return them to the place where they belong.
Just a little...
Just a little, I think I understand how you feel, Yuuno.
Yuuno, you take things very seriously.
Oh, that's right.
Did you put up signs saying these plants are under observation?
It would be quite the problem if someone plucked them out,
thinking they were weeds!
Oh, and of course, make sure to
write your name and the date you planted the seed on the sign.
Well...
I'm sorry I roped you into it last night by having to save me.
But all I want from here on is a little bit of time to rest,
until my magical powers are back to full strength.
A week...
No, five days should be enough to get my powers back,
so until then...
When they come back, what will you do?
I'll go on my search for the
Jewel Seeds again, alone.
I won't allow that.
You won't allow it?!
It's impossible for me to help you during school and cram school,
but other than that, I can help.
But there will be dangerous times, just like last night.
I mean, I've gotten to know you already,
and I've heard your story.
I can't just let you go.
Besides, if something like last night were to happen here often,
it would trouble everyone around us, right?
Yuuno, you're all alone and have nobody around to help you, right?
It's lonely to be all by yourself.
So let me help you.
If someone needs your help,
and you have the power to help them out,
you shouldn't debate whether to help or not.
That's what Dad taught me.
Yuuno, you're in trouble,
and I can help you out, right?
With the power of magic.
Yeah...
I'm not sure if I can be a proper mage or not, but...
You're already a mage, Nanoha.
I think you have much more talent for it than I do.
Really?
I'm not really sure about that myself,
but for starters, please teach me all sorts of things.
Bye-bye!
I'll do my best!
Yeah... thanks.
Okay, I'm almost home now!
For now, how about we have some snacks together?
Sure. Thanks.
I wonder what today's snack will be?
Excuse me...
Yuuno, that thing just now...
A new Jewel Seed has been executed!
It's really close by!
What should I do?
Let's head over there together.
Please help me.
Okay.
Nanoha! Use Raising Heart!
Okay!
It's already taken in one of the local creatures.
What's going to happen?!
It will be tougher, because it has a physical body!
It'll be all right, I think.
Nanoha!
Boot up Raising Heart!
How do I boot it?
Start at "I am the one who has been given a mission"! The boot password!
What?!
I can't remember such a long spell!
I'll tell you again, so repeat after me!
Got it!
Raising Heart?
Standby, ready.
Set up.
She booted up Raising Heart without a password?!
Nanoha, the protective armor!
Barrier Jacket
Nanoha!
Protect condition: all green.
No damage dealt from that blow?
Just as I thought, this girl has an amazing amount of talent.
Ouch... but it didn't hurt enough to make me say it.
Let's see. I need to do that sealing thing, right?
Raising Heart, please?
All right.
Sealing Mode, set up.
Standby, ready.
Lyrical, magical...
Jewel Seed, Serial 16...
Seal!
Sealing
Receipt No. XVI
Is this good enough?
Yeah, it couldn't have been any better.
What? Did I trip and hit my head or something?
I guess this is where you say "Thanks for the hard work"?
Yeah, that's right.
The first long day after I,
Nanoha Takamachi,
became a mage is about to end.
About my new friend Yuuno...
About magic...
About being uncertain, and what I don't understand...
All in all, there are lots of things.
Come to think of it, I'm starving.
For now, I think I just have to do my best in all sorts of things.
Make a little wish
Even though at times
I'll trip or get lost
Because you're with me, I can continue to smile and be energetic
Ah, going over the sea of cellophane and over the forests
Passing through the silver wind
I was looking for something neither of us had
Ah, I was just crying inside a diorama of a city
Until I met that warm hand that reached out to me that day
Among the swaying days,
I felt a strong gaze
Hey, I finally, finally found the secret key
Make a little wish
Collecting the lemon-colored drops from the moon
I want to keep a light shining on the road that you travel down
Make a little wish
I wonder if there is something I can do even though I'm so little
Because you're with me, I can continue to smile and be energetic
This and that as a mage, such and such as a magical girl...
I, Nanoha Takamachi, will do my best with lots of energy!
But problems are piled up like a mountain!
Next up is an incident so big it involves the entire city!
Geez, it's so tough!
Next episode of Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha:
Episode 3
The City's in a Lot of Danger?
Episode 3: The City's in a Lot of Danger?
Lyrical, magical, I'll do my best!