Under these vast skies,
there are thousands—tens of thousands—of people.
All sorts of people live their lives, harboring desires and emotions of all sorts.
Those emotions sometimes touch one another and clash with one another.
But still, a few of them are sure to bond to each other,
and can communicate with one another.
Such a story is about to begin,
one of new introductions and contacts.
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha
will now begin.
Cradling my knees in a corner of my room
I always shivered from uncertainty
I was scared of learning the truth,
so I closed the door
I found my own place within a kind lie and I fled inside my dreams
I dye a sea of loneliness that nobody knows of into a deep blue
An intense feeling to hide the loneliness
Is continually injuring your heart
The secret hidden deep within the eyes
To the truth behind the smile that draws me in
I will deliver a love so soft
Right now, a warmth that might break upon touching it
Parts itself from the past, and overflows
I'll be by your side forever
Do not be lured into the somber shadows
Melodious rhythm, turn into light!
Put those who must be stopped inside the ring of sealing!
Jewel Seed, seal!
I let it get away...
I have to go after it...
Someone...
Listen to my voice...
Lend me your power!
Magical... power...
Episode 1
Is This What You'd Call a Mysterious Encounter?
That was a pretty strange dream I just had.
I'm Nanoha Takamachi.
I go to Seishō University Magnet Elementary School,
and I'm in the third grade.
And in the Takamachi family,
I'm the youngest of three children.
Good morning!
Oh, Nanoha! Good morning!
Good morning, Nanoha.
Here, take these, please.
Okay.
These two are my father and mother.
You woke up all on your own!
Such a good girl.
This is Shirō Takamachi, my father.
He's the owner of Midoriya, a café located
across the street from the train station,
and the main pillar of our household.
Breakfast is almost ready.
And my mother, Momoko Takamachi.
She's in charge of baking
the sweets at the Midoriya café.
So beautiful and kind...
I love my mother!
By the way, Midoriya is located in the middle of the shopping strip,
across the street from the train station.
It prides itself on cakes, cream puffs, and house-roasted coffee.
It's a favorite after-school hangout for schoolgirls,
as well as for all the ladies of the neighborhood.
Where are my brother and sister?
They might be over at the dojo.
Good morning, you two!
It's time for breakfast!
Morning.
Oh, Nanoha. Good morning.
Here.
Thanks.
These two are my older siblings.
Then that's it for this morning, Miyuki.
My big brother, Kyōya Takamachi,
is a freshman in college.
He's a swordsman
following in Dad's footsteps,
and acts as coach to my sister.
Okay. Then we'll continue once
I'm done with school for the day.
And my sister, Miyuki Takamachi,
is a junior in high school.
It's tasty as ever this morning!
Especially these scrambled eggs!
Really? I topped it with tomatoes and cheese,
and a hint of basil to add to the flavor!
You're all really fortunate to have such a great chef for a mother!
Do you guys understand that?
We get it. Right, Nanoha?
Yeah.
Oh, stop it, honey!
The parents of the Takamachi family
still act like newlyweds.
Miyuki, your ribbon is all twisted up.
Wha—really?
Here, let me fix it.
And my big brother and
big sister get along really well...
But in such a loving family where everybody is paired up,
I think I'm a bit of a third wheel at times.
Good morning!
Nanoha!
Nanoha! Over here!
Suzuka! Alisa!
Morning.
Good morning, Nanoha.
Good morning.
Alisa Bunnings and Suzuka Tsukimura
have been in my class since first grade.
And this year, the three of us go to the same cram school too.
Just as I had you research,
there are many stores in this city.
Actually seeing and hearing the behavior and cleverness
of all the people who work in such stores
must have been a very educational experience for you.
Just like this, there are various jobs in all sorts of places,
so what kind of jobs would you like to hold when you grow up?
It might be a good idea to start thinking about that now.
Rise!
My future, huh...
Alisa, Suzuka,
you two know what you want to be when you grow up, right?
Both Mom and Dad run a company,
so I have to study a lot so
I can properly take over.
I like machines,
so I'm considering majoring in engineering.
I see. Both of you are amazing.
But Nanoha, won't you inherit Café Midoriya?
That's one vision for my future, but...
I have a feeling that there's something else that I want to do,
but it's not really clear what exactly that thing is.
I don't have any special traits or talents.
You idiot!
Don't say that about yourself!
That's right.
I'm sure there is something that only you can do, Nanoha.
In the first place,
your math and science grades are better than mine!
So whose mouth is blabbering that she has no talents at all, huh?!
But I'm not good at Japanese,
and I'm terrible in PE!
Both of you, stop it... come on...
Come on, already!
Something I can do...
Something only I can do?
You were amazing in dodgeball today, Suzuka.
Yeah, she was really awesome!
Oh, not at all...
Be quiet!
Over here!
There's a shortcut through here!
Really?
The path is a bit rough, though.
This is the place I saw in my dream last night.
Something wrong?
Nanoha?
No, it's nothing.
Sorry, sorry.
Are you all right?
Yeah.
Then let's go.
That's impossible.
Nanoha!
Y-Yeah!
Help me!
Nanoha?
Did you hear something just now?
Something?
Like a voice.
Not really.
I don't think I heard anything.
Help me!
Nanoha!
Nanoha?!
I think it was from over here.
What's wrong, Nanoha?!
You ran off so suddenly!
Look, an animal.
It looks like it's hurt.
Yeah... what should we do?
What should we do?
Maybe a hospital for starters?
You mean a vet!
Was there a vet around here?
Let's see... around here...
Wait, I'll try calling home.
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha
Nanoha!
Hey, Nanoha!
Okay, I'm coming right over!
Makihara Veterinary
His wounds weren't that bad,
but he seems to be very weak right now.
Maybe he's been on his own for a while.
Thank you so much, Doctor!
Thank you very much!
Oh, you're welcome!
Doctor, this is a ferret, right?
I wonder if he was someone's pet?
Is he a ferret?
He's a strange breed if he is.
And on the collar...
Is this a gem?
He woke up!
He's looking...
Nanoha, he's looking at you.
Y-Yeah...
Um... um...
It's best to let him rest for a while,
so I'll take care of him here until tomorrow.
Yes, please do!
Makihara Veterinary
So come by again tomorrow to see how he's doing, okay?
Yes, we will!
Oh no, it's time for cram school!
You're right!
Then, Doctor, excuse us...
We'll be back tomorrow!
Well, let's start with an application of what we learned last time.
Starting from the top of page 47 of the textbook.
Let's look at the sample problem.
What should we do
with this guy?
—N
The sample problem says 39/45.
What should we do
with this guy?
—N
We have dogs
running around
in our backyard...
—A
What should we do
with this guy?
—N
We have dogs
running around
in our backyard...
—A
What should we do
with this guy?
—N
Both the numerator and denominator can be divided by three.
We have dogs
running around
in our backyard...
—A
What should we do
with this guy?
—N
So it can be reduced to 13/15.
What should we do
with this guy?
—N
We have cats
in our house too.
—S
We have dogs
running around
in our backyard...
—A
We have cats
in our house too.
—S
What should we do
with this guy?
—N
We have dogs
running around
in our backyard...
—A
We handle food as our business,
so raising pets is basically out of the question.
Then let's have the answer to this question answered by...
Okay, #29, Miss Takamachi.
Okay!
Problem 3, on page 47!
Let's see... let's see...
5/42!
Yes, that's correct.
Some people stop here, thinking they've solved the problem,
Good going!
Nice!
but in this case...
I'll talk to my
family to see if we
can do something.
I'll talk to my
family to see if we
can do something.
I'll talk to my
family to see if we
can do something.
And so, that's the reason
I was wondering
if we can take care of that ferret for a while.
A ferret, huh?
By the way, what's a ferret?
It's an animal related to a weasel, Dad.
It's been popular as a pet for quite a while now.
Ferrets are small critters, right?
You know about them?
It was about this big.
If it's for a short while...
...and if you keep it in a cage and take proper care of it,
I don't mind.
Kyōya, Miyuki, what do you think?
I don't have any problems with it.
Neither do I.
And that's that.
Isn't that nice?
Yeah! Thank you!
Now, eat up before it gets cold.
Okay!
Momoko, can you pass me the salad?
Sure, here you go.
Me too.
Coming!
Alisa, Suzuka,
I have permission to raise the little guy in our house.
Let's go pick him up together after school tomorrow.
—Nanoha
Sending...
...and sent!
Can you hear me?
Can you hear my voice?
The same voice as last night's dream, and this afternoon...
Please listen to me.
You can hear my voice.
Please, lend me just a small bit of your power!
Is the little guy talking to me?
Please, come to me!
Time is... danger is... now...
Please reach her!
Makihara Veterinary
That sound again?!
That was...
What?! What in the world is going on?!
You came for me?
He talked!
Well... I really don't know what's going on here.
What in the world was that?
What's going on?!
You have talent.
Please, lend me just a small bit of your power.
Talent?
I came here from a different world,
in order to search for a certain something.
But I might not be able to make that happen with my power alone.
So, I know this will be a burden for you,
but I need someone with talent to help me out.
I will reward you. I will make sure to!
I want you to use the power that I have!
My power.... magic power!
Magic?
I will make sure to reward you!
This is no time to be talking about rewards and stuff!
What should I do?!
Take this!
It's warm.
Hold it, close your eyes, and open your mind.
Repeat after me.
Okay? Here goes!
Yeah.
I am the one who has been given a mission.
Under the contract, release your power.
Um... under the contract, release your power.
Winds in the sky, stars in the heavens.
An unvanquishable spirit...
in my heart!
Render your magic unto my hands!
Raising Heart, set up!
Standby, ready. Set up.
What magical power!
Calm down and imagine,
a magic staff that will control your powers,
and a sturdy armor that will protect you!
You say that, but everything being so sudden...
Let's see... let's see...
I think this will do for now!
Success!
What? What? You're kidding!
What is all this?!
What?!
Make a little wish
Even though at times
I'll trip or get lost
Because you're with me, I can continue to smile and be energetic
Ah, going over the sea of cellophane and over the forests
Passing through the silver wind
I was looking for something neither of us had
Ah, I was just crying inside a diorama of a city
Until I met that warm hand that reached out to me that day
Among the swaying days,
I felt a strong gaze
Hey, I finally, finally found the secret key
Make a little wish
Collecting the lemon-colored drops from the moon
I want to keep a light shining on the road that you travel down
Make a little wish
I wonder if there is something I can do even though I'm so little
Because you're with me, I can continue to smile and be energetic
Next Episode Preview
I'm Nanoha Takamachi.
I thought I was an ordinary third grader,
but by some stroke of luck or strange destiny,
I've been assigned to be a magical girl!
What kind of fate awaits me now?
And is it all right for me to raise this ferret,
whose name I haven't even asked, at my house?!
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha:
Episode 2
My Magical Incantation is Lyrical?
Episode 2:
Lyrical, magical, I'll do my best!