It was a small incident that happened to me, Nanoha Takamachi,
a girl who was supposed to be an ordinary third-grader.
I accepted the courage within my heart,
and I gained magical powers.
As my beliefs became stronger,
the unyielding wishes became stronger as well.
But I don't want to give up on communicating,
because I don't want things to end without understanding anything.
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha will now begin.
Cradling my knees in a corner of my room
I always shivered from uncertainty
I was scared of learning the truth,
so I closed the door
I found my own place within a kind lie and I fled inside my dreams
I dye a sea of loneliness that nobody knows of into a deep blue
An intense feeling to hide the loneliness
Is continually injuring your heart
The secret hidden deep within the eyes
To the truth behind the smile that draws me in
I will deliver a love so soft
Right now, a warmth that might break upon touching it
Parts itself from the past, and overflows
I'll be by your side forever
Do not be lured into the somber shadows
I've been thinking all this time.
About the girl who I'm sure is close to me in age,
and has such deep, pretty eyes.
I'm sure that we'll have another fight if we see each other again.
But...
Episode 6
Feelings That Can't
Be Understood?
That's enough!
Ever since that day, you always space out when we're talking!
I'm sorry, Alisa.
Don't apologize!
If talking to us is that boring,
you can just sit by yourself and space out as much as you want!
Let's go, Suzuka!
Alisa...
Nanoha...
It's all right, Suzuka.
That was all my fault, anyway.
I don't think that's the case.
I think Alisa said more than she should have too.
I'll go talk to her for a bit.
I'm sorry...
I made her mad.
I'm sorry, Alisa.
Alisa! Alisa!
Alisa...
What is it?
I kind of understand why you're so angry,
but you shouldn't have gotten that mad.
I mean, it irritates me!
It's plain obvious that she's worried about something.
It's plain obvious that she's in trouble!
But no matter what we ask her, she won't tell us anything!
She's lying, saying she's not confused or worried!
No matter how good friends we are,
there are things that we can't tell each other.
If it's something that Nanoha wants to keep a secret,
I think all we can do is wait for her to tell us.
I'm telling you, that's what irritates me!
I want to be of help to her, even if only by a little bit!
I don't care what it's about.
I may not be able to do anything.
But at least we can think it through with her!
Alisa, you really do care about Nanoha a lot.
Of course I do!
Because she was here, I was finally able to stop being all alone.
You're right. The same goes for me.
Because Nanoha was here, we were able to become friends.
See you, Nanoha.
I'm sorry, we both have lessons again today.
They last until late at night, right?
Take care, and do your best!
Alisa?!
It'll be all right, okay, Nanoha?
Yeah... thanks, Suzuka...
You know, it's been a while since
I last walked home by myself.
I think I'll take a detour on the way home.
Because I don't want anyone to see how I look right now...
Do you remember when we first met?
I used to be much more timid,
and I couldn't say anything that was on my mind,
and no matter what anyone said,
I couldn't argue back.
I hate to say it, but I think
I was a rotten kid.
Arrogant, selfish, boastful...
That's why I made fun of my classmates.
Because I really had a weak will.
That's...
And because I had a weak will,
I couldn't say what I needed to say.
"That is something very dear to me, so give it back."
Though people told me to stop it, I didn't listen.
I felt that I would somehow lose,
if I honestly listened to what someone else had to say.
What was it that Nanoha said back then?
"Did that hurt?"
"But the heart of someone who got something dear to her taken away"
"hurts much, much more than that."
That's right...
I think I ended up in a huge fight with you after that, Alisa.
And the one that stopped us was...
...the very quiet girl that caused it all.
Stop it!
Because I was really desperate right then...
And since then, we slowly started to talk to each other, right?
Right. The three of us...
And so, Suzuka, bringing up that old story,
what the heck do you want me to do?
As if you didn't know.
I know that she just doesn't want us to worry about whatever it is.
And that we probably can't be of any help to her, either.
If all we can do is to wait for her...
Then I'll just stay upset while waiting for her!
At the loneliness from not sharing our feelings,
and at myself for not being able to help a friend!
You're so stubborn.
Hmph!
I see. So you guys got in a fight.
It's not like that.
Alisa just scolded me because
I kept blanking out.
You're close friends, right?
Yeah, ever since we first entered school.
Here!
This is your share, Yuuno.
Since there's no cram school today,
we can take our time to search for Jewel Seeds until dinnertime!
Let's do our best together!
Yeah... let's do our best.
The food in this world...
Well, it's not that bad!
Now, where is my little princess?
Whoops, I forgot something!
Oh, you haven't eaten your meal again!
That's not good! You have to eat.
I ate, just a little. I'm fine.
Let's get going soon.
I've determined the approximate location of the next Jewel Seed.
I don't want to keep my mother waiting.
Well, Fate, you are my master,
and I am your familiar,
so if you're saying we need to go, we'll go.
We can leave after you're done eating.
That's not what I mean!
I'm worried about you, Fate!
Wide-area search magic takes a whole lot of stamina,
but you've barely been eating or sleeping!
And those wounds aren't that simple either, you know?
It's all right. I'm tough.
Fate...
Now, let's go.
My mother is waiting for us.
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha
Hey, Kyōya, about Nanoha...
Has she been worried about something lately?
Even I think that when I look at her.
It's really worrying Suzuka.
Maybe...
She's going out more often in the afternoons and evenings lately.
I don't want to meddle,
but should I try talking to her?
That would be great, but I don't think she'll tell you anything.
You don't think I'm good enough?
No, no, that's not what I mean.
It's not that she won't tell you personally, Shinobu.
I don't think she'd tell anyone.
She's always been like that when something's bothering her,
or when she's trying to decide on something.
Really?
Well, I don't think there's much you need to worry about.
I'm sure she will reach the answer on her own.
I see.
I think we're out of time.
We need to get home soon.
It's okay.
I'll stay here and search a bit more.
Yuuno, will you be all right by yourself?
I'll be fine, so save me some dinner, okay?
Okay.
Maybe Alisa and Suzuka are done with their lessons
and are on their way home by now?
There are no
new messages.
I think it's somewhere around here,
but I can only figure out the approximate location.
Yeah. When things are this crowded, it's a chore to find them.
It's a bit rough,
but I'm going to shower the area with magical power,
and force it to execute.
Hey, hold on!
I'll do that!
Are you all right?
It's pretty tiring, you know.
Just whose familiar do you think I am?
Then, please.
Here goes!
Forcing an execution in the middle of the city?!
A barrier... can I make it in time?!
Raising Heart, please!
Found it!
But they seem to be nearby too!
Let's get it over with quickly. Bardiche!
Sealing Form, set up.
Nanoha! Can you see the executed Jewel Seed?
Yeah. It's right here!
Those guys are close by.
Seal it before they do!
Got it!
Lyrical, magical!
Jewel Seed, Serial XIX...
Seal!
Device Mode
Stop it!
Neither Alisa nor Suzuka were friends with me when we first met.
Because we couldn't talk to each other,
because we couldn't understand each other.
The reason why I made Alisa mad
was because I couldn't tell her how I really felt,
what I was really thinking.
Alright! Nanoha, hurry up and capture it!
I won't let you!
Because we both have an objective,
we probably can't help clashing against each other.
But I still want to know!
I couldn't introduce myself the other day.
I'm Nanoha.
Nanoha Takamachi.
A third-grader at Seishō University Magnet Elementary School.
Scythe Form
Why do you have such sad eyes?
Flier Fin
Texting Nanoha?
Yeah. Saying my lesson is over.
Now, let's go home.
Okay... hold on a second!
I just got done with my
lesson. I'm going to go
home and have dinner
now. Alisa isn't all too
upset, so everything is
fine
I just got done with my
lesson. I'm going to go
home and have dinner
now. Alisa isn't all too
upset, so everything is
fine. Nanoha, I hope
I just got done with my
lesson. I'm going to go
home and have dinner
now. Alisa isn't all too
upset, so everything is
fine. Nanoha, I hope your
worries
I just got done with my
lesson. I'm going to go
home and have dinner
now. Alisa isn't all too
upset, so everything is
fine. Nanoha, I hope your
worries are solved
...your worries are solved soon.
Please do your best. I'll always be cheering you on.
From Suzuka.
Sending message
Flash Move
Divine Shooter
Defenser
Fate!
You said that just talking it out,
mere words, won't get the point across.
But I'm sure there are things out there that don't make it across
unless you talk, unless you put them into words!
Clashing with each other, competing with each other,
maybe that can't be avoided...
But I don't want to keep fighting without knowing anything at all!
I'm collecting Jewel Seeds because
Yuuno is looking for them.
Yuuno was the one that found the Jewel Seeds,
and Yuuno is the one that needs to collect them all back together.
I'm helping him out.
But even though it was coincidence that I started helping him,
I'm now collecting the
Jewel Seeds of my own will.
Because I don't want to see the city where I live in danger,
or all the people around me!
That's my reason!
I...
Fate, you don't have to answer that!
You don't have to tell anything to a little brat
who's lived her life surrounded by nice people!
Our primary objective is to capture all the Jewel Seeds!
Nanoha!
I'm okay!
Suzuka, what's wrong?
No, it's nothing.
There are no
new messages.
Man, I'm starving. Let's hurry home!
Okay!
Make a little wish
Even though at times
I'll trip or get lost
Because you're with me, I can continue to smile and be energetic
Ah, going over the sea of cellophane and over the forests
Passing through the silver wind
I was looking for something neither of us had
Ah, I was just crying inside a diorama of a city
Until I met that warm hand that reached out to me that day
Among the swaying days,
I felt a strong gaze
Hey, I finally, finally found the secret key
Make a little wish
Collecting the lemon-colored drops from the moon
I want to keep a light shining on the road that you travel down
Make a little wish
I wonder if there is something I can do even though I'm so little
Because you're with me, I can continue to smile and be energetic
For an explosion like that to occur...
That's just got to be bad!
But my mother is waiting.
What is the truth behind the Jewel Seeds?
And a new mage appears?!
Episode 7
Is This a Third Mage!?
Next episode of Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha:
Episode 7: Is This a Third Mage?
Lyrical, magical, hoping I won't lose!