It was a small incident that happened to me, Nanoha Takamachi,
a girl who was supposed to be an ordinary third-grader.
I accepted the courage within my heart,
and I gained magical powers.
The feelings that collided before differences were resolved
disappeared inside the bright light.
Is the path that I chose to fumble for
really the correct path?
I’m sure there will be times when I can’t decide.
But I’m sure that the footsteps where I ran without stopping
will lead toward what is to come for me.
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha
will now begin.
Cradling my knees in a corner of my room
I always shivered from uncertainty
I was scared of learning the truth,
so I closed the door
I found my own place within a kind lie and I fled inside my dreams
I dye a sea of loneliness that nobody knows of into a deep blue
An intense feeling to hide the loneliness
Is continually injuring your heart
The secret hidden deep within the eyes
To the truth behind the smile that draws me in
I will deliver a love so soft
Right now, a warmth that might break upon touching it
Parts itself from the past, and overflows
I’ll be by your side forever
Do not be lured into the somber shadows
April 26, 8:27 PM
City of Uminari, downtown, within the barrier
Fate!
Nanoha!
Episode 7
A Third Mage!?
It’s all right. You can return, Bardiche.
Yes, sir.
Fate?!
Fate!
No! That’s dangerous!
Stop...
Stop... stop...
Stop!
Fate!
Same day, 9:15 PM
City of Uminari suburbs, Takamachi residence
Nanoha
Raising Heart is a Device that
can withstand quite a bit of released power.
To think that one attack would damage her this much...
Was it the clash between that girl’s and Nanoha’s magical power?
No... besides, that doesn’t explain it all.
So it was, after all, the Jewel Seed’s...
Yuuno, is Raising Heart all right?
Yeah... she sustained extensive damage,
but I’m sure she will be all right.
She’s running her auto-repair function at full speed right now,
so I think she’ll be back up by tomorrow.
And are you all right, Nanoha?
Yeah,
because Raising Heart protected me.
I’m so sorry, Raising Heart.
Same day, same time
City of Tōmi residential area
I’m sorry, Fate.
Hang in there a little longer.
I’m fine.
Thanks, Arf.
I have to go back tomorrow to report to my mother,
so I need to heal this quickly.
I’m sure I’ll make her worry if I returned home all torn up.
Would that woman actually care?
My mother is just a little awkward.
I know that for certain.
If it’s just a report,
I can just go and do it.
My mother doesn’t really listen to what you have to say, Arf.
But you’re such a good, sweet girl, Arf.
Well... I’m sure you’ll be fine tomorrow!
In such a short time, you found Lost Logia...
Four of those Jewel Seeds!
She might not have anything good to say,
but I’m sure she won’t scold you for it!
Yeah...
You’re right.
April 27
6:15 AM, Takamachi residence
Hm? Nanoha?
Oh, Miyuki.
What’s wrong?
You’re up really early today.
Well, I just kinda woke up, so...
I see.
Hey, where’s Kyōya?
Oh yeah...
He’s gone running with Dad this morning,
a little further than usual.
Um...
Huh?
If it won’t bother you...
can I watch your practice?
I don’t think it’s very interesting.
But sure, I don’t mind.
Thanks.
Nanoha?
Yuuno?
What’s wrong?
It’s so early in the day.
I just kinda woke up, so...
Anyway, Yuuno,
I’ve been thinking.
I...
That girl...
Fate is still on my mind.
She’s on your mind?
She’s really strong,
and she seems really cold-hearted,
but she has very pretty, gentle eyes.
And yet...
Somehow, they’re very... melancholy.
I’m sure she has a reason behind it.
A reason why she’s collecting the Jewel Seeds.
That’s why I...
I want to have a good talk with her.
So... to do that...
Same day, 8:17 AM
City of Tōmi residential area, condominium rooftop
This should be enough for souvenirs.
An assortment of sweets?
Would she be happy with something like this?
I don’t know, but it’s the thought that counts.
Dimensional teleport.
Dimensional coordinates 876C4419.
3312D699... 3583A146... 779F3125.
Open, doors of luring.
To the Garden of Time, to the head of the House of Testarossa!
Same day, same time
The Dimensional Sea
Time-Space Administrative Bureau
Interdimensional Flagship
Arthra
How is everyone doing?
Is this journey going well?
Ma’am, we’re currently cruising at triple ship speed.
We will be arriving at the destination dimension
in approximately 160 bexas.
Since the last small dimensional tremor,
there hasn’t been much noticeable action,
but the danger of two seekers clashing once again is very high.
I see.
Excuse me, Captain Lindy.
Thank you, Amy.
Commodore, Time-Space Administrative Bureau
Captain of the Arthra
Lindy Harlaown
You’re right.
Even if it’s small, the creation of a dimensional tremor...
...is rather troublesome.
If it gets dangerous,
you must hurry over to the site.
Right, Chrono?
Time-Space Administrative Bureau
Enforcer
Chrono Harlaown
It’s all right. I understand, Captain.
That is the reason I’m here.
Somewhere in the Dimensional Sea
Garden of Time
Only four?
This is all but horrible.
Yes...
I’m sorry... Mom.
Look here.
Fate, you are my daughter.
The sole daughter of
the great mage Presea Testarossa.
Nothing should be impossible for you.
No matter what.
That’s right, you must accomplish everything,
no matter what the cost.
Yes.
You made me wait all this time,
and you come up with so few...
There’s no way I could have welcomed you with a smile.
You understand, right, Fate?
Yes... I understand.
That is why...
That is why I want you to remember,
so that you never disappoint your mother again.
What the hell?
What the actual hell?!
It’s too horrible!
That woman...
That woman’s—Fate’s mother’s tendencies,
and her cruelty to Fate, aren’t anything new.
But this time, it’s gone too far!
What the hell is wrong with her?!
Those Lost Logia... the Jewel Seeds...
are they that important?!
The Lost Logia are absolutely necessary in order to fulfill my dreams.
Yes, Mom.
Especially those Jewel Seeds,
which have a much higher purity than anything else.
Because you are a gentle child,
you may find yourself hesitating at times.
But if anything is getting in the way, crush it.
No matter what the cost!
Because you have the power to do so...
You’ll go for me, right?
My daughter...
My dear Fate.
Yes...
I’m on my way, Mom.
I’ll take a nap for a while.
Next time, please make sure to appease your mother.
Yes...
Fate!
Fate, I’m sorry...
Are you all right?
Why are you apologizing, Arf?
I’m fine. It’s nothing.
Because!
I didn’t think it would end up like this.
You brought back what she told you to bring back,
so I didn’t think she’d do something that cruel to you.
If I had known,
I definitely would have stopped you.
It’s not cruel.
My mother was thinking of my well-being.
The hell she was!
That... it’s nothing more than taking her anger out on you!
You’re wrong,
because we’re family.
I’m sure the Jewel Seeds are very important to my mother.
Because she’s been unfortunate and sad all this time...
I want to find some way to make her happy.
But... but still...
Arf, please.
I’m sure it will be all right.
If I come home with the
Jewel Seeds in hand,
I’m sure my mother will smile at me.
She’ll return to the kind mother that she used to be.
And I’m sure she will be nice to you too, Arf.
So let’s go.
This time...
We can’t fail.
April 27, 1:32 PM
Seishō University Magnet Elementary School
Third grade classroom 1
April 27, 4:10 PM
City of Uminari, downtown
How are you, Bardiche?
Recovery complete.
I see. You did your best. Good job.
You can feel it... even I can sense it.
There is one that will execute soon,
very close by.
April 27, 5:05 PM
City of Uminari suburbs
Raising Heart, you’re all fixed.
Thank goodness.
Condition green.
Will you do your best with me again?
All right, my master.
Thanks.
April 27, 6:24 PM
City of Uminari, Uminari Seaside Park
Time-sealing barrier...
Unfold!
It’s conceited enough to put up a barrier?
It’s the strongest one so far.
Besides...
That girl is here too.
Yuuno! Run!
Flier Fin
Please fly, Raising Heart! Even higher!
All right.
Arc Saber
Let’s go, Bardiche.
Shooting Mode
Let’s go, Raising Heart!
Shoot through it!
Divine...
...Buster
Pierce through, lightning!
Thunder Smasher
Sealing Mode, set up.
Sealing Form, set up.
Jewel Seed, Serial VII...
Seal!
It seems that we shouldn’t be jolting the Jewel Seeds.
Yeah... if something like last night happened again,
I’d feel sorry for both my
Raising Heart and your Bardiche, Fate.
But I can’t give it up.
Device Form
All I want to do is talk with you, Fate.
Device Mode
If I win...
If you can understand that
I’m not just a spoiled child,
will you listen to my story?
Stop!
Combat here is too dangerous.
I’m Enforcer Chrono Harlaown with the
Time-Space Administrative Bureau.
Would you tell me the details of this case?
Make a little wish
Even though at times
I’ll trip or get lost
Because you’re with me, I can continue to smile and be energetic
Ah, going over the sea of cellophane and over the forests
Passing through the silver wind
I was looking for something neither of us had
Ah, I was just crying inside a diorama of a city
Until I met that warm hand that reached out to me that day
Among the swaying days,
I felt a strong gaze
Hey, I finally, finally found the secret key
Make a little wish
Collecting the lemon-colored drops from the moon
I want to keep a light shining on the road that you travel down
Make a little wish
I wonder if there is something I can do even though I’m so little
Because you’re with me, I can continue to smile and be energetic
Next Episode Preview
With the emergence of Chrono,
the third mage,
and the truth of the Jewel Seeds finally unfolding,
the plot takes a big step forward?!
And I find out something that is very surprising.
Yuuno is... Yuuno is...?!
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha:
Episode 8
There’s a Really Big Crisis?
Episode 8: There’s a Really Big Crisis?
Lyrical, magical, I’ll do my best!