It was a small incident that happened to me, Nanoha Takamachi,
a girl who was supposed to be an ordinary third-grader.
I accepted the courage within my heart,
and I gained magical powers.
We met each other in the storm.
Feelings that cannot touch one another.
But even if the words don't reach,
I felt that I wanted to share the wishes, and the sadness.
There is a feeling I want to deliver to your heart,
to the only you in this world.
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha will now begin.
Cradling my knees in a corner of my room
I always shivered from uncertainty
I was scared of learning the truth,
so I closed the door
I found my own place within a kind lie and I fled inside my dreams
I dye a sea of loneliness that nobody knows of into a deep blue
An intense feeling to hide the loneliness
Is continually injuring your heart
The secret hidden deep within the eyes
To the truth behind the smile that draws me in
I will deliver a love so soft
Right now, a warmth that might break upon touching it
Parts itself from the past, and overflows
I'll be by your side forever
Do not be lured into the somber shadows
And so...
As of 0000 hours today, the entire crew's mission will be changed
to the search for and retrieval of the Lost Logia, the Jewel Seeds.
Now, concerning this case, we have made a special exception,
and welcome the discoverer of the Lost Logia,
a barrier mage...
Yes. I'm Yuuno Scrya.
And helping out his efforts, a mage from the local world...
I'm Nanoha Takamachi!
These two members will be treated as temporary staff
to help with the mission.
Nice to meet you all!
Episode 9
The Decisive Battle
Above the Ocean
We will determine the locations of the Jewel Seeds.
When we find them, we'll have you head to the site.
Okay!
Captain, your tea.
Thank you.
By the way, Nanoha,
is your school all right with this?
Yes.
I already gave an explanation to my family and friends.
And so, due to family circumstances,
Miss Takamachi will be absent from school for a few days.
But she's not out due to illness, injury, or personal tragedy,
so there's no need to worry.
While Miss Takamachi is absent,
note-taking and collecting hand-outs...
Yes, I'll do it!
Alisa, I'll leave it to you.
Okay!
Now, let's start today's homeroom!
Rise!
Bow!
Nanoha...
I wonder if she's still cheerful?
Be seated!
Caught it!
Nanoha!
Okay!
Sealing Mode, set up.
Standby, ready.
Lyrical, magical...
Jewel Seed, Serial VIII,
Seal!
Sealing.
Receipt No. VIII
Situation has been settled.
Jewel Seed No. VIII has been safely captured.
Good job, Nanoha, Yuuno.
Yeah!
I'll make a gate. Wait there.
Both of them are rather excellent.
At this rate, I might want to keep them!
This girl in black was named Fate?
Fate Testarossa.
The same family name as the great mage of yore.
Oh... is that so?
It's a story from a long time ago.
In the central region of Midchilda, during a magical experiment,
a great mage created dimensional interference and was banished.
And this has something to do with her?
Who knows? It might not be her real name.
It didn't work either. I can't find her.
Fate must be using a very efficient jamming barrier.
The canine familiar...
Most likely, she's supporting her master.
Thanks to that, two of the
Jewel Seeds that we've found
have been taken by them already.
Do a thorough search to make up for the loss.
We're counting on you.
Got it.
Fate isn't showing up.
Yeah. She seems to be collecting different Jewel Seeds.
Yeah...
It didn't work, Fate. Looks like a dud.
I see.
After all, it's pretty hard to search in hiding,
so that they can't find us.
But we should do our best for just a little longer.
And, on the tenth day after we boarded the Arthra...
We've obtained three Jewel Seeds:
VIII, IX, and XII.
And Fate and Arf found themselves two more, serials II and V.
Another six...
The last six... we haven't seen them around yet.
We have expanded the search area to cover more than just land.
Since we are near an ocean, they might have sunk into it.
Amy is searching for them, along with that girl in black.
I see.
We came up empty-handed again today.
It might take a long time to find them all.
Nanoha, I'm sorry.
Aren't you lonely?
Not really. I'm not lonely at all.
I'm here with you, Yuuno.
I'm more or less okay being by myself too.
When I was little, I was all alone a lot.
Back when I was really little,
Dad got into a huge accident at work,
and for a while, he couldn't move out of bed.
He had just opened up the café,
so it wasn't as popular as it is today, either.
So my mom and brother were always really busy.
My sister was always taking care of Dad.
So until recently, I was all alone at my house a lot.
That's why I'm kind of used to it.
I see.
Come to think of it, I don't know much about your family, Yuuno.
Yeah, I was all alone to begin with.
Really?
I didn't have parents,
but everyone in my clan took care of me.
So everyone in the
Scrya clan is my family.
I see...
Yuuno, when everything is taken care of,
let's talk a lot more about all sorts of things.
Yeah, when everything is taken care of.
When everything is taken care of...
When the Jewel Seed problem is solved...
Right... I'm sure that we...
Emergency!
A large magical reaction has been spotted
above the ocean within the search area!
What are those kids doing?!
Arcus cultus aegeas...
Swift glimmering thunder, fall under my guidance now.
Paruer zaruer brouzel...
The Jewel Seeds are probably under the ocean.
So your plan to pour a stream of electrical magic into the ocean,
to force an execution to determine their location,
isn't a mistake...
But Fate!
To pound is lightning, to echo is thunder.
Arcus cultus aegeas...
Found them...
The last six!
Pouring in this much magic, and sealing them all on top of that...
Even with Fate's magical powers,
we have to be past the limit!
Arf, please set up a spatial barrier and back me up.
Sure, leave it to me!
So no matter who comes, no matter what happens,
I'll protect her for sure!
Let's go, Bardiche. We'll do our best.
What's she's doing is so unreasonable, it's disgusting.
It's quite reckless.
She's sure to ruin herself doing that.
It's beyond the limits of how much magical power one person can emit!
Fate!
I'll hurry over to the site!
That won't be necessary.
Leave her alone, and she will ruin herself.
Even if she doesn't ruin herself,
we can smite her when all her power has been spent.
But...
We should prepare to capture her now.
Roger.
Fate! Fate!
We must always make the best choice for the situation.
Even if it seems very cruel to you, that's the reality.
But...
Go.
Nanoha, go.
I'll open the gate, so go and get her...
But Yuuno!
The fact that I want to talk to Fate
has nothing to do with you!
It may have nothing to do with me.
But I want to be of help to you, if you're in trouble.
Just like how you were for me.
You're...
I'm sorry.
Nanoha Takamachi is going to disobey orders,
and take action on her own!
Transport to a location within that girl's barrier!
Let's go, Raising Heart!
Winds to the sky, stars to the heavens.
Glimmering light to these arms...
And the unyielding soul to this heart!
Raising Heart, set up!
Standby, ready.
Don't get in Fate's way!
You're wrong! We're not here to fight against you!
Yuuno?!
That's absurd!
What are you two doing?!
I'm sorry. I'll apologize properly later for disobeying orders.
But I can't leave her alone!
I'm sure that she's all on her own!
It's lonely, being all on your own.
I understand that, even just a tiny bit!
We have to stop the Jewel Seeds first,
or we'll be in a bad situation!
So for now, support their sealing.
Fate!
Help me. Let's stop the Jewel Seeds.
Power charge.
Supply complete.
We'll split it evenly into halves!
Yuuno and Arf are stopping it for us.
So now's our chance!
When I say ready, let's both seal it in one shot!
Shooting Mode
When I was all alone and feeling lonely,
the one thing that I wanted people to do most
wasn't to ask me if I was all right,
or to be nice to me.
Sealing Form, set up.
Bardiche?
Divine Buster, full power.
You can do it, right?
All right, my master.
Ready, set...
Thunder...
Divine...
...Rage
...Buster
The sealing of all six Jewel Seeds has been confirmed.
What an irresponsible action.
But it's still amazing!
To share the same feelings...
To split the loneliness, the sadness in half...
So that's it. I finally understand.
I want to share with her.
I want to be friends with you.
Dimensional interference?!
A magical attack is headed towards our ship
and the combat air zone from another dimension!
Impact in six!
Mom?!
Fate?!
Don't get...
...in our way!
There's only three?!
They're escaping! Capture them!
It's no use!
The lightning strike has stopped the flincher from functioning!
Twenty-five seconds until all functions are restored!
We can't keep up with them!
Put up anti-magic defenses until all functions have been restored.
Prepare for the next attack!
Yes, ma'am!
And also,
we will retrieve Nanoha,
Yuuno, and Chrono.
Make a little wish
Even though at times
I'll trip or get lost
Because you're with me, I can continue to smile and be energetic
Ah, going over the sea of cellophane and over the forests
Passing through the silver wind
I was looking for something neither of us had
Ah, I was just crying inside a diorama of a city
Until I met that warm hand that reached out to me that day
Among the swaying days,
I felt a strong gaze
Hey, I finally, finally found the secret key
Make a little wish
Collecting the lemon-colored drops from the moon
I want to keep a light shining on the road that you travel down
Make a little wish
I wonder if there is something I can do even though I'm so little
Because you're with me, I can continue to smile and be energetic
The situation is reaching its final turn!
Each hold their own feelings in their heart,
in order to withstand the final storm.
And I also tell Fate how I really feel.
Next episode of Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha:
Episode 10
Everybody's Separate Heartfelt Vows
Episode 10: Everybody's Separate Heartfelt Vows
Lyrical, magical, in order to begin my true self.