Under these vast skies,
there are thousands—tens of thousands—of people,
yet there are even more hellos and goodbyes than that.
This is the story of a small incident and an encounter.
We met in the spring, when I was in the third grade.
It was a small encounter, but a precious one.
This is the story of our beginning.
You shouldn't be here.
Go back... to where you belong!
Melodious rhythm, turn into light!
Put this abomination inside the ring of sealing!
Preparing to seal.
Jewel Seed, seal!
I must... chase after it.
What a weird dream...
I'm Nanoha Takamachi, the youngest in a family of five,
and I'm a completely normal third-grader.
Good morning!
Nanoha!
Nanoha, over here! Over here!
Suzuka, Alisa, good morning.
Morning.
Good morning, Nanoha.
Even something like this is extremely important.
It helps everyone live their lives in safety.
As you can see, there are all sorts of jobs.
What kind of job do you want to have when you grow up?
It might be a good idea for you to start thinking about that right now.
My future...
What I want to do...
I'm not even sure if I have any hopes or dreams.
That's what my life is like.
It's not safe, so you should stay out.
Y-Yes, sir.
Hey, this was...
Excuse me, what happened?
Well, the dock and boats were wrecked.
We're cleaning things up now.
Oh, is that so?
This is a bit much for a prank.
We had the police come in and take a look.
Isn't this... the place from my dream last night?
Help me!
Nanoha?
Suzuka, did you hear something just now?
Hear what?
Sorry, I gotta go!
His wounds aren't deep,
but the poor thing seems to be fairly weak.
Thank you, Doctor.
Thank you very much!
Don't mention it.
He's a ferret, isn't he? Do you think he's someone's pet?
Do you really think he's a ferret?
If he is, he's an unusual breed.
Anyway, he looks like he could use some rest for a while.
Do you want me to look after him until tomorrow?
Yes, please.
Please take good care of him!
And... send.
Can you hear me?
Can you hear my voice?
Who said that?
Please, listen to me.
Whoever is listening to this... I beg of you.
Please help me.
Please.
Makihara Veterinary
There it is again!
What? What the heck is that thing?
You came for me!
Um, what's going on? What's happening?
I have a favor to ask!
Help me, just for a little while!
Please, I'll repay you!
This is not exactly the time to be talking about repaying me, okay?
I don't have enough mana to stop that thing right now.
But you, you have a chance!
Mana?
What do you need me to do?
Take this.
Hold it in your hands, close your eyes, and clear your mind.
Admin rights, new user setup function. Full open.
Repeat after me.
Winds in the sky, stars in the heavens.
An unvanquishable spirit in my heart.
Render your magic unto my hands!
Raising Heart, set up!
Standby, ready. Set up.
What an incredible amount of mana!
Welcome, new user.
Um, nice to meet you.
Your magic level qualifies you to use me.
May I select the optimum configuration
for the Barrier Jacket and the Device?
Um, for now, yes.
All right.
Standby, ready.
Barrier Jacket, set up.
It worked!
How much do you know about magic?
Nothing! Nothing at all!
Then I shall teach you everything. Please do as I say.
R-Right!
Flier Fin
Um, what is that? Some kind of creature?
No, it is not a living being. It is an entity from Lost Logia.
Protection
Your magical powers are impressive.
Incredible... she's even better than I expected.
With your mana, you'll be able to stop that thing.
Now, work with Raising Heart to seal it!
To seal, either get closer and invoke the sealing magic,
or use more powerful magic.
Um, how?
Imagine you're about to strike.
Don't make it sound so easy!
Hold out your strongest hand.
O-Okay.
Shoot the bullet.
Shoot!
It got away!
I can't catch them!
If those things reach a place where there's people, they'll...
That beam from earlier... can you make it reach far away?
If that's what you desire.
That's right.
Focus your internal spiritual heat through your arms.
Mode change: Cannon Mode
I don't believe it... a sealing cannon?
She switched her to a long-range firing mode?
Shoot in Buster mode.
Immediate fire when target is locked.
Nice shot.
She sealed them... with one blast.
These are Jewel Seeds.
Touch them to Raising Heart.
Like this?
Internalize numbers XVIII, XX, XXI.
Are you all right?
I'm okay... I think.
I don't know if you'll believe me,
but I'm not of this world. I come from another dimension.
What you used just now was called magic.
It's a technology used on my world.
Those creatures you fought
were dangerous, ancient relics from my world.
A kind of Lost Logia, the Jewel Seeds.
Jewel Seeds?
They are highly dangerous crystals of energy
that behave rather violently, as you saw.
They've been known to run rampant at the slightest provocation.
You're kidding...
What's something like that doing here?
I'm afraid... that's my fault.
For
Your
Ferret
Caring
I was working at an archaeological dig in my hometown.
I found them in some ancient ruins.
I contacted the Bureau to take them and keep them safe.
But it would seem the dimensional ship
I had arranged to transport them had an accident en route.
Twenty-one Jewel Seeds
have been scattered across this world.
I have only been able to recover the three you've assisted me with.
I'm sorry, I haven't introduced myself.
My name is Nanoha. Nanoha Takamachi.
And I am Yuuno. Yuuno Scrya.
Yuuno, huh?
Non-Administrated World #97, local designation: Earth.
The Jewel Seeds my mother is searching for are here.
Yes, sir.
Seishō University Magnet Elementary School
Raising Heart, can you hear me?
Yes, I can hear you.
All that flashy stuff yesterday...
Was that all you, Raising Heart?
Yes, mostly.
Gosh, you must be powerful.
But unfortunately, I can do little on my own.
In a sense, I'm merely a vehicle.
Without a driver, I cannot fully display my capabilities.
Will I be able to be your driver, Raising Heart?
If that is what you desire...
...and you are willing to put in the work.
Seishō University Magnet Elementary School
See ya, today is practice day for me and Suzuka.
See you later.
Sure, train hard.
Yuuno, can you hear me?
Yes, Nanoha.
Listen, about those Jewel Seeds yesterday...
This signature, it's...
Bardiche.
Get set.
Barrier Jacket, set up.
Axe Form
Nanoha! Nanoha!
Don't go! Wait until I get there!
I can't!
People and animals might get hurt!
I did just fine last night!
I have Raising Heart with me again today,
so I'm sure that it'll be okay!
Raising Heart,
I'm going to work hard and build up experience.
So tell me, what do I need to do?
I will do everything in my power.
Standby, ready.
Raising Heart, set up!
Jewel Seed, seal!
Sealing
Scythe Form
Jewel Seed, seal!
Um, excuse me! Wait!
Um, are you also looking for those? For Jewel Seeds?
Don't come any closer.
No, I... I just want to talk.
I wanted to ask if you're a mage, too.
Also... why are you looking for Jewel Seeds?
Fire!
Scythe Slash
Wait! I don't want to fight you!
Then stay clear of me and the Jewel Seeds.
I'm trying to tell you, it's Yuuno who's after those Jewel Seeds, not—
Arc Saber
Protection
Saber Explode
I'm really sorry.
Internalize No. XVI
The next time we fight, I might not be able to hold back.
Give up on the Jewel Seeds.
Nanoha!
Yuuno...
Nanoha...
I'm sorry. Are you all right?
Thank you, Yuuno.
I'm... okay.
Wide Area Search, quadrant four complete.
Arf, keep up the good work.
Fate!
Sorry to keep you working so late.
How are things on your end?
I found an unexecuted one a while ago.
I think I can scan this entire area tonight.
Thanks.
I only have the one that I sealed this evening.
Oh.
And what was the deal with
these two that you confronted, Fate?
You don't think they're from the Bureau, do you?
I don't think we've done anything yet that would put them on our trail.
I don't think so.
For one thing, she couldn't use magic properly.
I see.
Anyway, if it comes down to it, I'll beat those two up!
Don't worry about a thing, Fate!
Thanks, Arf.
Nanoha, are you sure you're all right?
I'm fine, so let me help collect the Jewel Seeds for you!
Raising Heart is giving me all sorts of pointers, too.
So please, Yuuno.
Teach me how. Teach me how to use magic.
Mommy, what's for lunch today?
Hm, what should we have?
I know, I know! Rice omelets!
What, again?
Aw, but they taste so good! Right?
I suppose they do. Well, all right.
Yay!
Thanks for waiting!
Mommy!
Do they have lots of jam inside?
You bet!
Yay! Mommy, you're the best!
Studying in progress!
Inside the heart of every mage, including me and you,
there's a mana-generating organ called a Linker Core.
Imagine that you're breathing in with your Linker Core,
collecting and condensing the ambient mana in the air.
That is application of magical power.
Commencing image training.
Speed and power are essential in combat,
but there are more important things.
Do you know what it is?
The desire not to lose?
Good answer, but what else?
Um...
Wisdom and tactics.
How to fly and shoot,
and the theory and practice of aerial combat...
I will teach you these things.
Seishō University Magnet Elementary School
You can't come again today, Nanoha?
No, sorry.
It's no big deal. It's important, right?
Sorry.
If you're gonna apologize,
it'd be nice if you'd at least explain what's going on!
Alisa...
I'm sorry.
See you. Come on, Suzuka.
Sorry, Nanoha. See you tomorrow!
Sure.
I think it's around here somewhere...
Yes, the signature is definitely...
...coming from around here.
But we can't pinpoint its exact location.
It's a bit much,
but I'll fire off a magic attack and force it to execute.
Is that a good idea?
I'll be fine.
I'm tough.
She's forcing an execution in the middle of town?!
Wide area barrier!
Raising Heart...
Please!
Standby, ready.
Found it.
They see it too. Fate!
Glaive Form, get set.
Nanoha, seal it before they can!
Right!
Raising Heart!
Cannon Mode
Divine Buster
Spark Smasher
Jewel Seed...
Seal!
Device Mode
You did it! Nanoha, hurry, grab it!
As if!
You're a...
I won't let you stand in Fate's way!
Of course she has a familiar!
I didn't get a chance to introduce myself earlier.
I'm Nanoha. Nanoha Takamachi.
A third-grader at
Seishō University Magnet Elementary School.
Scythe Form
I thought I told you to give up on the Jewel Seeds.
Be that way,
but you still haven't answered my question, have you?
You haven't told me your name, either!
Why are you collecting Jewel Seeds?!
They're dangerous!
Bag your face!
Cannon Mode, stun setting.
Shoot!
If you have a plan for them,
then it might be inevitable that we'll fight
and compete over them.
But I don't want to fight someone meaninglessly!
I'll tell you my side of the story, too.
So tell me!
Why do you need Jewel Seeds?
I'm just trying to—
Fate, you don't have to answer her!
Our job is to bring back the Jewel Seeds, remember?
Nanoha!
I'll be okay!
I'm sorry. Go back, Bardiche.
Yes, sir.
Fate?!
Fate, don't! It's too dangerous!
Stop... stop... stop...
Stop... stop...
Stop!
Fate!
Yuuno, will Raising Heart be okay?
Yes, I'm running her auto-regeneration functions
at full force right now.
I'm sorry, Raising Heart...
Sorry, Fate. Hang in there a while longer.
I'm fine. Thanks, Arf.
Nanoha?
Oh, Yuuno.
What's the matter? Why are you up so early?
Oh, I was just thinking...
Listen, Yuuno...
Go on.
I'm... I'm worried about that other girl.
That girl called Fate?
Yeah.
Her eyes seemed so lonely, somehow.
And when she fired at me, she said that she was sorry.
I'm sure there has to be a reason.
A reason why she's fighting.
A reason why she wants the Jewel Seeds.
I want to talk to her.
So to do that, I'll...
A souvenir? Sweets, you mean?
I'm not so sure this stuff is going to make her happy.
Me neither, but it's the thought that counts.
Dimensional teleport.
Destination, the Garden of Time.
Time-Space Administrative Bureau
L-Class Dimensional Cruiser
Arthra
How is everyone doing?
Is everything going smoothly?
Yes, ma'am. We're right on schedule.
There hasn't been any other suspicious activity
since that minor dimensional tremor.
It looks like the two mages who are our prime suspects
Arthra Chief of Staff/Assistant Enforcer
Amy Limietta
have ceased operations at the moment.
Commodore, Time-Space Administrative Bureau
Captain of the Arthra
Lindy Harlaown
Even if it was a small one on a non-administrated world,
we can't turn a blind eye to anyone
setting off a dimensional tremor.
Enforcer, Time-Space Administrative Bureau
Chrono Harlaown
Yes, ma'am. Let's wrap this up quickly.
These are Jewel Seeds, all right. No doubt about it.
Yes, Mom.
I'd love to compliment you on a job well done...
...but what did I say to you?
Um, you...
Did I or did I not tell you to go collect all 21 Jewel Seeds?
They are of vital importance to my research.
And in spite of all the time you've had,
you've collected only three of them?
What's that?
Um, this is for you, Mom.
If you had time to find this,
then surely you had time to do as you were told!
I'm sorry!
I'm disappointed, Fate.
You leave me no choice but to punish you.
Yes.
Why?! Why is she doing this?!
We brought her exactly what she told us to!
Those Jewel Seeds are absolutely vital
to making my dream come true.
Yes.
Now, make sure that you don't let me down.
Yes, Mom...
And so, the changing shape of the moon in the sky
is the result of how light from the sun hits it.
In this way, we only see the side...
Bardiche, how are you?
Recovery complete.
You sense it, don't you? I can, too.
Yeah. It's close.
Nanoha!
Yuuno!
Raising Heart, are you all better now?
Condition green.
Will you work with me again?
All right, my master.
Get set.
Um... Fa...te?
Fate Testarossa.
I just want to talk with you, Fate. That's all.
I won't let you have the Jewel Seeds, got it?
Neither will I.
I want to ask you the reason why.
Why are you collecting Jewel Seeds, Fate?
Why do you have such a lonely look in your eyes?
If I win, will you tell me all about it?
That's enough!
I'm Enforcer Chrono Harlaown with
the Time-Space Administrative Bureau.
The Bureau?!
Now, then. Would you tell me the details of this case?
Fate! We're retreating!
Fate?!
Fate!
Fate! Fate!
Don't!
Don't hurt them!
Enforcer Chrono, well done.
My apologies, Captain. One group got away.
That's all right.
I want to know exactly what's going on.
Bring those two aboard the Arthra immediately.
Roger.
Yuuno, what in the world is this?
We're aboard a Time-Space Administrative Bureau ship.
You there. Disengage your Barrier Jacket.
Okay.
You, too.
That isn't your original form, I take it?
Oh, now that you mention it...
I forget, Nanoha, has it been a long time since I let you see me in this form?
Yuuno, you've been a regular boy this whole time?!
Huh?
This wasn't the form that I first appeared to you in?
Pardon me, perhaps we could sort out that other matter first?
Y-Yes, of course.
Go on in.
Y-Yes, sir!
Ah, I see. So, you were the one
who uncovered those Lost Logia, the Jewel Seeds?
Yes, ma'am.
Excuse me, what are Lost Logia?
I suppose it wouldn't help
if I called them the remnants of lost worlds, would it?
You know that many worlds exist
within the Dimensional Sea, right?
Among those are worlds that evolved too far,
and not in a good way.
When a civilization discovers advanced science or technology they cannot handle,
after eventually destroying themselves,
they leave dangerous relics behind afterwards.
We use the general term "Lost Logia" for such relics.
Indeed, these are items that we of the Bureau
and the Protective Organization must strictly oversee.
The ones you and your friend here are looking for, the "Jewel Seeds",
are energy crystals of the dimensional interference type.
This dangerous type is known for using their infused magic
as a catalyst to trigger dimensional tremors.
The quake and flash of light when you and that other girl fought each other...
That was a dimensional tremor.
Even a single Jewel Seed has that kind of power.
The impact of multiple triggered at once would be tremendous.
If there were a large-scale dimensional tremor,
or even worse, a dimensional fault,
it could easily destroy a whole world, or even two.
We must prevent that at all costs.
For that reason, we are hereby taking charge of the Jewel Seed retrieval.
You should forget about all this
and go back to your respective worlds.
But we—
Now, I don't expect this to sit well with you,
coming out of the blue like this,
so why don't you two talk things over tonight,
and then we'll get a fresh start tomorrow?
Don't even think about it! If the Bureau's gotten involved,
there's nothing we can do!
We'll be fine.
No, we won't!
They might even find this place any moment now!
That old hag, your mom,
always treats you like garbage, Fate.
Don't lift another finger to help that crazy—
Don't insult my mother.
I will too! I mean, I'm worried about you, Fate...
You're my master, Fate,
and you're the most important girl in all the worlds to me.
You took me in when I'd been abandoned by my pack,
you made me your familiar,
and you've been so kind to me all these years.
I can't bear to see you cry or even be sad, Fate!
I'm sorry, Arf.
Everything you say may be true,
but I still want to make her dream come true.
And that is why Nanoha and I want you to allow us to assist you.
"Assist" us, eh?
To say nothing of my own,
I believe that Nanoha's magical ability will prove to be an effective asset to you.
We ought to prove most useful in retrieving Jewel Seeds,
as well as in countering those girls.
You've thought this through.
Sure, why not?
M-Mo—I mean, Captain?!
We'll let you help.
It always pays to have an ace up your sleeve.
Isn't that right, Enforcer Chrono?
Y-Yes, ma'am.
I've caught it! Nanoha!
On it!
Restrict Lock
Good! With the proper use of binds,
you can stop fast-moving opponents,
which also allows you to strike with major spells!
Hmm... both of them are pretty powerful.
It's no use, I just can't find them.
Our opponents are pretty skilled, too.
Since they escaped,
they've managed to steal two of the Jewel Seeds that we located.
They're really good.
No luck here either, huh?
Looks that way.
Still, we're collecting them.
And so, this is our tenth day after being brought aboard the Arthra.
We've obtained four Jewel Seeds.
And our best guess is that Fate and her friend
have obtained three.
There's just no sign of the remaining seven, is there?
We've expanded our search to areas offshore.
Emergency!
An immense mana signature was detected on the ocean's surface in the search region!
The Jewel Seed is probably in the sea around here.
I can't get a fix on its exact location,
so I'm going to fire a magical attack into the sea
to force its execution and then capture it.
But Fate, that's...
Found them...it's the last seven!
Let's go, Bardiche.
Yes, sir.
That girl is reckless beyond belief...
Fate!
Um, I need to go down there right away!
That won't be necessary.
Huh?
If we leave her to her own devices, she'll burn herself out.
And even if she doesn't burn out,
we'll hit her when she's used up all her power.
Prepare for capture!
Roger.
But...
Scythe Form
Fate! Fate!
This may seem cruel to you, but it's our best option.
But she...
Nanoha... go.
I'll open a gate, so go save her.
But what about you, Yuuno?
Just go.
What are you doing?!
I'm sorry! Nanoha Takamachi is hereby
disobeying orders and acting on her own!
Teleport to a location within that girl's barrier!
Let's do this, Raising Heart!
All right.
Winds in the sky, stars in the heavens.
A shining light in my arms...
An unvanquishable spirit in my heart!
Raising Heart, set up!
Standby, ready.
Don't try to stop Fate!
You have it all wrong!
We didn't come here to fight you two!
Yuuno?
I don't believe it! What do you two think you're doing?!
I'm sorry!
I'll apologize properly for disobeying orders later!
But I can't just stand by and do nothing!
For now, we have to stop the Jewel Seeds.
If we do nothing, they might fuse,
and this could grow into a situation that we can't deal with.
We have to stop them.
You and I have to provide support!
Fate!
Help me! Let's stop the Jewel Seeds!
Divide energy.
Charging.
Charging completed.
We'll split them evenly, right down the middle.
Yuuno and Arf are stopping them for us.
So now's our chance!
We'll seal them all on two!
Cannon Mode
I think I finally figured it out.
I know what I want to tell Fate.
What I want to talk to her about.
Glaive Form, set up.
Bardiche?
Divine Buster: Full Power
We can seal them away in one blast, right?
Of course, master.
One, two!
Thunder...
Divine...
...Rage
...Buster
Incredible! All seven were completely sealed in one blast!
That was the messiest work I've ever seen!
Sure was amazing, though.
I finally worked out what it is that I want to say to you, Fate.
I want to talk about all kinds of things with you
and share them with you.
I want to be friends.
Dimensional interference?
High-level magic is coming towards the ship
and the combat area from another dimension!
Impact in six!
Mom!
Fate!
Get out of my way!
Three?!
They're escaping! Seize them!
It's no use!
That electric shock knocked all our sensors offline!
Instructions and orders
are meant to protect the group as a whole.
By making independent decisions and taking action,
you put the people around you at risk,
not just yourselves.
You understand that, I take it?
Yes, ma'am.
Normally, you would be severely punished for this.
But in light of the fact that there was a chance of a stray fusion event,
I've decided to overlook it this time.
There will be no second time.
No, ma'am!
We're sorry.
Now comes the difficult part.
Chrono, do we have any leads?
Yes. Amy, bring it up on the monitors!
Sure thing!
Oh dear.
Indeed. She's a mage from Midchilda, just like us.
Presea Testarossa.
And that girl, Fate, is her—
During the fight, Fate said "Mom"...
Mother and daughter, eh?
Presea was employed as Director of R&D
at a civilian power company on Midchilda.
But it looks like she resigned after there was an accident.
There are court records from the trial.
How could you just stand there
when you had such a golden opportunity?!
I'm... sorry.
Fate, you're so cruel...
Are you that eager to break your poor mother's heart?
After using magic of that magnitude,
I doubt that Ms. Presea or Fate will be able to do anything for a while.
You two should get some rest, too.
But I—
Go show your family and friends a happy, healthy smile.
Yes, ma'am...
Fate! Fate!
Fate!
Just nine of them...
I can't reach Alhazred with so few.
I don't have much time left...
You're her mother, and she's your daughter, right?!
She tries so hard for you!
She works herself half to death for you!
How can you do such horrible things to her?!
You're bothering me. Disappear.
I'm sorry, Fate...
Wait just a little while for me.
Fate! Wake up, Fate.
Yes, Mom.
These nine Jewel Seeds that you obtained for me...
They're not enough.
Go get some more. For your mother's sake.
Will you do that for me, Fate?
Yes, Mom.
Seishō University Magnet Elementary School
Nanoha!
I'm glad you're feeling better!
I am. Thanks, Suzuka.
You, too, Alisa. Sorry for making you worry about me.
Well, I'm just glad that you're feeling better.
Oh, so you have to go again.
Yeah.
It must be tough.
It is. But it'll be okay!
What about after school? Wanna hang out?
Yeah, no problem!
Want to come over to my house, then?
I just got a new game.
Wow, really?
Oh, that reminds me. I found a hurt dog last night.
A dog?
Yeah. She was really big, and her fur was orange.
She was a breed that I'd never seen before.
And she had a red jewel right here, on her forehead.
I knew it, it's you, Arf!
You, huh?
How did you get hurt? Is Fate okay?
Uh-oh... is she okay?
Her injuries might be bothering her.
Why don't we let her rest?
Okay.
Yuuno! Be careful!
It's okay, Yuuno will be fine.
Nanoha,
I'll hear what she has to say, so go on ahead.
Sure.
Come on, let's have a snack!
If you're here, that means those people are watching.
They are.
I am Enforcer Chrono Harlaown with
the Time-Space Administrative Bureau.
If you're honest with us, things will go better for you.
Tell us about yourself and your mistress.
I'll tell you everything.
Hero takes 28 points of damage.
Nanoha, did you hear all that?
Yes, I heard everything.
This makes the capture of Presea Testarossa
our top priority.
What do you want to do, Nanoha Takamachi?
Well, I...
I want to help Fate.
For one thing, I still haven't gotten an answer
from when I said I wanted to be her friend.
I see.
Arf, are you all right with this?
Nanoha, was it?
You're under no obligation to help me,
but I'm begging you to help Fate.
It'll be okay. You can count on me!
What kept you, Nanoha?
Look, we're about to go on to the next level!
We've been waiting for you.
Sorry, sorry!
Take that!
Got him!
Here!
This mission to rescue Fate... what do you have in mind?
I have a few ideas about that.
This is the right place, isn't it?
Come out, Fate.
Fate! Let's stop this!
If you keep doing everything
that woman tells you to do, you'll...
I know that... but even so,
I'm her daughter!
You can't stop, Fate, but I want to stop you.
This is all about the Jewel Seeds.
Release Jewel Seeds
So let's make a bet.
We'll each bet all of the Jewel Seeds that we own.
That's when it will start.
When everything will start.
You haven't seen everything that I am and can do yet.
So to show you the real me, let's begin.
Our first and last real fight!
Looks like the battle's started, huh?
Yeah.
Is the combat zone secure?
I've set up a double barrier extending
into the sky and layered training structures.
They won't be seen,
and they can cause as much damage as they want.
I have to say, Chrono,
it's a little unusual for you to okay such a big gamble.
Nanoha winning would be the ideal outcome here,
but it doesn't really matter which one of them wins.
So, while Nanoha is buying us time by fighting Fate,
I guess I should get ready to trace her return destination.
We're counting on you. Don't let her get away.
Roger that!
But... are you sure we shouldn't tell Nanoha?
About Presea Testarossa's family and the accident?
She needs to win this.
For now, I don't want to burden Nanoha with any distractions.
Nanoha!
Photon Lancer
Fire!
Divine Shooter
Shoot!
Scythe Form
Thunder Bullet
Fire!
She is more advanced than you.
You won't beat her easily.
I'm using my wisdom and tactics to their fullest.
I even have an ace up my sleeve.
All we have to do is to go in with the desire not to lose, right?
All right, master.
If I'm beaten here,
I won't be able to help my mother.
We won't be able to go back to how things used to be.
I know I've made you suffer terribly,
but even now, you are
the most precious thing in all the worlds to me.
You are my treasure.
Mommy, will you be at work late again today?
I'm sorry.
You've always been so lonely because of me.
But once I'm done with this developmental work,
we'll be able to take a long vacation. Just the two of us.
I promised her that we'd spend time together
before she started school.
Ms. Testarossa,
the new reactor's test run
will be held in ten days.
Wait a minute! The test was scheduled for next month!
It's been decided.
But it's a new design! There's a chance of a meltdown!
Corporate HQ is sending in extra manpower.
This matter is settled, Director Testarossa.
We'll handle the safety protocols.
If this test doesn't off go without a hitch,
the company's reputation will take a hit.
Mommy...
Mommy, will you always be working this hard?
There's a test next week.
Once that's done, I'll be able to take a little break.
Honest?
You bet.
Can we go on a picnic?
We can go anywhere you want.
You promise?
I promise.
Yes. I was always thinking of myself,
causing trouble for my mother.
I remember everything that day as clearly as if it were yesterday.
Right up until the accident.
There was a flash of light in the distance
at the place my mother worked.
The next thing I knew, I was waking up,
with my mother looking down at me, crying.
She said that I'd been hurt in the accident
and had been asleep for a long time.
Look, this is your room.
Rest for a while, and when you're all better,
I'll take you on a picnic, to the amusement park,
anywhere you want.
But aren't you busy with work?
It's fine. Everything is fine now...
Mommy?
It's nothing. It's nothing at all.
Everything is fine, Alicia.
Alicia...
What do you think, Alicia? Is it good?
That's not my name.
Mom, I'm Fate.
You're so adorable,
Alicia!
I'm not—it doesn't matter.
I'll win!
I'll win, and I'll go back to my mother!
A grounding bind...
And it looks like she's...
Fate!
Phalanx,
smash her to pieces!
Spark...
...End
Can you move, master?
I'm good to go, Raising Heart!
Cannon Mode
A bind? When did she...?
Divine Buster
She has to be at her limit now, too...
If I can just endure this, I can—
Starlight Breaker
I'm harnessing all the mana in the surroundings
that we've been scattering around.
A long-range bombardment attack...
This is the ace up my sleeve that Raising Heart and I
came up with, using our wisdom and tactics!
Let's see if you can take this!
This attack is me at my full strength!
Starlight Breaker
Fate!
I'm so sorry... are you okay?
Can you move?
That's enough, Fate.
I'm done with you.
High-level magic detected!
Magical wavelength detected as Presea Testarossa!
A transdimensional bombardment attack is being directed into the combat area!
Nanoha! Yuuno!
Mom?
Fate!
Spell firing location has been pinpointed!
Spatial coordinates... confirmed.
Teleportation coordinates set.
Boarding squads, move out from teleportation ports!
Your mission is to take Presea Testarossa into custody!
Intruders detected.
Many intruders now in Garden.
It can't end yet...
I have to keep my promise to my daughter...
Move out!
Presea Testarossa,
you are under arrest for violating interdimensional law
and on suspicion of attacks against the Bureau!
What the...?
Stay away from my Alicia!
Alicia...
I don't know if I'll be able to
make it there with just nine Jewel Seeds...
But I don't care. I will end it all.
All the time I've had to endure since losing my little girl
and of treating that substitute doll of her as my daughter.
Are you listening?
I'm talking about you, Fate.
I went to all the trouble of giving you Alicia's memories,
but you're only identical to her on the outside.
You're useless and utterly worthless, nothing but a doll.
At the time of the accident,
Presea lost her biological daughter, Alicia Testarossa.
There was a magic reactor meltdown caused by lapses in safety management.
Alicia was caught in the blast.
Ever since, Presea's research focused on the creation of an artificial lifeform more advanced than a familiar
and on technology to revive the dead.
Special cloning technology designed to imprint memories.
Project Fate.
You're right. That's correct.
But it was no replacement for what I had lost.
Imitated life is just that. An imitation.
Alicia looked sweeter when she smiled.
She would be self-centered sometimes,
but she always did as she was told.
Alicia was always kind to me.
Fate,
you aren't my daughter.
You're just a failure.
I don't need you anymore.
Go away. Get out of my sight!
Let me tell you something real good, Fate.
Ever since I made you,
every single moment...
I've always hated your guts.
Fate!
Fate...
T-This is bad! Look at this!
I'm getting multiple mana signatures from inside the compound!
Magic signatures are all Class A!
Total is 60... 80... still climbing!
Presea Testarossa, what in the worlds are you up to?
We are going to depart!
To the eternal city, Alhazred!
With this power, we're going to go there
and take everything back into our hands!
It's a dimensional tremor!
Tremor defenses!
Nine Jewel Seeds have been executed!
Tremor magnitude is increasing!
Wave coefficient magnifying!
At this rate, a dimensional fault will open!
Alhazred, the forgotten city...
A land where secret, forbidden spells lie hidden.
Does she hope to use those secret spells to revive the dead?
It's not her! It's not! It's just not her!
The memory imprinting worked flawlessly!
She's carrying Alicia's memories, no doubt about it!
But it's not her!
Her dominant hand is different, so is her magical ability,
and even her personality!
What went wrong? Why isn't she her?
This girl isn't Alicia...
She's just a botched product.
Alicia's body is still perfectly intact.
Her soul has left it, that's all.
A way to retrieve Alicia's soul...
That's what I have to find.
I'm about to go down a forbidden road.
What I need is something
that I can send out to do my work for me.
Of course! Of course, that's the answer!
I simply need to raise that girl,
that fake, and use her to do what I need!
I'll create an instructor, as well.
Good morning, master.
Um, am I a newborn kitten?
I have no memories whatsoever about myself.
That doesn't matter.
Familiar Lynith. Your job is
the care and education of my daughter.
Raise her to be a first-class mage.
Young miss, what is your name?
It's Fate. Fate Testarossa.
So, how is the girl—how is Fate doing?
She is certainly your daughter, Presea.
With the proper training,
she will become a mage of the highest caliber.
There is no time.
Raise her so that I can send her into the outside world as soon as possible.
Presea...
Are you sure you can't arrange
to at least spend a little more time with her?
Fate never says as much herself,
but seeing how much she loves you...
It's just so sad.
Don't make me repeat myself! Do as you're—
Presea!
I don't have much time left...
Lynith? Is this a...?
Yes, this is your Device. His name is Bardiche.
He's an axe?
He's an axe, he's a glaive, he's even a glowing scythe
who can slice through anything.
It's good to meet you, Bardiche.
Presea?
Presea, where are you?
Presea!
Presea! Are you all right?
So, you saw it.
I know about all the research you've conducted,
as well as the technologies you're looking for now.
Presea, no matter how badly we wish for it,
the dead don't come back.
It's the same with time that's been lost.
Alicia's accident was a tragedy,
but here and now, you have Fate to—
What do you know about us?
What do you know about me and Alicia?!
I don't know anything!
You were the one who made me forget!
But there's one thing that even
a familiar who was born a lynx knows!
It's still not too late to turn back.
I was always absorbed in my work...
I was never able to show Alicia
the love she deserved, not even close.
Once I was done with work,
once the day I'd promised her finally arrived,
I had always planned to give Alicia
all my time and all my love!
But...
I don't have any love to lavish on that failure!
How could I?!
Your duties,
as well as your life as a familiar,
will end when Fate's training as a mage is complete.
Go complete Fate's training and disappear.
Dimensional tremor magnitude is steadily increasing!
Abnormal activity in the Garden's power core!
Is she trying to overload the reactor
to make up for the output she's missing?
You know what that is, right, Yuuno?
Watch out for these holes.
Imaginary number space!
It's a region where you can't execute spells!
Flying spells won't work, either.
If you fall, you'll plunge head over heels forever.
Roger!
We'll split into two teams.
You seal the reactor on the top level.
What about you, Chrono?
I'm going to stop Presea!
I'm going to carve a path to her right now!
I'll head out, too!
I'll slow the progress of
the dimensional tremor in the Garden!
I'm worried about those kids,
so I'm gonna go help them for a bit.
I'll be back soon, okay?
My mother never paid any attention to me,
not even once.
It was Alicia that she missed, not me.
I'm nothing but a failure to her.
Maybe I should never have been born.
Arf and this girl...
What was her name again?
I'm sure that she told me...
We fought so many times.
I did such terrible things to her.
In spite of that, she spoke to me.
She called me by my name.
So many times, over and over...
Bardiche...
Nothing with me—between us—has even begun...
Get set.
I hadn't thought of that...
You've been at my side
this whole time, haven't you, Bardiche?
You hate the idea of things ending like this, too, don't you?
Yes, sir.
I don't know if we'll be able to pull it off,
but let's both give it our best.
Recovery complete.
Our story has yet to begin.
Looking for strength, you keep fighting
That is why, in order for me to begin to be my true self,
Remember the fleeting weakness you notice
I have to put an end to what I have been until now!
You believed, ran, and felt the loneliness
There's nothing you can rely on
Always, right next to you, tenderness was doled out
In truth, looking back I embraced that yearning
Damn! They just keep coming and coming!
There's things you can't say well...
but the message that was born at last doesn't consist of words
Nanoha!
Thunder Rage
Don't be long, during our meeting the shining courage in my heart
shone so brightly I was surprised
Thunder Rage
I wish we'd never lose to fate, now let's move out with all we have
Our miscalculation becomes clear and cuts apart the future
Fate?
The scenery passing us by is fading away
It's a heavy model. It has tough defenses.
I'll accept even my weakness and not waver now that I'm with you
Yeah.
Decide on a goal, burn your bridges...
But if we work together...
Yeah! Yeah, yeah!
and let's swear on our hearts that we won't be afraid, that we will overcome it
Don't ever give up without showing a teary face with pain
I hid and overlooked them, but with resurging feelings,
nothing will end, and facing off becomes simple
You can be proud of the joy of fighting for real every day
Our wishes increasingly became something that will come true
Bardiche!
Get set.
Raising Heart!
Lets overcome reality with our power
Standby, ready.
Don't be long, during our meeting the shining courage in my heart
Thunder Smasher
shone so brightly I was surprised
Divine Buster
I wish we'd never lose to fate, now let's move out with all we have
And... now!
Our miscalculation becomes clear and cuts apart the future
Fate...
Fate! Fate!
Arf... I'm sorry that I made you worry.
Just a little more...
Presea Testarossa.
This is the end of the line.
I'm suppressing the dimensional tremor,
the reactor will be sealed away in due time,
and there is an Enforcer headed towards you.
The forgotten city of Alhazred
and all the secret spells that lie there
have all been lost and shrouded in myth for ages.
You're wrong. Alhazred exists to this day.
The path to it lies in the gap between dimensions!
For the sake of argument, let's say that the path does exist.
What would you do there?
I'll get her back.
I'll take back Alicia's and my past and future.
I'll take back everything in all the worlds
that isn't how it's supposed to be!
Don't act like you've got this planned out!
No matter what spell you use, you can't bring back the past!
Mom!
What did you come here for?
Get out of my sight!
You're of no more use to me.
I came here because there's something that I want to tell you.
Maybe it's true that I'm just a failure and a fake.
I'm sorry that I couldn't be Alicia or live up to your expectations.
If you tell me to go away, I'll go far, far away.
But ever since you gave me life, to this day,
and for the rest of my life, one thing is true.
I want to make you smile, Mom.
If nothing else, my desire to make you happy is real.
Those are my real feelings. The feelings of Fate Testarossa.
How stupid.
Captain, it's no use! The Garden is going to fall apart!
Chrono, you and the others have to escape!
It'll collapse any second!
Roger that!
Fate Testarossa! Fate!
I'm going. I'm going with Alicia.
Mom...
Don't you remember?
I told you I hated your guts.
Mom! Alicia!
Alicia...
Alicia, is there anything you want for your birthday?
Let me think... I want a baby sister!
If I had a sister, I wouldn't be lonely when you're away,
and we could do all sorts of stuff to help you!
Well, that's true, but...
I want a sister! Promise me, Mommy!
I've always been this way, haven't I?
I never notice things until it's too late.
Alicia... Mom!
Fate!
Fate! Chrono!
We're getting out! Amy, find us a path!
Roger!
The Garden is collapsing!
All mages are all back on board,
including Enforcer Chrono.
All hands are safe!
The dimensional tremor is ending.
There are no dimensional faults.
Roger that.
Chrono...
Is something the matter?
Where are Fate and Arf?
I'm sorry. The two of them are material witnesses in this case.
They're being kept in isolation.
I can't authorize you to see them.
In any case, it won't be like this forever,
so just be patient a while. Okay?
Okay.
I've brought you your dinner.
Let's eat together.
Fate is a key figure in this case.
I doubt she's going to be acquitted.
However, she didn't know the truth.
It might sound harsh, but she was just being used as a tool.
Extenuating circumstances can be taken into account.
At the very least, we'll try to get her a suspended sentence.
Thank you, Chrono.
The thing is, trials like this can drag on forever.
That's right. Six months at the very least.
But they can last two or three years. Or longer.
Still, if you behave yourselves during that time under the care
of your legal guardian,
you'll be able to lead fairly normal lives.
Who's our legal guardian?
That would be me.
Lindy Harlaown, Captain of the Arthra.
I am now your legal guardian.
I look forward to our time together, Fate, Arf.
And so, the Jewel Seed Incident came to an end.
But the one story that hasn't ended...
The one thing that worries me
is the girl with the kind, pretty eyes.
SMS
Time-Space Administrative Bureau
Yes? Hello?
Oh, Nanoha? Sorry for calling so early.
That's okay!
According to Fate's schedule,
she's set to go to the Main Office for trial next week.
Ma'am?
So before then, I thought, maybe...
You know, for a little while...
Yes, ma'am. Yes, ma'am. Yes, ma'am!
I'll be right there!
Nanoha? What's up?
They say we can see Fate for a little while!
What, really?
She said that Fate really wants to see me!
Fate!
We'll wait over there.
Sure, thanks.
Thank you.
There was so much that I wanted to talk to you about.
It's weird, but when I saw your face, Fate,
I forgot everything I was going to say.
I... you're right.
I can't get the right words out, either.
Still, I was glad that you were so honest with me.
Yeah, I was hoping that we could be friends.
But I guess you're leaving right after this, huh?
I suppose so. It's going to be a long trip.
We'll see each other again, right?
It's a little sad,
but this will finally let me be myself.
I asked you to come so that I could give you an answer.
What you said to me.
You said you wanted to be friends.
Yeah, I did!
I wanted to tell you, "If I'm able to, if you'll have me..."
But I don't know what I'm supposed to do.
So I want you to teach me.
How do you become a friend?
It's easy.
Becoming someone's friend is really simple.
You call them by their name.
At first, that's all you need.
Not "you", or "hey, you", or anything like that.
Look them straight in the eye, and call them by their name.
I'm Nanoha Takamachi!
Call me Nanoha.
Nanoha...
Yep. That's right!
Yeah!
Nanoha!
Yeah...
Thank you, Nanoha.
Nanoha...
Yeah!
Your hands are warm, Nanoha.
I think I learned something.
If your friend is crying, you feel sad, too.
Fate!
Thank you, Nanoha.
We're going our separate ways for now,
but I know we'll meet again.
When we do, can I call you by your name again?
Yeah, yeah!
When I miss you, I'm sure to be calling your name.
So, Nanoha, I want you to call for me, too.
If you're ever in trouble, Nanoha,
I'll be there to help you this time, Nanoha.
That girl of yours...
Nanoha is a really sweet kid, isn't she?
Look at that big smile on Fate's face.
It's time. Are you ready to go?
Yeah.
Fate!
It's not much to remember me by, but it's all I have.
Then let me give you something too.
Thank you, Nanoha.
Yes, Fate...
We'll meet again.
Yeah, I know we will.
Thank you! You take care too, Arf.
I will. Thanks for everything, Nanoha, Yuuno.
I should say goodbye as well.
I hope I see you soon too, Chrono.
Sure.
Bye-bye! Until we meet again.
Chrono.
Arf.
Fate.
Nanoha?
Yeah, I'm fine.
I know we'll see each other again soon.
I won't forget your eyes on the day we met for the first time
I understood soon that you're special
The sunlight through the leaves quivered
You see, my heart is so meek it's sad
Why is it that my words pass you by and dissolve without reaching you?
my wish my love, the things I thank you for become more and more
I'd accept the flowers because I want to make a bouquet of them,
but you can't carry them here
The feelings I couldn't tell you or reach you
through my very special smile
my wish my love
I've always been looking for a place
filled with true smiles
I reflected the future in
that faint warmth
and couldn't move
I put my hopes into
an invisible tomorrow...
rather than repeat the night
that makes me feel uneasy
I want to protect that little bit
of happiness I have right here
My clear, blue eyes are fixed
on the nameless sky of stars
Only I know of it,
and write down
their coordinates
But still, even if we really
did disappear
into impenetrable
darkness...
I'll never lose
the memories
that lead me to you
"Tell me...?"
You touched the door
to my heart
for the first time
I got used to spending
my time alone
before I knew it
The pain stabbing
my chest,
the feelings
that won't reach you...
I lied so you
wouldn't notice them
I thought that
there shouldn't
be a reason
in loneliness
The miracle of
meeting you that day...
is connected to
the prologue of a story
no one can imagine
Who cares if the words
are cliché, I want
to tell them to you
as soon as possible
I'm flying to you
"Let's go...", I won't
hesitate anymore
Somewhere, I wished
for an end
I don't even know
the destination...
but I hear your voice
It's the beginning,
I tell you
My clear,
blue eyes
are fixed on the
nameless sky of stars
I draw the coordinates
of the secret
only us two know about
The miracle of
meeting you that day...
is connected to
the prologue of a story
no one can imagine
Who cares if the words
are cliché, I want
to tell them to you
as soon as possible
I'm flying to you
I'll always be by your side...