A sudden incident has befallen me,
Nanoha Takamachi,
a girl who was supposed to be an ordinary third-grader.
I accepted the courage within my heart,
and I gained magical powers.
New introductions guided by magic...
Are they coincidence, or are they destiny?
Right now, I'm not sure which.
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha
will now begin.
Cradling my knees in a corner of my room
I always shivered from uncertainty
I was scared of learning the truth,
so I closed the door
I found my own place within a kind lie and I fled inside my dreams
I dye a sea of loneliness that nobody knows of into a deep blue
An intense feeling to hide the loneliness
Is continually injuring your heart
The secret hidden deep within the eyes
To the truth behind the smile that draws me in
I will deliver a love so soft
Right now, a warmth that might break upon touching it
Parts itself from the past, and overflows
I'll be by your side forever
Do not be lured into the somber shadows
The Lost Logia are in this area?
The form is a blue gem.
Normally called a Jewel Seed.
Right.
I'll have them in my hands in no time.
Episode 4
A Rival!? Another Magical Girl!
Here, Yuuno, over here!
Good job! Yuuno, you're so smart!
Still not ready, Nanoha?
Sorry! Just a bit longer...
Going out somewhere today?
Yeah, to the Tsukimuras' house.
Apparently, Nanoha got an invitation from Suzuka.
Oh, I see.
And you, Kyō, are going to go see Shinobu.
Well, my main purpose is to keep an eye on Nanoha.
Sorry to keep you waiting!
Then let's go.
We're barely going to catch the bus as it is.
Okay.
Yuuno, over here!
Okay, see you later!
We're on our way!
Today, we're planning a tea party at Suzuka's house.
I'm going to spend my day off
with Alisa and Suzuka.
And my brother is going to go see
Suzuka's older sister Shinobu.
No, it's nothing...
I see.
Welcome, Mr. Kyōya, Miss Nanoha.
Yeah. Thanks for the invitation.
Hello!
This is Noel, the head maid of the Tsukimura family.
She doesn't talk much, but she's so beautiful and so cool!
Please, this way.
Nanoha, Kyōya!
Suzuka!
Nanoha, welcome!
This is Falin.
She's Suzuka's personal maid.
She's a very bright and kind lady!
Welcome, Kyōya.
Yeah.
My brother and Shinobu have been classmates since high school,
and they really get along nowadays.
Shall I go prepare the tea?
What would you like?
I'll leave it up to you.
And for you, Miss Nanoha?
I'll leave it up to you too.
As you wish. Falin?
Yes, roger, sister.
Then Kyōya and I will be in my room.
Right, I will bring it over there.
Morning!
Yeah! Morning!
Suzuka's sister and Nanoha's brother
are as lovey-dovey as ever!
Yes.
My sister has seemed very happy ever since she got to know Kyōya.
I wonder if it's the same for my brother?
But compared to the past,
I think he's gotten a bit nicer.
I think he laughs a lot more now.
Oh, yeah, thanks for inviting me today.
Same.
Not at all. Thank you for coming today.
You seem to be cheerful enough today.
Nanoha, you haven't been too cheerful lately.
If there is something that is worrying you,
we'd like you to tell us.
At least, that's what the two of us were saying.
Suzuka... Alisa...
Yuuno!
Ein, stop that!
Here, sorry to keep you waiting!
Strawberry milk tea and cream cheese cookies!
Falin, look out!
Safe!
Suzuka, Nanoha, I'm so sorry!
There she goes again.
That girl is so troublesome.
Your house is cat heaven, just like always, Suzuka.
But the kittens are really cute!
Yes...
There are a couple of them that found new parents,
so I have to say goodbye to them.
I see. That's a bit lonely.
But I'm happy that the kittens will grow up.
I guess so.
Nanoha!
Yeah. It's really close by!
What should we do?
Well...
I got it!
Yuuno?!
Oh, my... Is something wrong with Yuuno?
Yeah, I think he found something.
I'll go look for him!
Would you like us to help?
I'm fine. I'll be right back, so wait here!
It's been executed?!
People will see us here.
I have to create a barrier!
A barrier?
A space like when we first met!
It slightly shifts the flow of time
between the space where the magic takes effect and normal space.
I'm pretty good at that magic.
I can't cut out too large of a space,
but if it's this house and its surroundings,
I can manage.
That's...
Most likely, that kitten's wish to grow has been properly granted.
I see...
But we have to turn it back to what it was before,
or it will be dangerous.
Right.
After all, Suzuka would be troubled if it stayed that size.
It doesn't seem like it's going to attack us,
so I guess I should hurry and seal it.
Then, Raising Heart!
Bardiche, attack with Photon Lancer.
Photon Lancer, full-auto fire.
Magical light?!
No way...
Raising Heart, please!
Standby, ready. Set up.
Flier Fin
Wide Area Protection
A mage?
She's not surprised by much now.
Maybe there's nothing more that I can teach Nanoha.
A similar type of mage.
One who searches for Lost Logia...
No doubt about it.
She's from the same world as me.
And she knows the truth about the Jewel Seeds!
The same type of Intelligent Device as Bardiche...
Bardiche?
Lost Logia, Jewel Seeds.
Scythe Form, set up.
I apologize, but I'm taking it with me.
Evasion
Flier Fin
Arc Saber
Protection
Nanoha!
Why?
Why, so suddenly...
Even if I answered, it would likely be meaningless.
Device Form
Shooting Mode
Divine Buster, stand by.
Photon Lancer, get set.
I'm sure she's my age.
Such pretty eyes, and such pretty hair...
But this girl...
I'm sorry.
Fire.
Nanoha!
Sealing Form, set up.
Capture.
Order?
Lost Logia, Jewel Seed, Serial XIV...
Seal.
Yes, sir.
Sealing.
Captured.
When I woke up again, the sky had changed color to that of dusk.
Yuuno had called for my brother and everyone else.
And I told a small lie,
that I tripped and passed out while searching for Yuuno.
I made everyone worry so much.
My heart was full of apologies.
That staff, that armor, how she used magic...
Most likely...
No, I'm positive that she and I are from the same world
Yeah.
If I'm going to collect more Jewel Seeds...
I wonder if I'm going to run into her again?
For some strange reason,
I wasn't scared at all.
But it made me feel kind of sad.
I had very complicated feelings.
There was a bit of interference, but I was all right.
Jewel Seed, Serial XIV.
I wonder if she has a few of them?
It's all right. I won't lose my way.
Wait for me, Mom.
I'll be home soon.
Make a little wish
Even though at times
I'll trip or get lost
Because you're with me, I can continue to smile and be energetic
Ah, going over the sea of cellophane and over the forests
Passing through the silver wind
I was looking for something neither of us had
Ah, I was just crying inside a diorama of a city
Until I met that warm hand that reached out to me that day
Among the swaying days,
I felt a strong gaze
Hey, I finally, finally found the secret key
Make a little wish
Collecting the lemon-colored drops from the moon
I want to keep a light shining on the road that you travel down
Make a little wish
I wonder if there is something I can do even though I'm so little
Because you're with me, I can continue to smile and be energetic
Students and working people alike,
at times they just need a break to relax.
And so we're here at the local resort, Uminari Hot Springs!
Just when we're relaxing, who's getting in our way?!
And what is the objective and intentions
of that mysterious magical girl in black?!
Episode 5
This is a Town of Hot Water,
Uminari Hot Springs!
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha:
Episode 5: This is a Town of Hot Water,
Uminari Hot Springs!
Lyrical, magical, I'll do my best!