It was a small incident that happened to me, Nanoha Takamachi,
a girl who was supposed to be an ordinary third-grader.
I believed in the courage within my heart,
and I gained magical powers.
I wished for a very small feeling to reach its destination.
The beginning of the journey must always be so sad,
but I'm sure the feelings have gotten across.
So I'm sure goodbye is the word that begins something.
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha
will now begin.
Cradling my knees in a corner of my room
I always shivered from uncertainty
I was scared of learning the truth,
so I closed the door
I found my own place within a kind lie and I fled inside my dreams
I dye a sea of loneliness that nobody knows of into a deep blue
An intense feeling to hide the loneliness
Is continually injuring your heart
The secret hidden deep within the eyes
To the truth behind the smile that draws me in
I will deliver a love so soft
Right now, a warmth that might break upon touching it
Parts itself from the past, and overflows
I'll be by your side forever
Do not be lured into the somber shadows
Please, everyone!
Hurry up and escape!
Fate!
Fate! Fate!
Fly! Over here!
Episode 13
Call My Name
Looks like the earthquake is over.
You're right!
The Garden's destruction is complete.
Everything has been absorbed into the imaginary number plane.
The dimensional tremor is ending.
There are no dimensional faults.
Roger.
Escaping at Speed Three.
Returning to our patrol course.
Where's Fate?
She's in the brig with Arf.
Since she's a material witness in this incident...
I'm sorry, but she will be detained for a while.
But that's... ouch!
Nanoha, stay still!
This incident was a major case, where one mistaken step
might have caused the creation of a dimensional fault.
The Time-Space Administrative Bureau has to be very careful
about the treatment of all involved parties.
You understand that, right?
Yeah.
Amy, do it over!
Darn.
And so, all sorts of things came to an end.
From the day that I met
Yuuno until today...
Now that everything's over, it seems like it all happened in an instant.
We spent several days aboard the Arthra,
until the aftershocks of the dimensional tremor subsided.
Rice bowl...
Since then...
You demonstrated outstanding service in the resolution of this case.
Even if it's a bit informal,
I'd like to award you for your distinguished service.
Miss Nanoha Takamachi and Mr. Yuuno Scrya,
thank you!
Chrono, what's going to happen to Fate now?
Though she had her reasons, it's an undeniable fact
that she was part of a conspiracy in meddling with the dimensions.
That's a felony.
Usually, you get locked up for several centuries, if not more.
That can't be!
However!
The situation is rather special, and it's clear that
she wasn't party to the dimensional crimes of her own will.
What we have left is to figure out
how to get the brass to understand those facts.
But I'm pretty confident on that score,
so you don't have to worry at all.
Chrono...
The Time-Space Administrative Bureau isn't a group
of cold-hearted people who'd pin a crime on a girl who knew nothing,
and was just doing her best to grant her mother's wish.
Chrono... can it be that you're actually a really kind person?
What...
That was just stating the obvious as an Enforcer!
There were no personal feelings involved!
You don't have to be embarrassed.
I'm not embarrassed!
What?! Don't laugh!
The dimensional tremor aftershocks will be subsiding soon.
I think we can get back to your world by tomorrow, Miss Nanoha.
That's great!
However, the route to Midchilda hasn't stabilized quite yet.
It looks like that will take some time.
I see.
A few months, maybe half a year...
It looks like it will take that long before we can cruise safely.
I see.
Well, my clan is full of people
who wander all over the world in search of archaeological ruins,
so there really isn't a definite necessity for me to hurry back.
But I can't really have you host me on this ship for that long...
Then you can stay at my house, like you have been!
Is that all right, Nanoha?
Yeah!
As long as you're fine with it, Yuuno.
Then, well...
Um, please take good care of me!
Sure!
Geez, it's because you slept so much!
But I was pulling so many all-nighters!
I'm still sleepy.
The place called Alhazred that she was aiming for...
You know of it, right, Yuuno?
Yes, I've heard of it before.
They say it existed in previous centuries, by the old calendar.
The land where many spells that have been lost now still rest.
But they also say
that it fell into a dimensional fault long ago and fell to ruins.
Hey there!
They say that there is no wish you can leave ungranted
using the powers of the secret spells of Alhazred,
with all sorts of magic in its ultimate state.
Magic that can turn back time and space, and even rewrite the past.
Magic that can bring back to the living a life that has been lost.
Those were the things she wanted, right?
Yes...
But everyone who learns magic knows for a fact
that turning back time and raising the dead is impossible.
That is why, seeking both of those ideals,
she could only rely on such a fairy-tale legend.
She had no choice but to rely on it.
But a mage of that level was risking her life in that search.
Perhaps she really had found the path to Alhazred.
Though there's no way for us to know now.
I'm sorry, this mealtime story has gotten quite long.
Let's finish our meals before they get cold.
I'm sure this will be your last meal aboard the Arthra, Nanoha.
Yeah...
If parting ways makes you lonely,
you should honestly just come out and say it.
Chrono, you're so shy!
What?!
Nanoha, you can always come by and visit us, okay?
Yes! Thank you very much!
Amy! The Arthra is not a playground!
Well now, it's all right.
When our mission is to patrol, we're always full of idle time!
Ca... Captain! You as well?!
And the morning where Yuuno and I were going home...
Well... thank you so much for everything you did this time.
We appreciated your support.
I'll inform you of Fate's treatment when it's been decided.
It's all right, I'll make sure that nothing bad happens to her.
Yeah... thanks.
Yuuno, when you want to go back, please contact us.
I'll let you use our gate.
Yes! Thank you very much!
Then, I guess we're about ready to go?
Yes!
Then...
I'll see you again, Chrono,
Miss Amy, Miss Lindy!
Should we go home now, Yuuno?
Sure.
I'm home!
Nanoha!
And what comes back is my everyday life.
It's the same as it had always been,
but adding everything that has happened,
Mom, I'm hungry!
everyday life is just a little bit different from before.
Welcome home.
Were you a good girl?
Yeah!
Nanoha!
I'm home! I came back!
The time that you're engrossed in something,
after it's all over, seems like a fleeting moment...
But in my heart, it surely remains true.
How we met... how desperate I was... all sorts of things.
It's been a while since I slept in my own bed!
Yuuno, you should rest up tonight too!
Right.
Thanks for all the hard work,
Raising Heart!
Thank you for all the hard work, Nanoha.
The one thing that's still on my mind...
About that girl with the gentle eyes, that must surely be very kind.
Several days later...
Incoming Call
Time-Space
Administrative Bureau
Yes, this is Nanoha!
Really?!
Yeah, it's been officially decided on a few moments ago.
Fate will be transferred over to the Main Office,
and there she will face questioning and a trial.
Fate will probably—no, almost definitely—be acquitted.
Everything will be all right.
Because Chrono was working overtime to gather all the evidence.
Amy! You don't have to mention unnecessary information like that!
Thank you, Chrono!
The questioning, trial, and everything else will take quite a bit of time.
But, before that...
Yeah...
Yeah!
I'll be right there!
What's up, Nanoha?
Fate is going to be transferred to the Main Office for a while.
But before that, I can see her for just a little bit!
I see.
She's saying that she wants to see me!
Fate!
We don't have much time, but sit down and have a talk for a while.
We'll be over there.
Thanks!
Thank you.
There were so many things
I wanted to talk to you about.
But it's funny.
When I saw your face, Fate,
I forgot all of them.
I... let's see...
I can't put it into words well, either.
But I was really happy.
That you looked at me so straightforwardly.
Yeah! I thought that it would be great if we could be friends!
But today, you have to head out right after this, right?
That's true. It will be a pretty long trip.
But I can see you again, right?
It's a bit sad, but I can finally begin to be my own self.
I had you come here so that
I could give you an answer.
The words that you told me...
That you wanted to be my friend.
Yeah, yeah!
If it's possible for me... if you're okay with me...
But I don't know what I should be doing.
So I want you to tell me.
How do you become a friend?
That's easy.
It's really easy to become friends.
Call me by my name.
In the beginning, that's all you have to do.
Not "you" or "hey, you" or anything like that.
Look directly at the person's eyes,
and clearly call them by their name.
I'm Nanoha Takamachi!
Call me Nanoha!
Nanoha...
Yeah! That's it!
Yeah...
Nanoha!
Yeah!
Thank you, Nanoha.
Yeah...
Nanoha...
Yeah!
Your hands are so warm, Nanoha.
There's something that I figured out.
When a friend is crying, you're sad in the same way.
Fate!
Thank you, Nanoha.
We'll part for now, but I'm sure we'll see each other again.
When that happens, can I call you by your name again?
Yeah, yeah!
When I want to see you,
I'm sure to be calling your name.
So Nanoha, I want you to call for me too.
If something is troubling you, Nanoha...
I'm sure that this time,
I will save you, Nanoha.
Your girl over there...
Nanoha...
She sure is a good girl.
Fate is smiling so much right now.
It's time. Are you about done?
Fate!
This is all I have that I can use as a token of our memories.
Then, I should too.
Thank you, Nanoha.
Fate...
I'm sure once again...
Yeah! I'm sure once again...
Thank you!
Miss Arf, you stay well too!
Thanks for everything,
Nanoha, Yuuno.
Well then, I'm on my way too.
See you later, Chrono!
Yeah.
Bye-bye, see you later...
Chrono...
Miss Arf...
Fate!
Nanoha?
Yeah!
Make a little wish
Even though at times
I'll trip or get lost
Because you're with me, I can continue to smile and be energetic
Ah, don't look down
as you walk, it's all right
The courage that you handed to me that day is still in my hands
Nanoha!
Coming!
Each time I blink,
more kindness is born
See, this love is something I want to nurture always, forever
Make a little wish
Wearing the lemon-colored
drops from the moon
I want to keep glimmering with a twinkle and keep on as your energy
Make a little wish
On rainy days and dawns
when I couldn't fall asleep
Because you were here with me,
I was able to smile my best
Just like this
Whenever we're apart, I still have something I can believe in
See, our hearts are always,
surely together as one
Make a little wish
Collecting the lemon-colored
drops from the moon
Let's turn them into warm tears, and make them spices for smiles
Make a little wish
Even though at times
I'll trip or get lost
Because you're with me, I can continue to smile and be energetic