It was a small incident that happened to me, Nanoha Takamachi,
a girl who was supposed to be an ordinary third-grader.
I believed in the courage within my heart,
and I gained magical powers.
The feeling that you can't twist something you've decided...
The feeling that you don't want to run away...
I understand those just a little.
That's why, right now, we'll have our first and last serious battle.
Risking everything we have on our magic!
I'll tell you over and over.
Because I want to see you smile.
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha
will now begin.
Cradling my knees in a corner of my room
I always shivered from uncertainty
I was scared of learning the truth,
so I closed the door
I found my own place within a kind lie and I fled inside my dreams
I dye a sea of loneliness that nobody knows of into a deep blue
An intense feeling to hide the loneliness
Is continually injuring your heart
The secret hidden deep within the eyes
To the truth behind the smile that draws me in
I will deliver a love so soft
Right now, a warmth that might break upon touching it
Parts itself from the past, and overflows
I'll be by your side forever
Do not be lured into the somber shadows
My mother... my mother...
My mother was always kind.
My mother called out my name so gently.
See? These are very pretty, Alicia.
Alicia?
That's not right, Mom.
I'm Fate.
Now, come here, Alicia.
See? You're so cute, Alicia.
I guess it's all right.
Because I love my kind mother...
Episode 11
Memories That Lie Beyond Time
It looks like the battle will begin.
Yeah.
But this really is unusual.
For you to allow such a gamble, Chrono...
Well, it's for the best if Nanoha wins.
But the winner of this battle doesn't really matter that much.
While Nanoha is buying us time with her battle,
we'll prepare for pursuit of that girl's route in returning home, right?
I'm counting on you.
So don't let her get away.
Yeah, leave it to me!
Oh?
But don't you have to tell Nanoha,
about Presea Testarossa's family, and about that incident?
It's best if she wins.
I don't want Nanoha to be worried about anything right now.
Photon Lancer
Divine Shooter
Fire!
Shoot!
Scythe Form
Round Shield
Flash Move
Scythe Slash
Fire!
When I first met her,
she was a novice, with nothing but high magical power.
Not anymore.
She's quick, and she's tough.
If I'm indecisive, she'll get me!
Phalanx Shift
Lightning Bind...
This isn't good. Fate is serious!
Nanoha! I'll back you up now!
You can't!
Miss Arf... Yuuno...
Please, don't interfere.
It's a duel at full strength between us.
A battle between Fate and me!
But that thing Fate's doing is really bad!
I'm fine!
Arcus cultus aegeas...
Spears of thunder becoming a gust,
shoot through that to which you are guided now.
Paruer zaruer brouzel...
Photon Lancer: Phalanx Shift
Hit and destroy! Fire!
Nanoha!
Fate?!
When you're done shooting,
that "bind" thing loses effect, right?
This time, it's my...
Divine...
...turn!
...Buster
It's a direct hit!
But I can withstand it!
Because she withstood my attack too!
Fate!
Try taking this one.
A variation on the Divine Buster...
Starlight Breaker
A bind?!
This attack is me at my full strength!
Starlight Breaker
What a ludicrous amount of magical power!
Wow... I wonder if Fate is still alive?
Fate!
Are you awake, Fate?
I'm sorry... are you all right?
I won, right?
Yes...
It seems so.
Put out.
Can you fly?
Alright, Nanoha, grab the Jewel Seeds,
and then get her...
No, she's here!
Fate!
Bingo! Caught her by the tail!
Steady...
A careless translocation will cost lives... the coordinates?
Already determined, and I'm sending them now!
All armed personnel, mobilize from the transfer ports!
Your mission is the capture of Presea Testarossa!
Yes, ma'am!
Just as I thought...
I can no longer physically bear dimensional magic.
And, with that last one, they discovered this location.
Fate...
That girl was useless after all.
I guess it's about time to call it quits.
Squadron Two has completed transfer.
Squadron One has begin infiltration.
Thank you for the hard work.
And... Miss Fate, was it?
Nice to meet you.
I'd prefer not to show her the scene of her mother's arrest.
Miss Nanoha, please take her to a different room.
Okay.
Fate, if you'd like, you can come to my room...
All men have entered the throne room
and have confirmed the target!
Presea Testarossa, you are under arrest
for violation of dimensional law
and charges of attacking a Bureau flagship!
Disarm yourself and come here.
Cover that side!
There's something over here!
This is...
Don't come near my Alicia!
Fire!
Shut up.
Look out! Block it!
This isn't good! Recall all agents!
Roger!
Alicia?
Coordinate lock: 012A503.
Locked!
Transfer operation, stand by.
It doesn't matter now. I have no time.
With only nine Lost Logia,
I don't know whether or not
I will reach Alhazred.
But it's fine now. I will end it all.
All the time spent in depression after losing this child,
and treating a scapegoat of a doll of her as my daughter.
Are you listening?
I'm talking about you, Fate.
I went through the effort of giving you Alicia's memories,
but the only resemblance was your appearance.
You were of no use whatsoever.
A mere doll of mine.
Back in that first incident...
Presea lost her real daughter,
Alicia Testarossa.
In the end, she was researching the creation
of an artificial life form different from a familiar,
a being that surpasses all familiars.
And the secret of reviving the dead...
"Fate" was the codename
that she had assigned to her research at the time.
I'm impressed you were able to find out that much.
You're right. That's correct.
But it wasn't good enough.
It didn't go well at all.
An artificial life is nothing but a fake life.
It doesn't take the place of something that you've lost.
Alicia smiled at me more kindly.
Sometimes Alicia was selfish,
but she listened well to what I had to say.
Stop it!
Alicia was always kind to me.
Fate...
You are, in the end, only a fake Alicia.
I went through the effort of giving you Alicia's memories,
but you weren't good enough.
Stop! Stop it!
A doll I used to comfort myself until
I could bring Alicia back to life.
So I don't need you anymore.
Wherever you want to go, begone!
Please, stop it already!
I'll tell you one good thing, Fate...
Ever since I made you, all this time...
I hated you!
Fate!
Fate...
All agents have been retrieved.
Big trouble!
Please take a look at this!
Magical responses from all over the mansion... so many of them?!
What?
What is going on here?
Magical responses from the Garden.
All of them are Class A!
Total numbers, 60.... 80...
The number is still increasing!
Presea Testarossa, what in the world are you planning on doing?!
I don't want you to interrupt our journey.
We are going to depart!
To the forgotten capital, Alhazred!
That's impossible!
With this power, we're going to depart,
and take everything back into our hands!
It's a dimensional tremor!
Mid-size, or even bigger!
Tremor defenses!
Put up the distortion shields!
Nine Jewel Seeds have been executed.
The dimensional tremor is going to get even stronger!
Move to an area that has a smaller affect,
while remaining within teleport radius!
Roger that!
The Radi coefficient is growing!
At this rate, there will be a dimensional fault!
Alhazred...
What idiocy!
Chrono?!
I'm going to go stop it!
Open the gate!
The forgotten capital, Alhazred...
The land where the forbidden secret spells that we have lost all lie.
What is she trying to do there?!
Does she think that she can bring back the past she has lost?!
No matter what magic you use,
there is no way you can bring back the past!
Alicia and I are going to bring back all of our past in Alhazred!
Make a little wish
Even though at times
I'll trip or get lost
Because you're with me, I can continue to smile and be energetic
Ah, going over the sea of cellophane and over the forests
Passing through the silver wind
I was looking for something neither of us had
Ah, I was just crying inside a diorama of a city
Until I met that warm hand that reached out to me that day
Among the swaying days,
I felt a strong gaze
Hey, I finally, finally found the secret key
Make a little wish
Collecting the lemon-colored drops from the moon
I want to keep a light shining on the road that you travel down
Make a little wish
I wonder if there is something I can do even though I'm so little
Because you're with me, I can continue to smile and be energetic
The dimensional tremor has been set off.
We head into the
Garden of Time to stop Presea.
So that many worlds aren't destroyed, including Nanoha's world and ours...
And at that moment, Fate...
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha:
Episode 12
When Our Fates Are Sealed
Episode 12: When Our Fates Are Sealed
Lyrical, magical, until the very end, I'm sure!