It was a small incident that happened to me, Nanoha Takamachi,
a girl who was supposed to be an ordinary third-grader.
I believed in the courage within my heart,
and I gained magical powers.
Even if your feelings break, even if your wishes are far away,
don't forget the kindness that has always been at your side.
There has been a heart that supported you,
and there is someone that is waiting for you to smile.
With true feelings, make a wish.
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha will now begin.
Cradling my knees in a corner of my room
I always shivered from uncertainty
I was scared of learning the truth,
so I closed the door
I found my own place within a kind lie and I fled inside my dreams
I dye a sea of loneliness that nobody knows of into a deep blue
An intense feeling to hide the loneliness
Is continually injuring your heart
The secret hidden deep within the eyes
To the truth behind the smile that draws me in
I will deliver a love so soft
Right now, a warmth that might break upon touching it
Parts itself from the past, and overflows
I'll be by your side forever
Do not be lured into the somber shadows
A dimensional tremor has started,
and its magnitude is gradually increasing!
If the magnitude continues to increase at this rate,
we estimate the creation of a dimensional fault in thirty minutes!
The Garden's reactors are Lost Logia of the same type as the Jewel Seeds!
She's engaged them, fully aware that they might
run out of control, to supply her the output that she lacks!
She meant this to be a one-way trip from the very beginning!
Chrono, where are you going?
I'm going to head to the scene!
I have to stop the cause of it all!
I'll go with you!
Me too!
Very well.
Arf, you stay by Fate's side.
Right!
Let's go!
Yeah!
Chrono, Miss Nanoha, Yuuno!
I'm going to head on-site as well!
I will trust you all with the arrest of Presea Testarossa!
Roger!
Episode 12
When Our Fates Are Sealed
There's lots of them.
This is only the entrance.
There are many more inside.
Chrono, what are they?
They're nothing but machines that attack nearby targets.
I see.
Then there's nothing to worry about.
You don't need to waste time on opponents of this level.
Stinger Snipe
So quick!
Snipe Shot
Break Impulse
Don't just stand there! Let's go!
Okay!
That hole... be careful of anywhere that has black spaces!
That's the imaginary number plane.
It's a space where no magic can be executed!
Flying magic will also be deleted.
If you fall in, you'll fall to the bottom of the gravitational pull,
and never be able to get yourself out of it!
I'll be careful!
We're going to split up here!
You two, seal the reactor on the top floor!
What about you, Chrono?
I'm going to head over to Presea.
That's my job, after all.
I'll make you a path right now!
When I do...
Yeah!
Blaze Cannon
Chrono, be careful!
I will be going as well!
Put up a distortion shield within the Garden,
and hold back the progress of the dimensional tremor!
I'm worried about those kids,
so I'm going to go help them out a little too.
I'll be back soon.
And when everything is all done...
It doesn't matter how slowly,
but I want you to turn back to the real Fate that I love so much.
From now on, you're free to use all the time you have for yourself.
My mother didn't smile at me once, to the very end.
The only reason I wanted to live was for my mother to accept me.
No matter how much she claimed I lacked,
no matter what horrible things she did to me.
Still, I wanted her to smile.
Even after she threw me aside so clearly,
I'm still clinging to my mother.
Arf...
Arf, you've been at my side for all this time.
I'm sure you were deeply saddened
when I didn't listen to what you had to say.
That girl in the white outfit who
I clashed with so many times...
The first person who looked at me straight on,
and treated me as an equal.
I saw her many times,
I fought her many times,
and she called out my name so many times.
Over and over...
The only reason I wanted to live was for my mother to accept me!
I had thought that there was no other reason for me to live!
I thought I wouldn't be able to live if I couldn't do it!
It's not good to just throw it out.
And it's even worse to just keep running away from it.
Nothing with me... between us... has even begun?
Is that so, Bardiche?
Perhaps I haven't even really started?
Get set.
That's right.
You've been at my side for all this time too, Bardiche!
You don't want it to end like this either, right?
Yes, sir.
I'm not sure if I can do it well, but let's try our best together.
You taught me to escape from the clear skies
The quiet wish that wells up in my heart
Recovery.
Let's get ourselves back into our hands
Nothing between us has even begun.
On the other end of the sky as I look up, your gaze
Gets hit by the rain of caring and disappears
That is why, in order for me to begin my true self,
Let me down, it doesn't stop
I have to put an end to what I have been until now!
Shake up, realizing for the first time, entrusting, take a shot
Looking around, you were there
The reason why I can fight without hesitation
Is so that I can bloom in wondrous colors
To look straight at my weak heart
Dammit! There are
too many enemies!
It would be nice if that was all.
Whichever way I turn, which way to walk headed for where
You...
I have to do something!
I just stood there, unable to decide on my own path to take
Nanoha!
Without losing hope in the distant future
Thunder Rage
Unbreakable courage hidden in the clouds
I have drive, call it awake
Get set.
Take off, shaken, woken up, asked, pave the way
Thunder...
...Rage
I will go with you, without worries
Why did you keep hesitating?
Fate?!
So that I can win a clear victory
Let's grab countless wishes in our hands
It's a big one... the barrier is strong.
Yeah. And that thing on its back!
But if the two of us are together...
Yeah! Yeah, yeah!
Let's go, Bardiche!
Get set.
Us too, Raising Heart!
Standby, ready.
Strongly, gently, give wind to the wings
Thunder...
Shake up, realizing for the first time, entrusting, take a shot
There is nothing that I can lose
...Smasher
Shaken, woken up, asked, pave the way
Divine Buster
So that I can win a clear victory
Let's grab countless wishes in our hands
Here we go!
You're here!
But you didn't make it in time!
Right, Alicia?
Oh, Alicia...
Fate!
Fate! Fate!
Arf...
I'm sorry I made you worry.
I'll end it with my own hands,
and after that,
I'll begin who I really am.
Just a little bit more...
We can head to the reactor from that elevator.
Okay, thanks!
Fate, are you going to head over to your mom?
I, um, I can't really put it into words well...
Good luck.
Thanks.
Right now, Chrono is headed there on his own.
If we don't hurry, we might not make it in time!
Fate!
Amy!
Nanoha and Yuuno have entered the reactor!
Fate and Arf are headed to the bottom floor!
It's all right! I'm sure we can do it!
Yeah!
I'll take care of defense.
Nanoha, concentrate on the sealing!
Yeah. Just like always, right?
Yuuno, you've always been together with me, and protected me.
Sealing Mode
That's why I can fight!
Because I have that warmth at my back!
Let's go!
Divine Shooter, full power!
Shoot!
Presea Testarossa...
This is the end.
I am suppressing the dimensional tremor.
The reactor will be sealed away in due time,
and there is an Enforcer headed towards you.
The forgotten capital, Alhazred,
and all the secret spells that lie there,
their existence is only a vague myth!
That's not true!
The path to Alhazred lies in the gap between dimensions!
When time and space are shattered,
the glimmers that fall into their gap...
The path surely lies there!
A gamble that has such a slim chance of winning...
What in the world do you want to do by going there?
Bring back lost time and take back the mistakes you made?
That's right!
I'm going to bring back into my hands
the past and the future for Alicia and I!
I'm going to bring it back.
This wasn't how it was supposed to be.
Everything in the world...
This world is always full of things
that weren't supposed to be this way!
From the past, for all time, for anyone, that's how it is!
Everyone is free to run away from or stand up against
the reality that wasn't how it was supposed to be!
But, nowhere, nobody has the right
to rope innocent people into your selfish depression!
Mom!
What did you come here for?
Begone. I have no more use for you.
I came here because I wanted to say something to you.
I...
I am not Alicia Testarossa!
I may be just a doll that you have created.
But, I, Fate Testarossa,
am your daughter that you brought to life and raised!
So what?!
Are you telling me to think of you as a daughter after all this?
If you so wish.
If you so wish,
I will protect you from anyone in this world,
and from anything that goes on.
Not because I am your daughter.
But because you are my mother!
How stupid.
Not good!
Captain, it's no good!
The Garden is going to fall apart!
Please come back!
Destruction of this caliber won't cause a dimensional fault!
Chrono, all of you should escape now!
There isn't much time before that place is destroyed!
Roger that!
Fate Testarossa!
Fate!
I am going to head to Alhazred!
And I will bring everything back!
My past, my future, and my one and only happiness!
Mom!
Fate!
Let us go together, Alicia.
This time, so that we don't part from one another...
Fate!
Please, everyone!
Hurry up and escape!
Make a little wish
Even though at times
I'll trip or get lost
Because you're with me, I can continue to smile and be energetic
Ah, going over the sea of cellophane and over the forests
Passing through the silver wind
I was looking for something neither of us had
Ah, I was just crying inside a diorama of a city
Until I met that warm hand that reached out to me that day
Among the swaying days,
I felt a strong gaze
Hey, I finally, finally found the secret key
Make a little wish
Collecting the lemon-colored drops from the moon
I want to keep a light shining on the road that you travel down
Make a little wish
I wonder if there is something I can do even though I'm so little
Because you're with me, I can continue to smile and be energetic
The incident has finally come to an end.
Finally, the ending that arrives, and the parting of the ways.
But an ending is always the beginning of something else.
Episode 13
Call My Name
Next episode of Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha:
Final episode: Call My Name
Lyrical, magical,
I'll see you again, right?