It was a small incident that happened to me, Nanoha Takamachi,
a girl who was supposed to be an ordinary third-grader.
I accepted the courage within my heart,
and I gained magical powers.
Destiny is set in motion once again,
thanks to yet another new introduction.
A small light shining on one's feelings
while walking through the forest of hesitation
is most likely found in one's heart.
Because I decided to believe, and move forward,
even if I am headed towards a shadowed sky.
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha
will now begin.
Cradling my knees in a corner of my room
I always shivered from uncertainty
I was scared of learning the truth,
so I closed the door
I found my own place within a kind lie and I fled inside my dreams
I dye a sea of loneliness that nobody knows of into a deep blue
An intense feeling to hide the loneliness
Is continually injuring your heart
The secret hidden deep within the eyes
To the truth behind the smile that draws me in
I will deliver a love so soft
Right now, a warmth that might break upon touching it
Parts itself from the past, and overflows
I'll be by your side forever
Do not be lured into the somber shadows
The battle between the two has already started on-site.
The Lost Logia in the center of it is Class A+.
Its mannerisms are quite unstable.
It's showing signs of an indiscriminate attack.
A taboo item that meddles with time and space...
We must hurry in its collection.
Enforcer Chrono Harlaown, can you head out?
I have determined the transfer coordinates.
I can go at any time, given the orders.
Then, Chrono,
stop the battle on-site immediately,
collect the Lost Logia,
and get a detailed report from both combatants!
Roger that, Captain!
Oh, and be careful!
Okay... I'll be going now.
Episode 8
There's a Really Big Crisis?
Stop!
Combat here is too dangerous.
I'm an Enforcer with the
Time-Space Administrative Bureau,
Chrono Harlaown.
Would you tell me the details of this case?
Time-Space Administrative Bureau?
First off, both of you, stow your weapons.
If you were to continue fighting...
Fate, we're going to retreat!
Step away!
Fate!
No!
Stop! Don't shoot!
We're gonna get outta here, Fate.
Hold on tight!
The fighting has stopped.
One of the two combatants has escaped.
Pursuit?
They are fleeing using multiple teleports.
We can't keep up.
I see.
Well, the battle was stopped quickly,
and we've finished securing the Lost Logia,
so I will say that was good enough.
And we'll be able to hear about the situation.
Chrono, well done.
I'm sorry. I let one of them get away.
It's all right.
You know, I'd like to hear some of the story,
so can you guide those kids aboard the Arthra?
Roger that. I'll return immediately.
Yuuno...
Yuuno, what in the world is this?
This is inside a dimensional transport
owned by the Time-Space Administrative Bureau.
Well, to put it simply, it's a ship that can freely move
through the many dimensions that exist in the multiverse.
I—I don't think that's really simple.
Let's see...
Other than the world that you live in, Nanoha,
there are many other worlds,
and my world is one of them.
This ship can cross between those worlds.
And it's them, the Time-Space Administrative Bureau,
that controls events that affect those worlds.
I see.
You must be uncomfortable wearing that outfit for such a long time.
You can release your Barrier Jacket and Device.
I see.
You're right. Then...
And you... I think it's okay for you to return to your normal form.
Yeah... come to think of it, that makes sense.
I've been in this form all this time, so I had forgotten.
It's been a while since you've seen me in this form, Nanoha.
What?!
Nanoha?
Yuuno... Yuuno...
Um, well, what...
But... you're kidding!
Are you two having a difference of opinion?
Hey, Nanoha?
When we first met, wasn't I in this form?
No, no! You were a ferret all along!
You're right, that's true!
Sorry about that.
I haven't shown you this form yet!
Right? You haven't, right?
You surprised me...
Er, can I have a moment?
I am not aware of what's going on here,
but the Captain's waiting on us,
and if it's at all possible, we'd like to hear your story quickly.
Oh... sure...
I'm sorry.
This way, then.
Captain, I have brought them here.
You must be tired!
Well, both of you, please, over here. Relax!
Please.
Okay...
I see, that's how it was.
Those Lost Logia...
You were the one that unearthed the Jewel Seeds.
That's why I was trying to collect them.
How admirable.
But, at the same time, very reckless!
Um... what exactly are Lost Logia?
They're legacies from the lost worlds...
But you don't understand that, do you?
Let's see...
In the Dimensional Sea, there are many worlds.
Each a world born unto its own
and growing on its own.
Among them, very rarely, there are worlds that evolve too fast.
When their progress in science and technology goes too far,
they destroy their own world.
And what's left over afterwards
are dangerous legacies of the lost world's technology.
We generically call such things Lost Logia.
How to use them is unclear,
but depending on how they're used,
they can destroy a world,
or even the Dimensional Sea itself.
Dangerous pieces of technology.
Items that need to be stored
in suitable locations, following proper procedures...
The Lost Logia you are searching for, the Jewel Seeds,
are energy crystals that interact with the dimensions.
If you collect a few and execute them in a certain manner,
you can create a dimensional tremor within the spatial area,
and, in the worst case, even a dimensional fault.
The tremor and explosion
that occurred when you clashed with that black-clad mage...
That was a dimensional tremor.
Just one Jewel Seed executing
at a tiny fraction, one ten thousandth, of full strength
had that much effect on the world.
It's impossible to gauge the effect several of them might have together.
I heard about that once.
Back in year 462 of the old calendar,
when there was a dimensional fault...
Yeah, that was a horrible incident.
Many neighboring parallel worlds fell to ruin.
A tragedy that left its mark on history.
We can't let it happen again.
From here on, the retrieval of these Lost Logia, the Jewel Seeds,
will be performed by the
Time-Space Administrative Bureau.
You guys should just forget this incident,
return to your respective worlds,
and go back to your normal lives.
But... that's so...
This case concerns interaction between dimensions.
It's beyond the level
a civilian can handle.
But...
Well, I'm sure you can't straighten out your feelings so suddenly.
Take your time, sleep on it tonight,
talk it out between you two,
and we'll discuss it again afterwards.
I'll see you out. Is where
I found you all right?
Sure.
Should we go home for now?
Yeah.
Um... are you about my age?
Yeah... well, I think.
Well... you're not mad at me, are you?
I didn't mean to end up this way, but...
It looked like I was keeping it a secret from you.
Oh, not at all.
I was surprised, but that was it.
I'm sorry. Thanks.
But for now...
I think it's better for me to be in this form for everyday stuff.
Yeah, you're right.
Let's have dinner, and then think it out properly.
What to do from here...
So amazing!
Both of them are AAA class mages.
Yeah...
This girl in the white outfit is cute.
She seems like your type, Chrono.
Amy!
That stuff doesn't matter right now!
This girl's average magical power is 1.27 million.
The girl in the black outfit has 1.43 million.
Their maximum execution power is more than triple that.
If it's just about magical power, they out-power you, Chrono.
Magic is not about the quantity of your magical power.
You need adaptation to suit the situation,
and decision-making skills to use them properly!
Of course, I trust you on that front.
Chrono, you're the Arthra's trump card!
Captain...
Oh, the data for those two.
Yes.
Certainly, these are amazing girls.
If this much magical power was poured into a Lost Logia,
I can understand why a dimensional tremor would occur.
Now we know the reason why those kids, Nanoha and Yuuno,
are collecting the Jewel Seeds.
But I wonder what the black-clad girl's reasons are?
She seemed to be rather desperate about it.
Perhaps she has a very strong motive.
Motive, huh...
She's still a young child, right?
If she has been leading a normal life,
I'm sure she's young enough to want to be spoiled by her mom.
You can't!
If the Time-Space Administrative Bureau has stepped in,
we can't do anything about it!
Let's make a run for it.
The two of us, somewhere...
We can't do that.
But!
It would have been fine if he was a wimp,
but that was a first-class mage!
If he starts a serious investigation,
we don't know how long we have before he finds us here.
That old hag, your mom,
keeps muttering things that make no sense,
and she keeps doing horrible things to you, Fate.
Don't say bad things about my mother.
I will too!
Because I'm worried about you, Fate!
When you're sad,
my heart hurts so much that it's like being torn apart!
When you're crying, my eyes and the back of my nose sting,
and I can't do anything about it!
I don't like it when you're crying or grieving over something!
Our spirits are linked together, just a little, Arf.
I'm sorry.
If it's hurting you,
I won't feel sad anymore, and I won't cry again.
All I want is for you to smile and be happy, Fate!
Why... why won't you understand that?
Thank you, Arf.
But I want to fulfill my mother's wishes.
It's not just for my mother.
I'm sure it's for myself as well.
So, just a little bit longer...
It's only a little more until the end.
Will you do your best with me?
Promise me.
That you're not just following her orders.
That you'll be doing your best for yourself, for your sake, Fate.
If you can promise that,
I'll protect you no matter what.
And so...
Both Nanoha and I would like to assist your operations.
Assist, huh?
Leaving me aside, I believe that Nanoha's magical powers
can be a useful combat force from your end.
Collecting the Jewel Seeds, fighting those girls...
In either case, I'm sure we can be very useful to you.
You've thought it out quite well.
In that case, I guess it will be all right.
Mo—
Captain?!
Let's have them help us.
We would like to save our own trump card as well.
Right, Enforcer Chrono?
Yes, ma'am...
I have two conditions.
Both of you need to be under the custody of
the Time-Space Administrative Bureau during this period.
That, and you must obey every order given to you.
Got it?
Understood.
Nanoha, it's been decided.
Thank you, Yuuno.
Now, then... Momoko, Nanoha,
we're going to go out to the hill in the backyard for a little bit.
Sure. Practicing again tonight?
Yeah.
Be careful!
Right.
Okay, let's go.
Sure!
It's been a while,
so I'm going to give you a workout!
Hey, wait!
I'm going to come watch!
If you're coming, hurry up!
Okay! Just a second...
Miyuki, you haven't changed a bit.
Okay, that should be it.
Yeah.
Now then, what is this important thing you have to tell me about?
Yeah...
What I told Mom was basically everything that has happened
from when I met Yuuno until today.
But I couldn't tell her about
the magic or Yuuno's true form,
so I told her what I could,
and that I have to leave for a while to do what I need to do.
It might be dangerous,
but it's something I started with a dear friend,
and I want to see it through to the end.
Right.
I might make you all worry.
But of course, I'm always worried about you!
I'm your mother, Nanoha, so I worry about you a lot.
But...
If you were still trying to decide on which path to take,
I would say that you shouldn't do anything dangerous.
But you've already made up your mind, right?
To properly finish what you started with your friend.
To talk things out once more with that girl you met.
Yeah.
Then take care.
So that you won't regret it.
I'll convince your father and brother for you.
Thank you, Mom!
I can't turn back now.
This is the path I chose for myself.
This is what I really want to do.
Hurry...
Hurry up, Fate.
The promised land...
Alhazred is waiting for me.
The land of my... our... salvation.
Make a little wish
Even though at times
I'll trip or get lost
Because you're with me, I can continue to smile and be energetic
Ah, going over the sea of cellophane and over the forests
Passing through the silver wind
I was looking for something neither of us had
Ah, I was just crying inside a diorama of a city
Until I met that warm hand that reached out to me that day
Among the swaying days,
I felt a strong gaze
Hey, I finally, finally found the secret key
Make a little wish
Collecting the lemon-colored drops from the moon
I want to keep a light shining on the road that you travel down
Make a little wish
I wonder if there is something I can do even though I'm so little
Because you're with me, I can continue to smile and be energetic
Next Episode Preview
The Time-Space Administrative Bureau's
flagship, the Arthra,
is now going to take care of me and Yuuno.
An abnormal, unprecedented reaction from the Jewel Seeds,
and the reunion of Nanoha and Fate.
What is the wish that Fate's mother has?
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha:
Episode 9
The Decisive Battle Above the Ocean
Episode 9:
Lyrical, magical, hoping I won't lose!