It was a small incident that happened to me, Nanoha Takamachi,
a girl who was supposed to be an ordinary third-grader.
I accepted the courage within my heart,
and I gained magical powers.
We've seen each other, and we came into contact many times,
yet we still know nothing about each other.
I want to hear the answer...
I want to share...
That is why I decided to face her straight on.
Getting rid of all doubts,
believing only in the magic that dwells in my heart.
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha
will now begin.
Cradling my knees in a corner of my room
I always shivered from uncertainty
I was scared of learning the truth,
so I closed the door
I found my own place within a kind lie and I fled inside my dreams
I dye a sea of loneliness that nobody knows of into a deep blue
An intense feeling to hide the loneliness
Is continually injuring your heart
The secret hidden deep within the eyes
To the truth behind the smile that draws me in
I will deliver a love so soft
Right now, a warmth that might break upon touching it
Parts itself from the past, and overflows
I'll be by your side forever
Do not be lured into the somber shadows
All three of you, come back.
Roger.
Now...
Nanoha and Yuuno,
you'll both receive a very stern lecture directly from me.
Episode 10
Everybody's Separate
Heartfelt Vows
Following all instructions and orders is a necessary rule
to protect an organization, not just individuals.
Selfish decisions and actions may have put not only you,
but everyone else around you in danger as well.
You understand that, right?
Yes, ma'am...
Normally I would put a very heavy punishment on you.
But as a result of what you did, we have gained a little as well.
So, for this one time,
I will let it pass by.
However...
There will be no next time.
Understood?
Yes, ma'am.
We're very sorry.
Now, the problem is what goes on from here.
Chrono, do you have any ideas on the cause of all this?
Yes.
Amy, bring it up on the monitors!
Gotcha!
Oh...
That's right.
A mage from Midchilda, just like us. Presea Testarossa.
Her specialty was development of energy for interdimensional travel.
She was a grand mage, yet was exiled
due to causing an accident through illegal research.
The wavelength of the magical attack just now matches the data on file.
And that girl Fate is, most likely...
Fate...
Back then, she said "Mom"...
Mom?
Parent and child, huh...
Um...
She didn't look like she was surprised so much as scared.
Amy!
Can you give me a bit more detailed data on Lady Presea?
Where she went in exile,
her family makeup, anything that you can find.
Aye aye. I'll look for them right away.
This is Fate's mother...
You had such a great chance in front of you,
yet all you did was stand there in a daze.
I'm sorry...
How horrible, Fate.
Do you really want to make your mother that sad?
I want to be friends.
Presea Testarossa...
According to Mid history, she was head of Sector 3
of the Central Technology
Development Office 26 years ago.
However, at the time, she was developing
a dimension travel energy motor called the Hydra,
where she conducted an experiment using illegal materials and failed.
Because it resulted in a mid-size dimensional tremor,
she was forced to leave the central region, and she was relocated to a rural branch.
There seems to have been much debate about it.
She argued that only the result was a failure,
and that there were no illegalities in the experimental materials.
After being relocated to the outskirts,
she was involved in tech research for several years.
After a while, she ended up missing...
And nothing ever since.
What about her family and her activities when she went missing?
All data concerning those questions has been completely erased.
We're contacting the Main Office now to have them looked over.
How much time will it take?
I believe it will be in the next day or two.
Neither Lady Presea nor Fate should be able
to move around too much after emitting so much magical power.
We have to use that time to strengthen the Arthra's shields, too.
It's best that you two rest for a while.
Oh, but...
Especially you, Nanoha.
It's not good for you to be absent from school for too long.
I will allow you to go home for the time being.
It's better for you to put in an appearance,
for both your family and your schoolmates.
Yes, ma'am.
Fate! Fate!
Fate... Fate...
Only nine...
I can cause a dimensional tremor with this many,
but I can't reach Alhazred.
I don't have much time left.
Neither for me, nor for Alicia...
You're her mother, and that girl is your daughter, right?!
She's doing her best right now,
she's honestly trying so hard...
How can you be so cruel to her?!
She's terrible at making a good familiar.
Too many excessive emotions...
Fate... your daughter wants you to smile so much,
wants you to be a kind person again, and does so much...
You're in my way.
Begone!
It doesn't matter where.
I have to teleport!
I'm sorry, Fate...
Just for a little while, wait for me!
Fate...
Yes, Mom.
The number of Jewel Seeds you have brought is nine.
This isn't enough.
I need at least five more.
If possible, even more than that.
Hurry and get them for your mother.
Yes...
Arf?
Oh...
That girl ran away.
She said she was scared and had had enough.
If you need one, I'll get you a better familiar.
Don't forget that your one true ally is your mother.
Got that, Fate?
Yes, Mom.
And that's how it's been for the past ten days.
Oh, I see!
Mrs. Lindy...
It's either a really great cover-up,
or a complete lie...
Amazing.
I can't tell them the truth.
Please say that it's me caring enough to not worry your family.
However, Miss Nanoha is an excellent child.
I really would like my child to be more like her.
Oh, my... that's going too far!
My Chrono isn't good at being kind to others.
Nanoha...
You can stay home for at least the next day or two, right?
Yeah.
Alisa and Suzuka have been worried too. Have you contacted them yet?
Yeah, I texted them a while ago.
And... send!
Miss Alisa, did you receive some good news?
Not really. Just an ordinary text.
Samejima, stop the car for a second!
It really was a big dog.
It's hurt, as well.
The wounds look severe.
But it's still alive.
Samejima!
Understood.
Fate...
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha
Oh, are you awake now?
This girl... I've seen her somewhere.
You're built really tough.
You were hurt so bad, but they said your life wasn't in danger.
I'll take care of you until your wounds are all healed up.
So rest easy.
It's that girl's friend.
Here. It's soft dog food.
Can you eat it?
There's nothing to worry about if you have that much appetite.
After you eat, take your time, rest, and get better soon.
Nanoha!
I'm so glad you're doing well!
Yeah! Thanks, Suzuka.
I'm sorry to you too, Alisa.
I made you worry.
Well, I'm glad you're doing okay.
I see... you have to go again.
Yeah...
That must be tough.
But it's all right!
What about after school? Will you be able to play with us a little?
Yeah, it's okay.
Then, wanna come to my place?
I bought a few new games.
Oh, really?
That's right... last night, I picked up a dog that was hurt.
A dog?
Yeah. It's really big, with orange fur,
and on its forehead is a red stone, like this.
Just as I thought...
It's you, Miss Arf.
Is that you?
Those wounds...
What happened to you?
And what about Fate?
Oh, no, it's lost its energy.
What's wrong?
Are you doing all right?
Maybe its wounds hurt.
Maybe we should leave it alone?
Yeah.
Yuuno!
Hey, that's dangerous.
It's okay. Yuuno will be all right.
Nanoha...
I'll hear what she has to say.
Nanoha, you go with
Alisa and Suzuka.
Okay.
Then how about some tea?
I have a couple really tasty tea snacks.
Yeah!
I'm looking forward to that!
What in the world happened?
Something happened between you two?
The fact that you're here means that
the guys from the Bureau are watching us now, right?
Yes.
Chrono Harlaown of the Time-Space
Administrative Bureau here.
It seems like the situation is very complex.
If you speak honestly, I will make sure it doesn't work against you.
About you, and about your master, Fate Testarossa.
I'll tell you everything.
But you have to promise me that you will save Fate!
She hasn't done anything wrong!
I promise.
Amy, the recorder.
Already recording.
Fate's mother, Presea Testarossa, is the cause of it all.
Hero takes 28 points of damage.
What you got a few minutes ago...
Correct. Here!
Which one?
Nanoha, did you hear that?
Yeah. I heard it all.
The conditions that you have described to us...
And examining her familiar Arf's testimony,
as well as her current physical condition...
It looks like there are no lies or contradictions in her story.
What's going to happen now?
We're going to capture Presea Testarossa.
Just the fact that she attacked the Arthra
is more than enough reason for us to arrest her.
So, as soon as we get orders from the Captain,
we will be forced to change our mission to the arrest of Presea.
What will you do then,
Nanoha Takamachi?
I...
I want to save Fate.
Miss Arf's feelings, and my own will.
A sad look on Fate's face somehow makes me sad as well.
That's why I want to save her, from all the sad things.
Besides, I told her that I wanted to be friends with her.
I haven't heard her answer yet.
I understand.
We're also thankful to have your magical powers on our side.
We'll leave everything concerning
Fate Testarossa up to you, Nanoha.
Is that all right?
Nanoha... was it?
I don't have the right to ask you, but please...
Save Fate!
She really is all alone right now.
Yeah. It'll be all right. Leave it to me!
You're late, Nanoha!
Come on, we've been waiting for you to enter the new dungeon!
Sorry, sorry!
Wow, this looks so cool!
As planned, our return to the Arthra is set for tomorrow morning.
In the event that you encounter Fate before then...
Yeah... it'll be all right.
I got really into that one!
After all, it's more fun when you're with us, Nanoha.
Thanks.
I'm sure everything will be over very soon.
And then everything will be all right.
Nanoha...
Hey, did you get over it, just a little?
Um, well... I don't know...
I was worried.
Actually, the reason why I was mad
wasn't because you were hiding something from me,
or because you were always thinking about something.
It was because you looked troubled and confused.
And every so often...
You looked like you were going to go somewhere,
and never come back to see us ever again.
I won't be going anywhere.
You're my friends.
I wouldn't go anywhere!
I see.
Right.
I won't go anywhere.
I'll make sure to come back right here.
It's just that for a short time,
I'm going to spend my time differently than usual.
So that in the future, I can live a straightforward life as myself.
A small journey so that
I won't regret anything.
You're looking better now.
Are your worries gone now?
Dad?
You knew that I was worried about something?
Of course I did.
I am your father, after all.
You're going to take off early in the morning tomorrow, right?
Yeah. I'm sorry to trouble you.
Well, you're a strong girl, Nanoha.
I'm not all that worried.
Make sure to do your best!
Yeah!
City of Uminari suburbs
Takamachi residence, 5:27 AM
Nanoha!
Uminari Seaside Park, 5:55 AM
It's all right if it's here, right?
Please come out, Fate!
Scythe Form
Fate, let's stop all this now.
You shouldn't listen to what that woman tells you!
Fate, you'll end up more and more miserable if you keep going.
So please, Fate!
But still...
I'm still her daughter.
It's not good enough to just throw it away.
And it's even worse if
I were to run away.
I'm sure it all started with the Jewel Seeds.
So, both of us should risk every
Jewel Seed that we have!
Put out.
That's where it starts.
Where it all starts.
Nothing between us has even begun.
So, in order to start our true selves...
Let's begin...
our first and last serious battle!
Make a little wish
Even though at times
I'll trip or get lost
Because you're with me, I can continue to smile and be energetic
Ah, going over the sea of cellophane and over the forests
Passing through the silver wind
I was looking for something neither of us had
Ah, I was just crying inside a diorama of a city
Until I met that warm hand that reached out to me that day
Among the swaying days,
I felt a strong gaze
Hey, I finally, finally found the secret key
Make a little wish
Collecting the lemon-colored drops from the moon
I want to keep a light shining on the road that you travel down
Make a little wish
I wonder if there is something I can do even though I'm so little
Because you're with me, I can continue to smile and be energetic
The duel with Fate that
I decided I would have,
and the two individuals past and present that it pieces together.
The Garden of Time begins to move.
What is the Alhazred that Presea is longing for?
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha:
Episode 11
Memories That Lie Beyond Time
Episode 11:
Lyrical, magical, full power, all-out!