Prayers echoing in the vast skies turn to miracles
Teardrops melt and flow into the blue of the middle of the night
I met a warmth that engulfs all without hesitation
Just like the pure white snow
Words that are honest no matter how far you go
It moves me as I wear wings of steel
Each time I am hurt,
I can become kinder
My only wish is to protect that smile of yours to the end
Memories of sadness engraved across the ages
You are an angel of light,
catching them straight on
An eternal blaze that stopped
in my heart that day
Releasing the deep darkness
It opens the door of freedom
Towards the strong, boundless future
June 3, 9:05 PM
City of Uminari, Nakaoka district
Sat
You have one new message.
Hello, this is Dr. Ishida from
Uminari University Hospital.
Let's see... tomorrow is
your birthday, right, Hayate?
I was calling to see if you would be interested
in eating together after the checkup tomorrow.
I'd be happy if you could give me a reply
before you come to the hospital tomorrow.
Best regards.
End of message.
It's already midnight.
Ich entferne eine Versiegelung.
I'm breaking the seal.
Anfang.
Start up.
The Beginning Comes Suddenly
December 1, 6:35 AM
City of Uminari, Sakuradai
Okay, to finish off
this morning's practice...
Let's try shooting control.
All right.
Lyrical, magical!
Glimmers to be blessings, come to my hands.
Ring and echo under the guidance.
Divine Shooter
Shoot!
Control...
18... 19... 20... 21...
Accelerate.
55... 60... 64... 68... 70... 73...
98... 100.
Last one!
Don't mind, my master.
Thanks, Raising Heart.
I'm Nanoha Takamachi.
Until fairly recently, I was
a very, very ordinary third-grader.
But because of a certain incident that happened this past spring,
I became a mage.
If you were scoring
today's practice, how was it?
About 80 points.
I see...
All the people back then who gave me magic,
many new introductions, and courage
are slightly distant from me right now.
But I'm sure that I'll see them again soon.
Nanoha, there's mail for you.
Oh, really?
Airmail from overseas, sent from Fate Testarossa.
Thank you, Kyōya!
It's that girl who always sends you mail.
Is it another video letter?
Yeah! I'm sure it is.
You've been pen-pals with her for over half a year now.
Fate is coming to visit us soon, right?
When she does come by, I'm going to give her a big warm welcome!
Yeah!
But it's kind of lonely here,
ever since we found Yuuno's owners.
You took particularly good care of him.
Well... we might end up taking care of him again.
It depends on the owners.
That'd be great!
Wouldn't it?
Hey, Mom, do you think
Yuuno remembers who I am?
Fate... Yuuno... Chrono and
Mrs. Lindy... Miss Amy...
I wonder if everyone is doing well?
Same time, the Dimensional Sea
Time-Space Administrative Bureau Flagship Arthra
Preparations to dock at the Bureau's Main Office are now complete.
Our plans are going well.
Isn't that good?
Excuse me...
Captain, would you like some more tea?
Thank you, Amy. I'll have some.
After we dock at the Main Office,
the Arthra and all of us
finally get a break.
Right.
Where are the kids?
Right now, the three of them should be resting.
Enforcer Chrono and Fate were
undergoing battle training until a few moments ago,
and Yuuno was hanging out there with them.
I see.
Even though tomorrow is the final day of the trial...
They're sure going at their own pace.
Here.
Well, it's a trial that we're sure to win.
Now... next up, the final examination.
Fate, you're on the defendant's side.
Answer the judge's questions honestly, according to this data.
Yes.
Today, we're going to have Arf go into the defendant's booth too.
Got it.
And Ferret Boy and I
will be in the witness seats...
The answers to the questions are exactly what you see there.
Yeah, got it...
Hey, wait!
What is it?
Who's Ferret Boy, huh, who?!
That would be you. What about it?
It's true that I'm in my animal form often,
but, you know, I have a fine name, Yuuno Scrya!
Yuuno, chill out.
Chrono, don't make too much fun of him.
It's all right.
It's only a lighthearted joke to ease the tense air.
With all facts considered,
I'm pretty positive that the verdict will be innocent,
though with several years of probation.
But I would like you to put all the answers firmly into your mind.
Okay!
Fine...
Thanks for your hard work,
Commodore Lindy.
Is everything going according to plan?
Right, Laty, if there's no problems on your end?
Yeah, nothing concerning the
Arthra's docking and maintenance.
On this end, there is a situation that isn't too happy.
An unhappy situation?
A Lost Logia.
A very dangerous item with a civilian search request.
Its marks have been found on several worlds,
and the one in charge of searching for it is all worked up.
Really...
They sent out investigators,
and we're currently waiting for a report from them.
I see.
Fate
Nanoha
December 2, 2:23 AM
City of Uminari, office district
Pushovers.
At this rate, they won't be much of an addition, but...
The Book of Darkness
is gonna snack on
both of your magical powers.
December 2, 4:24 PM
Kazegaoka Library
Then I'll see you again tomorrow.
Yeah.
Bye-bye!
Is this it?
Yes. Thank you so much!
I see. We're the same age!
Yeah. I saw you around here every so often,
and I thought, hey, it's someone my age!
Actually, so did I.
Let's see. I'm Suzuka Tsukimura.
Suzuka...
I'm Hayate Yagami.
Hayate...
Hayate is written all in hiragana.
Isn't it a strange name?
That's not true at all!
I think it's a beautiful name.
Thanks...
Thanks, Suzuka, this is far enough.
Yeah... well, then...
Thanks for having
a conversation with me.
Thanks a bunch!
See you again, Hayate.
Hayate, are you sure you're not cold?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Shamal, aren't you cold too?
I'm not cold at all.
Signum!
Yes...
About dinner...
What would you two like to eat, Signum, Shamal?
Oh, that's right.
I can't decide.
Why don't we think about it as we shop
for ingredients at the supermarket?
That's good.
Come to think of it, did Vita
step out somewhere again today?
Um, well... I believe so.
She seems to be playing around outside,
but Zafira is with her,
so there isn't much to worry about.
I see.
But even with a little distance between us,
we're always right by your side.
Yes... we are always at your side.
Thank you.
December 2, 7:45 PM
City of Uminari, downtown
How is it, Vita? Think you can find it?
It's like it's here, but it's not here.
A curiously large magical response
that's been appearing every so often for a while now.
If we can catch it,
I think we can gain about twenty pages at once.
Let's split up and search. I'll entrust you with the Book of Darkness.
Okay, Zafira. You search hard too, okay?
Understood.
Sealing area... unfold.
Magical Prison
Gefängnis der Magie
Caution. Emergency.
A barrier?
Magical response.
Found the big one!
Let's go, Graf Eisen!
Jawohl.
Roger.
It approaches at high speed.
It's coming closer to us?
Approaching target.
Gegenstand kommt an.
It comes.
Homing bullet.
Tödlichschlag
Deadly Smash
Raising Heart, please!
Standby, ready. Set up.
Flying Swallow
Schwalbefliegen
I can't think of why
someone would want to attack me.
Where are you from?
Why the heck
are you doing such a thing?
If you don't tell me,
I can't understand!
Kiss my ass!
Flash Move
Shooting Mode
Listen to...
Divine...
...what I have to say!
...Buster
Graf Eisen, Cartridge Load!
Explosion
Rocket Form
Raketenform
Rocket...
Raketen...
...Hammer
Protection
Bust through it!
Jawohl.
Roger.
Is this going to be the end?
No way...
Yuuno...
Chrono...
Fate!
I'm sorry, Nanoha. We were a bit late.
Yuuno?
Her allies?
Scythe Form
Her friends.
I won't forget even when I grow up
My love, the day that we came across each other
In this place, where flowers bloom intensely
I kept you in tears
I remember the promise
My love, the smile that I love so much
That day, when the secret door opened
I was chasing after a small white butterfly
I got lost, and I wanted to cry
My true wishes, my true feelings
Maybe you taught those to me
Guarded by such kind feelings
I'm sure I was spoiled for all this time
How you thought dear of me
My love, I won't forget all of you
Next Episode Preview
Beginnings always come so suddenly.
But this incident is just too sudden.
Confusion... worries...
What should I do?
The emergence of a powerful enemy puts us in a crisis.
What are the objectives of these girls who came after us?
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha A's:
Episode 2: Once Again,
the Storms of Battle
Lyrical, magical, we'll do our best.
Once Again, the Storms of Battle