It was only a small wish.
To exchange smiles...
To gently touch one another...
However, what welcomed us was a period of warfare.
The powers that were taken away from us.
The staves of magic that were damaged.
It is still unclear,
who we should be fighting against and what we can do.
But still, we...
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha A's will now begin.
Prayers echoing in the vast skies turn to miracles
Teardrops melt and flow into the blue of the middle of the night
I met a warmth that engulfs all without hesitation
Just like the pure white snow
Words that are honest no matter how far you go
It moves me as I wear wings of steel
Each time I am hurt,
I can become kinder
My only wish is to protect that smile of yours to the end
Memories of sadness engraved across the ages
You are an angel of light, catching them straight on
An eternal blaze that stopped in my heart that day
Releasing the deep darkness
It opens the door of freedom
Towards the strong, boundless future
December 2, 8:45 PM
Time-Space Administrative Bureau Main Office
According to the test results,
her wounds aren't that bad.
However, the source of a mage's power,
her Linker Core, has shrunk to an unusual size.
I see. Then that's the same flow of events as all the other cases.
Yes. There's no doubt about it.
Looks like our vacation's on hold.
From the looks of things, we'll have to deal with this case.
That can't be helped.
This is the type of job we're supposed to do.
Reunion and Relocation!
No, it's a good thing that your injuries weren't serious.
Chrono... I'm sorry I made you worry.
Between you and Nanoha,
I've gotten used to it.
Don't worry about it.
That's youth for you.
The recovery of your Linker Core has already begun.
But for a while, you won't be able to use most of your magic,
so be careful.
Okay.
Thank you very much.
Ah, Enforcer Harlaown.
Can I have a moment?
Yes, what is it?
This way.
Something wrong?
About that thing, you know, the...
Fate...
Nanoha...
Um... I'm sorry.
We finally got to see each other again, but this happened.
Are your wounds all right?
Oh... no, this is nothing.
More than that, Nanoha, you...
I'm fine too!
It's all thanks to all of you guys, Fate!
Happy and full of energy!
Fate?
Fate!
Nanoha!
I'm sorry, I'm still a bit woozy.
Yeah...
Thanks for saving me, Fate.
And I'm really happy that
I got to see you again.
Yeah... Me too...
I'm so happy I got to see you, Nanoha.
Nanoha! Fate!
Yuuno, Miss Arf!
Long time no see, Nanoha!
Nanoha!
Everybody...
Bardiche...
I'm sorry. I just wasn't strong enough.
What's the damage status?
Honestly, it's not looking too good.
Right now, we have the auto-repairs going.
After all the basic structures have been re-established,
we have to reboot them and change all sorts of parts.
I see.
Hey, come to think of it...
Wasn't there something strange about those guys' magic?
That was probably the Belkan style.
Belkan style?
It's a type of magic that, in the past,
was in a power struggle with the Mid style.
A type of magic that de-emphasizes long-distance and long-range attacks
in order to specialize in close-quarters combat.
Mages who excel in it are called knights.
That's right. She said she's a Belkan knight.
Their most noteworthy characteristic is the armament
known as the Cartridge System that's integrated into their devices.
They use shells filled with specially compressed magic into their devices
to gain explosive destructive power for a fleeting moment.
It's a dangerous, troublesome system.
I see.
Thank you for giving it your very best, Raising Heart.
For now, rest up a whole bunch.
Fate... it's almost time for the interview.
Yeah...
Nanoha...
Can I also have a moment with you?
Yuuno, Arf...
Amy.
I just ordered new parts for
Raising Heart and Bardiche!
They said they'd get everything to us today, or tomorrow at the latest.
Thank you so much.
And so,
moments ago, this case officially came under our jurisdiction.
But isn't the Arthra under maintenance?
That's right.
Oh, right! Do you know where Chrono is?
He's getting interviewed with Nanoha and Fate.
It seemed like a bigwig from the Bureau.
I see.
Chief Advisor, Time-Space Administrative Bureau
Gil Graham
Excuse me.
It's been a while, Chrono.
It has been quite a while.
They call me a probation officer, but it's only in name.
I've heard of the recent incident
and about who you are as a person from Commodore Lindy,
that you were a really nice girl.
Thank you very much.
Admiral Graham used to be
Chrono's instructor.
A historically-noted brave soul...
In his prime, he was the commander of an entire fleet,
and later, he became the Chief Enforcer.
He's a tremendously important guy!
Yeah, but he's a good guy.
He's really nice too.
Nanoha, you're Japanese, correct?
The scenery of Japan really takes me back.
I am also from the same world that you live in. I'm British.
Is that so?
Most people on that world have no magical powers.
But once in a while, there is someone
with high magical potential, like you and me.
Your encounter with magic was almost exactly like mine.
In my case, the person that I saved was an agent of the Bureau.
That was well over fifty years ago.
Fate, you are Nanoha's friend, right?
Yes...
There is one thing I want you to promise me.
Never betray your friends, nor all the people who believe in you.
If you can do that,
I promise that I will not put any limitations upon your actions.
Can you do that?
Yes, absolutely.
That's a good answer.
Admiral, I'm sure you've heard of this already,
but moments ago, we were chosen to search for and investigate
the Book of Darkness, a Lost Logia.
I see. So it is you.
I don't think I have the right to say this,
but don't do anything reckless.
It's all right.
In times of crisis, keeping your cool is your greatest ally.
Exactly as you taught us, Admiral.
That's true.
Then...
Same day, same time
City of Uminari, Yagami residence
Hayate, I've drawn the bath for you!
Yeah, thanks!
Vita, you should take a bath with us.
Okay.
Tomorrow, we're going to the hospital in the morning.
Make sure to not stay up too late.
Okay!
Then, there we go...
Signum, what about your bath?
I will pass tonight.
I will take it in the morning.
Really?
How unusual, for someone who loves baths so much.
Sometimes, there are days like this.
Then I'll go on ahead!
Yes.
In today's battle?
You're sharp. That's it exactly.
It pierced through your armor?
It was a very pure blade path.
She must have learned from a great master.
If not for the difference in weapon quality,
I might have had a harder time against her.
But even so, you wouldn't have lost.
That's true.
Thank you, Shamal.
It feels so nice!
I'm so glad.
This is paradise!
We, the Wolkenritter...
On our pride as knights...
Cloud Knights
Oh, Miss Fate!
Commodore Lindy.
Family? Mrs. Lindy and Fate?
Yeah. It hasn't been set in stone yet,
but they're talking about adoption.
Because of the Presea incident, Fate has become all alone in this world.
The Captain asked her, "Would you like to be our child?"
Fate had all sorts of things to work through with Presea.
For now, we're all waiting on her feelings to settle down.
I see.
How do you feel about that, Nanoha?
Well... somehow, I think it's a very good idea.
I see!
But that means Chrono becomes Fate's big brother.
Right, right!
But they seem to get along well,
so I think they'd make pretty good siblings.
Chrono?
Captain...
You're with her, Fate?
Yeah.
The materials for this case...
Have you read them yet?
Yes. I read all of it moments ago.
Nanoha's world is in the center of the Serial Mage Assaults Incident.
Right... it is almost strictly limited to an area
where you can reach by personal teleports from Nanoha's world.
That area is pretty far from the Main Office.
We can't teleport without using a relay port.
It's rather painful that we can't use the Arthra.
It would be nice if there were an open ship that we can use.
They said that no long-range cruisers are available for the next two months.
I see.
Or rather, Fate, are you all right with this?
With what?
Even though you're contracted with us, you're still outside help.
You don't have to force yourself to keep up with us in this case.
Chrono, you and Commodore Lindy are in trouble.
I can't just kick back and play around.
Arf says that she will help out as well.
So please let me help!
Yeah. I appreciate it, but...
I guess we'll do that, after all!
That?
Now, we, the staff of the Arthra,
have been assigned to investigate the Serial Mage Assaults Incident,
and the search for the Book of Darkness, a Lost Logia.
However, our key ship, the Arthra, is out of commission for a while,
so we will set up a temporary base near the site of the incidents.
Your orders.
Observation staff, Allex and Landy.
Yes, ma'am!
Investigation crew, your leader will be Garret!
At the command post will be myself and Enforcer Chrono,
Enforcer's Aide Amy, and Miss Fate.
We'll operate in three rotating shifts.
And the command post,
to secure the safety of
Miss Nanoha at the same time,
will be located in the vicinity of Miss Nanoha's house.
Amazing! This is really close to my place!
Really?
Yeah. See, that's my house over there!
Yuuno, Arf, you use those guises on this world?
My new form, a puppy!
I have to be in this form when I'm in front of Nanoha and Fate's friends.
Must be rough on both of you.
Arf, you're tiny! What happened?
Yuuno, it's been a while since
I last saw you in ferret mode!
Aren't I cute?
Yeah.
Nanoha, Fate, your friends are here.
Coming!
Hello!
We're here!
Alisa! Suzuka!
Nice to meet you... though it sounds strange to say that.
We've seen each other so many times in all the video letters.
Yeah.
But I'm so happy that I got to meet you, Alisa, Suzuka.
Me too.
Miss Fate, are these your friends?
Hello!
Hello. You must be Suzuka and Alisa?
Yes. You know about us?
I've seen the video letters as well.
I see!
If you'd like, why won't we go have some tea together?
Oh, if that's the case, let's go to our place!
Oh, that's true.
Then I'll take this opportunity to say hello to your folks, Nanoha.
Hold on just a second.
She's a very pretty lady.
Is that your mom, Fate?
Well, um... she's not, yet...
Yuuno, it's been a while!
You know, I think I've seen you somewhere before.
Maybe it's just me?
And so, starting today, we're going to be neighbors for a while.
I give you my best regards.
Oh, the pleasure will be all ours!
Please come by often.
Fate is in third grade, right?
Where will she go to school?
Yes, actually...
Commo—Mrs. Lindy!
Yes, what is it?
Um, this... This is...
I sent in the transfer request, so starting next week,
you'll be classmates with Miss Nanoha.
Oh, how wonderful!
Seishō Elementary School? That's a wonderful school. Right, Nanoha?
Yeah!
I'm happy for you, Fate.
Well, um... yes...
Thank you very much.
The defining characteristic of this Lost Logia, the Book of Darkness,
is its source of energy.
The Book of Darkness eats Linker Cores
to absorb a mage's magical powers and potential.
Nanoha's Linker Core was one of the victims?
Yes, no doubt about it.
When the Book of Darkness eats a Linker Core,
it fills pages according to the amount of magical power absorbed.
And when every last page is filled,
the Book of Darkness will be completed.
What happens when it's completed?
At the least, it won't be anything decent.
You're here.
Yeah.
The Bureau is starting to seriously move around now,
so things won't go like they have been so far.
It seems we need to range a little further.
Let's start absorbing powers in worlds as far away as possible.
How many pages have we finished now?
340 pages.
We got quite a few, thanks to that girl in white the other day.
Alright, we're over halfway done!
Let's grab the rest with a swoosh, and hurry up and finish it!
We'll finish it quickly,
and we can all live quietly, together with Hayate.
Let's go. We don't have much time left.
Yeah.
Let's go, Lævateinn.
Victory.
Sieg.
Guide me, Klarwind.
Start up.
Anfang.
Let's do it, Graf Eisen!
Move!
Bewegung!
Then, meet back here again before dawn!
Vita, don't get too hot-headed.
I know that!
Yes, yes, Amy here.
Oh, Ms. Amy, this is Marie from the Main Office maintenance staff.
What's up? Something wrong?
About the two Intelligent Devices that you entrusted me with...
They're acting kind of strange.
We're done with all the repairs and part exchanges,
but this error code doesn't go away.
Error? Which type?
Yeah, they say that they still lack necessary parts.
I'll send you the data right now.
Oh, here it comes!
The missing part is... this?
Yes... this is some kind of a mistake, right?
Error Code E203
Necessary parts are missing.
To fix this error,
please install the
system containing part CVK-792.
Both of them are stuck on this message,
and won't accept any commands at all.
That's why we're having trouble.
Raising Heart... Bardiche...
Are they serious?
CVK-792...
A Belka-style Cartridge System...
Please.
I won't forget even when I grow up
My love, the day that we came across each other
In this place, where flowers bloom intensely
I kept you in tears
I remember the promise
My love, the smile that I love so much
That day, when the secret door opened
I was chasing after a small white butterfly
I got lost, and I wanted to cry
My true wishes, my true feelings
Maybe you taught those to me
Guarded by such kind feelings
I'm sure I was spoiled for all this time
How you thought dear of me
My love, I won't forget all of you
Fate's transfer and a new battle!
In both aspects, all of my preparations are complete.
Both Raising Heart and Bardiche came back safe and sound, but...
Is this...
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha A's:
Episode 4: New Power, Start!
Drive Ignition!
New Power, Start!