Each time my heart passes by someone else,
each time we collide,
I had always thought
how it would be nice if words and feelings
could portray everything that we wish for.
But there are people with stronger wishes than words or justice.
What you need is not words, but a strong heart.
No lies, no hesitation...
We will stand against those straightforward eyes
with a determined heart.
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha A's will now begin.
Prayers echoing in the vast skies turn to miracles
Teardrops melt and flow into the blue of the middle of the night
I met a warmth that engulfs all without hesitation
Just like the pure white snow
Words that are honest no matter how far you go
It moves me as I wear wings of steel
Each time I am hurt,
I can become kinder
My only wish is to protect that smile of yours to the end
Memories of sadness engraved across the ages
You are an angel of light, catching them straight on
An eternal blaze that stopped in my heart that day
Releasing the deep darkness
It opens the door of freedom
Towards the strong, boundless future
That's all the data we have.
Is it of any help?
Yes... thank you. It's a big help.
Hey, all of you are going to come over here today, right?
Yeah, regarding the Arthra.
How about we find some time and have a meal together?
I'd like to hear about that girl, too.
That girl?
You know, the one you're taking care of.
The one you said you wanted to adopt.
Oh, you mean Fate.
Right, Fate. Is she doing well?
Yeah.
I feel bad about having her working with us on this case.
But she's together with her good friends,
so she looks like she's enjoying it as she works.
With the Broken Past and Present
There sure are a lot of them.
Well, lately all of them have similar specs.
So I think you can choose by how it looks, right?
But you still want one that has good text messaging capabilities!
With a good, clear camera, you can have all sorts of fun.
But in the end, the color and design is what's important.
Ease of use is also important!
External memory is very useful, so it's a good thing...
Really?
Yeah, you can keep lots of pictures and music in it.
And you can attach them to your text messages to send to your friends!
That's true!
It's rather useful.
That one's nice...
Thank you very much.
Yes, thank you!
Fate... here you go.
Thank you so much, Commodore Lindy.
Sorry to make you wait.
It's okay.
Did you find a good number?
Yeah.
What is it?
Let's see... here.
The supermassive database that has every book and piece of data imaginable
from every world the Bureau administrates.
Where many histories are packed whole,
you can say it's the place that stocks memories of entire worlds.
That is this place, the Infinity Library.
Though most of the contents are completely unorganized.
Looking for something here is a big hassle, you know?
Usually, people form large teams and research here for years on end.
Investigating past history is what my clan does for a living.
I brought search magic as well, so we'll be fine.
That's right.
You're one of the Scrya kids.
Both Lotte and I have work to do,
so we can't stay here the whole time until you're done,
but we'll help as much as we can.
After all, it's a request from
Chroboy, my cute apprentice.
I see... so both Alisa and Suzuka are taking violin lessons?
Yeah.
They text me to tell me about their lessons all the time.
I see.
I'm back!
Has the captain taken off for the Main Office already?
Yeah...
Apparently, the weaponry refit of the Arthra is finished,
so she went on a test drive with Allex and the others.
Weaponry... that must be the Arc-en-Ciel.
Hopefully we can get by till the end without using that scary thing.
Chrono isn't here, either...
So until either of them gets back,
looks like you're the temporary leader, Miss Amy.
So much responsibility!
That's a scary thought in a different way.
Well, I'm sure there can't be that many emergencies going on...
Civilization level, zero.
It's a desert world with no human inhabitants.
At least 45 minutes to assemble agents to form a barrier...
This isn't looking good.
Amy, I'll go!
Me too!
Right. Please do.
Sure!
Nanoha, you're our back-end defense.
Stay here on standby.
Okay.
Let's go, Bardiche!
Yes, sir.
Small wonder that Vita had such a hard time.
This is a slightly troublesome opponent.
Dammit...
Thunder Blade
Break!
Are you worried about your mistress?
You again...
Our mistresses are one-on-one right now.
The same goes for us.
Signum is our leader,
but she is not my mistress.
That means your mistress is the mistress of the Book of Darkness, huh?
Fate! What are you doing, helping her?!
You're supposed to capture her!
I'm sorry, I couldn't help it.
I won't give my thanks, Testarossa.
Did I get in your way?
You crushed our target for filling the Book.
Well, my job is to get in the way of villains.
I see. That's right, I'm a villain.
Another location?!
Is this end the real deal?!
Nanoha!
Yes!
It's been a while, Commodore Lindy.
Yes...
The Book of Darkness Incident...
Any progress on it?
It's quite a difficult task, but I will manage it well.
You do excellent work.
I'm sure you won't make a blunder, unlike the time that I tried.
I had mentioned this to you at my husband's funeral,
but that blunder was not caused by you, Admiral.
No commander could have ever predicted such a thing would happen.
Oh... how dextrous...
You can figure out what's inside like that?
Yes... well, sort of.
Um... Miss Lieselotte, you two were there for
the previous Book of Darkness Incident, right?
Yeah.
It was, after all, only eleven years ago.
Um... is it true?
That Chrono's father passed away in the incident...?
It's true.
Aria and I were together with Father,
so we saw it really close up.
The one transporting the Book of
Darkness that we thought was sealed
was Clyde... oh, that's Chrono's father.
Right.
We saw Clyde go down with the guard ship.
So the way to seal it turned out to be the Arc-en-Ciel after all.
There is no other weapon that can emit so much power at once.
That thing causes too much collateral damage.
I hope we can settle everything without firing it.
It would be nice if we could find its mistress.
Well, even if we got the mistress down,
the Book of Darkness has a respawn function,
so all we'd do is push back the problem for several years,
until it wanders into the hands of the next master.
Even then, it's better than having a huge disaster right now.
I suppose so.
Were it possible, I would like to postpone our promised showdown.
But you have higher speed.
If I can't escape, I must fight.
Yes.
That is why I've come.
Snake Form
Schlangenform
Load Cartridge. Haken Form.
Haken Saber
Blitz Rush
Haken Slash
The sheath!
Plasma Lancer
Assault Form
Sword Form
Schwertform
Plasma...
Flying Dragon...
...Smasher
...Flash
If you're a familiar... a guardian beast... like me,
shouldn't you be trying to correct your mistress' errors?!
We fill the Book of Darkness of our own will.
Our mistress has no knowledge of our filling of the pages.
What?!
What does that...
Fighting for your mistress, even if blood stains your hands?
As a fellow guardian beast like myself, would you not do so?
I would!
But, even so!
Signum's group is...
Yes... they're fighting in the desert now.
Against Testarossa and her guardian beast.
It'll be bad if it goes on for too long.
Should I go help her?
Vita?
Dammit... another one showed up over here!
That girl in the white outfit...
No-name Takamachi!
It's Nanoha, already!
Na-no-ha!
Vita...
Can't I hear what you have to say after all?
You never know,
it's possible that I can help you out.
Shut up!
I can't trust anything that someone from the Bureau would say!
I'm not from the Bureau.
I'm just a civilian helper.
I can only fill pages of the Book of Darkness once from any mage.
In other words, even if I defeat her, she won't turn into new pages.
I'd like to avoid wasting cartridges too.
Vita...
I'll defeat you...
...some other time!
Howl, Graf Eisen!
Iron Howl
Eisengeheul
Gotta escape!
Master.
Alright.
She can't attack me from that far away.
Dimensional transport...
Buster Mode
Drive Ignition
Here goes...
My first long-range blaster attack in a while!
Load Cartridge
No way...
She's going to shoot?!
From that far away?!
Divine Buster...
...Extension
Divine...
...Buster
You're kidding!
It's a direct hit.
Did we overdo it a little?
Don't worry.
You're...
Go.
You're going to finish the
Book of Darkness, right?
Divine...
Master!
A bind?!
It can't be!
From all the way over there, in an instant?!
Sorry, master.
No... I was caught off guard.
This far in the game, yet so fast...
She's starting to make attacks my eyes can't keep up with.
If I don't end this battle soon, it will go badly.
So strong...
She's overpowering me at both close-range and mid-range...
For now, I'm fooling her with my speed,
but if she lands a blow squarely, she'll crush me.
Will I be able to land a hit with Storm Falcon?
Sturmfalken
No choice but to use Sonic Form?
Testarossa!
Curse you!
Now, take it.
I won't forget even when I grow up
My love, the day that we came across each other
In this place, where flowers bloom intensely
I kept you in tears
I remember the promise
My love, the smile that I love so much
That day, when the secret door opened
I was chasing after a small white butterfly
I got lost, and I wanted to cry
My true wishes, my true feelings
Maybe you taught those to me
Guarded by such kind feelings
I'm sure I was spoiled for all this time
How you thought dear of me
My love, I won't forget all of you
Fate's Linker Core has been taken.
The Arthra is back,
but the mysteries of the case grow even deeper.
What is the history of the Book of Darkness
that Yuuno's research uncovers?
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha A's:
Episode 8: The Heartbreaking Decision
and the Courageous Choice
Drive Ignition!
The Heartbreaking Decision and the Courageous Choice