It was only a small miracle.
Prayers went far into the sky.
Tears became light and a rainbow.
The long night came to an end.
The farewell at the time of departure is not the end,
but a word of beginning.
The final episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha A's will now begin.
Prayers echoing in the vast skies turn to miracles
Teardrops melt and flow into the blue of the middle of the night
I met a warmth that engulfs all without hesitation
Just like the pure white snow
Words that are honest no matter how far you go
It moves me as I wear wings of steel
Each time I am hurt,
I can become kinder
My only wish is to protect that smile of yours to the end
Memories of sadness engraved across the ages
You are an angel of light, catching them straight on
An eternal blaze that stopped in my heart that day
Releasing the deep darkness
It opens the door of freedom
Towards the strong, boundless future
As expected, the damage is exceedingly serious.
The protection program was killed,
but my basic structure is still the same.
I, the core of the
Tome of the Night Sky,
will soon create a new protection program
and start to go out of control again.
As expected.
You can't repair the corruption?
It's impossible.
The original Tome of the Night Sky has been erased from me,
its operating system.
As long we don't know the original system,
there's no way we can restore it.
That's right.
Is Mistress Hayate okay?
There's no problem.
I won't encroach on her further,
and her Linker Core is also functioning normally.
Her disabled legs should heal soon, as well.
I see. Well then, we should say we've had a good life.
Yes, there's nothing to regret.
Since it doesn't have its protection program,
it's easy to completely destroy the Tome of the Night Sky.
As long as we destroy it, it won't ever go out of control again.
But in return, we will get erased.
I'm sorry, Vita.
Why are you apologizing?
I don't mind.
We all knew this might happen.
No, that's not true.
You guys will stay.
I'm the only one who will go.
Standby, Ready
Destroy the Tome of the Night Sky?
Why?
I thought we already killed the protection program!
It's a suggestion from the Book of Darkness,
which is the operating system of the Tome of the Night Sky.
The operating system that everyone was fighting?
Yeah.
We were able to kill the protection program,
but the Tome of the Night Sky quickly relaunches its programs.
There is a high probability that
Hayate will be further affected.
As long as the Tome of the Night Sky exists,
that danger will not disappear.
That is why the Book of Darkness asked for us to destroy it,
when it does not have its protection program running.
No way...
But then, Signum and the others will...
No.
We will remain.
Signum...
Along with the protection program,
it seems that the guardian knight programs were freed from the operating system.
Reinforce is asking for a favor from you two.
A favor?
Hayate's happiness is our greatest happiness.
So Reinforce said she will go smiling.
So even if it's in your dreams, please praise her, okay?
Oh, you came.
Reinforce...
You'll call me by that name?
Are you sure you want us to return you to the sky?
I wanted to ask it of you two.
Thanks to you, I was able to listen to Mistress Hayate's words.
I didn't have to eat away at Mistress Hayate anymore,
and I was able to help the knights live.
I'm grateful.
That's why I want you two to put an end to me.
Don't you have to say goodbye to Hayate?
I don't want to make Mistress Hayate sad.
Reinforce...
But that's just too sad!
You will understand someday,
when you meet someone who you love as deeply as the sea,
and whose happiness you want to protect.
Shall we begin soon?
The end of the
Tome of the Night Sky.
Reinforce?
Ready to set.
Stand by.
We didn't know each other long, but I give thanks to you two as well.
Don't worry.
Take a good journey.
Yes.
Reinforce!
Everyone!
Hayate?
Hayate!
Stay back!
Please stay back.
My consciousness will cease.
No! Stop!
Stop, Reinforce!
You don't need to be destroyed!
I'll hold on to it!
It's okay. You don't have to do this!
Mistress Hayate...
It's for the best.
No, it's not!
It isn't for the best at all!
I have lived a long time,
but in the end, you gave me a beautiful name and a soul.
The knights will be beside you.
You don't have to worry.
I'm not worried!
That's why I can go smiling.
I don't like people who won't listen!
I'm your master, so listen to me!
I'm sure I can do something.
We promised that we won't go out of control!
You've kept that promise magnificently.
Reinforce!
My duty as a magical vessel is to protect my mistress from danger.
Please let me choose the best way to protect you.
But...
But you were always so sad,
and we... we finally saved you!
My will remains in your magic and the knights' souls.
I will always be beside you.
That's not true.
That's not true, Reinforce!
Your friends don't like whiners.
Please understand, my mistress.
Reinforce!
Why? Everything was going to begin now.
Now I can make you happy...
It's okay.
I am the happiest magic book in the whole world.
Reinforce...
Mistress Hayate,
I have one favor to ask.
When I disappear, a powerless fragment will remain.
If you like, can you give my name, not to that,
but to the next magical vessel you will obtain someday?
Reinforce, the Wind of Blessing.
I'm sure my soul will dwell within it.
Reinforce...
Yes, my mistress.
Mistress Hayate...
Guardian knights...
And you young heroes.
Thank you and goodbye.
Hayate...
Hayate!
I see... okay, got it.
Thanks for the message.
Please rest at home for today.
I'll go home tomorrow.
Yeah.
Was that Fate?
She confirmed the destruction of the Tome's core.
I see...
As for Admiral Graham, he resigned his commission in response to this case.
Seems like he's going back to his homeland.
Well, he basically hacked and interfered with the investigation.
That's about it, right?
I wonder what's going to happen with Hayate?
He said he's going to continue supporting her financially.
When she becomes independent,
he said that he's going to tell her the truth.
I see.
Now you can tell your husband.
When are you going?
Next week.
With Chrono and Fate, all three of us.
What are you planning to say?
Let's see...
Probably the same as always.
I'll say that it's as busy as ever, but I'm doing fine.
I see.
I guess the case is over.
Yeah.
But I feel a little lonely.
Chrono said that cases related to
Lost Logia always end up like this.
Sad things link together as we get pulled in by a massive power.
Yeah.
I think I'm going to continue working with the Bureau,
because I want to become an Enforcer.
Cases like my mother's and this one...
Even if it's just a little, I want to help stop them quickly.
What about you, Nanoha?
Nanoha, have you been thinking about what's going to happen now?
I don't think I can become an Enforcer,
but I'm sure I'm headed the same direction as you, Fate.
I want to be able to properly use my magic.
Yuuno, even though you came back,
I was barely able to be with you.
I had to research things the whole time.
What are you going to do now?
The Bureau has asked me to become
the Chief Librarian of the Infinity Library.
I think they have a dorm for me at the Main Office,
and they said I can continue my archeology studies.
I'm thinking about accepting the offer.
If it's the Main Office, then that's close to Midchilda,
so I'll be happy.
Really?
Yeah!
Then, I'll leave here.
They said I can stay on the Arthra until I decide about the job.
I see.
Yeah.
Yuuno, if you have time during the end of this year or New Year's,
let's spend some time together, okay?
There's a lot of things
I want to tell you!
Yeah.
Do you have time tomorrow?
After I go to see Hayate with Alisa,
I' m thinking about having a Christmas party at my house.
I've invited Fate too.
I'd be happy if you came.
I need to tell you about everything that happened.
Hayate went back to the hospital?
Oh yeah, she left when she was still hospitalized.
Good morning.
Good morning, Nanoha, Fate.
Huh?
What happened? Are you leaving?
Unfortunately not.
I'll be here a little longer.
I see.
Well, I'm feeling well,
and I told Suzuka and Alisa that they didn't need to come visit.
We're going straight to the Christmas party!
Oh.
A lot happened yesterday,
but thanks for everything, from beginning to end.
No problem.
Don't worry about it.
Is that Reinforce?
Yeah.
She went to sleep, but she will always be with me.
I'm thinking about building my new Device into it.
Hayate, are you still going to be a mage?
Yeah, because it's the power that she gave me.
Due to this case, the knights and I
are going to be put on probation by the Bureau.
Really?
I guess.
It also includes doing community service for the Bureau
as restitution for our crimes.
Enforcer Chrono handled it for us.
The term is quite long,
but this was probably the only way we could stay with Hayate.
I see.
I will be treated as a part-time employee,
so that makes me your junior!
Hayate, you have to return for sure today.
Promise me.
Okay, I promise.
Did you have a hard time last night and today?
You always respond well.
Yeah. Since we went out without permission,
Okay, just make sure not to over-extend yourself.
Signum and Shamal got into big trouble.
Yes, we will be sure about that.
What a scary doctor...
So let's do a pinky promise.
But...
Okay!
She's a good doctor.
It seems like it.
Thank you very much.
Be careful, okay?
Okay!
Thanks for waiting.
No prob.
Testarossa.
Yes, Signum.
Let's someday put an end to our duel.
Yes, fair and square.
We can do it several times.
Good morning, Kyō.
What do you mean, morning?
It's already past noon.
What are you looking at?
A letter from Nanoha.
Let me see.
Dear Mom, Dad,
Kyōya, and Miyuki,
I have something really important to talk about.
Mrs. Lindy and Fate will also be coming,
so can we maybe talk before dinner? Nanoha.
An important talk?
What could it be about?
Let's see.
Maybe it's about her future plans.
Nanoha and Fate are almost here with Hayate.
They said that all three of them want to tell us something.
Yeah.
Hayate might have been involved with that thing last night too.
I wonder?
Well, if Nanoha wants to keep it a secret, then I don't mind.
If they're gonna tell us, then let's listen.
Yes...
I wish she could tell us the part about how she met Fate.
I feel we can become much closer if they tell us everything.
Yeah, that's right.
I see, so you are going to work at the Main Office too.
Yeah.
Nanoha is going to continue her part-time job,
and it seems like everyone is working for the Bureau.
It's admirable.
There are rumors about Nanoha becoming a combat instructor.
I'm also counting on you a little as the Chief Librarian.
Well, thank you very much.
Honestly, it causes less trouble to go outside in this form,
and it's really fuel-efficient!
Is that true?
And so the Book of Darkness Incident finally came to a close.
By going through many encounters and farewells, new days begin.
We will definitely...
I won't forget even when I grow up
My love, the day that we came across each other
In this place, where flowers bloom intensely
Hayate Yagami
9th Grader, Seishō Junior High School.
Special Investigator,
Time-Space Administrative Bureau.
Shamal,
please send the parcel to Uncle Graham.
I kept you in tears
Yes, leave it to me.
I remember the promise
Signum, I'll see you later.
Yes, later.
My love, the smile that I love so much
Okay!
Hayate, see you later!
I'm off!
That day, when the secret door opened
As the brilliant mage-knight leader of the Wolkenritter,
her guardian knights, she plays a large part in the investigation of cases related to Lost Logia.
Cloud Knights
I was chasing after a small white butterfly
Lindy Harlaown
Commodore,
Time-Space Administrative Bureau
There we go.
Fate, here's your lunch!
After stepping down from her position as Captain, she now works a desk job at the Main Office.
I got lost, and I wanted to cry
Thank you, Mom.
Fate T. Harlaown
9th Grader, Seishō Junior High School.
Enforcer, Time-Space Administrative Bureau.
My true wishes, my true feelings
Along with her familiar, Arf, she is handling front-line duties as an Enforcer.
Maybe you taught those to me
Guarded by such kind feelings
Chrono Harlaown
Commodore,
Time-Space Administrative Bureau.
Captain of the Arthra.
Everyone's getting together
for the first time in a while.
I'm sure I was spoiled for all this time
You're right.
Amy Limietta
Commander,
Time-Space Administrative Bureau
It might be for the first time
How you thought dear of me
since you became Captain, Chrono.
Well, it's a peaceful mission.
My love, I won't forget all of you
Even though they both got promoted, they still work well together.
It's like a little reunion.
Seems that way.
Yuuno, how about you?
Yeah, I'm right on time.
Yuuno Scrya
Chief Librarian,
Time-Space Administrative Bureau
Database, Infinity Library
That's right, Yuuno,
Has anything happened
Sometimes I get worried and want to cry
between you and Nanoha?
Well, we see each other often,
but nothing has happened...
But everyone passes by those times
Oh, dear.
Alongside his librarian position, he published a paper on ancient history and gained a good reputation as a scholar.
Amy, it's work time, you know.
Yeah, yeah.
During hard times, just remember
Nanoha!
Nanoha...
True tears and true smiles
Alisa! Suzuka!
Nanoha Takamachi
9th Grader, Seishō Junior High School.
Tactical Combat Instructor,
Time-Space Administrative Bureau
Armed Services.
Are polished through ordinary encounters
Good morning.
I won't forget even when I grow up
Do you have work today?
Yeah.
We're all getting together today.
Along with training incoming staff in combat tactics, she is doing amazing work as an investigations officer.
The days when we met
I'm gonna leave after lunch,
I want to convey from my heart
so can you please lend me your notes?
Okay. I'll take clear notes,
My love, I'm glad we met
so they'll be easy for you to copy.
Thank you.
Good morning!
Good morning.
I heard you're having a get-together today.
Yeah.
I'm really looking forward to it.
I want to smile like the flowers
Gil Graham
Retired Admiral,
Time-Space Administrative Bureau
True tears and true smiles
After his return to his hometown in England, he has retired and is spending time with his familiars.
Appear in innocent hearts
I won't forget even
when I grow up
The bond we forged
that day is still strong.
The days when we met
I want to convey from my heart
Raising Heart.
Yes, my master.
My love, I'm glad we met
Bardiche.
Yes, sir.
Reinforce.
Yes, Meister Hayate.
Standby, ready.
Set up!