I had always been alone,
so I wasn't too afraid of dying from illness.
But now it's different.
There are days I want to protect.
There are people I hold dear, who I want to make happy.
For everyone's sake,
I want to stay alive.
It's okay to smile, to stay strong.
That's what I thought.
Because I am everyone's master.
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha A's
will now begin.
Prayers echoing in the vast skies turn to miracles
Teardrops melt and flow into the blue of the middle of the night
I met a warmth that engulfs all without hesitation
Just like the pure white snow
Words that are honest no matter how far you go
It moves me as I wear wings of steel
Each time I am hurt,
I can become kinder
My only wish is to protect that smile of yours to the end
Memories of sadness engraved across the ages
You are an angel of light, catching them straight on
An eternal blaze that stopped in my heart that day
Releasing the deep darkness
It opens the door of freedom
Towards the strong, boundless future
December 22, 4:45 PM
Uminari University Hospital
Yes... everything is going well to this point.
Right.
Because I haven't gone back to that end,
the Bureau doesn't seem to be able to fully follow our activity.
I hope Mistress Hayate isn't feeling too lonely about this?
She hasn't said anything to me.
But it seems that her friends do visit often.
Suzuka and her friends.
I see.
But I don't want her to worry.
I'll return in a few days.
Okay. Please be careful.
Yes...
Sixty more pages remaining.
Christmas Eve
December 23, 7:12 PM
City of Uminari, Fujimi district, Takamachi residence
Here you go.
Oh, that looks tasty.
Wow!
Time to eat!
You should eat up too, Fate.
Yes... thank you so much.
Here, Nanoha, a plate for you.
Thanks.
Miyuki, you've gotten much better at cooking!
Here you go, Fate.
Thanks.
Are you going to be spending Christmas Eve
with your family after all, Fate?
Yes... well, for the time being.
I see.
We'll be busy as hell this Christmas Eve too.
I'll make the price tags and pop-up signs tonight!
Please do.
We'll need a good night's sleep tonight!
Midoriya's Christmas cakes
are very popular,
so we have lots of customers on Christmas Eve.
On top of that, we're open really late,
for the people who spend
Christmas Eve with lovers or friends.
I see.
You lucked out, Kyōya!
You can spend the entire time together with Shinobu in the café!
That doesn't have much to do with anything.
We'll make sure to keep the reserved cakes
for Alisa's and Suzuka's houses.
Yay!
I also have a reservation from Mrs. Lindy.
Look forward to it.
I will...
Thank you so much.
Is everybody all right with what we're doing
after closing ceremonies at school tomorrow?
We're going to go deliver
a present to Hayate, right?
But is it all right to go and surprise her?
Well, if it turns out to be inconvenient,
we'll have Dr. Ishida give it to her.
Then we'll go with that.
See you again tomorrow.
Good night.
And... send!
Orbit, Time-Space Administrative Bureau Flagship
Arthra
Hey... what's up, Chrono?
Nothing. Just looking something up.
What? I'd do it for you if you asked.
No, it's okay. It's something personal.
That report by Yuuno about the Book of Darkness...
Did you send it to
Nanoha and the others?
They seem to have mixed feelings
about the past of the
Book of Darkness as well.
I see.
Uminari University Hospital
December 24, 4:25 PM
Hayate...
I'm sorry I couldn't come to see you much.
It's okay... have you been doing well?
Super mega well!
Hello!
Oh? It's Suzuka.
Yes, come in!
Hello!
Is everyone here today?
Hello, nice to meet you.
Oh, I'm sorry...
Did we get in the way?
Oh, no...
Welcome, everyone.
Oh, okay. I'm so glad!
So what brings you all by today?
One, two...
Surprise presents!
It's Christmas Eve today,
so here's Christmas presents for you, Hayate.
Oh, really?
Thank you!
We all picked them out together.
Open them later, okay?
Yeah!
Nanoha, Fate, is something wrong?
Oh, no... nothing...
Just a little introduction, right?
Yes.
Oh, everyone, I'll take your coats...
Okay!
I can't use telepathy.
Are you blocking communications?
Shamal is our support expert.
She finds it quite simple at this distance.
Um, well... don't glare so much...
I'm not glaring.
I was born with eyes like this.
Vita, don't lie.
Hey, bad girls get something like this!
May we go ahead and visit?
Yes.
Uminari University Hospital
Goodbye!
What's wrong, Vita?
It's nothing.
Really?
I wonder if it'll snow tonight?
Hayate is the mistress of the Book of Darkness.
Our wish will be granted in just a little while.
If you get in our way,
even if you are Hayate's friends...
Wait, wait just a minute, listen to what we have to say!
You can't!
If the Book of Darkness is completed, Hayate...
Nanoha!
It would be a problem if you told the Bureau about our mistress.
I can't let you out of my area of communications jamming.
Vita...
Stay out of our way.
In just a little bit, we can save her.
Hayate's going to get better and come back to us!
We've been desperately giving it our all!
It's only a little bit more...
So stay out of our way!
You devil...
Then I'll be the devil.
Accel Mode. Drive Ignition.
I'll just fight like hell and make you listen to what I have to say!
Shamal...
You stay away and concentrate on the communications blocking.
Right.
The Book of Darkness is currently corrupted,
after an alteration of ill nature.
If you complete it as it is now, Hayate will...
We are, in a way, a part of the Book of Darkness!
That's why it's obvious!
We know the most about the Book of Darkness!
Then why?!
Accel Shooter
Then why are you calling it the Book of Darkness?!
Why aren't you calling it by its real name?!
Real name?
Barrier Jacket: Sonic Form
Haken
You made your thin armor even thinner?
I can move that much faster.
You'll die if even a weak attack lands a direct hit.
Are you insane, Testarossa?
It's so that I can win against you.
To stand up against you,
a tough opponent...
I thought that this was the only way!
If we hadn't met in this manner,
would we not have been able to become good friends?
We still can!
I can't stop!
We guardian knights...
If it's so our mistress can smile,
we decided that we would discard even our pride as knights!
We can't stop anymore!
You'll be stopped, by Bardiche and I!
Yes, sir.
I can't communicate with anyone.
What in the worlds has happened?
There was a true name for it, right?!
The true name of
the Book of Darkness...
A bind?!
Again?!
Nanoha!
Plasma Lancer
There!
It won't be like last time!
Two of them?!
What the heck is this?
With this many people,
I can't keep up the bind or the jamming for long.
Please get with it quickly.
Right.
When did they...?
The final pages are filled with the guardians,
who are no longer needed.
As it sometimes has been in the past, as well.
Sammlung
Collecting
A broken, cursed Lost Logia...
There is no way such a thing would be able to save anyone.
Shamal! Signum!
What are you?
What the hell are you?!
There is no need for
a mere program to know that.
That's right. There was one more.
Take it.
Sammlung
Collecting
Are those two...
Are Nanoha and Fate under control?
They're in a quadruple bind
and a Crystal Cage.
It will be several minutes before they can break free.
More than enough...
Mistress of the Book of Darkness,
your time of awakening has come.
No...
Time to end this cursed saga.
Nanoha? Fate?
What... what is this?
You're ill,
ill with the curse of the Book of Darkness.
You can no longer get better.
Even if the Book of Darkness is completed, you won't be spared.
There is no method by which you can be saved.
That doesn't matter...
Let go of Vita.
What did you do to Zafira?
They were all broken already,
even before we did this to them.
They thought they could still use functions
of the Book of Darkness that were broken ages ago,
persisting with a futile effort.
What do you mean, futile?
What about Signum? And Shamal?
Broken machines are of no use, right?
That's why we should break them.
No... wait... stop!
If you want us to stop...
Then stop us by force.
Why...
Why is this...
Why is such a...
Hey, Hayate...
Destiny is cruel.
Don't! Stop!
Stop it!
Good morning, mistress.
Guten Morgen, Meister.
Hayate!
I am the mistress of
the Book of Darkness.
Render great power unto my hands.
Release the seal.
Freilassung
Releasing
Once again, everything has come to an end.
How many more times must I repeat such sadness?
Hayate!
I am the Book of Darkness.
The use of all my powers...
Diabolic Emission
...is in accordance with the wishes of my mistress.
I won't forget even when I grow up
My love, the day that we came across each other
In this place, where flowers bloom intensely
I kept you in tears
I remember the promise
My love, the smile that I love so much
That day, when the secret door opened
I was chasing after a small white butterfly
I got lost, and I wanted to cry
My true wishes, my true feelings
Maybe you taught those to me
Guarded by such kind feelings
I'm sure I was spoiled for all this time
How you thought dear of me
My love, I won't forget all of you
Next Episode Preview
The Book of Darkness uses
her power controlled by sadness,
with her feelings trapped under heavy chains.
So many pasts...
So many misfortunes...
The intertwined spirals play a melody of sadness.
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha A's:
Episode 10: Destiny
Destiny
Drive Ignition!