It was only a small wish.
Everyday life where nothing happens,
each day gently continuing on to the next.
During those days which were more dear than anything else,
a shadow silently descended.
The power to sever
the chain that is destiny...
If it could be granted to these hands,
I would not mind throwing everything else away.
Our oath under the stars of the night sky...
With sword in hand,
to set forth the future!
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha A's
will now begin.
Prayers echoing in the vast skies turn to miracles
Teardrops melt and flow into the blue of the middle of the night
I met a warmth that engulfs all without hesitation
Just like the pure white snow
Words that are honest no matter how far you go
It moves me as I wear wings of steel
Each time I am hurt,
I can become kinder
My only wish is to protect that smile of yours to the end
Memories of sadness engraved across the ages
You are an angel of light, catching them straight on
An eternal blaze that stopped in my heart that day
Releasing the deep darkness
It opens the door of freedom
Towards the strong, boundless future
Um...
An artificial lifeform that isn't a familiar or a human...
Is that something like me?
No, it's not!
Fate, you just had a slightly different way of being born.
You are a human who was properly granted life into this world.
The test results said so too, right?
Stop talking like that.
Yes...
I'm sorry.
Oh!
Do you want me to explain on the monitors?
The guardians are programs
embedded within the Book of Darkness taking on human forms.
The Book of Darkness is reincarnated, reborn over and over,
but these four, together with the Book of Darkness,
have been through many masters.
Enough conversational skills to maintain consistency
have been confirmed in past cases as well,
but there's never been a case where they have shown any emotions.
Their only objective is to collect for the Book of Darkness
and to act as the master's guardians.
But that girl in the hat,
Vita, was acting angry and sad.
I felt a clear personality from Signum as well.
That she had something she needed to accomplish.
That it was for her comrades and her mistress.
For her mistress, huh...
Well...
Concerning that,
let's wait for information
from the operatives who are investigating right now.
Looking at their teleport patterns,
there's no doubt that their master is somewhere in this vicinity.
It just may be the case that we'll be able to catch the mistress first.
Oh, that would be great, because it's easy to understand!
Wouldn't it?
If it's before the Book of
Darkness is complete,
she should be an ordinary mage as well.
In any case, I'd like more detailed data about the Book of Darkness.
Yuuno...
I'd like to ask something of you, starting tomorrow.
Huh? Sure, but...
Hey, Yuuno...
What kind of a person do you think the Book of Darkness's mistress is?
The Book of Darkness randomly chooses someone
with potential to control it as its new host.
I see...
You never know.
Maybe she's someone our age.
Of all things, I think that's...
Suzuka has a friend sleeping over today.
Really?
Yeah.
See?
Hayate Yagami.
She said she'll introduce us next time.
I see.
It Was Only a Small Wish
(part 2)
Well then, thanks a lot, Suzuka!
Yes. See you later.
Please, please do come again, Hayate.
Thank you very much!
Signum...
Hayate says she will be back shortly.
I see.
Is Vita still...?
Apparently she's gone pretty far.
She said she'll be back by evening.
What about you, Signum?
What about me?
Are you all right?
Your magical powers seem to be quite drained.
Your leader was not made to be that weak.
I am fine.
You have changed quite a bit too.
You never laughed like that in the past.
Was that so?
Not just you.
All of us have changed quite a bit.
Ever since the day that
Hayate became our master.
I see.
If you're together with relatives, it must be very good and merry.
Yes...
It's like every day is needlessly fun.
That's wonderful.
That's right.
It's already been over six months since everyone came by...
Anfang.
Start up.
Confirmed startup of the Book of Darkness.
We are the guardian knights
who will collect for the Book of
Darkness and protect its mistress.
Clouds that gather under the Mistress of the Night Sky.
The Wolkenritter...
Cloud Knights
We serve at your command.
Hey, hold on.
Vita, shh!
But...
Stay quiet. Discourtesy in front of your mistress is forbidden.
Discourtesy, or whatever,
she looks like she's passed out.
You're kidding!
Hayate...
I'm so glad nothing is wrong.
Well... I'm sorry.
So...
Who are those people?
We really were surprised by what happened back then.
Well, yes.
What kind of people are they?
Though it's spring, it's still cold,
and they brought you in without even putting on a jacket, Hayate...
They're dressed so strangely,
and I don't understand what they're talking about.
They're all so suspicious.
Oh, well, um, how do I put it...
If you give us an order, we can be of help.
What would you have us do?
It's telepathy. If you can form a command in your mind...
Okay, it's more like a favor to ask than a command.
Play along with what
I'm going to say, okay?
Yes.
Well, Dr. Ishida,
actually, those people are my relatives.
Relatives?
They came by to wish me a happy birthday
from their distant home country.
And they tried to surprise me and dressed up in costumes...
But I got too surprised by all of this, and....
Well, that's how it goes... right?
That's exactly what happened!
Just as she said.
Our new mistress...
Mistress Hayate.
Her young age was one thing,
but she differed in many ways from our previous masters.
I see...
So this is what you call the Book of Darkness?
Yes.
It's been on the bookshelf as long as I can remember.
I took good care of it because it was a very pretty book.
At the time of awakening, and while you were asleep,
did you hear the voice of the Book of Darkness?
I'm not a mage or anything, so everything's kind of vague.
Ah! There was.
There's one thing that I found out.
As the mistress of the Book of Darkness,
I have to provide
clothing, food, and shelter
for all the guardian knights.
Fortunately, I have a place to live, and I'm good at cooking.
I'll go buy clothes for all of you,
so let me measure you and figure out your sizes.
Yes... really...
Everything was different from all our previous masters.
Mistress Hayate's treatment of us,
unlike our other masters,
wasn't beating down on us or treating us like tools.
It was as if she were treating us like family.
Okay, it's ready! Let's all eat!
I'll have some to eat now!
I'll have some to eat now.
We had our hesitations...
However, as our new mistress wished,
we were starting to live a quiet everyday life.
Seconds, please.
Sure!
Knight Armor?
Yes...
We possess weapons, but we must be given armor by our master.
We can make them with our own magical powers,
so if you could think up images of their forms...
I see.
But I'm not going to make you fight or anything like that.
Oh!
How about clothes?
Clothes that look like knights!
Okay?
Yes, that would be fine.
Then I have to look things up.
I have to think up really cool-looking ones!
Toys 'R' Oos
This is...
It's okay, it's okay...
Places like this have materials of the sort...
Right?
What's the matter, Vita?
Vita?
This is a nice breeze.
Really.
It's such a nice day out.
The perfect day to go on a stroll!
Vita...
You can take it out of the bag now.
Hayate, than—
Time passed by so slowly.
We, together with our mistress,
had been spending our lives with nothing going on.
Wow, so pretty!
Mistress Hayate...
Is it really all right?
Is what all right?
About the Book of Darkness.
As soon as you wish it so,
we can fill the pages of the Book of Darkness,
and you can gain great power.
I'm sure your legs would heal as well.
No way.
To fill the pages of the Book of Darkness,
you have to trouble all sorts of people, right?
That's wrong.
It's wrong to trouble other people for your own selfishness.
I'm plenty happy as I am right now.
Dad and Mom are up in the skies already,
but my uncle is keeping tabs on the inheritance for me.
One of your father's friends, was it?
Right.
Thanks to him, I don't face any troubles in everyday life.
Besides, more than anything else, right now I have all of you!
Hayate!
Oh, what's up, Vita?
Hayate, can I eat the ice cream in the freezer?
You ate that much dinner, yet you're going to eat more?
Shut up! I'm on a growth spurt!
Hayate's meals are giga-delicious, too!
Oh, all right...
Just a little bit. Got it?
Yeah!
Signum...
Yes?
Signum, you're their leader,
so promise me one thing.
Yes?
Your current master, Hayate Yagami,
wishes nothing from the Book of Darkness.
As long as I am your master, forget about the Book of Darkness.
Your job is to all live together happily in my house.
That's all.
Can you promise me that?
I so pledge, on my sword as a knight.
It's life-threatening?
What's wrong with Hayate?
Yes...
Hayate's legs, for some unknown reason,
suffer from a nerve-based paralysis.
In the past six months, the paralysis has slowly moved up.
Especially in the past two months...
At this rate, there is a risk
that her internal organs will become paralyzed as well.
Why...
Why didn't we notice?!
Sorry...
I'm sorry, I...
I'm not talking about you!
I'm talking about myself!
Mistress Hayate's condition...
was not an illness.
It was the curse of
the Book of Darkness.
The Book of Darkness, with
Mistress Hayate ever since she was born,
was closely linked to our mistress' body.
The strong magical powers that have been suppressed
ate away at our mistress' body, as she had a young Linker Core.
Getting in the way not only of healthy physical activity,
but threatening basic operations for survival.
And when our mistress met her first awakening, the process accelerated.
That meant our mistress was using her magical powers,
though only a very tiny amount,
to sustain the activities of the four of us.
We can't possibly claim to have had nothing to do with it.
We have to save her...
We have to save Hayate!
Shamal! Shamal, you're good at the healing stuff, right?!
An illness like that...
Fix it!
I'm sorry...
My powers cannot...
Why...
Why is this happening?!
Signum...
We can do so little.
However...
It is the curse of the Book of Darkness
that is eating away at our mistress' body.
If Hayate were to truly awaken
as the mistress of the Book of Darkness...
Our mistress' illness would fade away!
At the least, it would stop progressing!
I don't want to tarnish Hayate's future with blood,
so I won't kill anyone.
But I won't stop at anything else!
I am terribly sorry, my mistress.
Just this once, we will break the vow we have made to you.
Please forgive us for this wrongdoing!
Everyone, they look so good on you!
Time for dinner!
Crap...
You completely trashed the knight's outfit Hayate gave me.
Well, the clothes will heal,
and I got a decent amount of pages, so I guess it's okay.
It...
...doesn't...
...hurt!
It doesn't hurt!
Something like this doesn't hurt at all.
It's not like the past.
When I get home,
I'm sure that I have a warm bath—and Hayate's food—waiting for me.
Kind Hayate is waiting for me with a smile!
Oh yeah!
I'm super happy!
So!
Something like this doesn't hurt one bit!
The three of us came together, but is it all right?
Well, we left Allex to do the monitoring.
We just have to investigate the Book of Darkness, right?
Yeah.
The two we're about to meet are in the know for that kind of thing.
The Liese....
It's been a while. It's me, Chrono.
Wow!
Chroboy!
Wow, long time no see!
Lotte!
Lemme go!
What was that?
You're being so cold to the trainers you haven't seen in a while!
Aria! Do something about this!
It's been a while, so let her do what she wants.
Besides, well, you know...
It's not that you hate it, right?
Of course that's not...
Hey! Hey!
Liesearia, long time no see.
Yeah, long time no see!
Get away from me!
Lieselotte is as always...
Do something about this, dammit!
Well, despite being my twin,
there's no accounting for some things.
Thanks for the meal!
Lieselotte, long time no see.
Amy! Long time no see!
There's a tasty-looking little mouse-boy here...
Who is it?
Why is someone like that my trainer?
Oh, I see.
You're searching for the Book of Darkness, right?
I heard the situation from Father.
We'll be as much help as we can.
We'll be counting on you.
Miss Amy...
Who are these people?
They're the trainers who taught
Chrono magic and melee combat.
Liesearia, in charge of magical training,
and Lieselotte, in charge of melee combat training.
They are twin familiars of Admiral Graham,
and as you can tell, their base form is a cat.
Got it.
It would be really reassuring
if the two of you could come out to the outpost,
but you have jobs right now, right?
Well, we still have to teach a few new armed operatives.
So we can't stay over on your end for too long. Sorry.
No, actually, what I wanted to ask of you was about him.
Can I eat him?
Sure.
When you're done with everything, do what you want with him.
Hey, wait a minute!
So, what's your request?
I would like you to help him in his research in the Infinity Library.
I won't forget even when I grow up
My love, the day that we came across each other
In this place, where flowers bloom intensely
I kept you in tears
I remember the promise
My love, the smile that I love so much
That day, when the secret door opened
I was chasing after a small white butterfly
I got lost, and I wanted to cry
My true wishes, my true feelings
Maybe you taught those to me
Guarded by such kind feelings
I'm sure I was spoiled for all this time
How you thought dear of me
My love, I won't forget all of you
Next Episode Preview
Thanks to Yuuno's research,
the truth of the Book of Darkness
is becoming clearer and clearer!
How my serious duel with
Signum will turn out...
And that masked man shows up again?!
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha A's:
Episode 7:
With the Broken Past and Present
Drive Ignition!