It was only a small hope.
For our days to begin anew.
What we decided on was to never give up on fighting.
What we swore was to become stronger than yesterday.
So that we can stand up against
the destiny that's been set in motion.
So that we never hurt
the people dear to us again.
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha A's
will now begin.
Prayers echoing in the vast skies turn to miracles
Teardrops melt and flow into the blue of the middle of the night
I met a warmth that engulfs all without hesitation
Just like the pure white snow
Words that are honest no matter how far you go
It moves me as I wear wings of steel
Each time I am hurt,
I can become kinder
My only wish is to protect that smile of yours to the end
Memories of sadness engraved across the ages
You are an angel of light,
catching them straight on
An eternal blaze that stopped
in my heart that day
Releasing the deep darkness
It opens the door of freedom
Towards the strong, boundless future
6:30 AM
Yagami residence, Hayate's room
6:35 AM
City of Uminari, Sakuradai forest path
6:41 AM
City of Uminari, downtown, building rooftop
I'm sorry. Did I wake you?
No...
You should sleep properly on a bed.
You'll catch a cold.
I'm sorry.
Signum, were you up late again last night?
Yes, well... just a little bit.
Oh, Signum... here.
It's hot milk. It'll warm you up.
Thank you so much.
I have some for you too, Zafira.
Come on, over here!
I'm so sorry, I overslept!
Good morning, Shamal.
Good morning!
Oh, geez, I'm so sorry, Hayate.
It's okay.
Morning...
Wow, you look really sleepy.
Sleepy...
Geez... go wash your face.
After I drink some milk.
Here.
So warm...
Now, everyone!
This was on very short notice,
but we are going to introduce
a new friend to this class today!
She's an overseas student!
Miss Fate, come in!
Excuse me!
She's so cute!
Um... my name is Fate Testarossa.
Nice to meet you all!
New Powers, Start Up!
Hey, what is school like over there?
School? Oh, I—
It was a really sudden transfer, right? How come?
Well, yeah, there were all sorts of—
Your Japanese is really good.
Where did you learn it?
What kind of a place did you live before you came here?
Well, um, er...
Fate is so popular.
But all this might be
a bit tough to manage.
Murr... guess I have no choice.
Now, now!
She's a transfer student on her first day,
so don't toss her around like a ragdoll, guys!
Alisa...
And ask questions in order!
You're causing trouble for Fate!
Okay! Then I'll start with a question!
Okay, go ahead!
What was school over there like?
Well... I didn't go to ordinary school.
I had lots of tutors, or people that seemed that way, to teach me.
Oh, I see!
Okay, okay! I'm next!
Now, wait.
Wait!
Chrono, how is everything at the outpost?
We finished carrying in all the machinery.
Now we're establishing the network for investigating the vicinity.
I see.
Thanks to Admiral Graham's advice,
you've been given command of that company of armed operatives.
Thank you so much, Commodore Laty.
That, and Admiral Graham's familiars wanted to see you.
They said that they wanted to see their cute apprentice.
You mean the Liese twins?
Well, can you treat them as you see fit?
Hey, Chrono, how's it going over there?
We were able to borrow one entire company of armed agents.
We'll have them help our investigation.
And you?
Not good.
We lost another one yesterday.
In a world slightly farther away than all the previous ones,
a dozen mages and something like four wild animals.
Wild animals?
Large creatures with high magical power.
Apparently it doesn't have to be human, if it has a Linker Core.
They really don't care what they're targeting.
So I kinda looked at the data for the Book of Darkness...
But what exactly is it?
A Lost Logia that builds up magical power...
Eating the Linker Cores that serve as a mage's source of power,
and filling up its pages...
When all 666 pages of the Book are filled,
it uses all the stored magical power as a base to reveal its true powers,
a power so large that it will affect other dimensions.
And when the main body is destroyed,
or its owner dies,
all the pages turn blank, and it respawns in a different world...
It has wandered across all sorts of worlds,
protected by the guardians that it has created for itself.
Eating magical power, living forever.
Even if we destroy it, it will recreate itself over and over.
A dangerous magical book that we cannot ever stop.
That is the Book of Darkness...
But we can capture the Book of
Darkness before it's completed?
Right.
We have to capture those guardian knights,
and then drag their master out into the open.
Fate, what did you think of your first day of school?
I've never had so many people my age near me.
My head's still kind of spinning.
Well, you'll get used to it really soon, I'm sure.
Yeah. I really hope so.
Then, Signum, I trust you to escort Hayate to the hospital.
Yeah. Vita and Zafira already went?
They've already stepped out.
Cartridges?
Yeah.
I have to make new ones during the day.
Sorry to leave everything for you to do.
Backing you guys up is my job,
so don't worry about it.
Rise! Bow!
Goodbye!
Yes, goodbye!
Bureau: Chrono
New message
The investigation is going well.
Both you and Fate should live normal lives
until we request your assistance.
Nanoha, you still don't have your magical power back,
and both Raising Heart and
Bardiche are being repaired.
If there's an emergency, please just evacuate without complaining.
P.S. Apparently, repairs on the two devices will be done by next week.
P.P.S. I would like you to tell Fate
that she can stop on the way home from school,
but we'd like her to come home by dinnertime.
Uminari University Hospital
Maybe the results aren't showing too well after all.
But for now, we don't see any side effects,
so would you like to continue this treatment for a while?
Yes... um... I'll leave it up to you.
Leave it up to me?
This is about you,
so can you think about it a little more seriously?
Well, um...
I really believe in you, Doctor!
How is Hayate's everyday life?
She is perfectly fit other than the paralysis in her legs.
That's right. I know that this may be tough for all of you,
but we are doing our best too.
Yes...
For now, we're concentrating
on slowing down the progress of the paralysis as much as possible.
I'm fine.
From here on, we might have to start tougher treatments
that involve hospitalization and things like that.
I understand. I will talk with her later.
Sorry for barging in!
Well, we'll see you tomorrow!
Yeah, see you tomorrow.
Bye-bye!
Hey, Nanoha, what do you think about those people?
Those people? You mean the ones with the Book of Darkness?
Yeah, about the guardian knights of the Book of Darkness.
Lesse...
I was attacked so suddenly and was defeated so quickly,
so I didn't really get what was going on,
but you had a conversation with that swordswoman, right, Fate?
Yeah. It was a very strange feeling.
I can't put it into words well,
but I didn't feel any kind of ill will at all.
I see.
It would be nice if they could tell us the reason why
they're trying to complete of the Book of Darkness,
but it didn't look like we could sit down and have a talk with them.
When you harden yourself with strong will,
it's hard for words from people around you to reach you.
I was like that too.
I was doing it for my mother's sake,
but no matter how much she hurt me,
no matter how much I thought
I was doing something wrong,
no matter how much doubt I had...
But while I had thought that I was absolutely doing the right thing,
back when I was trying to believe that,
nobody's words came into my ears.
But speaking to someone, and delivering your feelings to someone,
is never a waste of energy!
For my mother's sake,
for my own sake...
I had tried to believe it so much,
but I was shaken by your words so many times, Nanoha...
If you need to fight and win for your words to be delivered...
If that's the case, I think I can fight without hesitation.
Fate...
Nanoha, you were the one who taught me
how to have a strong heart.
I don't think that's really the case...
So I'll become stronger.
So that I can plunge through with how I feel.
You're right. I'll become stronger too.
Let's do our best together, Fate.
Yeah, let's do our best, Nanoha.
Hayate!
Suzuka!
Suzuka, what did you borrow today?
Well, it's a fairy tale.
But it's a book that somehow touches your heart when you read it.
Oh, I like fairy tales too.
That sounds interesting!
Would you like to read it?
Volume one was still on the shelf.
Yeah! I'll read it next.
You like fairy tales too, Hayate?
I really love them!
What kind of a story is it?
That's for you to read and find out!
Book of Darkness, absorb.
Sammlung
Collecting
That thing just now was three pages.
Crap, it's got a big-ass body,
but such a dinky little Linker Core.
Well, it's much easier than facing a mage,
and the results show up faster.
Let's go to the next one, Zafira.
Vita, are you really all right to go on without resting?
I'm fine. I'm a knight too.
I'm not so weak that puny fights like this tire me out.
Thank you very much!
Nanoha!
How did the test results go?
Thankfully, fully healed!
Fully healed over here too.
Is that so? That's great!
Where are you now?
We're about to the second relay port.
I think we can get back over there in about ten more minutes.
I see. Then, when you get back,
I'll give you a rundown about
Raising Heart and Bardiche.
Oh no, this isn't good!
An emergency situation has emerged at close range!
We have found two of the targets in the skies above the city area!
They are now fighting inside one of the fortified barriers.
The opponent is tremendously tough.
Avoid direct combat.
Strengthen and maintain the barrier from outside!
Ma'am!
I will have the Enforcer head to the scene!
The Bureau...
But these dudes are pushovers.
We can kick their asses instead!
Above us!
Stinger Blade: Execution Shift
Did some of them get through?
Zafira!
Don't worry.
I'm not so weak that puny sticks like these can take me down!
Oh hell yeah!
All armed operatives have taken their positions!
Okay, Chrono?
Roger!
And we just delivered powerful helpers to the site!
Nanoha! Fate!
Those chicks!
Raising Heart!
Bardiche!
Set up!
Order of the setup was accepted.
Operating check of the new system has started.
Exchange parts are in good condition.
Completely cleared from the neuro-dyna-ident Alpha-01 to Beta-865.
This is...
It's different from what we've had before.
Both of you, calm down and listen carefully!
The deformation mechanism, confirmation is in good condition.
Both Raising Heart and Bardiche have brand new systems on board.
Main system, start up.
Brand new systems?
Haken Form deformation preparation.
They chose, by their own will,
with their own feelings!
The battle with the maximum performance is always possible.
An Accel and a Buster, the modes switching became possible.
The percentage of synchronicity 90 are maintained.
Call out to them, with their new names!
Condition all green. Get set.
Standby, ready.
Raising Heart Excelion
Bardiche Assault
Drive Ignition
Their Devices... no way!
Assault Form. Cartridge set.
Accel Mode. Standby, ready.
I won't forget even when I grow up
My love, the day that we came across each other
In this place, where flowers bloom intensely
I kept you in tears
I remember the promise
My love, the smile that I love so much
That day, when the secret door opened
I was chasing after a small white butterfly
I got lost, and I wanted to cry
My true wishes, my true feelings
Maybe you taught those to me
Guarded by such kind feelings
I'm sure I was spoiled for all this time
How you thought dear of me
My love, I won't forget all of you
Next Episode Preview
Both Raising Heart and Bardiche
have undergone an amazing power-up!
Now we can fight at
full strength, full throttle, full power!
And among the storms of battle,
the truth about those girls becomes apparent.
One of a silent past and a sad destiny.
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha A's:
Episode 5: It Was Only a Small Wish
(part 1)
It Was Only a Small Wish
Drive Ignition!