It was only a small wish.
What I wished for were peaceful days.
What awaited me was a reunion with a dear friend who lived far away.
Fate
Nanoha
But what visited was a sudden attacker.
An encounter... a battle... a great power...
Destiny is quietly being set in motion.
Even in the storm, believing in the bonds that tie hearts together.
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha A's
will now begin.
Prayers echoing in the vast skies turn to miracles
Teardrops melt and flow into the blue of the middle of the night
I met a warmth that engulfs all without hesitation
Just like the pure white snow
Words that are honest no matter how far you go
It moves me as I wear wings of steel
Each time I am hurt,
I can become kinder
My only wish is to protect that smile of yours to the end
Memories of sadness engraved across the ages
You are an angel of light,
catching them straight on
An eternal blaze that stopped
in my heart that day
Releasing the deep darkness
It opens the door of freedom
Towards the strong, boundless future
I see, so that's what it was.
Yeah... right, and then...
Yeah, yeah...
But I'm kind of looking forward to seeing Fate.
Yes, you're right.
But since we're looking forward to seeing her this much,
I'm sure Nanoha is even more enthusiastic about it,
because she has so many memories together with Fate.
You're right.
When she heard Fate was coming,
Nanoha really seemed happy.
Yeah.
How about we think up
a welcoming event for Fate?
Oh, that sounds good!
Yeah, let's have a blast!
Whose house should we hold it in?
Hmm... how about Café Midoriya?
Once Again, the Storms of Battle
Magical attacks on civilians...
This crime won't be a mere felony.
Who the hell are you?
A mage from the Bureau?
A part-time mage with the Time-Space Administrative Bureau,
Fate Testarossa.
If you don't resist, you have
the right to speak in your defense.
If you're willing to cooperate,
disarm yourself!
Who'd be that dumb?!
Yuuno, take care of Nanoha!
Right.
Yuuno...
Fate's trial ended, and everyone was trying to contact you, Nanoha.
But we couldn't reach you at all,
and when we looked over from the Bureau,
we found a wide-area barrier.
That's why we came here in a hurry.
I see.
I'm sorry...
And thank you.
Who is that?
And why is she after you, Nanoha?
I don't know. She attacked me
out of the blue.
But it's all right now.
Fate is here, and Arf is too.
Miss Arf too?
Bardiche!
Arc Saber
Graf Eisen!
Flying Swallow
Schwalbefliegen
Wall!
Armored Barrier
Panzerhindernis
Barrier...
...Break
Jerk!
Horses
Pferde
Crap...
It's easy to just beat them down, but that doesn't mean anything.
I need to take magical power back with me.
Two cartridges left.
Can I do it?
Miss Arf came here too.
Chrono and everyone on the Arthra are mobilizing for us too,
putting their maintenance on hold.
Allex, can you pull the barrier away yet?
Just a bit longer until the analysis is complete!
The equations are different.
This isn't a Midchilda-style barrier.
That's right.
Where is this magic from?
Jerk!
End of the line!
I'll have you give out your name,
the world you're from,
and the motive for all of this.
Something's wrong, Fate!
Signum?
Lævateinn, Cartridge Load!
Explosion
Glittering Swordflash
Defenser
Fate!
Why you...!
Fate... Miss Arf...
This isn't good! I have to help them!
Melodious rhythm, turn into light!
Within the circle of healing, grant the protecton of steel!
It's a barrier magic that heals and protects.
Nanoha, whatever you do,
don't step outside of here, okay?
Okay.
What's wrong, Vita?
Were you caught off guard?
Shut up! I was just about to turn the situation around!
I see. I guess I got in your way.
My apologies.
But don't push it too much.
If you get injured, our mistress would be worried as well.
I know that, geez.
That, and you dropped this.
I fixed all the damage dealt to it.
Thanks, Signum.
The situation is,
for all purposes, a three-on-three.
If it's one-on-one, there is
no way that we knights of Belka...
...would lose!
What?
The Book of Darkness... it's gone!
Are you all right?
Yeah. Thanks, Yuuno.
Bardiche too?
It's fine. The main body is all right.
Recovery
Yuuno...
Can you teleport everyone out of this barrier simultaneously?
Yeah, if I can get some help from Arf.
I can manage.
I'm going back into the fight,
so can you do that at the same time?
Got it.
Are you fine with it too, Arf?
It's a bit tough, but I'll find a way to make do!
Well, then... let's do our best!
Yeah!
Fate...
There we go...
Hello?
Oh, hello, Hayate?
This is Shamal.
What's going on?
I'm terribly sorry. I couldn't find the usual olive oil.
I'll go look for it in a supermarket slightly further away.
Oh, that's all right.
Don't go out of your way.
While I'm out, I'll pick everyone up before heading home.
I see.
I'm sorry that I cannot help you with any of the cooking.
It's fine.
I'll be home as soon as possible.
You don't have to rush.
Be careful!
Yes... then, excuse me.
Right. I will surely finish this as soon as possible.
Klarwind, please guide me.
Yes. Pendulum Form.
Ja. Pendelform.
Photon Lancer
Lævateinn, my armor.
Armor Spirit
Panzergeist
Pierce through! Fire!
Your instincts as a mage are not bad.
But, in order to challenge a Belkan knight to a duel,
this is still not enough!
Lævateinn! Slam the blade and slice!
Jawohl!
Roger!
Fate!
I can prepare the teleport,
but I can't break through the spatial barrier!
Arf!
I'm trying on this end too, but this barrier is incredibly hard!
Reload
Nachladen
It's those things... those shells...
They're temporarily increasing their magical power with them.
Is that it?
Then stay still. If you don't resist, we won't take your life.
Who would?!
Good fighting spirit.
I am a Belkan knight.
Leader of the Wolkenritter, Signum.
Cloud Knights
And my sword, Lævateinn.
What is your name?
A mage from Midchilda,
working part-time with the Time-Space Administrative Bureau,
Fate Testarossa.
This guy is Bardiche.
Testarossa
and Bardiche?
I have to save—
I have to save everyone!
Master.
Shooting Mode. Acceleration.
Raising Heart?
Let's shoot it. Starlight Breaker!
But that's impossible in your condition!
I can be shot.
That magic is too big a burden.
Raising Heart, you'd break!
I believe, master.
Trust me, my master.
If you're going to believe in me, Raising Heart,
I'll believe in you too.
Fate... Yuuno... Miss Arf...
I'll destroy the barrier,
so get yourselves synched up and teleport!
Nanoha!
Nanoha, are you really all right?
It's all right!
I'll shoot through it with
Starlight Breaker!
Raising Heart, start the countdown!
All right.
Count 9...
8... 7...
6... 5... 4... 3...
3... 3... 3...
Are you all right, Raising Heart?
No problem.
Count 3... 2... 1...
Nanoha?
Oh no... I missed!
Nanoha!
Linker Core, captured.
Begin assimilation!
Sammlung
Collecting
Count 0.
Starlight...
...Breaker
The barrier has been broken!
Incoming visual feed!
What is this?
What condition are they in?
This is...
They are...
The barrier has been pierced!
Let's get out of here!
Understood.
Sorry, Shamal. You saved me.
Let's split up for now
and regroup in the usual place!
Oh, they're getting away!
Hurry up with the coordinate lock!
The paths of their teleports!
I'm doing my best!
That's...!
This isn't good!
Hurry up and dispatch a medic ship that way!
Opening the relay teleportation port!
And get the medical facilities at the Main Office ready as well!
Roger!
It's no use! We lost the lock.
Oh, man!
I'm sorry, Chrono. We screwed up.
Chrono?
A first-class artifact
registered on the search list...
Lost Logia, the Book of Darkness...
Chrono, you recognize it?
Yeah,
I recognize it all right.
I have something of a long-standing grudge against it.
I won't forget even when I grow up
My love, the day that we came across each other
In this place, where flowers bloom intensely
I kept you in tears
I remember the promise
My love, the smile that I love so much
That day, when the secret door opened
I was chasing after a small white butterfly
I got lost, and I wanted to cry
My true wishes, my true feelings
Maybe you taught those to me
Guarded by such kind feelings
I'm sure I was spoiled for all this time
How you thought dear of me
My love, I won't forget all of you
Next Episode Preview
This case is one where mysteries
keep piling up!
Its roots seem to be very deep.
But Nanoha and Fate finally got to see each other again!
And there's one more good thing!
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha A's:
Episode 3: Reunion and Relocation!
Reunion and Relocation!
Lyrical, magical, we'll do our best!