It was probably a strong bond
that tied them together.
But the relationship between master and servant that should be strong
is now a chain of sadness that ties them together.
A cold reality covered with both the recent and distant past.
The magic in my hands has the power to pierce through sadness and tears.
I will definitely save you.
So don't cry anymore.
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha A's
will now begin.
Prayers echoing in the vast skies turn to miracles
Teardrops melt and flow into the blue of the middle of the night
I met a warmth that engulfs all without hesitation
Just like the pure white snow
Words that are honest no matter how far you go
It moves me as I wear wings of steel
Each time I am hurt,
I can become kinder
My only wish is to protect that smile of yours to the end
Memories of sadness engraved across the ages
You are an angel of light,
catching them straight on
An eternal blaze that stopped
in my heart that day
Releasing the deep darkness
It opens the door of freedom
Towards the strong, boundless future
Is this the school?
Yes, it is.
Amy!
I'm researching the situation.
Fate's vital signs are still there!
She's just trapped in the Book of Darkness's pocket dimension.
I'm searching for how to save her!
My mistress and that girl will live
an everlasting dream in an eternal sleep.
A dream trapped between life and death.
It is eternal.
Nothing is eternal.
Everyone changes.
They have to change.
Even me... and you!
A Gift for Christmas Eve
Huh?
This place...
Fate, Alicia, Arf, it's morning.
Could it be...?
Good morning, Fate.
Are we all awake?
Yeah.
I'm sleepy.
Did you two stay up late again?
Just a little bit.
Right?
Alicia, since you're the big sister,
I want you to learn
from how Fate goes to bed early
and wakes up early.
Um...
Lynith?
Yes, what is it, Fate?
Alicia...
I take back what I just said.
It seems like Fate's also a sleepyhead.
Come on, get dressed.
It's breakfast time.
Presea is already in the dining room.
Okay!
Mom...
Good morning, Mother.
Good morning, Presea.
Alicia, Arf, good morning.
We have a problem, Presea.
It might rain or even snow today.
Here, Fate.
Fate, what happened?
It seems like she had a bad dream.
She thinks all this is
a dream or an illusion.
Did you study too much, Fate?
That could be it.
Fate, come over here.
Seems like you had a nightmare.
But you'll be okay now.
Your mother, Lynith, and Alicia are all beside you.
Presea, me too.
Yes, you too, Arf.
Well, your bad dream will go away after breakfast.
So have a seat, and let's eat.
Okay!
No.
This is the dream.
My mother never smiled at me
like that, not even once.
Alicia and Lynith are both gone.
But this is...
Let's go out to the village today.
That sounds great.
I need to buy a new pair of shoes for Fate.
It's not fair, always for Fate.
It's a reward for getting 100 on her magic test.
Alicia, you need to try harder.
That's right!
Fate, tutor me for the next test.
Uh... sure.
Fate?
This is the life I always wanted.
The life I dreamed of, over and over...
I'm sleepy.
Stay asleep, just like that.
My mistress,
I'll grant all your wishes.
Please close your eyes and dream peacefully.
Black Impact
Schwarze Wirkung
Mrs. Lindy, Miss Amy...
I moved the battlefield over the ocean.
Please take care of the fire in the suburbs!
Don't worry.
The disaster team is headed there.
And Ms. Book of Darkness seems like a whiner,
but I think she's getting it.
Please let me give it a little more!
Let's do it, Raising Heart!
Yes, my master.
The team has reached the site.
We'll start putting out the fires.
It's not like I can tell her not to push herself.
Reload
Three magazines and eighteen cartridges left!
I wonder if I can shoot
Starlight Breaker?
I have a method.
Call me "Excelion Mode".
I can't do that!
You can't use that until we strengthen your core system!
If I mess up with the control,
Raising Heart, you'll break!
Call me.
Call me, my master.
What was I wishing for?
To dream.
The sad reality will all become a dream.
Sleep in peace.
Really?
I really wish for...
You should sleep too.
I will sleep one day.
But not now.
Right now, I'm going to save Hayate and Fate.
And you too!
Raising Heart!
Excelion Mode, Drive...
...Ignition
I'm sure we can stop the cycle of sadness and nightmares.
Photon Lancer: Genocide Shift
Huh?
Looks like it's gonna rain.
Fate, let's go home.
Come on, Fate!
Sorry, Alicia.
I'll stay here for a bit.
Really?
Then, me too!
We're taking shelter from the rain together!
Hey, Alicia.
This is a dream, right?
You and I are not of the same world.
If you were alive, then I wouldn't have been born.
That's right...
Our mother was never that nice to me.
She was a nice person.
Because she was nice, she broke down,
in order to bring me back from the dead.
Yeah.
Hey, Fate.
Who cares if it's a dream?
Let's stay here.
Together forever.
I can stay alive here.
I can be your big sister.
You can stay with
Mom, Arf, and Lynith.
I'll give you all the happiness you wanted.
The happiness I wanted?
A healthy body.
A life always together with your loved ones.
Please sleep.
If you do, then you can stay in that world in your dream forever.
But that's only a dream.
The only attack you know.
You think that will work?
I'll make it work.
Raising Heart is giving me the power.
She's risking her heart and life to support me!
She's telling me to save the crying girl!
A.C.S., standby.
Starting the Accel Charger.
Strike Flame
Open.
Excelion Buster A.C.S.
Drive!
Make it through!
Break...
Impossible!
...shoot!
At point-blank range.
A direct hit from Excelion Buster
through the barrier...
If that didn't work...
Master!
I need to give it a little more.
Yes.
This isn't my wish.
It shouldn't be yours either!
Isn't that right?
My heart is closely linked with the knights' hearts.
Just like the knights,
I also adore you.
That's why I can't forgive myself for killing you
with the power that I can't control.
I can't stop eating away at you
by going out of control.
At the time of the awakening,
I realized a little bit about what's happened so far.
The sadness of not being able to live life as you wanted.
I can understand that too.
Just like Signum and the others!
I've been sad and lonely.
But you can't forget.
I am your master now.
You have to listen to your master.
Sorry, Alicia.
But I have to go.
I know.
Thank you.
Sorry, Alicia.
It's okay.
I am your big sister, after all, Fate.
Strong and nice people are waiting for you, right?
Then go ahead, Fate.
I wish it was like this in reality too.
I'll give you a name.
We finally reached the place we met
I won't let them call you
Book of Darkness or
the cursed tome anymore...
I won't let them!
I'm the systems administrator.
I can do that.
It's impossible.
The autonomous protection program won't stop.
The mage from the Bureau is fighting it, but that too is...
Stop.
You out there!
Embedded in
the fragment of time
You from the Bureau!
I'm Hayate Yagami,
the administrator
of the girl right here!
Hayate?
The stars disappear into the distance
Nanoha?!
Really?
It's Nanoha.
A lot happened, and I'm fighting with Ms. Book of Darkness.
Within the pain
far into the distance
Sorry, Nanoha.
Can you stop
her somehow?
The wishes seem to freeze
I've cut the control
from the main tome,
but if she's running,
The heart was hurt
by those eyes
I can't use
my administrator rights.
The one you see there
is just the autonomous protection program!
But you were
able to find me
The administrator awakened
after the Book of
Darkness's completion?
Then we can...
Nanoha!
I'll make it simple.
At the end of the world far into the distance
If you do what I say,
Hayate and Fate can both come out.
The color of miracles that I touched
It doesn't matter how you do it.
Just blast the girl head-on with magical damage.
With all the power you've got!
Like the white of snow
Clear as crystal, Yuuno!
That's easy to understand!
We softly feel each other
It's so.
You and I melt together
Excelion Buster: Extended Barrel
Mid-range attack mode!
All right. Barrel Shot.
And we finally become our true selves
The snow melts into the night and shines
As Mistress of the Night Sky,
The wind that invites the departure
I grant thee a new name.
One who uses her strength
to support others.
You are a tailwind of fortune,
a shout of blessing.
The wish of the wind of blessing
Reinforce.
Becomes the unbreakable bond
Bardiche, I'm going to get out of here.
Can you do Zanber Form?
Yes, sir.
Good boy.
Zanber Form
With lightning speed!
Everyone departs someday
Excelion Buster: Force Burst
By holding on to the scar of sadness
In search of an answer at the end of the journey
Sprite Zanber
Break shoot!
The snow melts into the night and shines
The wind that invites the departure
New name, "Reinforce", recognized.
Use of administrator rights
is now possible.
The wind of blessing becomes the unbreakable bond
The journey can be walked with smiles
Fate!
But the protection program
is out of control.
The massive power that was freed from supervision
will soon go out of control.
Well, let's do something about it.
Shall we go, Reinforce?
Yes, my mistress.
Everybody, be careful!
I'm still getting a reading from the Book of Darkness!
Now, from here it gets serious.
Are you ready, Chrono?
Yes. I'm almost there at the scene.
The Arc-en-Ciel...
I hope we don't end up using this...
I won't forget even when I grow up
My love, the day that we came across each other
In this place, where flowers bloom intensely
I kept you in tears
I remember the promise
My love, the smile that I love so much
That day, when the secret door opened
I was chasing after a small white butterfly
I got lost, and I wanted to cry
My true wishes, my true feelings
Maybe you taught those to me
Guarded by such kind feelings
I'm sure I was spoiled for all this time
How you thought dear of me
My love, I won't forget all of you
Next Episode Preview
The autonomous protection program
freed from the Book of Darkness goes out of control.
The ones who will stand against it are us, the Bureau team, and...
and...
This must be the last battle of the Book of Darkness Incident.
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha A's:
Episode 12: Night's End, Journey's End
Night's End, Journey's End
The long night is almost over.