The oldest memory I have is
of me smiling with my beloved mother.
But it wasn’t me who was with my mother.
It was my deceased older sister, Alicia.
I was then born with Alicia’s memories.
But in the end, I was unable to become her.
My mother ended up not taking my hand.
Leaving a somewhat lonely feeling behind, she left me.
I don’t want my kids to have those same feelings.
But I...
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
The things that I can do for you and no one else
I honestly feel and wish for those
I am frozen by uncertainties
By the rules I have been relying on
My past embellished with excuses
I want to get over it
Staining the stars in heaven scarlet
Gather the grains of miracles
Before the still, unseen night
I want to tell you that I am escaping from illusions
The twilight moon calls out to me
Removing my veil of delusions
My hidden, deceitful self
And took all of my weaknesses
I don’t want words that seem passionate
The fact that I’m here right now is my truth
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
We weren’t able to protect them again.
Twenty-five dead. Twenty-one of those were civilians.
There really are too many crimes on Mid.
We don’t have enough men or firepower.
We’re lacking in everything.
This time the damned Navy managed to overlook a criminal mage.
Yet, all of the firepower and gifted mages
are taken by the Main Office.
It’s not that I don’t understand the Navy’s problems.
Over there, the scope of
the incidents they deal with is different.
Does that mean that it’s okay to ignore
when a small area of a small planet is destroyed?
I’m sorry.
I do not carry any magical powers like you do,
nor do I have the power to teach people.
But, at least, if I can rise in the ranks of the Bureau and collect power, we might be able to change this.
For you, it may very well be possible.
We need a revolution!
If you leave peace and justice in this city to my hands,
I can guarantee a higher level of security for each person.
A rise in the functionality of the regulation system.
Amazing results!
But, regarding that system,
the Main Office has said there’s been a problem.
Tell them to deal with it themselves.
Those people have no concept of justice on the surface.
It’s amazing how hard you’ve worked.
Taking into account your impeccable sense of justice,
we have something to ask of you.
Regius, I’ve been hearing
some not-so-good rumors about you lately.
I’m not doing anything different.
The Ground Armed Service
has been gaining strength on Mid.
Your unit seems to be investigating
the Combat Cyborg Incident, correct?
That’s correct.
I should have more important things for you to do.
I’ll give it to you in the morning.
That will be your priority from then on.
Nakajima, Alpine. We’re going to conduct our raid earlier than planned.
We go tonight.
Make sure you’re ready.
Roger.
Seems that we were right.
This is a combat cyborg plant.
Deputy captain, this is Team C.
The captain was protecting us, and...
So, they managed to get in this far.
We’ll have to distance ourself from this base, as well.
That’s too bad.
Let’s take the corpse.
At least, he’ll serve some purpose as the Doctor’s research sample.
Thanks a lot, Lt. General Gaiz.
You let one of our important facilities get destroyed.
Seems that my order didn’t get there in time.
Well, no matter. There wasn’t that much damage anyway.
Oh yeah, one more thing. Your dream,
the combat cyborgs, just proved their excellent skill.
One-on-one, they took down
an S rank knight. Pretty awesome, right?
Among the Bureau members we took, there are people who could be adapted as artificial mage samples.
Zest Grangeitz, Mégane Alpine.
Also, Mégane had a daughter.
I’d like to secure her as a base for an artificial mage.
Sure, we’ll take care of it.
Should we tell Regius about this?
No.
We’ll need to put him under
our complete control eventually.
Zest Grangeitz may become a useful pawn to us.
I want to ask you this.
I was prepared to sacrifice myself for your justice,
but for whose sake did my men die?
Why did it turn out this way?
The planet we wanted to protect.
The power we wanted.
The justice you and I dreamed of.
When did it turn into something like this?
Why?!
I thank you for playing your part.
You’re just a hindrance to the Doctor’s plans.
Zest, I...
I...
Regius.
Now, your usefulness and your revenge
have come to an end.
It’s always this way. I’m always too late.
Sir.
Did you...?
That’s right,
I did it.
I was too weak and too late.
Episode 24
Lightning
Didn’t Tre tell you once?
That we were like father and daughter.
Your mother, Presea Testarossa, was indeed a talented mage.
She perfected the cloning technology that I created.
But you were a failure to her.
You were nothing like her biological daughter,
Alicia, who she wanted to revive.
You were just a defective copy.
So you didn’t get a real name.
You were just given the name of the project.
The first product of the memory-transfer cloning technology, Project Fate.
Fate Testarossa.
Fate?
There’s no reason for us to fight, Lu.
Nothing will come of it.
Galue, if you’re a warrior who protects his mistress, stop Lu.
Lu’s being tricked by them. She’s just being controlled.
You don’t understand.
I had people who were nice to me.
I had friends.
Everyone I care about is forgetting me.
I don’t want to be alone.
I’m tired of being lonely.
I don’t want to be alone!
Caro!
Great, grand howl which pierces the skies above,
that which eternally guards distant land.
Come forth, join me, and stand beside us now,
o jet black flame, protector of the land.
We are very much alike, Lu and us.
We were both always alone,
with no one to protect us, no one to believe in.
Nothing made sense.
And we couldn’t do anything but hurt things.
But that can change.
With just one chance, just one feeling,
We can change it!
Summoning Dragon Mount
An imperial, thunderous roar.
Come forth, Voltaire!
We will definitely help with finding your mother.
I promise.
Stop doing this.
You’re lying.
I’m not lying.
You’re lying!
Hakuten-Oh, Galue, kill them.
Kill the people who are in my way.
Everyone. All of them!
Galue.
Kill them!
Galue!
Boosted Protection
It’s wrong to make your precious summons suffer.
Galue and Hakuten-Oh are crying.
Erio.
Jirai-Oh!
Fried!
Blast Ray
Fire!
Lu.
Glittering Swordflash
Caro.
I managed, somehow.
The summons are getting all confused.
Is it because Lu is still trying to fight?
Riot
Riot Blade
Is that your final trump card?
No matter.
Seems the A.M.F. is draining you.
But are you sure it’s okay to use that?
Even if you defeat me here,
you can’t stop my creations and the Cradle.
If you use Project F the right way, it’s pretty helpful, isn’t it?
A copy of me already exists within
the wombs of each of the twelwe combat cyborgs.
If just one of them survives, then I’ll come back.
And in just one month,
they’ll be revived with my memories.
That’s ridiculous.
In the old era, the era of Alhazred,
this was everyday technology.
In other words, if you can’t kill me and all twelve of my combat cyborgs, you can’t stop me or my plan.
Have you fallen into despair?
You and I are quite similar.
The organic weapons that I’ve made myself,
and that which you sought, the children who can’t deny you.
That which you have formed in your own way, and that which you are using for your own means.
Shut up.
Am I wrong?
You raised them so they cannot deny you and made them fight.
Just like me, and your mother as well.
Everyone around you is nothing more
than a tool that you can use.
And yet, you’re terrified that
the love they direct at you is fading.
Your mother was like that as well.
You will also become like that, eventually.
Terrified of making a mistake,
clinging to your weak bonds and shaking in terror.
Don’t you think a life like that is without meaning?
You’re wrong!
It’s not meaningless.
We chose our own path.
We had no place to go,
and Fate found us a warm home.
She gave us tons of kindness.
She taught us the happiness of protecting what’s important to us.
She helped us and protected us.
At Riot Force 6, we were trained by Nanoha.
And we finally were able to try to stand and walk by ourselves.
Fate isn’t wrong about anything.
If she’s in doubt, then we will be right there by her side.
If she’s in trouble, we’ll be right there to save her.
If she, for some reason, is wrong,
we’ll be there to scold her and then return back to her.
We—all of us are here for her.
So, don’t give up. Don’t hesitate.
Fight!
Get set.
Overdrive. Complete Sonic Form.
Sonic Drive
I will look only straight ahead...
I will have faith in my belief...
Sorry, and thank you, Erio, Caro.
Both love and despair will become indestructible wings.
There’s nothing to doubt, right?
Awaken now, my heartbeat!
Riot Zanber
Because I was weak,
I hesitated and let my worries get to me.
I will probably always fall into this pattern.
But,
that’s fine.
The moon and stars in the darkness
are holy tears that lament at their loneliness.
Because all of that makes me who I am.
Let’s weave and depict a cross together until our shine dies out.
Her mana values have increased?
I’ve been searching for you, Miss.
Even if it’s a razed opera stage with a serenade of destruction playing,
Scaglietti’s other brain
and the leader of the twelve combat cyborgs,
Number I, Uno.
As long you’re singing,
I’ll be able to flap my wings again towards the dawn.
Shall I take a peak inside of your mind?
Unie? This is bad.
I am still weak and unable to draw out my sword of light.
I.S.: Deep Diver
I won’t let you run.
It order to live a valorous life,
do not run away from your cruel fate,
Windenschaft!
Someday our tears will light up tomorrow
and turn into a miraculous sun.
She has movement magic?
Let’s go, for we have things to protect...
Gale Burst
That armor is weak.
You’ll go down if you’re hit.
Even for just a little, as long as you can smile for me,
I will become a knight of dusk and devote to you my all.
Ride Impulse
A nameless rhapsody is the courage blooming in my heart.
If you wish for it, I can fly even to the ends of the galaxy.
If I can save just one person, then I don’t need power.
Even if time loops back for a hundred years, I’ll go pick you up.
Magnificent. You truly are magnificent.
No matter how many times I collapse,
when I look at the sky, there will be an answer,
I wanted this power.
But the cost of capturing me
is that you’re going to be stuck here.
For there is no such thing as a world without daybreak...
You can’t stop the dream I entrusted to the Cradle!
Large-scale interdimensional criminal, Jail Scaglietti.
I hereby place you under arrest.
There’s been a communication from Scaglietti’s hideout from Inspector Acous.
A confirmation on the last position of the combat cyborgs, as well as their current operational status, has been received!
It seems like the only ones left
are Number IV in the ship and you.
I don’t know what you’ve been through,
but if you recognize your crimes and turn yourself in,
I think you’ll be allowed a fresh start.
No way that’ll happen.
We’re combat cyborgs.
Weapons for the purpose of fighting.
There’s no other way of life for us
other than fighting and winning!
Snipe Shot
Even weapons that exist only for fighting
can laugh and live as kind people.
You may have been born a combat cyborg, but
I know a girl who’s more human than anyone,
who’s sweet to the point of stupidity, and who tries her best.
Stars 4 has captured Number IX.
Number IV is the only remaining combat cyborg.
They’re all complete losers.
Well, it’ll all work out if I’m around.
Isn’t that right, Doctor?
Their final trump card should soon be smashed to pieces, anyway.
The Cradle will reach
orbit in
1 hour
1 hour and 35 minutes
Etched into this amulet, these precious times
In my precious days
“The bluebird ran away”
I cried, embracing the empty cage
I still remember the color of the high-rising sky
That I looked up at that day
Rewinding
Inside my memories
In painful times, in happy times
You were always there at important times
The thing which I looked for to the ends of the labyrinth
Is deep within my heart
Etched into this amulet, these precious times
Soft and secret pieces of my memory
No matter what type of tomorrow it is, I can walk towards it
In my precious days
Next
Episode
Preview
Next
Episode
Preview
Only a small amount
of time remains
before the Cradle
reaches its orbital position.
The final battle will take place just beneath the light of the stars.
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS:
Episode 25: Final Limit
Episode 25
Final Limit
Toward your true feelings, take off.