Jail Scaglietti.
A wide-area interdimensional criminal
with an arrest warrant on several worlds.
Many video and voice recordings are available,
but he’s never shown himself in public or been captured.
He’s toyed with lives to create biological weapons,
committed a terrorist attack on the Bureau’s Surface HQ,
and even awakened an ancient legacy.
With the ship of the holy one rising into the sky, we...
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
The things that I can do for you and no one else
I honestly feel and wish for those
I am frozen by uncertainties
By the rules I have been relying on
My past embellished with excuses
I want to get over it
Staining the stars in heaven scarlet
Gather the grains of miracles
Before the still, unseen night
I want to tell you that I am escaping from illusions
The twilight moon calls out to me
Removing my veil of delusions
My hidden, deceitful self
And took all of my weaknesses
I don’t want words that seem passionate
The fact that I’m here right now is my truth
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
The large ship has surfaced from beneath the earth!
This can’t be! This is...
Knight Carim, this is what was in your prophecy.
The dancing dead.
The ship returning from
the holy land under the king’s direction.
From the age of Ancient Belka, the ultimate physical weapon,
the ship of the holy one that rules heaven and earth,
the Holy King’s Cradle.
Episode 20
Unlimited Desire
This is the situation I wanted to avoid at all costs.
It’s the Church’s—no, it’s my fault.
My interpretation of the prophecy was insufficient.
It’s natural to not know the future.
It’s not your fault or the Church’s.
Now, what do we do?
Hayate, it’s Chrono.
The Main Office has judged the Holy King’s Cradle
to be an extremely dangerous Lost Logia.
The Dimensional Navy is already on the move.
The G.A.S. is helping as well.
Can Riot Force 6 move out?
Yes.
The Vessel of the Holy King and the Cradle have stabilized.
Quattro and Dieci, switch with me inside the Cradle.
Okay.
Roger.
Tre, Sette, and Sein are to guard the Doctor at his lab.
Understood.
Nove, Deed, and Wendi are to go with Number XIII.
We’re on our way.
The Cradle will continue to rise
to a level where it can strike the surface.
If it reaches a point where it can receive
the magic of the two moons and attack the surface,
the Cradle will truly be invincible.
Everyone on Mid will be our hostages.
If that’s our position, then we can even deal with the Main Office’s fleet.
I do have one question though.
What?
That Vessel of the Holy King inside the Cradle, who is she?
I’ll tell you.
Doctor.
It was ten years ago.
There was a certain priest in the Church of the Holy King.
He was a devout, noble, and kind man.
Thus he earned the position of curator of the holy relics.
Holy relics?
The bones and possessions of the Holy King,
the sacred ruler of Ancient Belka,
who is the focus of worship of the Church of the Holy King.
But, even if he was a priest, he was human.
His love for a woman made him take the remains.
The genetic data from the small amount
of blood left in the Holy Shroud was removed:
The genetic data of the grand ruler of ancient Belka, the Holy King.
And the seed of the Holy King was duplicated in secret
in a number of research facilities all around the dimensions, and it awaited rebirth.
To be our king, right?
A living, breathing Holy King is the key to turn on the Cradle.
It’s a king, but just a tool.
Hey, Doctor, question.
Go ahead, Sein.
Besides old man Regius...
The High Council, are they okay?
They were the ones who supported the Artificial Mage Project and the mass-production of the Gadgets, right?
Yeah, that’s right.
And Miss Lu and Mr. Zest
were revived thanks to them, right?
You don’t think they had a plan
or something of their own, do you?
Regius and the High Council both have the same hope.
The peace and security of Midchilda and every dimension.
For that reason Regius remained obsessed with the discarded combat cyborg plan,
and the High Council with the Relic weapons
and Artificial Mage Project.
They’re shouldering a rather huge contradiction:
they’re willing to sacrifice innocents to maintain the peace.
Well, I don’t really get it.
Yeah.
Anyway,
because they’re our sponsors and we ignored them in calling up that huge Cradle,
I’m worried that they’ll get mad at us.
I’ve made sure they won’t.
Don’t worry about a thing. Go have fun.
When you’re done playing,
come back to our new home, the Cradle.
If you do, the whole world shall be our playground.
I don’t really get what the Doctor’s saying, as usual.
I agree.
Well, we don’t really have any hopes or dreams.
We’ve just gotta do what Uno says.
That’s right.
Now that I think about it,
there’s one more thing I don’t understand.
The woman who made that priest steal the relics of the Holy King...
...was who?
Jail has overdone it.
Even Regius is an important pawn to us.
And he is trying to make the Holy King’s Cradle
we sought into his own toy.
We must stop him.
But Jail is a valuable individual.
It’s a shame to eliminate him so early.
But Zest of the Artificial Mage Project failed.
And while Lutecia was also incomplete,
it seems the Vessel of the Holy King is a perfect success.
Is it not time, perhaps?
What we seek is a world ruled by a great leader.
We must pick that leader
and rule the world from the shadows.
That’s why we developed the life-extension technology.
That’s why we have the Cradle.
We have lived many years watching over the world
by abandoning our bodies, ever since
the olden days, but we won’t last much longer.
But we must still protect
the Dimensional Sea and the Bureau.
Excuse me.
If only Zest were in perfect health,
he would’ve been the perfect keeper for Jail.
Everyone, it’s time for your auto maintenance.
Oh, it’s you.
We’re in a conference.
Be quick about it.
Yes, sir.
He is a warrior.
We can’t control him.
By feeding him information on
the combat cyborg plans and guaranteeing Lutecia’s safety,
we’re barely managing to chain him.
If he reaches Regius, it ends there.
You seem worried.
No, it’s nothing important.
It’s nothing you must worry about.
Yes, sir.
Has there been no contact from Regius or the G.A.S.?
No, nobody’s contacted us yet.
I see.
It’s going to be busy soon.
We’ll need you to work as well.
No.
I’m here because I want to be.
In the old era, it was the three members of the High Council who brought the separated worlds together.
Even after they entrusted the leadership to us and the Time-Space Administrative Bureau’s system,
they created the Council System and watched over us.
Young Reggie—Lt. General Regius—is a bit violent occasionally, but he’s protected the peace of the land.
So I don’t want to believe they’re involved in this matter.
Whatever the reason, the High Council and Lt. General Regius tried to use Jail Scaglietti, the brilliant criminal.
But they ended up being used instead and were betrayed.
I don’t know how much was
whose plan, or who was behind what,
but now the massive ship in the sky,
the combat cyborgs, and the Gadgets have appeared,
Threatening the safety of the city.
That’s the truth.
We must stop them.
The Main Office’s fleet is heading towards the Cradle.
All other squads are cooperating to
deal with the combat cyborgs and Gadgets.
But there aren’t many mages who can handle a high-level A.M.F. in battle.
We will split into three groups and help in all areas.
Fate?
Uh...
You’re in a different group, huh?
I’m sorry. I can never be with you when it counts.
It’s not that.
Fate.
I’m worried you’re going to face Scaglietti alone.
I want to leave Signum on the ground in case of emergency.
Inspector Acous and Sister Schach will be with me, so I won’t be alone.
Both of you do your best.
Don’t overdo it.
Yes.
You too, Fate.
That knight and the red girl may show up again.
Zest Grangeitz and his Unight, Agito.
Major Nakajima told me about Knight Zest.
He was a striker-class mage attached to the Bureau’s Capital Defense Corps.
A good friend of Lt. General Regius who supposedly died eight years ago.
Three minutes until the Group 1 drop point.
Our mission this time will be harder than ever.
And Nanoha and I won’t be able
to come save you if you’re in trouble.
But close your eyes for a moment and remember your training.
The basic skills that you’ve repeated over and over again.
Your special skills that you’ve polished and polished.
The defense training where you were hurt.
The formations you repeated until your whole body hurt.
The mock combats you did with us
over and over again until you were barely able to stand.
You can open your eyes.
Well, I don’t know if I can say it, but it was tough.
You’ve done well to make it this far, the four of you.
“All four of you are stronger than anybody else.”
I can’t really say that yet.
But I’ve trained you to deal with anybody in any situation.
The power to protect what you must protect,
the power to save what you must save,
and the power to stand up
in the face of a desperate situation.
After how hard you’ve worked, you have all of those things.
This is what you dreamed and longed for
all those times you did your best together,
all those times you put all that effort into no matter how painful it was.
They’ve all been worth it.
Don’t forget that.
It’s the ability to overcome
a desperate situation that makes a striker.
Yes, ma’am!
Okay, Riot Force 6 forward squad,
move out!
Get going!
Yes, ma’am!
I’m going on ahead.
Subaru.
I know you’re worried about Ginga, and I’m sure—
You’re wrong!
Ginny is most likely fine.
I’ll save her for sure.
For now, Nanoha, I’m worried about you and Vivio.
Thank you, Subaru.
But I’m okay.
The thing I was most afraid of was not being able to go out there, but Commander Yagami gave me the go-ahead.
If I can go out and do my best,
then there’s nothing I’m worried about.
Vivio will be okay too.
I’ll save her.
So don’t worry.
The Nanoha you’ve always admired
is an invincible ace who won’t lose to anybody, Subaru.
Yes, ma’am.
And Subaru, you’re our front attacker,
the pride of our squad.
Do your best with your partner, Mach Caliber.
Yes, ma’am!
Just what are you doing crying before a mission?
I tried to give Nanoha a pep talk.
And she gave you one instead?
Yeah.
You idiot. It’s ten years too early
for you to be doing that to Nanoha.
If you want to cheer Nanoha on, you need to be far stronger and better than you are now.
Yeah.
Okay, Officer Team, you’re up!
Ma’am!
Opening bottom hatch!
Ability limiters for Riot Force 6’s captains and lieutenants are now completely released.
Hayate, Signum, Vita, Nanoha, Fate, everyone, be safe.
Do your best.
We’ll handle this as quickly as possible.
Leave it to us.
Limit release!
Exceed
Drive...
...Ignition
Nanoha?
Fate.
Nanoha, about your and
Raising Heart’s limit break, Blaster Mode...
I’m sure you won’t listen to me if I tell you not to use it, Nanoha, so I won’t.
But, please, don’t overdo it.
I’m more worried about you, Fate.
Bardiche’s and your limit break is extremely powerful, Fate,
but it’s also very dangerous
and puts a lot of stress on you to use.
I’m fine.
Don’t worry.
Fate, you’re being as stubborn as always.
N-Nanoha, you’re always doing dangerous things!
I’m an aerial mage.
Doing dangerous things in my job.
Even so, you do too much, Nanoha!
I...
Do you know how much we’ve worried?
I do.
I know very well how much you’ve worried about me.
So I’ll come back safe today.
I’ll come back with Vivio, happy and safe.
Hey, Fate?
It’s kind of time we...
Don’t overdo it, Captain Fate.
We’ll make sure the land and sky are safe.
Great! I’ll be all right.
Good luck.
Yep, good luck to you too.
Sad events, unreasonable pain, and unchangeable fate.
I hated those, and I didn’t want to allow them.
So I wanted the power to break through them.
I chose this path.
And chose the path of sharing my skills
and power with those kids who felt the same way.
Magic like this is there to protect what means the most to you.
A power I need to make my wishes come true.
Wait for me, Vivio!
Welcome back, Uno.
Thanks.
Tre, Sein, and Sette are back.
Counterattack preparations are complete.
Quattro and Dieci are inside the Cradle.
And my other sisters are heading to
their respective mission points and Surface HQ.
I asked Lutecia, and she’s going to help us as well.
Knight Zest is on the move, as well.
If he acts in an unexpected manner—
It’s not a problem.
As soon as she completes her present mission,
Due will head for Surface HQ.
W-Why?
Why?
It’s not healthy for you old folks to work so hard.
It’s time for you to say good night.
You witch! Jail’s...
The genius that you found, created, and raised.
With the knowledge of a lost world and
the infinite greed within him, the pride of Alhazred.
Development codename:
Unlimited Desire.
Jail Scaglietti.
The moment you created him
and gave him power, your fate was sealed.
No matter what chain you put around his neck, or what prison you put him in,
the power you cannot master
will bring about your destruction.
Nonsense! Impossible!
Good night.
Mages, group into formation!
Were going to take out the smaller units!
Look for a way inside!
Assault Team, report your position!
Enemy group 7 destroyed!
Next!
Yes, ma’am!
Mama.
It will be a little over three hours before the Dimensional Navy reaches their location for the assault on the Cradle.
We estimate three hours until we reach the orbital point.
Three hours.
Etched into this amulet, these precious times
In my precious days
“The bluebird ran away”
I cried, embracing the empty cage
I still remember the color of the high-rising sky
That I looked up at that day
Rewinding
Inside my memories
In painful times, in happy times
You were always there at important times
The thing which I looked for to the ends of the labyrinth
Is deep within my heart
Etched into this amulet, these precious times
Soft and secret pieces of my memory
No matter what type of tomorrow it is, I can walk towards it
In my precious days
Next
Episode
Preview
Next
Episode
Preview
Lt. Vita and I
infiltrate the Cradle.
Sister Schach and I infiltrate Scaglietti’s hideout.
And the forwards...
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS:
Episode 21: Decisive Battle
Episode 21
Decisive Battle
Take off.