My hero is the person who saved my life.
It’s my dream to become as strong as that person,
who I admire, who I dream about, and who I aim to be like.
However, our reunion after four years was all too sudden,
and there’s a lot I’m not sure about.
But something’s about to begin.
That’s the feeling I get.
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS
will now begin.
The hot comet dwelling within my heart beats towards the beginning.
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
My fingers tremble, grasping upon a silent wish
I cower, wanting to flee from the inescapable past
Even if it is merely a faint light fading
I want to chase after it, just like that star
And accept everything, no matter how high it is
An angel’s whisper dancing throughout the galaxy
Pursuing these certain memories
The door to the truth will surely be born now
No matter what kind of cold darkness binds me
Because I want to know
I won’t be stopped
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
So you remember me.
Not just remember...
I’ve always admired you, Nanoha.
I’m glad.
When I saw your Buster, I was a bit surprised.
I’m sorry for not asking!
It’s okay... I don’t mind.
P.F.C. Lanster, do you know about Nanoha?
Yes, I do.
The ace of aces of the Main Office’s Armed Services,
one of the youngest but best air-combat instructors,
Captain Nanoha Takamachi.
Righty-o!
Do they know each other?
From back then, remember?
Four years ago,
when you two came to visit me while I was training...
the airport fire incident.
When we helped with disaster relief?
That’s right.
Subaru was one of the people Nanoha saved.
Incidentally, Fate, you saved Subaru’s sister.
Really? I remember saving a girl, but...
That’s the one, that girl!
Now they’re both operatives of the Bureau,
though they’re in different battalions.
That’s right.
Now that you mention it, they do look alike.
Episode 2
Riot Force 6
Four years ago, in Mid’s coastal sector,
a fire, started due to a dangerous smuggled item,
engulfed the airport at an overwhelming rate.
Even the Reserve G.A.S. trainees were called in to help with the rescue efforts.
It had become a large incident.
Squads 203, 405, please deploy to the east.
Follow your mage leaders and protect those fuel tanks!
Hayate, it’s not going to work.
We don’t have enough mages!
I know, but we don’t have any choice but to hold on until aerial support arrives.
Hang in there!
Okay...
Being a Special Investigator with the G.A.S.,
Hayate took command of the operation.
Nanoha and I were over visiting Hayate during our vacation,
so we also took part in the rescue efforts.
Aerial mage, this is Main Office 02, please respond.
Copy that. Main Office 02, this is Testarossa-Harlaown.
We have a response within Gate 8,
but our operatives cannot advance any further.
Can you look into it for us?
Gate 8...
Bardiche!
Optimal route calculated.
Route retrieval end.
We will arrive in under two minutes.
It arrives within two minutes.
I’ll be there shortly.
Keep going south!
Hayate, the guard squad’s commander has arrived!
Sorry for being late.
Not at all. I’m currently stationed with the Ground Armed Service.
Captain Hayate Yagami, a Special Investgiator from the Main Office.
I have taken charge of the rescue squad for the time being.
Major Genya Nakajima of the Ground Armed Service’s 108th Battalion.
Over here! Quickly!
Okay, Major Nakajima.
Can I ask you to take over command of the squadron?
Sure. Are you a mage yourself?
Quite an experienced one.
I want to help put out the fire from the sky.
Hayate, following your instructions I’ve taken a girl to safety.
Her name’s Subaru Nakajima.
I just dropped her off with the rescue team,
but she said her sister is still inside!
Roger, I’ll be joining you in the sky soon.
Roger!
Nakajima?
They’re my daughters.
They were supposed to visit me at the base.
Well then, Major Nakajima, please take command of the rest.
Rein, do your best!
Once you’ve explained everything, I want you to meet up with me!
Gotcha!
I’m from the Bureau!
Over here!
It’s okay now!
Defenser Plus
I’ll take you to safety right away.
Excuse me.
Yes?
You see... a mage girl put up this barrier for us.
And then she said she was going to look for her little sister in that direction!
I understand.
As soon as I get you to safety, I’ll look for her.
Subaru?
Subaru? Subaru, please answer me!
Your sister is coming to save you.
You there! Don’t move!
I’m coming to save you now!
Sonic Move
That was dangerous.
Sorry I’m late.
It’s okay now.
What’s your little sister’s name?
Do you know where she is?
We got separated at the entrance hall.
Her name’s Subaru Nakajima...
...she’s 11 years old.
This is Communications HQ.
Subaru Nakajima, an 11 year old girl,
has already been rescued.
She was saved by Instructor Takamachi.
She is uninjured.
Subaru! Thank goodness!
Roger. I have her sister here.
What is your name?
Ginga, Ginga Nakajima, military trainee, 13 years old.
A trainee, huh?
You’ll be my future colleague.
I’m honored.
The reinforcements?
Eighteen more minutes until Rescue Squad 7 arrives.
The Air Armed Service will also arrive at the operation within one hour.
Slowpokes!
How many are in need of rescue?
Roughly twenty victims.
The mages are working hard... we’ll manage somehow.
Does it look like we can avoid the worst-case scenario?
Yeppers!
Great! That should do for now, my little collaborator friend.
Why don’t you go meet up with your mistress?
It’s okay. I’d like to stay a bit longer to organize information and give instructions.
Oh, I see. Well, that’ll really help.
O ruler of the white snow,
with silver wings,
turn all earth in sight to ice!
Capt. Yagami, the block’s evacuation is complete.
It’s up to you!
Roger!
Come forth, breath of ice.
Breath of Ice
Atem des Eises
Incredible!
So this is the power of an S+ rank mage!
Sorry to get you two involved!
I have trouble controlling this by myself.
Not at all!
We’ll search for the next evacuated block.
Sorry we took so long!
We thank the gentlemen at the scene as well as the aces for the emergency support.
Please leave the rest to us!
Roger! I’ll continue helping with the rescue effort,
so please give me instructions.
This is First Squadron, arriving from the north.
We’ll deploy immediately.
They’ve finally arrived.
Yes!
But we can’t let our guard down yet.
Can I rely on you some more for information management?
Roger!
Good morning. We’re now going live to the scene.
I’m reporting live from the scene.
Although the fire has been extinguished,
smoke continues to rise from the area.
As I speak, operatives from the Time-Space Administrative Bureau
are conducting investigations into
the dangers as well as the cause of the accident.
Luckily, thanks to the efforts of a group of aerial mages
from the Main Office, there were no casualties.
Just as I thought.
the G.A.S. trainees, plus Nanoha and Fate
worked just as hard as Disaster Response
but never got the credit for it
Well, we are on vacation, anyway.
And the civilians are safe.
You know, Nanoha, Fate,
I want my own unit after all.
For disaster relief like this time and crime investigation as well as Lost Logia investigation.
No matter how you look at it, Midchilda’s Bureau units have too many assignments.
And we shouldn’t just be the rear guard
and do desk work all the time.
Unlike before, I’ve been busy
here and there and have no freedom.
I don’t feel like I’m moving forward at all.
It would be an elite unit.
And if I succeed, the people above might change just a bit too.
If I did make a unit like that,
Fate, Nanoha, would you cooperate with me?
Of course if you two don’t want to, or if you have any worries about it, I understand, but...
Hayate, what are you being so reserved for?
Haven’t we known each other since third grade?
Anyway, if you didn’t invite us to such a fun unit, we would be mad instead.
Right, Fate?
Right.
Thanks! I appreciate it, Nanoha, Fate!
And well... because of that, Lt. Colonel Yagami put her efforts towards creating her new unit.
It took four years, but finally we’ve reached the start of its formation.
And that’s that.
The squad is called the Time-Space Administrative Bureau Main Office’s
Antiquities Department, Riot Force 6!
Registered as a part of the Ground Armed Service,
Riot Force 6’s forward squads will work under G.A.S. mages.
Missions will include investigating antiquities as well as management and protection.
Antiquities. You mean Lost Logia, right?
That’s right.
But, we’ll investigate everything from public safety to large-scale cases and counter-measures as well.
Is that so?
Tia. Tia!
In short, we’ll investigate anything to do with the Lost Logia,
What is it?
What’s a Lost Logia?
as well as other cases the Main Office gives us.
Shut up! We’re in the middle of a meeting! Save it for later!
Okay.
So, Private First Class Subaru Nakajima...
And also, Private First Class Teana Lanster...
Yes, ma’am!
I am considering assigning the two of you as forwards in Riot Force 6.
I know it’ll be hard work to start,
but you’ll gain a lot of experience and have a greater chance of promotion.
What do you think?
Um... well...
Subaru would learn magic
directly from
Instructor Takamachi.
Okay.
And as Teana is aiming
to be an Enforcer,
if you have no objections,
I should be able
to give you advice.
Oh no, I don’t mind at all!
Well, in fact, I’m honored! That is...
Um... am I interrupting?
It’s all right.
For the time being, let’s talk about the results of the examination.
Both of you have almost no problems with technique.
However, your dangerous actions and inability to foresee accidents are too great to allow a pass.
A mage who doesn’t consider her partner’s safety and can’t abide by the exam’s rules
cannot be trusted to protect people, right?
That’s right.
That’s why I’m sorry to say that you both failed the exam.
On the other hand.
Taking your magical powers and abilities into consideration,
it might be more dangerous to keep you two at C rank until the next exam half a year away.
That is the conclusion that the proctor and I have come to.
Righty-o!
So with that said, take this.
It’s a written application as well as a letter of recommendation for a special training course.
Take this with you to a three-day course offered by the Armed Services at the Main Office,
and on the fourth day you’ll be able to retake the final exam.
From next week on, you’ll be under the care of the strict officers at the Main Office.
Be sure to learn about safety and rules from them.
If you do that, then B rank will be easy for you to obtain.
All right?
Thank you, ma’am!
Until you pass, you’ll want to concentrate on the exam, right?
Let’s leave your answers until after you’ve passed the exam.
Sorry and thank you, we are grateful, ma’am!
Gah! I was nervous about so many things...
Yeah, I guess.
It’s too bad we didn’t pass but...
Well, I guess it can’t be helped.
Aren’t we lucky though?
To be able to retake the exam.
We sure are.
And well, about the new unit,
Tia, what do you want to do?
You want to go, don’t you?
Nanoha is your hero.
It be wonderful if you’re in the same unit, wouldn’t it?
Well, I guess so.
I wonder what I’ll do.
Normally for an elite unit,
You’d have to be an expert or have special abilities.
Otherwise you can’t get in, right?
With that said, I wonder if I can do that job the way I am now.
What is it, you’re creeping me out.
“That’s not true at all! You can definitely do it, Tia!”
Isn’t that what you want me to say?
What are you talking about? I don’t want you to say that! Don’t be an idiot!
That hurts! That hurts...! I give, I give, I give up!
That really hurt.
Hey, Tia!
I already know.
Whenever you voice your insecurities,
you’re really thinking the opposite.
As for Enforcer Fate, you’re seeing a hot rival scene, aren’t you?
A rival scene? It’s nothing outrageous like that though.
You know, right? It’s my dream to be an Enforcer.
So if I can accomplish that through studying, I want to do it.
In that case, let’s do it, Tia!
I’ll learn lots of stuff from Nanoha because I want to become even stronger!
Tia, you’ll gain experience in the new unit
and achieve your dream through the shortest route.
And let’s not forget...
We aren’t even experts in our fields yet
We should be grateful that they’re accepting us!
Stop mentioning that!
That irritates me so much!
No matter what we talk about,
no matter where I am, you’re always fooling around with me!
Well fine then. If this goes well,
it’ll shorten the road to my dreams.
Though it’s a pain looking after you, I guess I’ll put up with it.
Wait, what are you laughing about?
I guess it’s pretty clear those two will sign up.
You’re right.
Nanoha, you look pretty happy.
Both of them seem like they are willing to learn,
so I can take my time and teach them properly.
That’s for certain!
There were two more forward candidates.
What about them?
Both of them are from other worlds.
Signum is picking them up now.
Nanoha, Hayate! Sorry for the wait.
Sorries!
The next time we meet will be at Riot Force 6’s building.
Your room will be made up super-duper well!
Great!
I’m looking forward to it!
Well then, let’s leave it at that and go back.
I drove in today,
so I can take you to the central region.
Really? Thanks!
By the way, Nanoha, are you feeling all right?
I’m perfectly fine! No problems at all!
Then that’s okay, but...
You worry too much, Fate.
You know how tough I am, right?
I know, but I still worry
Because I’m your friend.
I’m really okay, so don’t worry.
Thank you for coming!
I apologize for being in civilian clothing.
I’m Private Erio Mondial.
Sorry I’m late in picking you up.
First Lieutenant Signum, of the Antiquities Department, Riot Force 6.
You must have travelled far to get here.
Not at all!
What about the other person?
About that, it doesn’t seem she’s come yet.
So... it’s already past the designated time. She might be lost.
Is it okay if I go look for her?
Can I count on you?
Yes, ma’am!
Ah, so the forward candidates really are those kids.
They’re both still children, so I’m a bit worried.
But, ability-wise it looks like they’re no problem.
Well they are in my squad,
so if we’re together I can be a bit at ease.
Miss Lushe! Miss Lushe!
New recruit for the Bureau’s Riot Force 6, Miss Lushe!
Are you there? Miss Lushe?
Yes, that’s me! Sorry I’m so late!
You’re Miss Lushe, right? I’m—
Sonic Move
Ow... ow... ouch.
S-sorry, I screwed up.
No, thank you very much. You saved me.
I’m sorry. I’ll move now.
Um... uh... I’m also sorry!
Oh! Fried, I’m sorry! Are you okay?
A baby dragon?
Excuse me, I’m sorry.
You’re Private Erio Mondial, right?
Er... yes!
Nice to meet you, I’m Private Caro Ru Lushe.
And also, this is Friedrich, my dragon.
Vita, Zafira, you’ve cornered them
Gadgets Type 1. There are three.
Eisen!
Flying Swallow
Schwalbefliegen
Have we finished cleaning up?
Shamal, any remaining?
No responses or shadows.
We’ve destroyed them all.
They’re deploying more frequently and in greater numbers.
Yeah, and their movements are gradually becoming smarter.
But with this much,
we can still manage with just us.
That’s right.
Also these opponents will give our newbies some problems.
No choice, we’ll have to manage with just us.
That’s the reason we have the new unit.
Hayate’s—no, our new unit.
Riot Force 6, huh?
Without end, the dreams continue to weave
Surpassing thousands of nights
Like a prayer, the journey continues
Be my guide any day, oh small jewel
Spica among the stars
I engrave beyond the horizon
The faint footsteps that are connected to everywhere
The reflection of your eyes casts away the loop of anxiety
The midnight sun
The Orion of Midsummer
Just now from somewhere, I heard your voice
This heart without darkness
Illumine it, o distant blue star
No matter what the time, I will be able to start walking
Sparkling far and near
Watching over me
The thing inside my heart, overflowing
More than tears, I want to be loved
Like a prayer, the journey continues
Be my guide anyday, oh small jewel
Spica among the stars
Next
Episode
Preview
Next
Episode
Preview
Riot Force 6
has finally been formed!
All members are assembled.
I’ll have to work hard enough to not lose to anything!
And right away, Nanoha’s combat training starts!
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS:
Episode 3: Gathering of Troops
Episode 3
Gathering of Troops
Take off!