The massive ship rising in the sky
above Midchilda, the Holy King’s Cradle.
If we allow it to reach orbit,
then everyone on Mid will be a hostage.
Incredible danger is upon us,
and every member of Riot Force 6 is involved.
Captain Fate heads for Scaglietti’s hideout.
The forwards head for the combat cyborgs on the surface.
And the two officers of Stars head inside the Cradle.
We have a little over two hours left.
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
The things that I can do for you and no one else
I honestly feel and wish for those
I am frozen by uncertainties
By the rules I have been relying on
My past embellished with excuses
I want to get over it
Staining the stars in heaven scarlet
Gather the grains of miracles
Before the still, unseen night
I want to tell you that I am escaping from illusions
The twilight moon calls out to me
Removing my veil of delusions
My hidden, deceitful self
And took all of my weaknesses
I don’t want words that seem passionate
The fact that I’m here right now is my truth
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Quattro, can I give my honest opinion?
Go right ahead.
I don’t really like this plan.
Why is that?
Do we really have to stoop to using
such a small girl to power such a huge ship?
I’m not really sure about this “engineer’s revenge.”
Oh, that.
That’s just the Doctor’s excuse.
Doesn’t mean a thing.
Really?
The Doctor’s always had one goal:
The completion of biomanipulation technology
and a space to do that.
The Cradle is here to make that dream a reality.
Well, I’m sure a minimum of
several thousand people are going to die here,
but it won’t even take a hundred years to make up for that.
The Doctor’s research is there to save people!
What’s wrong, Dieci?
Have you stopped believing in your big sister and the Doctor?
No, that’s not it.
Not at all, but...
...but, when I see such a weak, small life,
living and moving like this,
I think that maybe they don’t have anything to do with it.
Before you saw them,
you could easily pull the trigger, right?
Sorry, I just got distracted for a second.
Forget it.
Really?
I’ll do as I was ordered.
If I don’t, it’ll be bad for my sisters on the ground.
Stupid Dieci, you’re a boring girl like Cinque and Sein.
A weak life that can’t do anything is no different than an insect’s.
No matter how many you kill, more will just keep being born.
Playing with them and abusing them,
throwing them in a cage and watching them suffer
is so much fun!
Right?
Episode 22
The massive ship which rose from the mountains of central Midchilda continues to ascend.
At the same time, gadgets and a group that is being considered dangerous
are heading toward the capital, Clanagan, from the 7th Abandoned City Area.
An emergency evacuation order
has been issued for the surrounding area.
We ask that all citizens remain calm and follow the orders of any Bureau operatives as well as the safety broadcasts.
Are you awake?
Just woke up.
What time and day is it today?
How many days did I sleep?
It’s been a full week since Riot Force 6 was attacked.
It seems a new incident has occurred.
Everyone in Riot Force 6 who can move is deployed.
Without a chopper?
Damn! At a time like this I...
Alto is piloting the helicopter.
Signum and Alto told me.
Laguna.
And they said you were hurt,
and I should go see you since you’re my brother.
Are you okay, Vice?
I hear your wounds are nothing major.
If you just stay in the hospital, they’ll heal right away.
That’s right.
You know, about that time...
After that, you and I never really spoke,
but I was hoping we could go back to how we used to be.
My left eye
is fine now.
They said I won’t have to wear an eyepatch anymore.
You’re a visitor?
You need to hurry up and evacuate,
and somebody will be here for the patients soon.
Please wait until then.
Once you’re better, can we talk like we used to?
I’m sorry, you’ll have to talk after the evacuation.
Vice, I...
What a pathetic story.
I ran from my failure, my responsibility!
I still haven’t faced them.
I screwed up again, and I’m like this.
I haven’t gotten over anything.
I can’t even look Laguna in the eyes.
I can’t hold her, Storm Raider, in my hands.
How you live and how you fight is for you to decide.
Alto and the others asked me to watch you until you woke up, but that’s done now.
Hey, where are you going all beat up like that?
There’s something I must do.
Hey!
Storm Raider.
Just tell us why you’re fighting already!
If you don’t,
we’ll all really...
The Doctor asked me to.
Wing Shooter
The Doctor is helping me find what I’m looking for, Relic Serial XI.
So I do what he asks.
For something like that?
For something like that.
It might not be much to you, but it is to me.
No, no!
Not like that!
Zest will be gone soon.
Agito will go somewhere too, I’m sure.
But when this celebration is over, Doctor, Uno, and the others will look for Serial XI for me.
Then my mom will come back.
Then I won’t be unhappy anymore.
No!
That’s not true!
I don’t like talking to you.
If you want to be happy, no matter how unhappy
you are, you can’t make others unhappy or hurt them!
If you do that, you won’t find what you want, especially happiness!
I’m a dragon summoner from Alzus
and a mage with the Bureau’s Riot Force 6.
Caro Ru Lushe!
And with the same,
Erio Mondial.
And the flying dragon, Friedrich.
Tell us about how you’re looking for the Relics and your mother!
We, Riot Force 6, will help you!
What’s your name?
Oh, that’s a no-no, Miss Lutecia.
You too, Galue.
You mustn’t listen to the enemy in the middle of a battle.
If something gets in your way, kill it and keep going!
That’s how you use our power!
We have a lot of work for you to do after this, Miss Lu.
We need you to cut off the city’s lifelines and smash their defensive base.
Quattro. But...
You’re hesitating, aren’t you?
To a pure, innocent girl like you,
Miss Lutecia, that child’s words are poison.
And so, press!
Lu!
Galue! What is this?
I made it so Miss Lu won’t hesitate anymore.
This is a consideration console that the Doctor implanted in her.
I presented her with a stone heart
that won’t listen to anybody.
Miss!
Can you hear me?
The ones in front of you are your enemies.
If you don’t use all your power to kill them,
you’ll never see your mother.
Why you!
Insects, Jirai-Oh, Galue...
Kill.
Kill them.
Kill them!
Galue!
I.S.: Slaughter Arms
Thunder Arm
The A.M.F. is slowing me down.
I need to defeat them quickly and go on ahead,
but I can’t use Sonic or Riot.
If I use them now, I won’t be able to use them later.
If I can’t get to Scaglietti, it’s game over,
and even if I do capture him,
I won’t be able to help the others.
Oh, how are you doing, Enforcer Fate Testarossa?
Scaglietti!
The legacy of F and the dragon summoner
who are fighting my works,
can you hear me?
The first part of our wonderful celebration is at its climax.
What do you mean, “wonderful celebration?”
You’re a felon who’s plunged the surface into chaos!
Felon?
Do you mean the Artificial Mage or Combat Cyborg Projects?
Or do you mean the basis for Project F that I designed and your mother, Presea Testarossa, completed?
All of it.
In every era, revolutionaries are despised.
You callous...! You play with people’s fates and lives...
I haven’t destroyed valuable ingredients
or killed without reason.
I just turned useless, worthless lives into valuable experimental subjects.
Why, you...!
It’s coming!
Right!
Normally gentle and calm
but loses herself easily to anger or sadness.
Oh cr—
That personality of yours is truly from your mother,
Fate Testarossa.
Fate!
Lævateinn!
Snake Form
Schlangenform
Flame Acceleration
Draconic Swordflash
Flame Purge
Shock Acceleration
Dammit.
We haven’t lost them.
We can chase them!
Yes.
Sir.
Sorry, Agito.
Even under Unison, I can barely use your flame anymore.
I don’t care.
I’ve got a lot of ways to protect you, sir.
She called herself Signum, right?
She’s a good knight.
With such sword skills and firepower,
she’s a suitable candidate for being the ideal lord you spoke of.
W-What’s that?
Her stance was definitely
that of a true Ancient Belkan knight.
It’s likely that she was preserved like you.
That can’t be!
Why would somebody like that be in the Bureau?
Even the color of her magic armor matches yours.
Which means it’s possible...
Stop it!
She’s an enemy!
Please, don’t think about me.
Do your best for yourself.
Blitz Caliber, no response.
Her A.I. unit’s been messed with.
Ginny... I have to hurry.
I’ll save Ginny and everyone.
Load Cartridge
Revolver...
...Cannon
Ginny...
Ginny.
Ginny!
We were able to use DNA analysis to discover when the person Vivio was cloned from was born.
Her DNA is from Ancient Belka, 300 years ago,
during the age of the Holy King.
I’m sure that Vivio’s mom lived in that age, which means...
She’s not around anymore.
But it seems like Vivio thinks a mom
is somebody who’s especially gentle to her.
But she’s really taken to you.
Are you going to adopt her as your daughter?
I’m looking for a place that will take her in.
A warm family who will accept her and who needs her.
She won’t like that.
I don’t think I can make her happy.
Why not?
I’m always busy with myself,
and I don’t have the right to be a gentle mother.
And more than anything, I’m a person of the sky.
You can’t say that!
It’s a possiblity.
I’ve been shot down once already.
But still!
Mama.
Vivio, what’s wrong?
You look sad, Mama.
Really?
Mama, be a good girl.
You’re nice, Vivio.
I’m fine.
As long as you’re happy and smiling, Vivio,
Mama Nanoha will always be happy and smiling too.
I can’t fight every one of them.
Raising Heart!
All right.
Strike Flame
A.C.S. Driver
Charge.
It’s no use, Quattro. I can’t handle her.
That’s as we thought.
She’s going to die here in the throne room.
They’re all doing better than we thought,
but it’s just a matter of time.
We just have to stand here and wait.
The Cradle will reach
orbit in
1 hour
1 hour and 44 minutes
Etched into this amulet, these precious times
In my precious days
“The bluebird ran away”
I cried, embracing the empty cage
I still remember the color of the high-rising sky
That I looked up at that day
Rewinding
Inside my memories
In painful times, in happy times
You were always there at important times
The thing which I looked for to the ends of the labyrinth
Is deep within my heart
Etched into this amulet, these precious times
Soft and secret pieces of my memory
No matter what type of tomorrow it is, I can walk towards it
In my precious days
Next
Episode
Preview
Next
Episode
Preview
My own battle
that I can’t run from.
The strength I admired,
that I truly longed for.
It’s always the courage to step forward that brings victory.
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS:
Episode 23: Stars Strike
Episode 23
With feeling, take off!