What has been lost.
What has happened.
The past can’t be changed,
so I don’t want to lose them.
I want to protect them.
To protect them, I want to be strong.
What I chose was to fight and to win,
to change an unseen future into what I wish.
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS
will now begin.
The hot comet dwelling within my heart beats towards the beginning.
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
My fingers tremble, grasping upon a silent wish
I cower, wanting to flee from the inescapable past
Even if it is merely a faint light fading
I want to chase after it, just like that star
And accept everything, no matter how high it is
An angel’s whisper dancing throughout the galaxy
Pursuing these certain memories
The door to the truth will surely be born now
No matter what kind of cold darkness binds me
Because I want to know
I won’t be stopped
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
I don’t remember when I was born.
I never knew my Meister,
or my parent as humans would call them.
I just slept silently, probably for a very long time.
Then the next thing I knew,
I was a test subject in a white room.
Just not knowing why I’d been born was painful.
And I suffered, not knowing
a single reason why I’d been born.
I didn’t even have the freedom to die.
And I thought that someday my body and mind
would break, and that would be it.
What changed that
was the appearance of a very rough hand and a small girl.
What?
You’re leaving her?
That’s an actual Ancient Belkan Unight, not a replica.
She should be properly cared for,
assuming one of the Bureau staff members who notices the fire finds her.
And she’ll be used for experiments again.
They aren’t as evil as the people here.
I’d like to think so, anyway.
Zest, let’s take her.
Are you sure?
Yes.
I’m sure she’s just like us.
Dammit! What an awful dream.
It’s their fault I remembered that.
The white Unight with the strange x-mark who was using ice magic,
And the red knight who is probably her Lord.
She probably doesn’t know how lonely it is to be a Unight without a Lord.
Dammit, this pisses me off!
Stupid cross-marked midget!
Next time I see you, I’m gonna burn you!
Episode 13
The Reason I Live
I’m sorry, Signum, for having you drive me like this.
Why? I’m borrowing this car from Testarossa anyway.
And Sister Schach is waiting there.
I should go as an intermediary.
I suppose.
Anyway, once the examination is finished and we know what’s going on,
what do you think will happen to her?
Riot Force 6 or the Church will have to take care of her for a while.
If we were to find a place to take her,
we’d have to be assured of their long-term safety.
Knight Signum, this is Schach Nouera of the Church of the Holy King.
What’s wrong?
I’m sorry.
We failed to properly secure her
and she vanished in the middle of the examination.
I’m terribly sorry.
Can you tell us what’s going on?
Yes.
We’ve sealed and evacuated
the special wing and the surrounding areas.
As of yet, we’ve found no indication that anyone came in via flight or teleportation.
She can’t leave the building, right?
Then, let’s split up and look for her.
Lt. Signum.
Yes, ma’am.
The examination failed to find anything dangerous, correct?
Indeed. Her mana capacity is higher than average,
but it’s well within the range of a normal child.
But, even so...
I’m sorry to say it, but there’s
no doubt that she’s an artificial being.
There’s no way to tell what kind of latent threat she poses.
There you are.
I’ve been worried.
That’s...!
Spin up, Windenschaft!
Sister Schach, may I handle this?
I’m sorry.
You were scared, right?
Are you all right?
Can you stand?
I don’t think there’s any immediate danger.
Thank you, Sister Schach.
Yes, ma’am.
Nice to meet you.
My name is Nanoha Takamachi.
Can you say your name?
Vivio.
I see. That’s a cute name.
Did you want to go somewhere, Vivio?
My mom isn’t here.
That’s terrible.
Then let’s look for her together!
An emergency inspection?
For Riot Force 6?
It seems like there’s talk of it at Surface HQ.
Inspections by Surface HQ are pretty tough, I hear.
We, this team, have a lot of challenges to begin with.
If we were ordered to change
our shifts or our position right now,
to be honest, it would be the end of us.
Urgh... we have to overcome this somehow.
Ah, this has something to do with the inspection as well, but
can you tell me the real reason Riot Force 6 was established now?
That’s right.
Well, it’s a good time, I guess.
I’m heading to the Church of the Holy King’s headquarters to meet with Carim today.
Chrono will be there, too.
Chrono.
Could you and Nanoha come with me?
I’ll tell you there.
Sure.
I wonder if Nanoha’s back...
Hey, don’t cry, don’t cry.
Come play with us!
What’s happening?
Captain Fate, actually...
Don’t go!
Commander Yagami!
Fate!
I guess there are some opponents even the ace of aces can’t defeat.
Fate, Hayate, save me.
Subaru, Caro.
For now, let’s calm her down.
Go rest somewhere.
Yes, ma’am.
Hello there.
Is this your friend?
Vivio, this is Fate.
She’s my closest friend.
Vivio, what’s wrong?
I brought her here from the hospital
for the time being, but she won’t leave me alone.
Perhaps she’s fallen in love with you.
So I thought I would have the forwards take care of her.
Sorry.
It’s okay. Leave it to me.
Say, do you want to be with Nanoha, Vivio?
But Nanoha has to go do something important.
And your selfishness is bothering her, Vivio.
This girl too, see?
You don’t want to bother Nanoha, do you, Vivio?
F-Fate’s pretty good at this!
Fate still has a young niece and nephew.
She’s raising her familiar too.
And she took care of you when you were younger too, right?
So be a good girl and wait, okay?
Thanks, Vivio.
I’ll only be gone a little while.
Sorry about all that.
No, that was pretty funny.
But what should we do with her?
We could have the Church take care of her.
It’s okay.
When I get back, I’ll talk to her
a little more and think of something.
I see.
For now, I think she’s just nervous because she has nobody to rely on.
Okay, all done!
That was fast!
Don’t be so slow.
Give me some. I’ll help you out.
Thanks.
I’m not good at writing reports.
We agreed to do Lightning’s reports for them too.
Even so, I’d rather do this than babysit.
Aww, but I was having fun.
Those are the ones from yesterday with all the data Alto recorded.
They could do all that, and it was another type of energy, not magic, that they were using.
The fact that they have that inside them means that they’re...
T-Tia?
Are you dense, or what?
Figuring out what these guys are isn’t our job.
It’s the Long Arch staff and
the captains that make the decisions.
What we’re writing are reports to help them make that decision.
So get to work.
Yeah, whatever.
And even if that was certain,
it’s nothing for you to worry about.
Get to work.
Tia.
Thanks.
Quiet!
Come in.
Excuse us.
Captain Nanoha Takamachi.
Enforcer Fate Testarossa-Harlaown.
Welcome.
Nice to meet you.
I am Carim Gracia, a knight of the Church of the Holy King’s Church Knights.
Please come in.
Excuse me.
Admiral Chrono, it’s been a while.
Yes, Enforcer Fate.
Don’t be so stiff, both of you.
We’re friends as well.
Act like you would normally would.
Well then, you heard Knight Carim.
Same as always.
You’re fine.
Okay then. It’s been a while, Chrono.
How have you been, brother?
Don’t call me that.
We’re both adults now.
That has nothing to do with us being brother and sister, Chrono.
Now then, we need to discuss what happened yesterday,
As well as the full story behind the creation of Riot Force 6
and what we do next.
I’m glad she calmed down.
Me too.
She’s like a normal girl, isn’t she?
Yeah.
If she’s a sample for an artificial mage project,
then her intelligence and language are far too advanced.
Artificial people aren’t made like this.
She probably has her original’s memories.
Erio?
Is something wrong?
S-Sorry! It’s nothing.
Project F is continuing somewhere.
The reason given for the creation of Riot Force 6
was to deal with Lost Logia such as Relics,
as well as to experiment with the creation of small, highly independent forces.
As you know, the sponsors of
Riot Force 6 are myself, Knight Carim,
and my and Fate’s mother as well as our superior, Lindy Harlaown.
Furthermore, unofficially, the Three Admirals have backed us and given us promises of cooperation.
The reason for this is connected to my ability.
My power, Prophetic Writings,
Prophetinschriften
can see the future from a minimum of a half a year to a maximum of a few years away,
and record it in the form of a poem.
The alignment of the two moons’ magical power
has to be perfect, or I can’t do it.
So I can only create pages once a year.
The prophecies are in Ancient Belkan
and are difficult passages
whose interpretations are up for debate.
They randomly record things that happen all around the world.
If you include misinterpreted passages,
they’re about as useful and prophetic as a fairly accurate horoscope.
In other words, it’s not a very useful ability.
The Church of the Holy King and the top brass of the Dimensional Navy look through these.
Putting whether or not they believe them aside,
they’re treated as predictions by an expert.
By the way, the Ground Armed Service hates them.
Their de facto leader dislikes this kind of Rare Skill.
Lt. General Regius Gaiz, right?
Little by little for the past few years,
Knight Carim’s prophecies have begun to converge on a single event.
In the land where ancient crystals and
unlimited desire gather and intertwine,
the wings shall be restored from the holy land of the dead King.
The dead shall dance, and the tower of law in the central lands shall burn to the ground,
and from there, the ship of law
that guards the many seas shall be torn apart.
That...
...can’t be!
The Lost Logia will commence the destruction of the Bureau’s Surface Headquarters.
And then, the Bureau’s entire system.
Has the date for the inspection been decided?
I’ve secured the necessary personnel.
We will perform it next week.
I don’t know what they’re planning,
But we’re the ones who have shed blood and covered ourselves in dust to support the land.
We won’t let the Navy, who makes light of that,
or the ignorant Church, have its way.
More than anything else,
the High Council is on my side.
Right, Auris?
Yes, sir.
The press conference is happening soon.
Use the inspection to find anything you can to use against the Church or the Main Office.
Regarding that,
I performed a preliminary investigation of Riot Force 6.
It’s rather cleverly put together.
It has a young commander with
no real credit to her name at the head,
and its two squad leaders didn’t actually transfer,
but are on loan from the Main Office.
If you disregard the commander’s private forces, who are her family,
all the rest of them are relatively new recruits.
And more than anything,
they’re an experimental squad only being allowed to operate for a limited time.
In other words, they’re expendable?
If there was any kind of trouble that could implicate the Main Office
they would simply be cut off.
That’s how they’re set up.
So, the girl is a sacrificial lamb, huh?
That’s a perfect role for a former criminal.
Well, it’s most likely a role that she chose.
Nothing.
You have two appointments for press conferences after this.
Please come with me.
Okay then, Nanoha, Fate.
That’s plenty of information.
We’re okay.
Hey, wait!
To me, you’re the people who saved
my life and the lives of my dear friends.
I don’t know what will happen to Riot Force 6, but...
You already told us that when we joined.
Both Nanoha and I chose to be here, knowing that.
It’s okay.
Besides, getting me into the Instructor Corps
and setting up Fate’s examinations
were things that you and the whole
Yagami family were instrumental in, Hayate.
So now, Hayate, we need to help you achieve your dreams.
That’s no good—we’ll just keep helping each other forever.
That’s what friends are.
Commander Yagami, I don’t think you’re doing anything wrong right now.
So, it’s okay.
Give us your orders like always, with pride in your heart.
And next he went to a baker in the next town.
We’re back!
We’re back.
Vivio, I’m back.
Were you a good girl?
Thanks, Erio, Caro.
Not at all.
Vivio was a good girl.
I see.
Uncle Graham.
You raised me my whole life, Uncle Graham.
And the little ones protected me.
Nanoha and her friends saved us.
This is the life that she,
the first Reinforce, left me.
I don’t want anyone else in the world to be sad or have regrets like that.
This is my purpose,
the reason I live.
Without end, the dreams continue to weave
Surpassing thousands of nights
Like a prayer, the journey continues
Be my guide any day, oh small jewel
Spica among the stars
I engrave beyond the horizon
The faint footsteps that are connected to everywhere
The reflection of your eyes casts away the loop of anxiety
The midnight sun
The Orion of Midsummer
Just now from somewhere, I heard your voice
This heart without darkness
Illumine it, o distant blue star
No matter what the time, I will be able to start walking
Sparkling far and near
Watching over me
The thing inside my heart, overflowing
More than tears, I want to be loved
Like a prayer, the journey continues
Be my guide anyday, oh small jewel
Spica among the stars
Next
Episode
Preview
Next
Episode
Preview
As we spend days
on standby,
the training continues,
as do our daily lives.
Riot Force 6’s destination,
and that girl who has no place to go...
Where do I go from here?
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS:
Episode 14: Mothers & children
Episode 14
Take off!