The team is still split up,
and the situation is desperate both in the sky and on the ground.
But the moronic kindness of the one that was always with me
and the teachings of the person who beat power and technique into my useless self
are telling me to stand and fight.
Those words she said to me, “Don’t lose to anyone...”
The time I spent,
the future I believed in...
I can’t let those dreams be dreams.
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
The things that I can do for you and no one else
I honestly feel and wish for those
I am frozen by uncertainties
By the rules I have been relying on
My past embellished with excuses
I want to get over it
Staining the stars in heaven scarlet
Gather the grains of miracles
Before the still, unseen night
I want to tell you that I am escaping from illusions
The twilight moon calls out to me
Removing my veil of delusions
My hidden, deceitful self
And took all of my weaknesses
I don’t want words that seem passionate
The fact that I’m here right now is my truth
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Target point is near.
She’s the mother of that small girl, right?
I’ve got nothing against you, but...
Five.
Four.
Three.
Two.
One.
Excelion...
Zero.
...Buster
Blaster System: limit 1, release!
Blaster set.
Booster shoot!
This kind of power right from the start...
Is she really human?
Stay put.
The Assault Team will secure you
and take you to a safe place.
Sealing
We’re going to stop this ship.
Episode 23
Master.
I’m fine.
Maintain Blaster 1.
We need to hurry, Raising Heart.
All right.
I heard the name “Blaster System” and thought it was some advanced, incredible technology, but that’s just stupid.
Hey, Your Majesty? Your mom’s an idiot.
Welcome.
We’ve been waiting.
Thanks for coming all this way, even though it was totally pointless.
Now then, your companions are being beaten all over the world.
You’re under arrest for a large-scale disturbance of the peace!
You will cease and disarm immediately.
Your friends are all in danger, your kid’s in trouble,
and you’re still worried about your job?
How nice! That almost demonic sense of justice.
But I wonder if you can still stay calm.
Vivio?
Let me tell you something interesting.
It was this girl who destroyed the transport truck and the Gadgets when she was still asleep in her case.
And that attack of Dieci’s that took everything you had to block?
If she had been hit by it,
it wouldn’t have slowed her for a second.
That’s the unique skill of the Ancient Belkan royal family,
the Armor of the Holy King.
By joining with the Relics to achieve full power,
which the Ancient Belkan royalty created by
altering their own bodies into the ultimate bio-weapons.
Her power as a Relic Weapon.
Mama!
Vivio!
No! Mama!
Vivio! Vivio!
With the power of the Cradle added to her own,
our king will be complete soon,
and she will be invincible.
The ultimate warrior.
Mama!
Vivio!
Mama.
Oh my, Your Majesty. Don’t cry.
Your mother wants you to save her, Your Majesty.
The scary devil who kidnapped her
is right in front of you, Your Majesty.
Do your best to kick the crap out of her
and get your real mother back.
You have the power to do that now, Your Majesty.
Release that power you maintain in your heart and emotions.
Vivio!
You took my mama somewhere.
Vivio, no, it’s me!
It’s Mama Nanoha!
No!
Liar!
You aren’t my mama!
Give me back my mama!
Vivio!
If you can stop her, you might be able to stop the Cradle.
Raising Heart.
W.A.S., full driving.
Now then, kill each other like a good mother and daughter.
Give me back my mama!
Booster limit 2!
Yes, the city’s defensive line is holding up for now.
We can deal with the Gadgets.
Yes, sir.
The members of our squad that your redhead trained
and Miss Takamachi’s students in
the A.A.S. are maintaining the front lines.
But we’re at our limit.
We can’t send any additional forces elsewhere,
and if the combat cyborgs or that summoner show up, we may go down instantly.
Five of the combat cyborgs and that one summoner are fighting Riot Force 6’s front-line soldiers.
I see.
There’s so many.
Your shooting and your illusion magic is all worthless!
She’s pretty tough.
But if she can keep running
until her backup comes,
we could be in trouble!
We need to hurry up, kill her,
and move on to the next one!
Found her.
They’ve confirmed our position.
They are moving in our direction.
Shooter and silhouette control is okay.
Maintain present status.
All that’s left is to take them out here.
Yes.
I can’t run, and I’m almost out of mana and cartridges.
I’m not sure if trying a final fight with my last bullets will work.
To be honest, I’ve known for a while.
No matter how hard I try, I’ll never be a first-class mage.
It hurt, it was pathetic, and I didn’t want to accept it.
That hasn’t really changed, but...
But still...
Twin Dagger
An illusion?
She’s not running?
Is this a trap?
There’s no doubt... she’s the real one.
Yes, she is.
Don’t underestimate her.
We’ll all rush her at once and take her out.
I knew it. The same positioning as the first time.
That’s the one hole in their strategy.
It’s a perfect but simple combination.
If I can hit at the exact instant their combination strikes...
Oh, Subaru?
What’s wrong?
Mom!
Ginga!
My, my. You slipped, didn’t you?
Hey, Subaru.
Don’t cry just because you tripped.
You’re my daughter and Ginga’s little sister.
You’re actually a strong girl, Subaru.
The results from the test are undeniable.
Your genetic structure is identical
to both Subaru’s and Ginga’s.
We think that your genetic data was stolen somewhere and used.
I see.
You should practice Shooting Arts more, Subaru.
I don’t like pain and scary stuff.
I don’t like being hurt myself,
but I hate hurting or scaring others more.
Our bodies aren’t normal.
I’m scared of breaking something I don’t want to.
I see.
Well, you might not need to be strong, Subaru.
Mom and Dad are here, and so am I.
Okay!
Cease resistance and shut down.
A change in operational specifics.
Damage until out of commission and then recover.
Ginny!
It was impossible after all.
I guess I’m weak and pathetic.
And it’s going to end with me not being able to do anything.
By the way, why did you want to get stronger, Subaru?
Oh! Well, that’s... because I really look up to you, Nanoha.
Well, that makes me happy and all, but I mean,
what do you want to do if you get stronger?
Wingroad
Caliber Shot, left turn!
Shoot it!
Just as rehearsed.
Mach Caliber?
We can still take actions, you and I.
We can still fight, so why abandon now?
You taught me the reason of my being here,
my strength and power which you adore so much.
Don’t make everything a lie.
When a war or a disaster, something bad like that happens,
I want to be able to save people
who are sad, in pain, and shouting “Save me!”
To take them straight to someplace safe, by my own power.
To be honest, I’m always scared and uneasy about fighting,
about hurting somebody: my hands always shake.
But this power in my hands isn’t to destroy.
It’s to protect.
The power to break through a sad reality.
Let’s go, Mach Caliber!
All right, buddy!
Full Drive...
...Ignition!
Gear Excelion
A.C.S., standby.
That helicopter is shooting down the Gadgets?
You’re the commander of the land battle and the one in charge of all the barriers.
You were well-hidden,
but you can’t get away from Klarwind’s sensor.
On suspicion of a large-scale disturbance of the peace,
as well as the attack on Riot Force 6...
You’re under arrest.
Otto.
Otto got taken down, huh?
Yeah.
Why, you...!
Now!
Wendi, Deed!
You’re all under arrest.
Safety your weapons and lay them on the ground.
Let’s go, Ginny!
With a single blow!
Divine...
...Buster
Knight Zest has entered HQ.
This is bad!
Auris, I order you to evacuate.
No, you will.
You have no authority anymore.
You should have no reason to be here.
I must be here.
Sorry for the rough entrance, Regius.
I don’t care, Zest.
Zest?
I won’t let you go any farther!
You’re...!
Sir Zest won’t do anything bad.
He just wants to talk with an old friend.
Sir Zest doesn’t have any time left.
If you’re going to get in his way, then...
Our plan has always been
to ask you what the situation was.
If it’s got to do with what’s going on, then even more so.
We need to hear it.
Is Auris your adjutant?
She’s smart but selfish.
She hasn’t changed since she was a kid.
I’ve just got one question.
Was it on your orders that my men and I were killed eight years ago?
What about the justice of ours that we spoke of, where is it now?
Etched into this amulet, these precious times
In my precious days
“The bluebird ran away”
I cried, embracing the empty cage
I still remember the color of the high-rising sky
That I looked up at that day
Rewinding
Inside my memories
In painful times, in happy times
You were always there at important times
The thing which I looked for to the ends of the labyrinth
Is deep within my heart
Etched into this amulet, these precious times
Soft and secret pieces of my memory
No matter what type of tomorrow it is, I can walk towards it
In my precious days
Next
Episode
Preview
Next
Episode
Preview
Scars that won’t go away, and pain that won’t stop.
To take them straight on without running away.
Because you taught us, we can.
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS:
Episode 24: Lightning
With courage, take off!
Episode 24
Lightning