I think we guardian knights of the Book of Darkness
were just weapons,
like the Relics or the Cradle in the sky.
Hayate gave us a reason to live,
and we’ve spent our time together atoning for our sins.
Before we knew it, ten years had passed,
and now there are many more things that matter to us:
Hayate, our friends, and our students.
We have things we must protect.
And so...
We’ll fight.
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
The things that I can do for you and no one else
I honestly feel and wish for those
I am frozen by uncertainties
By the rules I have been relying on
My past embellished with excuses
I want to get over it
Staining the stars in heaven scarlet
Gather the grains of miracles
Before the still, unseen night
I want to tell you that I am escaping from illusions
The twilight moon calls out to me
Removing my veil of delusions
My hidden, deceitful self
And took all of my weaknesses
I don’t want words that seem passionate
The fact that I’m here right now is my truth
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Fleets 1 and 2 will reach orbit over Mid in three hours.
Their first priority is to create a defensive field over the city.
Three and a half hours until
the counterattack fleet is in position.
Yes. The Fleet Operations and
Communications Departments are in an uproar.
But Advisor Leone is handling the upper ranks
while Laty and her group take good care of the Operations Department.
I doubt it will delay the operation.
That really helps.
Yuuno, how are things there?
Data on the Holy King’s Cradle is scarce,
but I’ve finished digging up what little there is.
I’ll send it now.
Thanks. I’ll send it to
all the front-liners and the fleet from here.
How dangerous is that ship?
Extremely.
Even in the Warrior Age of Ancient Belka,
it was treated as an ancient weapon and a Lost Logia.
Some say it’s a relic from the lost world of Alhazred.
Alhazred.
To my family, that’s not a name we really want to remember.
Fate’s Familiar
Arf
Fate...
Chief Librarian, Infinity Library
Yuuno Scrya
Regardless of that fact,
the biggest threat is if it reaches orbit.
By taking an orbital position where it can absorb mana from the two moons,
its defensive capabilities improve considerably,
and it will be able to launch precise strikes and magical bombs against the surface.
The Church’s documents record this.
Though according to my research,
it will also be capable of transdimensionial attacks
and even combat in the Dimensional Sea.
If it unleashes its full power,
it may be a match even for the Dimensional Navy.
We need to stop it before it reaches orbit, is that right?
Is there any way to deal with it?
If its key, the Holy King, orders it to stop, or its engine is destroyed from inside.
There’s a high probability the key, the Holy King, Vivio, is being controlled by Scaglietti’s combat cyborgs.
So capturing Scaglietti would take care of it as well, right?
Mom, Chrono.
Fate will capture Scaglietti.
Arf.
Fate has been chasing after him for so long.
I’m sure she’ll capture him.
Episode 21
Decisive Battle
Defensive formation!
Don’t break formation!
Y-Yes, ma’am!
It’s immense.
No number of mages will be able to take it out from outside.
Small units have appeared from Launch Chute 24!
From the south too?
Nine hundred!
They’re heading straight for the city!
Everyone, calm down!
If they split up, we’ll never be able to deal with them.
We’ll take out all the units and cannons that we can.
Midchildan ground and aerial mages,
time to show us what you’re made of!
Yes, ma’am!
Capt. Takamachi!
We’ve found what we think is a way in!
Twenty members of the Assault Team have gone on ahead!
Hayate.
I’ll take care of the outside.
Nanoha, Vita, will you go?
Of course!
Roger!
Stars 1 and 2 of Riot Force 6
have entered the inner corridor.
An A.M.F.?
All throughout the corridor?
Gale Burst
Cut them down, Windenschaft!
The other squad has found a passage.
We will immediately seal any dangerous objects.
Roger.
Handle all assault routes as instructed by Inspector Acous.
Yes, ma’am.
Thank you very much, Sister Schach.
Thanks to your investigation,
we can go on ahead without getting lost.
Investigation is his specialty.
These dogs did their best.
Let’s keep going until we get to Scaglietti.
Yes.
I’m sorry, everyone.
It’s gonna get bumpy, so hang on!
Okay, I got rid of them!
Amazing, Alto!
Thanks, Subaru.
Hey, we’re almost at the drop point.
Are you ready, everyone?
Yes!
I’ll outline our mission.
We’re going to join up with the counterattacking front
in the city in Central Mid.
We’ll work together with the G.A.S. and take care of the more annoying forces, the summoner, and combat cyborgs.
Very few of the other squads have anti-A.M.F. or cyborg combat experience.
So we’ll hit them at the top and just take down as much of their combat power as we can.
The rest of them will be handled by the counterattacking front, right?
Right.
But, somehow
I kind of feel like an ace.
That’s right.
If the Gadgets and the combat cyborgs break through the defensive line,
they’ll have a straight path to the city and Surface HQ.
Protecting the citizens and their property is the job of all operatives of the Bureau. We must not let them through.
And if Ginga appears...
...we make her a priority
...and rescue her.
Okay, let’s go!
Go!
Nove, Deed, Wendi, those four are heading toward you.
Are you serious?
Yes.
But the situation’s different this time.
They’re coming to fight us head on.
What?
Sounds good to me.
We’ll take over Central Command
before the Cradle surfaces.
I want to take out their command center.
I want to take out as many unpredictable elements as possible.
That girl.
Fried!
Caro!
Change of plans!
I’ll take this one out first.
Right, Subaru?
Right!
Wing...
Execute I.S.
Ray Storm
Tia!
Aerial Cannon
Subaru and Tia are...
Let’s get back to them...
Wheel Protection
Tia!
It’s dangerous to fight alone here.
Let’s meet back up!
Too bad, we’re not letting you get together!
Ginny.
I’ve trapped the illusionist.
I’ll keep them apart while you fight.
All righty!
You too, Miss, if you please.
How does it feel when you, a useless gunner,
who’s half of what she is when she’s with that girl with the ribbon, finally gets separated from her group of four?
I’ll make you taste Cinques’s pain
and suffering instead of the girl with the ribbon.
I’m inside their barrier.
Lightning and Subaru are both a good distance away
and in difficult fights themselves.
If I show my back to them, it’ll be over in an instant.
Lightning, Subaru, bit of a change of plans.
There’s no need to force yourself
in defeating the enemy in front of you.
Just hinder them and wear them down. That’s enough.
We can protect the city and Central Command.
Are you an idiot?
It won’t take that much time.
You’re not somebody we’re supposed to capture.
Nobody will get mad if we kill you.
They can hear us communicating?
Transmission over!
Everyone, concentrate on your fight!
These are...
Bases for human experiments?
I think so.
He plays with people’s lives and treats them as ingredients for experiments.
This is the type of research he’s done.
We need to stop him as soon as possible.
Agreed.
Sister!
Sister?
Enforcer Fate,
I’m fine. It’s all right.
I’ve caught a combat cyborg.
As soon as I secure her, I’ll meet up with you.
Roger.
Miss Fate.
Has the prodigal daughter returned,
or does she yet rebel?
Neither.
I’m here to capture a criminal.
That’s all.
Giant Form
Gigantform
Let’s go, Eisen!
Roger.
Jawohl.
Flying Comet
Kometfliegen
Vita.
If you hit it too hard...
Shut up!
Letting the center and rear hold back
their most powerful magic is part of the front line’s job.
Assault Team, Riot Force 6, Stars Squad.
Here.
We’ve found the routes to
the throne room and engine room.
Totally different directions!
Aren’t the Assault Team members here yet?
We’re getting them from everywhere we can,
but it’ll still take forty minutes.
No way around it.
Stars 1 and Stars 2 will split up.
Roger that.
We’ll get your support there as soon as we can.
Vita!
Stopping just one of the engine and Vivio
in the throne room may stop this, and it may not.
And while we’re standing here,
things are getting worse outside.
But you’ve expended so much energy, Vita.
That’s why I’m going to the engine room.
You go save Vivio.
But.
This is what Eisen and I are best at.
You know that?
Destroying and smashing.
There’s nothing in the world Vita, Knight of the Steel Hammer, and Graf Eisen, the Iron Count, cannot destroy.
I’ll destroy it in a second and come to back you up.
We’ll finish this and meet up with Hayate out front.
Take care.
Make sure you come meet me, okay?
Of course!
Riot Force 6, Stars 1 is heading toward the throne room.
Stars 2 is heading toward the engine room.
Nanoha. Vita.
It was an illusion after all.
You need to learn more than one trick,
Dumbass-with-Illusions!
Her bullets are sharper than they were.
One or two shots from that
spud cannon aren’t enough to hurt me.
Well, that’s true.
It’s all I can do to last against
these two in such an enclosed environment.
Until the barrier-destruction staff come, I have to survive.
Deed, you too?
Otto’s orders.
She said that if we don’t take out
that illusionist for sure, it’ll be a real problem.
To think they’d hit my leg.
Three combat cyborgs, plus the Gadgets.
This is impossible, maybe.
Don’t worry. I’m sure you can do it, Teana.
You’re strong, Tia! I’m sure you’ll be okay.
Let’s both do our best, Tia.
Why? Why am I thinking of her even now?
Let’s go.
To make our dreams come true.
Shooting Ray
Why are you...
Why are you doing this?
What’s making you do this now, at a time like this?
If you’re after something, tell us!
If it’s nothing bad, we may be able to help you!
Fried!
Caro!
Strada!
Jet
Düsen
Sir, it’s them.
Are you a knight of the Bureau?
First Lieutenant Signum, with the Main Office’s Riot Force 6.
Formerly of the Capital Defense Corps,
which means you have seniority over me.
Is that so?
Are you going to destroy Central Command?
I’m just going to see my old friend, Regius.
Is that for revenge?
It’s not something that can be put into words.
I’ll ask you to let me pass.
If you don’t put it into words, I won’t allow you through.
Agito, is something wrong?
N-Nothing!
Babbling isn’t how knights do things!
Knights or not, this means we’re fighting for pride instead of talking!
Shut up, cross midget!
I, Agito the Sword Faerie, for justice and
my friend Zest, come forth with flames in my hand!
I, Reinforce Zwei, the Wind of Blessing,
will stop you in the name of the Bureau!
Here we go.
Ginny.
It’d hurt Ginny, so I won’t use Oscillating Breaker.
What I’m after isn’t to destroy or wound her, but to knock her out with magical damage.
I’ve never had a real fight with Ginny.
But I’ll save you!
I’m almost there.
I’ve still got cartridges.
I’m fine.
It’ll be easy.
So it was your kind who took out Nanoha back then?
No more miss nice girl.
Every single last one of you, I’ll...
...destroy you all!
The Cradle will reach
orbit in
2 hours
2 hours and 16 minutes
Etched into this amulet, these precious times
In my precious days
“The bluebird ran away”
I cried, embracing the empty cage
I still remember the color of the high-rising sky
That I looked up at that day
Rewinding
Inside my memories
In painful times, in happy times
You were always there at important times
The thing which I looked for to the ends of the labyrinth
Is deep within my heart
Etched into this amulet, these precious times
Soft and secret pieces of my memory
No matter what type of tomorrow it is, I can walk towards it
In my precious days
Next
Episode
Preview
Next
Episode
Preview
The battles continue,
and soldiers get hurt.
Pain that we face, and pain that we can’t.
An unerasable past, and each of their scars.
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS:
Episode 22: Pain to Pain
Episode 22
Take off.