Combat cyborgs.
Research that greatly increased combat ability by allowing machines to fuse with a body.
But due to many issues, including those of ethics and feasibility, the research was heavily criticized.
So the research was stopped.
And it was soon deemed that research of that sort was taboo.
In the current case investigated by Riot Force 6,
combat cyborgs made an appearance.
We’ve made a request for further help in the investigation.
The Combat Cyborg Incident is one which holds a special meaning to my family.
This is Ginga Nakajima with the 108th Battalion.
The hot comet dwelling within my heart beats towards the beginning.
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
My fingers tremble, grasping upon a silent wish
I cower, wanting to flee from the inescapable past
Even if it is merely a faint light fading
I want to chase after it, just like that star
And accept everything, no matter how high it is
An angel’s whisper dancing throughout the galaxy
Pursuing these certain memories
The door to the truth will surely be born now
No matter what kind of cold darkness binds me
Because I want to know
I won’t be stopped
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Well then, before we practice this morning, there’s one thing I’d like to announce.
Today, Sergeant Ginga Nakajima from the 108th Battalion will be temporarily stationed with Riot Force 6.
Yes, ma’am.
I’m Sergeant Ginga Nakajima from the 108th Battalion.
I am honored to be working with you.
The honor is ours.
And one more.
Nice to meet you.
She’s been working on our captains’ Devices
for the past ten years,
and she’s the head of Precision Engineering, part of the Main Office’s Technical Department.
I’m Mariel Atenza.
She seems to have some business on the surface, so she’ll be staying with Riot Force 6 for a bit.
It also looks like she’ll perform maintenance for your Devices.
Call me anytime, okay?
Yes, ma’am.
All right!
Now that introductions are over,
shall we get going with this morning’s practice?
Yes, ma’am!
Lightning, gather here.
Teana, you’re with me today.
Yes, ma’am.
Today is part six on how to decide
which attack pattern to use.
Please go ahead.
Ginga.
Ma’am?
I want you to check up on Subaru’s skills a bit.
Oh, yes, ma’am.
A light mock battle, one-on-one.
I want you to see how much Subaru’s grown.
Yes, ma’am!
Episode 15
Storm Tooth
Protection
I see.
Not bad.
Agreed.
Both of them are doing pretty well.
Revolver...
Defenser
...Cannon
Buddy!
Gear 2nd
Wingroad
It’s almost like...
Subaru and Ginga
look like they’re having fun.
It’s because Subaru loves her sister, right?
Ginga loves Subaru, as well.
Subaru’s improved quite considerably.
Ever since she joined, it’s because we’ve been monitoring her close-range combat basics.
Nanoha and I have been bringing down the pain
on her every single damn day.
At least that much.
Okay! That’s it.
Subaru, you were close!
That’s great! You’ve gotten a lot better.
I still have a long way to go.
Your responses weren’t bad.
So you lost in speed, eh?
Thank you, ma’am.
During the last attack,
what would you have done, Erio?
Well, I guess...
Ginga, what did you think about Subaru’s growth?
I was surprised.
Our exchange of blows was rather smooth.
The difference in her power is astounding.
Did she pass?
Yes, ma’am!
By far.
You’ll both be in the same unit for a while.
So try your best together.
Yes, ma’am!
Okay, everyone, gather around.
It’s sudden, but why don’t we try a team battle with Ginga?
The five forwards against
a four-person team of the captains.
You know Ginny, this happens from time to time.
The captains will come at you quite seriously.
First, you use your knowledge of the area
and illusionary magic to run from place to place,
and if by some chance you’re able to land a blow on them, they’re out.
Ginga, you attack using your Device like Subaru, right?
The left knuckle is the one that attacks.
Yes, ma’am.
Then let’s go at it.
Yes, ma’am!
Aina, I’m done!
Okay, you’ve done well.
Wait just a second.
We have to make you really cute for when you go meet your mothers, don’t we?
Okay.
We’ll end with this today.
Everyone release your protective clothing.
Yes, ma’am.
You guys were close.
If only you pushed a bit harder.
We could have caused an upset if the last shift went well!
How frustrating!
I guess I wasn’t able to keep up.
Sorry.
No.
Not at all, Ginga.
Put together a report reflecting on
the battle while you’re still disappointed.
Yes, ma’am.
After you’ve rested a bit, let’s cool down and finish up.
Good work.
Thank you, ma’am!
Amazing!
You guys do this every morning?
A battle with the captains, well, might be a bit special, but...
This is pretty normal for us.
They need to push us right to our limits so that we’ll be okay if we’re deployed.
It’s rather tough.
And after practicing, we eat a lot,
rest up, and then we’re completely restored.
I see.
They all seem like nice kids.
You mean Erio and everyone else,
or do you mean their Devices?
Both.
Good morning.
Morning, Vivio.
Excuse me.
Yeah, thank you.
Don’t fall, all right?
Hey, Zafira!
It’s been a while.
Shari, who’s that girl?
She’s...
Mama!
Vivio!
It’s dangerous.
Don’t fall, okay?
Oh no!
It’s okay.
The ground is soft, and she fell cleanly.
She’s not hurt.
That might be true, but...
Vivio, are you okay?
You’re not hurt, right?
Try your best to stand on your own.
Mama.
Mama Nanoha is right here for you.
Come on.
Nanoha, you can’t. Vivio’s still small and all.
Mama Fate.
Be careful.
If you got hurt, Vivio,
Mama Nanoha and Mama Fate would cry.
I’m sorry.
Geez.
Mama Fate, you’re spoiling her a bit.
Mama Nanoha, you’re just too strict.
Vivio, try your best next time, okay?
Something like that.
Oh, in other words, she’s their chil—
Come on, Vivio.
Vivio, your hair is cute.
It’s Mama Nanoha’s ribbon.
Aina did it for you, didn’t she?
Yep!
It’s nice, Vivio.
I see. So she’s their foster child.
Kind of like me.
Nanoha is her legal guardian.
Fate is her godmother.
I see.
Chew properly, okay?
Children sure do switch between crying and laughing in an instant.
Subaru was like that too when she was a kid.
That’s! Is that so?
Rein too.
Rein was an adult from the beginning.
Liar.
On the outside maybe,
but on the inside you were just like a baby.
Aww... Hayate, that’s not true, is it?
I wonder.
Vivio, that’s not good.
You can’t leave your green pepper there.
I hate bitter things.
They’re good!
If you don’t eat properly, you won’t get bigger.
You know, if you’re too picky, you won’t become beautiful like your moms.
What are you going to do?
Eat.
Sorry about this, but I’ll be borrowing Ginga and Subaru for a bit.
Sure. Please look after them.
Subaru and Ginga will be going out
with Chief Engineer Mariel?
It’s their normal physical.
At the Cranagan Medical Center.
I think this should be all of them.
Well, if we can’t find them
we’ll go out and look for them ourselves.
Hurry up and go.
Sorry about that.
Thanks.
Oh yeah, Subaru?
You know, those things you bought
for me when you had those medical exams?
Oh yeah, the Chocopods?
Yeah, that’s it.
I’ll pay as well, so buy some for the captains and the little ones.
Roger.
We’ve found no damaging information from the investigation into Riot Force 6.
I see.
There’s not much time before the press conference.
We need to get harder evidence to use for the negotiations.
I’ll continue to have our investigation unit look into it.
Even so, the Main Office’s investigation unit,
as well as a certain unit, seem to be investigating us.
The usual, and you should deal with them as usual.
Within the Main Office’s inspection unit,
there is a troublesome officer with a rather Rare Skill.
If he gets serious, there’s a possibility that he might be able to dig up quite a bit.
How despicable!
This is all necessary.
For everyone else to realize that, time and results are needed.
You won’t get support from the High Council?
I’ll ask them.
How is Einherjar doing?
The final check on Unit 3 is running late,
but it’s proceeding smoothly.
Don’t fall behind!
Make it happen before the press conference.
I have plans to do an investigation after this.
Einherjar, huh?
What do you think?
Ma’am.
I believe it’s the hope of the surface world.
With that, we will be able to protect the safety and peace of the surface
without relying on anyone with Rare Skills, or the Main Office’s interdimensional navigation fleet.
That may be.
Whether it’s that other plan, or Einherjar, I can’t help but think they’re too powerful.
Because it’s the path he’s chosen.
Yes, ma’am!
That’s the end of my report.
Time-Space Administrative Bureau High Council Central Meeting Room
The Church, as well as the senior staff
of the Main Office, seem to be plotting something.
Member, High Council
The Three Admirals? It should be fine to ignore them.
Recorder of same
That’s right.
President of same
They no longer control anybody or the world.
I shall leave the press conference to you.
Do as you have up until now.
Roger.
Yes, we can continue to act as we have.
There will be no problems.
Capital City of Cranagan, High-Tech Medical Center
You two, I know you’ve been working hard lately,
but do you feel any discomfort anywhere?
None!
I’m feeling great!
Ditto.
That’s great.
In that case, let’s begin the periodic physical scan.
Okay.
Uno, you’re great.
How’s your new body?
Of course, it’s nice.
It’s the result of your movement data, in the flesh.
All of our little sisters are coming along nicely.
Number VII, Sette.
Number VIII, Otto.
Even Number XII, Deed.
Their base and I.S. movements have been completed.
Number IX, Nove, and Number XI, Wendi, have their personal armaments completed.
Number II, Due, and Number V, Cinque,
are already running a mission.
A nice pace.
Our scrap-iron comrades have easily passed the planned production output.
Were these called Gadget Ddrones?
That’s what the losers at the Bureau called them.
And I heard eventually the Doctor and Uno began calling them that.
How irresponsible.
Who cares, it’s just a name.
Our names are just numbers too.
I like them quite a bit: our numbers and the names of our powers.
How pointless.
The day of the festival draws near.
I’m sure you guys are excited too.
My weapons are finished...
I want some fights and explosions.
You guys have the most marvelous power.
Perfect for getting rowdy.
You heard him.
Aren’t you excited, Nove?
Not really.
I just have something I want to confirm.
Just what type of person our leader is.
Just if he really is someone proper to stand above us.
Well, I don’t really understand. I guess it’ll come to me soon.
That’s right.
While the preparations are finishing up,
why don’t we shoot off one rather large firework?
Without a doubt, this will be one hell of an event.
Here you go. Sorry for making you wait.
Thank you very much.
Oh yeah, and I’ll need three more ready-to-eat portions.
Sure, I’ll bring those right out.
Ginny, sorry for making you wait.
It’s okay.
You sure bought a bunch today, didn’t you?
Some for everyone.
Ginny, say “ah.”
Here.
It’s good.
But Subaru, you and Teana are so lively in Riot Force 6.
It’s really nice.
Well, sometimes a lot happens, and it gets a bit tough.
But I’m glad I got invited in.
Besides being with your best friend,
you get to be in the same unit as your hero.
Ginny, you’re my role model too, you know.
To get stronger and someday pass you.
You won’t be able to pass me that easily.
Because I’m going to get stronger too.
Well, I’m trying my best.
Subaru.
After this, we’re most likely going into battle with the combat cyborgs.
Let’s do our best.
It’ll be okay.
We have the Revolver Knuckle our mother left behind for us,
and right now we have our Calibers with us.
Calibers?
Mach and Blitz Calibers.
Mach Caliber, this is your little sister, Blitz.
Sorry for making you wait.
Oh, Marie, would you like a Chocopod?
Sure, I’ll take one!
It’s good!
Isn’t it?
Here you go.
Open up.
I received the latest prophecy interpretation from the Church today.
It seems the chance that the press conference
will be targeted is rather high.
Of course, security will be as strict and good as ever.
They’ll have Riot Force 6 protect the attendees.
Really, it’d be great if we could all protect the perimeter,
but it seems that only the three of us will be allowed to enter the building.
Well, with the three of us together, we’ll figure something out.
The front-line soldiers will do fine.
We’ve trained them hard.
The lieutenants are in as good a shape as ever.
We’ll be raising everyone’s Device limiters to the third level tomorrow as well.
If we can hold this place down,
I believe we’ll turn this situation around quickly.
It will definitely be all right.
Time-Space Administrative Bureau Surface Headquarters
Press Conference
In 7 days
Etched into this amulet, these precious times
In my precious days
“The bluebird ran away”
I cried, embracing the empty cage
I still remember the color of the high-rising sky
That I looked up at that day
Rewinding
Inside my memories
In painful times, in happy times
You were always there at important times
The thing which I looked for to the ends of the labyrinth
Is deep within my heart
Etched into this amulet, these precious times
Soft and secret pieces of my memory
No matter what type of tomorrow it is, I can walk towards it
In my precious days
Next
Episode
Preview
Next
Episode
Preview
We head to protect Surface HQ,
and the members of Riot Force 6
see us off at the base.
The attack comes silently at first, then abruptly.
Next episode of
Magical Girl Nanoha StrikerS:
Episode 16
That Day, Riot Force 6
(part 1)
Episode 16: That Day, Riot Force 6 (part 1)
Take off!