What we searched for was the meaning behind courage.
We couldn’t see the present,
and instead we ran away to our dreams and the future.
When I couldn’t do anything and kept hurting things.
When I couldn’t do anything but hang my head.
What we were taught was
the heart and power to face these things.
That which we can do now.
So that we can protect what’s important to us...
We will focus on what’s ahead of us.
So that this incident doesn’t end in regrets and tears,
we will go and save you right now.
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
The things that I can do for you and no one else
I honestly feel and wish for those
I am frozen by uncertainties
By the rules I have been relying on
My past embellished with excuses
I want to get over it
Staining the stars in heaven scarlet
Gather the grains of miracles
Before the still, unseen night
I want to tell you that I am escaping from illusions
The twilight moon calls out to me
Removing my veil of delusions
My hidden, deceitful self
And took all of my weaknesses
I don’t want words that seem passionate
The fact that I’m here right now is my truth
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
The fleet is in position.
We’re ready to attack.
Nanoha.
Fate.
Hayate.
Please hurry and escape.
Episode 26
To the Promised Sky
It’s impossible.
I can’t gather any mana!
Comms are down too!
Looks like we have no choice but to escape on foot.
But Nanoha is...
I’m fine. I can walk.
Mama.
All hands to your stations. Repeat, all hands to your stations.
Alle Mann, auf seine Position. Ich wiederhole. Alle Mann, auf seine Position.
Commencing emergency repair of damaged areas.
Wir beginnen die Notregeneration des Beschädigungsschiffs.
Please step away from any damaged walls
Entfernen Sie sich von der Beschädigungsmauer
or emergency barriers.
sowie vom Notverschlag.
Let’s hurry to the exit.
I’ll leave her in your custody.
Yes, Sister.
I’ll go save Enforcer Fate.
Schach.
You can’t go with those wounds.
I’ll go instead.
But...!
Please wait.
I think I’ll be able to escape on my own.
Besides, if we don’t stop the collapse...
All the people in these pods might still be alive.
We can’t let them die in the collapse.
But...!
I’ll stop it!
Shari!
Yes, Fate.
I will head to the sky.
Agito, what will you do?
Y-You killed him!
But you gave him his last moment of honor as a knight.
He entrusted me to you.
So, I will go with you.
I will stay by your side and watch you.
If by chance you betray what he was saying...
If that were to happen,
I wish for you to kill me with your flame.
Unison in!
T-That’s...!
Sergeant Vice!
Listen up.
It seems that the further into the ship you go,
the stronger the A.M.F. becomes.
We’ll get you close enough that a Wingroad will reach.
Break through with that, and pick up the officers!
Yes, sir!
Let’s go, Storm Raider.
I told you before, I’m not an ace, nor am I an expert.
I got frightened in an incident that a relative was involved in and fired a shot I couldn’t take back.
I felt so pathetic that I thought I’d die.
But you know, I’m at least good enough
to create a path for my reckless, rash subordinates.
Variable Barret
Okay, go!
Yes, sir!
Wingroad
Go!
The smaller aerial units are descending to the ground!
Are there any aerial mages?
At this current point in time,
the only mages who can act are...
There’s one!
Riot Force 6, Lightning 2, First Lieutenant Signum.
That voice... is that you, Lucino?
Yes, ma’am.
Huh? Lt. Signum, you look...
A strong ally came with me.
I’ll intercept them from my current position.
Understood.
Forty-eight of them and counting.
Can you do it, Agito?
I can.
Flame on!
Raging Fire Sword
Lævateinn.
Snake Form
Schlangenform
The blazing flash of my sword!
Firebreathing...
...Swordflash
F-Fifty units have been wiped out all at once!
I wonder why, Agito.
When I’m in Unison with you,
my heart strangely feels warm.
Agito?
It’s nothing!
Nothing!
At distance 450, a second formation incoming.
Got it. Let’s go, Agito!
Right, Signum!
Erio. Fried.
Voltaire and I will help the G.A.S.
Got it.
Kerykeion, give Erio and Fried a speed boost. Full Drive!
Boost Up
You’re overdoing it, Second Lieutenant Vita!
Shut up!
Lt. Vita, we’re glad you’re okay.
We’re going to rescue Nanoha and Commander Yagami!
We’re off!
They’re...
Those girls.
I can’t gather any mana at all.
But if I’m in combat cyborg mode, I can shoot and run.
The two of us together will rescue them and return.
Yeah!
Data analyzed. Passcode cracked.
Fate!
Done.
It stopped.
Yes, ma’am.
Sonic Move
Erio?
Yes, ma’am.
I chose this path the day I started looking up to Nanoha.
This sound...
No way!
Way.
Subaru.
Mom,
Ginny,
lend me your power for just a bit.
Sorry for making you wait!
We’re here to save you!
Tremors have ceased at Scaglietti’s HQ.
Escape has been confirmed for the Assault Team,
as well as Lightning 1 and Lightning 3.
The mages which had infiltrated the Cradle,
units 1 through 4, have escaped the scene.
The Riot Force 6 members in the deepest areas...
We have confirmed their escape.
So it’s our job from this point on.
Yes, sir.
The Cradle has been shot down.
Mission complete.
We did it! We really did it!
Shari, just for a second...
Everyone, good job.
And so ended the case that started as the Relic Incident.
It was long after this incident,
which involved many people and things, had ended
that it came to be called the Jail Scaglietti Incident,
or simply the J.S. Incident.
3 months after the J.S. Incident
Scaglietti, who had been arrested, and the combat cyborgs who didn’t show interest in helping with the investigation
are on various planets in orbital detention facilities.
Those who recognized their crimes
and seemed like they would help with the investigation
are in a maritime quarantine facility on Mid.
The two whom the Lightning squad protected, Lutecia and Agito, decided to stay there on their own.
Still, I think you guys can leave soon.
Your psych eval showed that you were not liable due to lack of control.
But besides that, there are a lot of other factors.
It didn’t seem like Agito had to come.
I was worried about Lulu.
And on top of that, after this, I’ll have to do my part.
Oh yeah, Miss Lu, how’s your mother?
She’s sleeping at the hospital.
They said if they treat her, even without a Relic, she’ll wake up eventually.
Peace had come to Mid’s surface once more,
and repairs to the Riot Force 6 HQ have been completed.
All members have returned to their posts.
Vivio has returned after being examined in protective custody for a short period and is living peacefully with her mamas.
But Hayate, since the incident, you’ve been pretty quiet.
Has fatigue finally set in?
I heard from Signum concerning Lt. General Regius.
It’s kind of like, you know, his thoughts were just like mine.
I wanted to protect because I had lost many things, and due to that, I became frantic to do so and ended up overdoing it.
No matter what type of feelings or thoughts you have,
if they get too strong, they’ll sabotage everything.
And the more time you spend on them,
the more you lose them, and the more moot it becomes.
But if we rush too much to find an answer,
only pain will result.
But you know, with colleagues like you,
I feel like I’m the youngest child in the family.
So you’ve finally realized?
You’re still a kid.
So, have you decided on the future of the kids in your unit?
Well, for the most part.
That’s right. It’s been a year since
Riot Force 6’s probationary operation period began.
When spring comes, we’ll be graduating.
Thanks to the data you brought back, we were able to clean up the Combat Cyborg Incident very nicely.
My wife, as well as the rest of the people
in Zest’s team, will finally be able to rest in peace.
April 28, 0076
Riot Force 6 Headquarters
And then...
It’s been a year, though it felt like much longer,
so Riot Force 6 will disperse, having completed its mission.
I am truly happy from the bottom of my heart,
having worked and fought alongside all of you.
I pray that you all fare well
in your next unit and that you do to your best there.
It kind of seems like it ended pretty quick.
Doesn’t it?
Well, after this, I hear there’s a farewell party.
Subaru doesn’t seem too happy.
Well, she’s leaving Nanoha,
and Tia won’t be with her in her next assignment.
Hey, everyone! Wait up!
Nanoha.
Ginny too.
Before the farewell party,
we’d like to see all the forward members.
These flowers, they’re...
Yes, they’re flowers from the world Nanoha and I are from.
They’re flowers that represent a farewell and the beginning of a new season.
Okay, forwards, line up!
Yes, ma’am!
Okay, first of all, you four have done a great job
on your missions and training this year.
This past year, I haven’t praised you much, but...
...you guys have gotten pretty strong.
You’ve had tough training, were put in hard spots,
and had difficult missions.
But you’ve tried your best
and gotten past all of them without fail.
All of you have really gotten stronger.
The four of you are already great strikers.
Ach, don’t cry, you idiots.
Yes, ma’am.
Well then, since you’re finally graduating,
and the cherry blossoms are in full bloom,
let’s not be gloomy.
Yes.
You’ve brought your partners with you, right?
What is it?
You didn’t hear?
Full power, without holding back, Riot Force 6’s last mock battle!
Yes, ma’am!
I didn’t hear about us not holding back!
Well, let us go at it anyway.
This is a memory too.
Aw... Vita, Nanoha.
Don’t be so stiff.
We finally got our limiters taken off, after all.
There’s nothing to worry about. They’re all strong, after all.
Mama Fate, it’s okay.
Full power!
They all seem like they’ll enjoy it.
Let’s do our best!
Fate, please!
Please try your best to win!
Aw, man...
Try your best!
Etched into this amulet, these precious times
Well then.
In my precious days
Ready!
Go!
“The bluebird ran away”
Lt. Colonel Hayate Yagami
She returns to being a Special Investigator.
Settling down on the surface, she is in charge
of investigating smuggling and criminal mages.
Lt. Colonel Hayate Yagami
She returns to being a Special Investigator.
Settling down on the surface, she is in charge
of investigating smuggling and criminal mages.
I cried, embracing the empty cage
I still remember the color of the high-rising sky
That I looked up at that day
She discharges her duties
alongside her guardian knights
Rewinding
Enforcer Fate T. Harlaown
She returns to duty in the Dimensional Navy,
along with her assistant, Shario Finieno
Enforcer Fate T. Harlaown
She returns to duty in the Dimensional Navy,
along with her assistant, Shario Finieno
Inside my memories
Assistant Enforcer Teana Lanster
In painful times, in happy times
She’s undergoing her residency
to become an Enforcer, as Fate’s second assistant
You were always there at important times
She is progressing toward her dream
The thing which I looked for to the ends of the labyrinth
Is deep within my heart
Etched into this amulet, these precious times
Lutecia Alpine
After having a large seal placed on
her magic, she was quarantined to
an uninhabited planet as a form of probation
After having a large seal placed on
her magic, she was quarantined to
an uninhabited planet as a form of probation
Soft and secret pieces of my memory
No matter what type of tomorrow it is, I can walk towards it
She’s spending the long isolation period quietly,
with her mother and her summons
In my precious days
Specialist Alto Krauetta
Officially becomes a helicopter pilot at Surface HQ
Sergeant Major Vice Granscénic
Surface HQ helicopter pilot.
Reacquired the armed operative permit he surrendered.
Sergeant Major Vice Granscénic
Surface HQ helicopter pilot.
Reacquired the armed operative permit he surrendered.
He’s returning to the path of being a pilot/sniper
Connected by a silver chain
Administrator Griffith Lowran
Transfers to the Dimensional Navy.
He handles administrative matters aboard his ship.
Administrator Griffith Lowran
Transfers to the Dimensional Navy.
He handles administrative matters aboard his ship.
This old, lonely melody
Assistant Administrator-cum-
Helmsman Trainee Lucino Liilie
Serves as an assistant to Griffith
while working towards becoming
a ship’s navigator
Serves as an assistant to Griffith
while working towards becoming
a ship’s navigator
That day I got lost deep in that forest
You quietly left me there
Private First Class Caro Ru Lushe
Returns to her former position
in the Frontier Nature Conservation Corps
Private First Class Caro Ru Lushe
Returns to her former position
in the Frontier Nature Conservation Corps
Just by the fact that you’re alive
Private First Class Erio Mondial
Requests and is granted a transfer
to the Frontier Nature Conservation Corps
Private First Class Erio Mondial
Requests and is granted a transfer
to the Frontier Nature Conservation Corps
As a dragon knight and a dragon summoner, the two work together
as Nature Conservators, working to defeat poachers
I’ll always be able to become stronger
Your whispers are always sweet melodies
The thing which I looked for to the ends of the labyrinth,
Vivio Takamachi
Requests and is accepted into
a magic academy run by the Church of the Holy King
Vivio Takamachi
Requests and is accepted into
a magic academy run by the Church of the Holy King
Is right here
That sparkling amulet that only belongs to me
Watched over by her mother and her mother’s friends,
she lives the life of a normal girl
Soft and secretive pieces of my memory
Even on nights I feel as if I were to cry, you still give me strength
Warrant Officer Ginga Nakajima
On the advice of all concerned parties, she’s conducting
a reformation program for the combat cyborgs
In my precious days
The program is progressing well
Specialist Subaru Nakajima
Changed positions at her own request
Someone!
Save me!
Protection
You’ve tried your best. That’s great.
As part of Disaster Response,
she works as the top forward for
the Special Rescue Unit on the front lines
As part of Disaster Response,
she works as the top forward for
the Special Rescue Unit on the front lines
It’s okay now.
I’ll take you straight to a safe place.
She continually saves the lives of those struck by disaster
The thing which I looked for to the ends of the labyrinth
Is right here
Those days which I ran by are engraved on this amulet
For the next three weeks, I’ll be in charge of training you all.
Soft and secretive pieces of my memory
I’m Captain Nanoha Takamachi.
Captain Nanoha Takamachi
She declined a promotion for
her meritorious service in the J.S. Incident
Captain Nanoha Takamachi
She declined a promotion for
her meritorious service in the J.S. Incident
No matter what type of tomorrow it is, I can walk towards it
The training will be a bit tough, but stick with it, okay?
In my precious days
Yes, ma’am!
She stays on the front lines
as a tactical combat instructor and aerial mage,
continuing to protect and raise the next generation
She stays on the front lines
as a tactical combat instructor and aerial mage,
continuing to protect and raise the next generation
Okay, so let’s go at it!
Yes, ma’am!
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha