Our meeting was just chance,
and at first, I didn’t know anything.
But when I saw you crying
in front of me, for some reason, I felt sad.
And it tore my heart in two when you clutched at me and yelled, “Don’t go!”
And when you smile, I’m so happy.
I can’t put it into words, but you mean the world to me.
I didn’t keep my promise.
I will definitely keep it this time.
So just wait a bit longer.
Mama will save you!
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
The things that I can do for you and no one else
I honestly feel and wish for those
I am frozen by uncertainties
By the rules I have been relying on
My past embellished with excuses
I want to get over it
Staining the stars in heaven scarlet
Gather the grains of miracles
Before the still, unseen night
I want to tell you that I am escaping from illusions
The twilight moon calls out to me
Removing my veil of delusions
My hidden, deceitful self
And took all of my weaknesses
I don’t want words that seem passionate
The fact that I’m here right now is my truth
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Are you okay, Eisen?
No problem.
Kein Problem.
Nanoha must be in the throne room by now.
Yes.
Ja.
And Hayate’s fighting outside, waiting for the ship to stop.
Correct.
Richtig.
I’m going to smash this thing into pieces and stop the ship.
You can do our Limit Break, right?
Roger.
Jawohl.
Obliteration Form
Zerstörungsform
Obliteration...
Zerstörungs...
...Hammer
Mana signature detected.
Eine magische Reaktion wurde ausfindig gemacht.
Engaging defense mode.
Wir gehen in die Verteidigungssituation ein.
Anything that approaches the engine room
Alles, was sich in dem generator annährt,
will be immediately attacked.
wird unbedingt bedigungslos angegriffen.
Bring it on!
Forty-five minutes until the Dimensional Navy arrives.
Thirty-eight minutes until the Cradle reaches its destination.
A seven-minute gap.
The Cradle’s main cannon
is pointed directly at Mid’s capital.
Seven minutes is enough...
...to fire the cannon, yeah.
Maintain present defense line!
Someone take over command for me!
I’m going in!
I can’t let it reach orbit. I can’t let it attack the surface.
Commander Yagami!
But...
Excuse me! This is Long Arch 3.
Alto?
Commander Yagami, wait just a little longer.
I have an important item for you!
Episode 25
Final Limit
Vivio.
Don’t say my name!
Chain Bind
This stuff...
...won’t work!
Round Shield
W.A.S.: Area 2 complete, beginning Area 3.
This will take some time.
Blaster 2
Blaster 2nd
Blaster Bit: Crystal Cage
Lock!
I already know this trick!
I thought so!
Your Majesty, keep making that devil use her power-up.
That “Blaster” system is an experimental booster that far surpasses the physical limits of the user’s body.
Every shot fired and every blow blocked
whittles away at her life and the life of her Device.
For a special move that just kicks the crap out of everything, it’s almost unbeatable.
It’s quite powerful.
But it’s useless in this situation.
They’re crying!
They don’t know what to do.
Jirai-Oh, don’t!
Galue.
Caro, take Lu and head up!
We’ll stop Jirai-Oh and the others!
You’re coming with me.
I refuse.
I must go save Lutecia and stop Scaglietti.
Scaglietti and the combat cyborgs have already been captured,
and my men are moving to secure Lutecia Alpine.
Is that so?
Then, there’s only one thing left for me to do.
Sir, why?
Be quiet!
I was supposed to dream and gaze at the future,
but before I knew it, I stepped off the path.
To protect what you must truly protect
is all there is to it, but that’s truly difficult.
Glittering Swordflash
Sir!
That mini-knight in the engine room.
Crap.
Why?
Why isn’t it working?
If I don’t destroy it, it’ll hurt everybody!
I won’t be able to protect
Hayate and Nanoha!
If I can’t break through that shielding, there’s no point!
So then, Eisen!
Roger!
Jawohl!
Rest in pieces!
It didn’t work.
I couldn’t protect them.
Hayate...
Everyone...
Sorry.
There’s nothing for you to apologize for.
Hayate.
Rein.
Yeppers.
Vita, Knight of the Steel Hammer, and Graf Eisen
fought valiantly until they ended up like this.
There’s nothing in the worlds...
...they cannot destroy.
The engine.
They’re sealing the hallways?
Rossa!
Feels like they’re going to activate a self-destruct device or something.
What is this?
Quattro has decided to abandon this base, it seems.
Stop her.
You’ll die with it.
I told you, my copy is inside of her.
There’s no longer a use for this body.
Defense systems at full power.
Reserve engine activated.
Self-repair systems in effect.
We’re not finished yet.
That’s...!
Wide Area Search successful.
Coordinates are specific. Distance calculated.
Found you!
Area Search?
No way! She’s been looking for me this whole time?
But this is the deepest part of the Cradle!
Nobody could make it all the way down here.
She’s going to just blast through the walls?
No way! Can’t be! Ridiculous!
Clearance confirmation: firing lock is cancelled.
Blaster 3
Divine...
...Buster
The Doctor’s dream... we... will...
The Gadgets have completely stopped.
Same for the other areas.
The Riot Force 6 girls did it?
Vivio?
Vivio!
Mama Nanoha...
No, run!
It won’t work?
I can’t go back?
Engines damaged. Helm unmanned.
Generator beschädigt. Niemand die Kontrollposition.
The Holy King has lost the will to fight.
Heiliger Kaiser verliert Kampfeswille.
Now entering automatic defense mode.
Ab jetzt gehen wir in die Automatikverteidigungssituation ein.
All fighters, scramble!
Jagdflieger, aufbieten!
Eliminate all objects.
Alle objekte wegbekommen.
Let’s go, Rein!
We’ll blow through them and keep going!
Vivio, I’m going to save you.
It’s hopeless!
I can’t stop!
It’s not hopeless!
Stay away.
I know.
I’m a copy of a person from the distant past.
And Nanoha, I know you and and Fate
aren’t my real mamas.
I’m just a key to move this ship.
I’m a living weapon that protects the throne room.
That’s not true!
I never had a mama.
I was just looking for a person who would protect me,
who would let me gather magical data.
That’s not true!
It is!
All my sadness, my pain, they were all fake, created things.
I can’t be allowed to live!
That’s not true!
No matter how you were born, the Vivio that’s there crying isn’t a fake or something that was merely created.
She’s the spoiled girl who cries all the time
and can’t even get up on her own when she trips.
The girl who hates her green peppers,
the girl who gives me headpats
and calls me “good girl” when I’m feeling lonely.
My beloved Vivio.
I’m not your real mama, Vivio,
but I’m going to try my best to be.
So don’t say that you can’t be allowed to live.
Tell Mama your true feelings.
I...
Mama Nanoha...
I love you!
I want to be with you forever, Mama!
Mama.
Save me!
I will.
No matter when, no matter what!
Restrict Lock
Vivio, this might be a bit painful.
I’ll blow her defenses
and knock her out with magical damage.
You can do it, right, Raising Heart?
Clear to go.
Full power!
Starlight...
...Breaker
Break...
...shoot!
Vivio.
Vivio!
Stay back!
I can do it on my own.
I promised I’d be strong.
The Cradle’s speed has dropped!
The rate of ascent has dropped dramatically.
The fleet will get there first!
The seven-minute gap is filled!
Holy King unresponsive. System down.
Heiliger Kaiser, keine Reaktion. Funktionsverlust des Systems.
Nanoha!
Hayate!
Blocking all mana links. Restoring ship functionality.
Alle magische Verbindung wird abgegangen. Die Regeneration des Raumschiffs.
All personnel aboard, enter sleep mode!
Alle Mann am Ort, in ihrer Ruheposition!
Everything I know about the incident is inside here.
I’ll take them.
Can I ask you to take care of Agito and Lutecia?
They’re unfortunate children
who never met the people they were supposed to meet.
Sir!
Agito.
The days I spent with you and Lutecia
really weren’t that bad.
It’s a lovely sky.
It is.
Please continue to watch over
the world that Regius and I
wanted to protect, without faltering.
Sir!
Subaru!
Tia!
The Gadgets are shutting down everywhere.
What happened?
I don’t know.
I’m sure that Nanoha and the others...
Subaru, is Ginga okay?
Yes.
They stopped the ship from going up any further,
but the battle is continuing inside.
We can’t contact Nanoha or the others who went in.
An indoor evacuation and rescue mission...
That’s a ground mage’s job.
Yes, sir.
Subaru.
Ginny.
Take this.
Nanoha.
Etched into this amulet, these precious times
In my precious days
“The bluebird ran away”
I cried, embracing the empty cage
I still remember the color of the high-rising sky
That I looked up at that day
Rewinding
Inside my memories
In painful times, in happy times
You were always there at important times
The thing which I looked for to the ends of the labyrinth
Is deep within my heart
Etched into this amulet, these precious times
Soft and secret pieces of my memory
No matter what type of tomorrow it is, I can walk towards it
In my precious days
Next
Episode
Preview
Next
Episode
Preview
When the case is closed,
and when Riot Force 6’s
mission is complete.
Even when we’re apart, there are things that remain, things we won’t ever forget.
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS:
Final episode: To the Promised Sky
Episode 26
To the Promised Sky
Take off!