The pain of being alone,
and the loneliness of everything being different...
I’m sure everyone knows these things.
Because there was somebody important to me, who shared things with me and supported me,
I am here now.
But without the power of magic, without fighting,
what can I do?
How should I answer those small eyes with nowhere to go?
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS
will now begin.
The hot comet dwelling within my heart beats towards the beginning.
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
My fingers tremble, grasping upon a silent wish
I cower, wanting to flee from the inescapable past
Even if it is merely a faint light fading
I want to chase after it, just like that star
And accept everything, no matter how high it is
An angel’s whisper dancing throughout the galaxy
Pursuing these certain memories
The door to the truth will surely be born now
No matter what kind of cold darkness binds me
Because I want to know
I won’t be stopped
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Episode 14
Okay, everybody come here.
Morning practice is done for the day.
Yes, ma’am!
There were no major problems today...
everything’s looking good.
Keep at it!
Thank you, ma’am!
I guess we’ve finally gotten used to our secondary modes.
Yeah.
It’s not a major change for Caro and I, but it must be hard for Tia and Erio.
The whole form’s changed.
To me it’s nothing.
Dagger Mode is just a backup.
Yes!
It’s Erio’s that’s complicated.
Strada’s secondary is pretty crazy.
You think?
Wirklich?
I think it’s cool, Strada.
Thanks, m’lady.
Danke schön, mein Fräulein.
I’ll continue to train with Strada.
I’ll do my best!
Vivio!
Morning, Vivio.
Did you get yourself up today?
Yep!
Good morning, Fate.
Good morning, Nanoha.
Vivio, say good morning to Nanoha.
Good morning.
You can eat breakfast with us, right?
Breakfast?
That’s right.
Come on, let’s go.
What’s on the menu today, I wonder?
Attention all operatives: would P.F.C. Lanster please report to the commander’s office?
You see, I’m heading to the Main Office today.
And I wanted to know if you’d come with me, Teana.
I see.
The person we’re meeting today is Captain Fate’s brother.
Admiral Chrono Harlaown.
I see.
He’s a ship’s captain and an Enforcer.
I thought it’d be good for your future if you had some experience meeting important people like that.
Thank you, ma’am!
I’d be honored to go with you!
Oh, where’s Teana?
She seems to be accompanying Commander Yagami
to the Main Office or something.
I see.
Are you staying in the office today, Nanoha?
That’s right.
Lightning Squad is out investigating today,
and the lieutenants are off.
You and I are the only
front-line soldiers here today, Subaru.
I’ll pray nothing happens.
By the way, what’s Vivio doing during the day?
She’s staying in her room.
The housekeeper, Aina, is looking after her, and Zafira is on guard.
Did I do it?
I did it!
Oh, that’s great, sweetie!
Thanks!
The Dimensional Sea
Time-Space Administrative Bureau Main Office
Anchor placement location secured.
Dimensional Navy XV-class Battleship Claudia
Initiating standby status.
Begin resupply and inspection.
Everyone who’s free, go and get some rest!
Sir!
Good work, Chrono.
We still have some time until Hayate gets here.
Well, let’s just relax and wait.
Oh, right.
Want some cake?
It’s homemade, but it’s pretty good.
I told you I don’t like sweet things.
It’s not too sweet.
I guess I’ll have some.
Anyway, just like you asked, I secretly looked into the internal situation at Surface HQ,
Especially the people around Lt. General Gaiz.
He’s quite the character, an amazing strong-arm politician.
He’s a powerful force and has an air of authority that draws people to him.
I’ll admit he’s impressive.
The head of administration is his subordinate as well.
Even though there’s no end to the bad rumors about him,
he is the guardian of order on the surface.
And he’s well-supported by various corporations and political groups,
plus he’s in good standing with the Bureau High Council.
He’s definitely somebody who’s hard for the Main Office to deal with.
Yes.
We can’t intervene carelessly, with relations between the ground and naval forces being as they are.
And with relations between Surface HQ and
the Main Office, conflict with every single thing—
Excuse me, Captain Chrono.
Lt. Colonel Hayate Yagami is here.
Hayate.
Welcome to the Claudia.
It’s quite the ship. Just as I imagined one of the latest ships would be like...
I guess.
I heard you underwent a special inspection.
Did it go well?
Yes, we managed to avoid an immediate hearing.
Oh, right.
I’ll introduce you. This is the leader of
the forwards... she wants to become an Enforcer.
Private First Class Teana Lanster.
Hello.
Nice to meetcha.
Thanks.
Have a seat.
No, I’ll stand here.
You told the front-line soldiers everything?
Not about the prophecy.
You want some too, right?
But that Surface HQ might be attacked.
No, I’m fine.
I see.
A terrorist attack on Surface HQ?
It’s possible, that’s all.
But, if you think about it,
The magic defenses at HQ facilities are impressive,
but if they use the Gadgets...
Yes.
The Bureau generally forbids the use of mass-based weapons, so it would be hard to deal with them.
Mass-based weapons?
I guess you could say they’re
physical weapons that don’t use magic, maybe.
They fire physical matter that strikes the enemy or explodes.
Historically, Midchilda made heavy use of
those weapons during wartime, as did Ancient Belka.
I’ve heard of them. Once they’re made,
even a kid can use them.
And that moving a finger could destroy a town or an entire world.
Yes.
Ever since its founding, the Bureau
has rooted out those weapons
and started to regulate the use of Lost Logia
for peace and safety.
That was about 150 years ago.
But weapons are needed for a variety of reasons.
Now then, what did we do?
Being both relatively clean and safe, we encouraged society towards magic.
That’s right.
The Bureau’s effective use of magic is what enabled it to manage the various worlds.
They established their Main Office
in the Dimensional Sea where all the worlds float.
And on their homeworld, Midchilda, they built Surface HQ.
Oh! That was the beginning of the New Calendar, 75 years ago.
Yes.
And who was it that saw the Bureau through the beginning of the New Calendar,
when things were most chaotic,
and brought peace to the worlds?
The renowned Three Admirals.
I see.
But let’s put worlds history aside for now...
I’m sorry.
What I’m saying here is that if it looks like the Gadgets are going to appear,
Riot Force 6 will go into action
even if it has nothing to do with the Relics.
Do your best, okay?
Yes, ma’am!
We’ve gotten pretty used to fighting Gadgets... it’ll be okay.
To be honest, I wanted Erio and Caro
to go down a more peaceful path.
Yes, it’s true that the information comes from an unreliable source,
but everyone says the notion that
the Bureau might be destroyed is absurd.
Even if Surface HQ did fall to terrorism or a coup d’etat,
nobody’s willing to believe that
the Main Office could be taken down with it.
Well, the Bureau is enhancing its defenses.
The problem is Surface HQ.
Lt. General Gaiz refuses to believe the prophecy.
He’s not taking any special precautions.
It’s difficult for different organizations to cooperate.
If “cooperation” is recast as “interfering with our internal affairs” or “meddling”, then it becomes a matter of dispute.
And even without that, the military power and influence of Surface HQ has on Mid has been considered a problem.
Therefore, you couldn’t offer any major help that would be noticed in terms of military forces.
I’m sorry.
I’d like to keep political problems away from the front lines.
Even if it’s cheating, you would need a force
that could act freely on the surface.
If it all that happens is we have a Relic Incident, that’s fine.
And if things get worse, we’d need somebody who could watch the situation up close...
And until Surface HQ starts to take things seriously
or the Bureau and the Church
send their own forces in to keep things stable.
That’s what Riot Force 6 is for.
Of course, we won’t cause any trouble for you outside your missions.
Don’t worry about it.
We’ve received a firm promise from
Lt. Colonel Yagami that she’ll take care of her staff.
Yes.
Once again, as a knight with the Church of
the Holy King’s Church Knights, I, Carim Gracia, ask you.
It will be an inglorious and dangerous mission,
but will you help us?
We can’t do much, but we’ll do all we can.
We accept.
The safety and peace of the land and sea...
The future and security of everyone in the unit, including these children...
Hayate’s position...
And the sky where Nanoha flies...
It’ll be hard to protect them all,
but I will do my best.
Lend me a hand, Bardiche.
Okay!
Nanoha?
Hey, Nanoha?
Huh... wha... sorry.
What?
Nothing really, I just wanted to let you know
that you finished the data set.
Oh... you’re right.
I need to pay attention.
Not at all.
It’s lunch time.
I’m going back to the dorms and eating with Vivio.
Would you come with me, Subaru?
Yes.
I’ll go with you.
But what’s going to happen to Vivio now?
If we find a family who’ll accept her, that’d be the best.
That’s hard.
She’s not normal, after all.
That’s true.
I think it’ll take time to find one.
So, for now, I think it would be best if I looked after her.
I’m thinking of being her guardian, like Captain Fate is to Erio and Caro.
That’s a great idea!
I’m sure Vivio will be happy.
Happy, huh?
Definitely!
See?
She doesn’t really understand.
What should we say so that she understands?
So, for a while, Nanoha will be your mom, Vivio.
Mama?
You can call me that if you want.
Until we find your real mother, Vivio,
I’ll be your mama for a little while.
Is that okay with you, Vivio?
Mama.
Yes, Vivio?
Why are you crying?
It’s okay, Vivio.
By the way, what about the Arthra?
It’s going to be dismantled next month.
I see.
It seemed like it could still work for a while longer last I saw it.
We don’t think it could last through a long mission.
That’s sad. The Arthra holds a lot of memories for us.
It’s worked hard for a long time.
We need to let it rest.
Here’s your data.
It’s important data, so be careful.
Yes.
Teana, was it?
Y-Yes.
What do you think of Hayate?
Well,
I think she’s an impressive mage and a talented commander.
I see.
Hayate, Chrono, and my stepsister Carim.
The three of them have been friends for a long time.
And thanks to that, they get along with me.
Yes.
I know that.
She’s another user of Ancient Belkan magic, but more than that, Hayate is a good girl.
She’s a sweetheart.
Yes.
I think of her like a little sister.
So I’m kind of worried about her.
I see.
Rare Skills and powerful magic, strong power, and the authority to have other people serve her...
Having that power also implies a degree of isolation.
That’s what I think.
I see.
Of course, she’ll be needed.
She’ll be relied on.
But not as a person.
It’ll be the power she possesses being relied on.
Of course, that’s an extreme case.
It’s not actually like that.
Yes, I understand.
“Pressure and loneliness come with that power,” is what you’re saying.
Yes, that’s right.
Anyway, so what I’m trying to say is, well...
I’m sure that a lot of things may happen between a commander and her front-line soldiers.
But I’d like you to treat her not just as a superior,
but as a person—as another girl.
Not just Hayate, but your captains too.
Roger.
We front-line soldiers will do the best we can.
I took another look at the squad data,
But Hayate is truly blessed to have family and staff like that.
Agreed.
Teana’s a good kid,
but I’m sure her guilt isn’t going to go away that easily.
I think Hayate is trying too hard, as always.
If she can make it through this incident,
that will be proof of her suitability as a commander.
And there will be less that people can say about the Book of Darkness Incident.
Even if Nanoha and Fate are with her, I’m worried.
I’d like to help her.
The Main Office can’t act openly, as you just said.
Leave it to me.
The position of Inspector is suited to covert actions.
Thanks, I’m counting on you.
Teana, you haven’t eaten yet, right?
Want to stop somewhere and get a bite?
Yes.
Commander Yagami, it’s a bit far,
but there’s a great restaurant up ahead.
Really?
Inspector Acous told me about it.
Would you like to go?
That sounds nice. Let’s go.
Okay, I’ll show you the way.
Great
What kind of place is it?
They say the fish there is great.
Midchilda Surface, 108th Battalion HQ
We’ve received data once again from Riot Force 6
along with their inspection of the scene.
With the template they’re using for their magic circles
and the signals from the power source they’re using,
they’re at a far higher level than what we’ve run into before.
I guess there’s no doubt then.
Manager, Main Office Technical Department 4
Chief Engineer Mariel Atenza
Yes.
All of them are combat cyborgs
created using the latest technology.
I need to match Marie’s analyzed data with Riot Force 6’s.
It’s not something we can do without meeting in person.
I guess I’ll go.
Yes.
Commander Yagami seems like she will return after 0800.
Are you busy, Chief Engineer Mariel?
I’ll go along.
I haven’t seen Subaru lately.
Thanks.
Okay, keep yourself busy until it’s time to go.
Ginga.
Yes, sir.
Let’s go to the break room, Marie.
Sure.
I guess I should have expected it.
Nothing’s finished yet.
This is tough!
I see. Nanoha’s your mom now.
Yeah.
And I’ll be your mom in a way too, Vivio.
I’m your godmother.
Vivio, it’s my job to watch over you and your Mama Nanoha.
Mama Nanoha and Mama Fate?
Yes.
Right.
Mama?
Yes?
Both Nanoha and Fate being her mom...
Vivio is really invincible.
But Fate’s your guardian, and Nanoha’s teaching you.
Well, that’s true, but...
By the way, how do you both think of Fate? As more like a mother or an older sister?
I think of her as a kind older sister.
It could go either way for me.
It’s hard to decide.
I wonder if Fate would rather have Erio as a kid or as a younger brother.
Let’s ask her tomorrow.
I’m sorry, Caro, but don’t do that!
A mother, huh?
What happened then isn’t over.
The Combat Cyborg Incident that killed my mother.
Without end, the dreams continue to weave
Surpassing thousands of nights
Like a prayer, the journey continues
Be my guide any day, oh small jewel
Spica among the stars
I engrave beyond the horizon
The faint footsteps that are connected to everywhere
The reflection of your eyes casts away the loop of anxiety
The midnight sun
The Orion of Midsummer
Just now from somewhere, I heard your voice
This heart without darkness
Illumine it, o distant blue star
No matter what the time, I will be able to start walking
Sparkling far and near
Watching over me
The thing inside my heart, overflowing
More than tears, I want to be loved
Like a prayer, the journey continues
Be my guide anyday, oh small jewel
Spica among the stars
Next
Episode
Preview
Next
Episode
Preview
The investigation
gets closer to the truth.
As mother and child,
and as sister and sister,
we enjoy a time of peace.
Along with everyone’s bonds with each other.
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS:
Episode 15: Sisters & Daughters
Episode 15
Take off!