A girl appeared, shrouded in mystery and bound by chains to a Relic.
Shadows began to move, seeking it.
The Gadgets dance in the sky, along with a mistress of illusion.
The summoner appeared underground along with her companions.
All of us have the power to stand against them.
To protect them
so they may fight without hesistation.
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS
will now begin.
The hot comet dwelling within my heart beats towards the beginning.
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
My fingers tremble, grasping upon a silent wish
I cower, wanting to flee from the inescapable past
Even if it is merely a faint light fading
I want to chase after it, just like that star
And accept everything, no matter how high it is
Dancing throughout the galaxy is the angel’s whisper
Pursuing these certain memories
The door to the truth will surely be born now
No matter what kind of cold darkness binds me
Because I want to know
I won’t be stopped
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Episode 12
Numbers
How’s this?
Tia, what should we do?
Our mission is to retrieve the case.
We’ll fall back and draw them in.
Lt. Vita and Command Sergeant Major Rein are on their way.
If we can hook up with them,
we may be able to stop them.
Right?
Okay.
Alright.
That sounds good, Subaru, Teana.
Lt. Vita!
I’m here too.
Both of you read the situation appropriately. Nice decision!
Lieutenant, Command Sergeant Major Rein, where are you?
Lulu, something’s coming.
The mana signature is huge!
Eisen!
Giant Form
Gigantform
Rein, let’s charge in!
Okie-doke!
Grab them in a frozen hold.
Freezing Fetters
Frierenfesseln
Take this!
Sorry to keep you waiting.
I’m glad you’re all safe.
Your team is really strong, Lieutenant.
But is it okay for members of the Bureau to damage public facilities like this?
Well, this place has long been abandoned anyway...
Caro!
Erio.
Fried.
Crap.
Same here.
So they got away, huh?
What.
I’m sensing a large-scale summoning.
That’s probably the cause.
Let’s get out of here!
Subaru!
Yes, ma’am!
Wingroad
Subaru, Ginga, take the lead!
I’ll fly up last.
Yes, ma’am!
Caro, here. Your hat.
Thank you very much.
Hey, would you be able to seal the Relic for me?
Yes, I can.
I have an idea.
Give me a hand.
Okay!
How many left?
You’ve knocked it down by nine—no, eight formations.
We’ve started breaking down the illusion’s pattern.
Incoming transmission from the observation team.
Composite signal discrimination is proceeding as scheduled.
We’re almost there!
Great! You are the best operators Riot Force 6’s could have.
Okay, let’s keep it going.
Please take care of my targeting.
Yes, ma’am!
Time-Space Administrative Bureau
Midchilda Capital/Surface Headquarters
What is it?
What’s going on here?
Same place, top floor, observation room
This is real-time footage of the Main Office’s
Antiquities Department, Riot Force 6.
What you’re seeing destroyed here are the reported A.M.F.-equipped U.F.O.s.
The one performing the shooting is most likely the commander of Riot Force 6, a SS rank mage.
A SS rank mage in the Ground Armed Service?
I haven’t heard of this.
She’s attached to the Main Office itself.
Who is this commander,
and who are her supporters?
Her chief supporters are
Admiral Chrono Harlaown of the Main Office’s Dimensional Navy
and Director-General Lindy Harlaown,
as well as Knight Carim Gracia from the Church of the Holy King.
A bunch of amateurs who think they’re heroes.
The unit’s commander is Lt. Colonel Hayate Yagami.
Hayate Yagami!
That Hayate Yagami?
Yes, sir.
The Hayate Yagami from the Book of Darkness Incident.
The ward of Gil Graham, the man who was behind that attempted medium-scale dimensional incident.
Both of them are criminals!
Her suspended sentence has long since been expunged,
and the incident with Admiral Graham
was overlooked.
So then—
Irrelevant!
Once you’ve committed a crime, it doesn’t just go away.
That is a dangerous remark.
I’ll ask you not to announce that in public.
I know.
How annoying! The Navy is always like that.
It continually underestimates dangerous elements.
Lt. General, for two years you have continually denied the Ground Armed Service’s requests
for funds devoted to develop countermeasures for A.M.F. weapons.
So it’s quite likely that the Main Office and the Church of the Holy King
created them as an independent means of dealing with the problem.
Sometime soon, I want you to go investigate them.
If you find any problems, any at all, I’m going to see her dragged in front of a committee.
Sir!
She may provide an excellent means of attacking that impotent Church.
Understood, sir.
You can’t, Lulu.
This is a bad idea.
How are we going to find the case in the rubble?
Even if they’re Bureau staff,
they might get crushed and die!
If they’re that powerful,
I doubt this is enough to kill them.
I’ll have Quattro and Sein find the case for me.
That’s not a good idea, Lulu.
You need to stay away from the Numbers and that twisted doctor.
Sir Zest told you that too, didn’t he?
They say a lot of things, but in the end we’re nothing but guinea pigs to them—
He did it.
Galue, are you okay?
You may go back.
Agito is here.
You too, Jirai-Oh.
What?
This is the end of the line.
Dammit!
I don’t like this. It’s like I’m beating up a little kid.
You’re under arrest for using dangerous magic inside city limits
and for obstruction of justice.
Dieci, can you see it?
Yup.
There’s nothing in the way, and the air is clear.
I can see it clearly.
But are you sure it’s okay to fire, Quattro?
The case will probably be fine,
but it’ll destroy the material.
According to Uno and the Doctor,
if that material really is the right one...
If it really is the Vessel of the Holy King, then cannon fire won’t kill it. It’s okay.
Quattro. Miss Lutecia and Agito were captured.
Is that right?
That mini-knight caught them, did she?
Sein is keeping an eye on them right now.
Should I give her a hand?
If you please.
Sein?
Hey there, Quatty!
I’ll give you your orders.
Do as your big sister says, okay?
Hmmm... roger.
Hi, Miss Lu!
Quattro.
Seems like you’re in a pinch.
If you’d like, I’ll give you a hand.
Yes, please.
Okay!
Then Miss, would you give my message to that red knight?
I can see it.
Thank goodness! The helicopter is safe.
I’ve spotted an energy signal inside the city!
It’s enormous!
No... that can’t be right!
I’m seeing a cannon charge,
physical destruction-type. Estimated at S rank!
Inherent Skill:
executing Heavy Barrel.
You can capture me if you want,
but can you really leave that helicopter of yours alone?
Twelve seconds remaining.
Eleven.
Ten.
Oh, Miss?
Can I add more more thing?
You might not be able to
to protect them again.
Fire!
The cannon struck the helicopter directly.
That’s impossible. Give me a sitrep!
There’s too much interference!
I can’t get any data!
No...!
Sgt. Vice and Dr. Shamal!
Why you...!
Lieutenant, calm down!
Shut up!
You have people working with you, right?
Where are they?
Tell me!
Erio, there’s something under you!
I’ll be taking this.
Crap!
Miss Lu, this is Number VI, Sein.
I’ll save you with my I.S., Deep Diver.
Turn your field and barrier off and stay right there, okay?
Hold it!
Where’s Agito?
Agito ran away just then.
Good work, really.
Uh... we’ve lost them.
Crap!
Long Arch, is the helicopter all right?
It hasn’t been shot down, has it?
A perfect plan, wouldn’t you agree?
Quiet.
I’m confirming my kill.
What?
It’s still in the air!
Stars 2 and Long Arch,
This is Stars 1. I was just close enough to save the helicopter.
That was close.
Too close.
Limiter released!
Nanoha’s and Raising Heart’s Exceed Mode!
Oh my.
Even if that’s not our full power,
you’ve got to be kidding me.
I’ve found you.
Here too?
She’s fast!
Stop!
You’re under arrest for attempted murder and the use of dangerous magic inside city limits.
Not today!
Execute I.S.
Silver Curtain
Hayate!
Position confirmed.
Preparation complete.
Four seconds until execution.
Roger.
She turned around?
Why?
It can’t—
A wide-area spatial attack!
No way!
In a distant land, sink into the darkness.
Diabolic Emission
They won’t surrender...
We won’t surrender...
Flight risk confirmed.
Just as there is danger of escape.
Knock them out via Buster,
Knockout by Buster.
and take them into custody.
After that, arrest it.
Dieci, Quattro!
Stay still.
Execute I.S.
Ride Impulse
Trident...
...Smasher
Excelion...
...Buster
Bingo!
No, they dodged it!
They were rescued at the last second.
Alto, track them.
Yes, ma’am.
Tre, thanks for the help.
Thanks.
Don’t just sit there.
Stand up.
I’m surrounded by idiots.
I was just here to keep an eye on you,
but I’m glad I came.
Sein has already finished recovering the girl and the case.
We’ll meet up with them and return.
We lost the signal.
The abnormal signal is gone too.
They got away, huh?
Sorry.
We’ve totally failed here.
The summoner got away,
and they took the case too.
We can’t track them either.
We failed.
Um, Lt. Vita?
Yes. The forwards did their best.
This was totally my failure.
Mine too.
Lieutenant, uh...!
What is it? I’m in the middle of my report!
There was so much tension that we really didn’t have time to say it, but...
We sort of did a little something with the Relic.
We’re finally back.
It’s thanks to your mass teleportation spell, Miss.
Thank you very much.
Oh, Sein!
Take a look in the case.
Okie-dokie!
Ta-daa!
It’s empty?
What’s going on!
Sein?
You couldn’t have...
I retrieved it perfectly!
You didn’t screw up Deep Diver and drop the contents, did you?
I did not!
I scanned it and confirmed that it was the real case!
See?
Well, the case certainly is the real thing.
That’s strange, isn’t it?
You idiots!
Are you blind?
Here!
The case wasn’t a silhouette: it was real.
My silhouettes are weak to shock,
and they would have found out when they took it.
So we opened the case and then put a heavy seal on the Relic itself.
So the Relic...
Like this.
We thought we’d have Caro hold it since she has the least direct contact with the enemy.
I see!
Seems there’s no need for us to do anything.
The mission was completed successfully.
Let’s be happy for it.
We were tricked.
I’m sorry, Miss.
It was a foolish mistake.
I don’t care.
The only thing I’m looking for is the XI Core.
This is number VI.
But this is bad.
If the core and the material
fell into the hands of the Bureau,
Uno will be mad at us!
What a pain!
Holy King Hospital
We finished the examination.
There don’t seem to be any real problems,
so I’ll be heading back.
Roger.
How about the forwards?
All of them are fine.
Erio’s and Caro’s wounds were pretty minor.
They’ve probably finished
their reports and are in their quarters.
I see.
I need to get back and write a report myself.
I think this one’s going to be pretty long.
It’s all right.
I have the documents and data ready for you.
Thanks.
Mama...
Everything’s fine.
I’m right here.
Don’t be scared.
Mama...
Without end, the dreams continue to weave
Surpassing thousands of nights
Like a prayer, the journey continues
Be my guide any day, oh small jewel
Spica among the stars
I engrave beyond the horizon
The faint footsteps that are connected to everywhere
The reflection of your eyes casts away the loop of anxiety
The midnight sun
The Orion of Midsummer
Just now from somewhere, I heard your voice
This heart without darkness
Illumine it, o distant blue star
No matter what the time, I will be able to start walking
Sparkling far and near
Watching over me
The thing inside my heart, overflowing
More than tears, I want to be loved
Like a prayer, the journey continues
Be my guide anyday, oh small jewel
Spica among the stars
Next
Episode
Preview
Next
Episode
Preview
Lives created.
Lives saved.
Each longs for something different,
for what their hearts are set on.
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS:
Episode 13: The Reason I Live
Episode 13
The Reason I Live
It was only a small wish.