It’s been a week since the destruction of Surface HQ and Riot Force 6.
Our soldiers were wounded, and our beloved were kidnapped.
I’ve failed as a commander.
I can regret my decisions and
take responsibility when the case is closed.
I decided four years ago that
if there was a crime, I’d head straight for it,
and that I’d send the best aces and strikers toward it.
No matter who gets in my way, I won’t let them stop us.
So that I can end this as soon as possible.
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
The things that I can do for you and no one else
I honestly feel and wish for those
I am frozen by uncertainties
By the rules I have been relying on
My past embellished with excuses
I want to get over it
Staining the stars in heaven scarlet
Gather the grains of miracles
Before the still, unseen night
I want to tell you that I am escaping from illusions
The twilight moon calls out to me
Removing my veil of delusions
My hidden, deceitful self
And took all of my weaknesses
I don’t want words that seem passionate
The fact that I’m here right now is my truth
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Sergeant Vice, congratulations on finishing your surgery.
Riot Force 6 and our 704 helicopter were destroyed.
But your Storm Raider was saved, Sgt. Vice.
Lt. Signum brought her to us.
Don’t worry about anything else, okay?
Just stay here and rest, please.
Let’s go, everyone.
Right!
As Vice’s junior, and as a member of the Long Arch staff for Riot Force 6,
I inherit the job of taking everyone to the places they need to be.
Episode 19
Cradle
Time-Space Administrative Bureau Dimensional Navy
L-Class Cruiser Arthra
Lucino, is the control okay?
Yes, Fate.
I know everything about her—the Arthra, I mean.
I see.
Alto and Lucino are...?
Yes. Alto is going to pilot the helicopter
while Vice is in the hospital.
Lucino will helm the Arthra.
I didn’t know you had a helicopter license, Alto.
Yeah. I always did like helicopters,
and Sgt. Vice taught me a lot.
And you too, Lucino.
I used to work on this ship.
I always wanted to helm a ship,
and I got my license while I was a clerk here.
Everybody’s here.
Excuse me.
Good timing.
Riot Force 6’s next actions have been decided.
Unfortunately, the response from Surface HQ is as lackluster as usual.
They say that they’re going to investigate it themselves and are strongly rejecting outside interference.
Thus, the Main Office won’t send in any forces yet.
At the same time, no information will be given
to Riot Force 6, as it is attached to the Main Office.
But what we’re investigating isn’t
the terrorist attack or its perpetrator, Jail Scaglietti.
It’s the Lost Logia, the Relics.
And Scaglietti and his gang
just happen to be involved in that.
That’s how we’re doing it.
So we will find and recover
Sergeant Ginga Nakajima, who was kidnapped,
and rescue Captain Nanoha and Captain Fate’s child, Vivio,
while we are in the process of this.
Captains, any thoughts?
It’s an ideal situation,
but you’re not overreaching again, are you?
Is it okay?
I’ve reinforced our backing from all our superiors.
It’s okay.
More than anything, this is why I created Riot Force 6.
If we can’t act here, then I wasted my time creating it.
Roger.
Then I’m fine with that policy.
Okay, then we’ll begin within the day.
Get ready, and wait for further orders.
Yes, ma’am.
Teana, is Subaru still...?
Yes, she’s at the Main Office.
But she’ll be heading here this afternoon.
Your nervous system is back at full strength.
You can move at full power, and it won’t hurt.
Yes, ma’am.
Thank you so much, Marie!
No problem! All that’s left is Mach Caliber.
Right.
I’m sorry, Mach Caliber.
You’re mad at me, right?
Perhaps I don’t have the feeling of “anger.”
You have nothing to worry about.
Worry is not needed.
Mach Caliber, I said that even though you’re an A.I., you have a soul,
and that you’re my buddy who runs with me,
but during that moment,
I wasn’t thinking about you at all, Mach Caliber.
I was selfish, and I treated you like a tool.
I hurt you so much.
No!
I had a problem!
I couldn’t handle your full power
Your best status was not supported
due to my own inadequacy.
due to my power shortage.
Oh, sorry.
Are you in the middle of something important?
No.
We’re having a postmortem.
Reconsideration meeting.
Shari, are you okay?
Riot Force 6 is in big trouble,
and I need to look after the Devices.
I can’t just sit there.
Yes, ma’am.
Hey, Subaru.
Mach Caliber created a power-up plan for me to implement when I repair her.
It will strengthen the outer frame
and your armor’s strength.
It’ll be a lot heavier and harder to use.
I told her she needed to ask you first, Subaru.
Mana consumption up 1.4 times.
Main unit weight up 2.5 times.
I’ll do it!
I know I can handle this!
Well then, we’ll use this plan.
Aren’t you glad, Mach Caliber?
Thank you.
Well, I’ll go get the parts.
Subaru, wait just a while.
Thank you very much!
Please give me one more chance.
Your best will be supported without fail this time,
so that you can go as far as you want.
This time we’ll run together, Mach Caliber.
Did you move the training data over okay?
It was completed without trouble.
Oh! Nanoha!
Raising Heart!
Rein!
Are you okay now?
Yes indeedy, I’m totes okay!
I see.
Shari asked me to handle the final limiter removal
of Cross Mirage and the other Devices.
Yes, I asked her to.
Thanks.
I wanted to proceed a bit more carefully, but the situation won’t allow for that.
But I’m sure everyone will master them.
Sure.
Nanoha... for you and Raising Heart,
normal Exceed Mode is okay,
but Blaster Mode is dangerous.
I won’t use it.
Blaster is Raising Heart’s and my
last-ditch ace up our sleeves.
It’s so.
Exceed alone has more than enough power.
We’ll take care of it until the very end.
Yes.
It’s only a little more.
Mama Nanoha will come to save you.
Strada!
Roger.
Jawohl.
It’s time.
Y-Yes, ma’am.
As usual, there’s nothing I can teach you.
Are you okay with that?
It’s fine! I’m stealing a lot of your techniques.
Silly kid.
You can’t be worrying Captain Fate.
Don’t overdo it too much.
Thank you, ma’am.
Testarossa, it’s you.
Thanks.
Thank you for taking care of Erio, Instructor Signum.
I’m sorry for not asking you.
Erio asked you, and you accepted. That’s fine.
I’m just a bit lonely.
Erio just doesn’t want to worry his mother.
Try to understand that.
Yes, I’m fine.
How is Erio doing?
He’s not bad. To be honest,
I’m shocked at his rate of improvement.
For a kid who only knows the basics,
his learning rate and judgement are incredible.
He has the ability to make judgements
and take action on the fly.
Nanoha trains them that way.
They’re firmly grounded in the basics,
and they’ve got the ability to adapt and
take action in an instant thanks to their mock battles.
The practice they’ve done thus far is preparation for them to get even stronger from here on out.
So they can be strong, as strong as they want to be.
Stronger than yesterday, and far stronger than today.
Shamal, are you done yet?
Almost. Just a little more.
I’ve got work to do.
I need to hurry up and get back.
Just a bit more. Stay still.
We’ve known for years that my wounds are healing slower and that my accumulated damage isn’t going away as easily.
It’s not just your recovery abilities.
The guardian knight system itself
is acting strange, and that bothers me.
The link between us is getting weaker,
and we’re gradually losing the ability for Hayate to restore the system in an emergency or give us additional power.
It doesn’t matter!
If we do our best every day, it’s not an issue.
That’s enough. I’m leaving.
Vita.
I don’t think the problem with our bodies is due to any damage to the guardian knight system or anything like that.
We’ve started to get what we wanted
ever since we were a part of the Book of Darkness.
We’ve lived so long, unable to even die, and we wanted to live out our limited lives with our final mistress, Hayate.
It’s what the first Rein gave to us.
This is just a continuation of that.
And what’s wrong with it?
Not being able to heal as easily if we’re wounded,
or to completely redo something.
It’s kind of like being normal humans.
Yes... Signum and Zafira said the same things.
Our first and last lives.
We need to treasure them
but use them as best we can, they said.
And you, Shamal?
I’m the same.
I’m not scared of the danger,
and I’ve got no interest in eternity.
But I worry about you, Signum, and Zafira
as much as our gentle mistress, Hayate.
I want to support Hayate and Rein for
as long as we can, without losing anybody.
Then don’t worry.
The second Wind of Blessing, Rein, will help us.
Signum and I won’t fall.
And Zafira will wake up soon.
For the last ten years, the number of things we’ve gotta protect has really gone up.
I’ll protect them all and come back fine.
So I don’t make a certain worrywart
Knight of the Lake who’s terrible at cooking cry.
Silly.
Subaru!
Oh! Tia!
Everyone!
Subaru, welcome back.
Are you okay?
Yep! Mach Caliber and I have totally recovered.
Dammit! Our magic’s barely getting through!
Everyone who can use anti-field magic, group together and counterattack!
City ground defenses!
City defenses!
Hey, respond!
Thanks to the data I’ve accumulated, it’s a lot easier to move.
Right, Otto, Deed?
Don’t you think?
Damn, I’m bad with these guys.
Wendi. Nove, Sette, and I have taken down Unit 2.
Oh, good work!
Are you done too?
Totally finished.
Otto and Deed did some major damage to the main unit.
I see.
Good work.
So Unit 1 was handled by Quatty, Sein, and Dieci,
our long-time veteran backup trio?
It seems they took it out without any problems.
The attacks on Einherjar are almost complete,
and my little sisters are applying
all the data they got from their patrols.
That’s good. Wonderful.
Wonderful!
Compared with the artificial mages,
where the failures really stand out,
we combat cyborgs are a lot easier to work with.
It’s a technology that the Bureau almost brought
to completion under the direction of the High Council.
I spent a lot of time improving it.
Of course it’ll be good.
And I’ve gotten a lot of good data on the creation of artificial mages thanks to the long-term activities of Zest and Lutecia.
And thanks to their failures and successes,
the Vessel of the Holy King was completed wonderfully.
Ever since you were able to find and touch this,
the Holy King’s Cradle, activating it has been your dream.
For that, you sought out the one who could be
the Vessel of the Holy King and made preparations.
Your dream is about to come true.
No, not yet.
My dream is just beginning, Uno.
Through the power of the Cradle,
product of Ancient Belka’s wisdom, it begins here.
Nobody will stop it!
It’s the beginning of a wonderful dream!
Somebody has infiltrated our base?
Inside this cave?
They found my hunting dogs
and destroyed them in one shot.
It’s no normal security system.
This is definitely their hideout.
You’re amazing, Rossa.
I’m amazed you found this place.
Schach, stop treating me like a kid.
I’m just like Carim and Hayate....
I’ve inherited a Rare Skill from Ancient Belka.
Infinite hunting dogs, Endless Hunt.
Unendlichjagd
I’m aware of your power.
Well, this was only possible thanks to Enforcer Fate’s
and Major Nakajima’s thorough investigation.
They’re coming from inside the cave too.
Yeah. I guess they’re not going to just let us go home.
I’m not the best fighter, but I think I can take out this many.
Leave it to me.
Protecting you and Carim is my job.
Einherjar 1 and 2 are under attack from the combat cyborgs.
They’re faster than last time.
If we don’t hurry and take them out, it’ll be really bad.
But they’re split up. It’ll be hard to send in the captains.
Incoming call from Inspector Acous.
Hayate, this is Verossa.
We’ve found Scaglietti’s hideout.
Schach is taking out the Gadgets that came for us.
I’m calling in firepower from the Church Knights,
but can you send us some too?
Yeah, of course.
The combat cyborgs have withdrawn from Einherjar.
They’re heading to Surface HQ!
That knight is heading there via a different route?
Another energy signature from
the abandoned city. It’s expanding.
This is a combat cyborg?
It’s heading toward Surface HQ too!
I’m sending the footage now.
Ginny.
They’re still coming.
It might be a bad idea to stay here.
What? I can still kick their asses.
Now, it’s time to revive!
This is for my sponsors and for the Bureau who made this world,
and for the Church of the Holy King, which lauds a hypocritical peace.
Can you see it?
This is the absolute power
that you people longed for even as you avoided it.
That which in the old years created a world
and then destroyed it.
The demonic wisdom of Ancient Belka.
The Holy King’s Cradle.
Can you see it?
With the master it’s longed for, this product of ancient wisdom and technology will now bring forth its power.
Mama.
It hurts!
I’m scared!
Mama! Mama!
Vivio.
The dream begins now!
Etched into this amulet, these precious times
In my precious days
“The bluebird ran away”
I cried, embracing the empty cage
I still remember the color of the high-rising sky
That I looked up at that day
Rewinding
Inside my memories
In painful times, in happy times
You were always there at important times
The thing which I looked for to the ends of the labyrinth
Is deep within my heart
Etched into this amulet, these precious times
Soft and secret pieces of my memory
No matter what type of tomorrow it is, I can walk towards it
In my precious days
Next
Episode
Preview
Next
Episode
Preview
The ship has returned from the holy land
as predicted in the prophecy.
With the Cradle in his grasp,
Scaglietti’s plan moves toward its final stages.
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS:
Episode 20: Unlimited Desire
Episode 20
Unlimited Desire
Take off.