Let’s rehash our mission.
This is the first step toward the Doctor’s dream
and our most important plan.
Out of the twelve Numbers,
eleven participated in the operation.
Additionally, Knight Zest, as well as
the summoner Lutecia, both participated.
The objective of our work is
the neutralization of the Bureau’s Surface HQ,
as well as Riot Force 6, with minimal human collateral.
The recovery of the Vessel of the Holy King is top priority.
If the possibility arises, any Type-0 should be captured.
The commander responsible for
mission control is me, the first Number, Uno.
The hot comet dwelling within my heart beats towards the beginning.
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
My fingers tremble, grasping upon a silent wish
I cower, wanting to flee from the inescapable past
Even if it is merely a faint light fading
I want to chase after it, just like that star
And accept everything, no matter how high it is
Dancing throughout the galaxy is the angel’s whisper
Pursuing these certain memories
The door to the truth will surely be born now
No matter what kind of cold darkness binds me
Because I want to know
I won’t be stopped
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Episode 17
That Day, Riot Force 6
(part 2)
Zest, was it? Tell me just what you’re planning and what you’re after.
If it’s something reasonable,
the Bureau will listen to your request.
You’re young.
But you’re a good knight.
Now isn’t the time to be praising her, sir!
Rein, have you noticed?
Yes.
The timing in their Unison attack, although only slightly, is off.
Their Unison compatibility doesn’t seem to be very good.
Damn them.
Their Unison compatibility seems to be good, and they’re highly skilled. They keep coming at us together.
Agito, let’s cancel out of Unison.
I’ll take her out in one hit with my Full Drive.
You’re kidding, right?! If you use your Full Drive, sir, your body will...
I won’t go down.
Not until we finish what we must do.
Don’t even joke about that!
I told you I would protect you, sir!
I won’t let her chip away at your life, sir!
I’ll open a path for you, sir!
Extreme blaze!
Raging Fire Sword
He keeps moving!
Wendi, you piece of junk, get him already.
An illusion?
No way!
More energy needed for silhouette control.
The load by the silhouette control increases.
Approaching energy boost limit.
The limit of the energy boost is near.
Just a little bit longer.
Try your best until we can escape.
Yes, sir.
All right.
Since she can fool my eyes,
does this illusionist know about the combat cyborg system?
It doesn’t matter if they’re illusions or something else.
I’ll just smash them all!
Nove!
Form III
Form Drei
Storm Form
Unwetterform
Thunder...
...Rage
Let’s go!
Damn those assholes!
Nove, Wendi. You two, help me out a bit over here.
There’s another Type-0.
I’m in combat with one of the first produced.
Captain Takamachi!
Sister Schach.
Sister, weren’t you in the Conference Room?
Along with some other men, we managed to open the door,
and then I hurried after you two.
What about Hayate and her group?
The three of them are still in
the Conference Room along with the representatives.
They’re explaining about the Gadgets and the attackers.
Nice timing.
Sorry to make you wait.
Here you go.
Thanks, everyone.
I’ll go deliver these.
Please do.
I will
Ginny?
Ginny!
Subaru?
Transmissions aren’t getting through to Ginny.
We engaged in combat with two of the combat cyborgs.
There should be more in the front.
Could Ginny be in combat with them?
Long Arch, this is Lightning 1.
Lightning 1, this is Long Arch.
Griffith? What’s wrong? You’re breaking up...
We’re currently taking fire from Gadgets and unknowns.
We’re holding out, but...
Let’s split up.
Stars will confirm Ginga’s well-being
and take down any attack force.
Lightning will return to Riot Force 6.
Yes, ma’am!
Sister Schach, I’ll leave everyone above to you.
I’ll risk my life for it.
Hurry!
You two have done well just by yourselves.
But it’s all over now.
Before my I.S., Ray Storm, there is no point in resisting.
Klarwind, protect against it!
Yes.
Ja.
Deed.
I.S.: Twin Blades
Goodbye.
Shamal.
Zafira.
Okay, you can still shoot.
Your skills haven’t atrophied yet.
Sonic Move
Combat cyborgs.
Erio, Caro, go ahead of me.
But Fate!
I’ll catch up to you soon.
Go!
Fried.
Erio.
They’re opponents who can outrange us in air combat.
If we stay, Fate can’t fight to her fullest.
Okay,
Bardiche, third form!
Zanber Form
Several S+ ranks have begun to move.
Have their defenses already recovered enough?
Oh goddammit!
Vita, Signum is heading this way!
Is this it?
Let’s retreat.
God damn...
At least... at least let me take them down!
Vita, above you!
I’ll smash you down right here!
Full Drive, start.
Grenzpunkt freilassen.
Agito, we’re retreating.
J-Jackass...
Rein!
Hey, Rein!
That’s...
Signum.
Rein is...
..and Eisen!
Subaru, you’re getting too far ahead of us.
Sorry, but I’m fine.
She can’t help it.
In a place like this, Subaru is faster than us.
It’s okay if we just hurry.
Yes, ma’am.
Ginny.
Ginny!
Give her back.
Give Ginny back!
Get out of my way!
Nove, Wendi, let your sister stop her.
Retreat from here.
Roger.
Dammit.
Is her I.S. a contact weapon?
I.S.: Aerial Rave
Let’s go, Nove.
But Cinques will be left alone.
Do not worry about it, Nove.
Your sister can fight without any contact.
Don’t get in my way!
Sein! Sein! Hurry up and give Cinques a hand!
I understand, I’ll head over there right now. Leave it to your sister!
Ginny!
You won’t get by...
Protection
Give her back.
Give Ginny back!
Here comes Sein!
I’m saved...
The main body was damaged to the end. The system rests.
Subaru!
The system is completely down.
The defense system is already...
You’re in the way.
There’s no mistake that this is the girl.
Agreed, that’s correct.
Thank you for saving her.
She looks to be in bad shape, too.
You must be tired.
We’ll come and pick you up
I’m okay.
I’ll just fly on a Type 2 until I get
to a safer place to teleport out.
This is too much.
That’s...?
That girl.
It’s Vivio!
Papa! Mama!
Stop it!
Stop it please!
Just what right do you guys have?
That should be our line.
The son of the Mondial family, Erio, has already died from illness.
And this kid is a special clone of your late son.
A degraded copy, born by using the terrible life fabrication technology of Project F.
No!
Papa!
Mama, save me!
No!
Strada, Form Zwei!
Jet Form
Düsenform
Erio?
Caro, please back me up.
Erio!
Explosion
Booster...
...start!
Get out of my way!
Excuse me.
Erio!
Was that one of the remaining F kids?
Well, I imagine he’s not dead.
We’ll leave the final bits to the Gadgets.
Let’s go, Galue.
Where is Scaglietti?
Why would he cause something like this?
If you want, we’ll guide you to him anytime.
Of course, that is if you comply with us.
He’s a criminal.
And the worst kind, at that!
Please don’t say such unfortunate things.
The Doctor effectively fathered you and that boy, among others.
You guys have life because the Doctor established the framework for Project F.
Shut up!
I guess there’s no helping it.
I believe we’ll meet again.
And, at that time, we’ll talk in detail.
Oh, and you may have realized already, but...
Next time, you will no longer be able to defeat us.
In five minutes, the fleet of Gadgets in the sky and other aerial forces will start a mission to destroy the facility.
Their goal is to destroy the facility,
and they will not hinder anyone attempting to flee.
Please withdraw calmly and without resistance.
Why did you do this?
Summoning Dragon Mount
Voltaire
Don’t destroy....
Don’t destroy our home!
Bureau operatives on Midchilda’s surface, did you like it?
While it’s somewhat small, this was my present to you.
They were oppressed under the flag of “maintaining order” and “keeping the Lost Logia from causing harm.”
I hope you’ll consider this present
a gift from all the brilliant engineers
who brought about great advances in legitimate technology.
But I am also one who loves humanity and life.
I tried hard not to shed any blood in vain,
to not spill any blood and to be as humane as possible.
Technology can completely conquer the enemy, whom you should hate. Do you think I’ve done enough to show that?
I’ll leave it at this today.
If you have a need for this wonderful power and technology,
feel free to contact me anytime with a request.
I’ll hand it over to you under special circumstances.
We couldn’t stop the prophecy.
Not yet.
Riot Force 6 isn’t—we aren’t—through yet.
Etched into this amulet, these precious times
In my precious days
“The bluebird ran away”
I cried, embracing the empty cage
I still remember the color of the high-rising sky
That I looked up at that day
Rewinding
Inside my memories
In painful times, in happy times
You were always there at important times
The thing which I looked for to the ends of the labyrinth
Is deep within my heart
Etched into this amulet, these precious times
Soft and secret pieces of my memory
No matter what type of tomorrow it is, I can walk towards it
In my precious days
Next
Episode
Preview
Next
Episode
Preview
Surface HQ and Riot Force 6
are in tatters.
But we cannot just stand defeated.
We will start back up once again, with everyone.
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS:
Episode 18: Wings Anew
Episode 18
Wings Anew
Take off!