It took quite a while for my dream to be realized,
but now it’s finally within my grasp.
Even if my head and my heart disagree,
they are beginning to come together as one.
With the meetings and reunions,
this is the beginning of it all.
But for everyone, this is just a small stepping stone along their lives’ paths.
The troops will gather soon,
and new bonds will be forged.
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS
will now begin.
The hot comet dwelling within my heart beats towards the beginning.
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
My fingers tremble, grasping upon a silent wish
I cower, wanting to flee from the inescapable past
Even if it is merely a faint light fading
I want to chase after it, just like that star
And accept everything, no matter how high it is
Dancing throughout the galaxy is the angel’s whisper
Pursuing these certain memories
The door to the truth will surely be born now
No matter what kind of cold darkness binds me
Because I want to know
I won’t be stopped
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
April 0075, Time-Space Administrative Bureau
Antiquities Department, Riot Force 6 Headquarters
Same place, same time
Commander’s Office
This room is finally fit for a commanding officer, isn’t it?
That’s true.
It’s a good thing we were able to find a desk that’s your size, Rein.
It totes fits me!
Yes, come in!
Excuse us.
So you’ve finished changing into your new uniforms!
You two look fabulous!
Thanks, Rein.
The three of us haven’t been in the same uniform since junior high, right?
It really brings back memories.
Anyway, seeing as you’ll be flying or running around so much, Nanoha,
you might end up spending more time in your instructor’s uniform.
Well, I’ll be wearing this while performing official duties and during ceremonies as well.
Well then, it’s about time.
Indeed.
From today onwards,
Captain Nanoha Takamachi
Enforcer Fate Testarossa-Harlaown
The two of us will hereby be stationed at Riot Force 6.
It’s a pleasure to be working under your command.
Okay. I’ll be counting on you!
Please enter.
Excuse me.
Captain Takamachi,
Enforcer Testarossa-Harlaown,
it’s a pleasure to see you again!
Could you be Griffith?
Yes, ma’am. Griffith Lowran.
It’s been so long! But that aside,
it’s amazing! You’ve really grown!
Yeah. Last time we met, he was only this tall.
I’m grateful I was under the care of you two back then.
Have you joined this unit too, Griffith?
Yes, ma’am.
He’s my adjutant, in charge of logistics.
He also helps manage relations with our superiors.
Is your mother, Admiral Laty, doing well?
Yes. Thank you for your concern!
Oh! May I report to you first?
Go ahead.
The four forwards, as well as the staff of Riot Force 6, have all arrived.
At the moment, they are standing by in the lobby.
Really? That was rather fast.
In that case, Nanoha, Fate,
let’s greet everyone in the unit.
Episode 3
Gathering of Troops
I’m Riot Force 6’s chief, this unit’s commanding officer, Hayate Yagami.
As a department of the Time-Space Administrative Bureau,
the protectors of peace and law,
it is our mission and responsibility to take on many cases to protect the people we serve.
With our team of instructors with excellent achievements and strengths,
our young but promising forwards,
and our talented mechanics and support staff,
I believe that everyone can work together and overcome any and all obstacles.
Well, since I don’t like long speeches,
that is all for now.
I’m Hayate Yagami, director of Riot Force 6
and your commanding officer.
Signum, it’s really been a while.
Indeed, Testarossa.
We haven’t met in person for half a year.
Right. And this is the first time both of us are in the same unit.
Please look after me.
I’m the one who should be saying that.
After all, you are my immediate superior.
That again. I haven’t gotten used to that yet.
Our relationship is one of a superior and subordinate now.
It would be poor form if I called you Testarossa or called out “Hey, you!”
Or shall I address you as “ma’am”, instead?
Please stop making fun of me like that.
It’s okay if you call me Testarossa or just “you.”
I’ll do just that.
By the way, have all of you introduced yourselves to each other yet?
We know each other’s names,
experience, and abilities.
We also know each other’s squads and callsigns.
I see. Then, I would like to begin your training. Is that all right?
Yes, ma’am!
Vice!
Is everything prepared?
Everything’s a-okay!
We can take off anytime.
Isn’t this helicopter one of the newer models?
The JF704... this model was introduced to
the Armed Services only last year. You bet it’s new.
Its mobility and load capacity are second to none!
For a pilot, flying a baby like this is the ultimate joy!
Geez, Sergeant Vice!
Sergeant Vice, when you are a pilot, everyone’s lives are in your hands!
You can’t be goofy about this!
Yeah, yeah! I’m well aware of that, Command Sergeant Major Rein.
Commander Yagami, Fate, where are we heading?
The capital city, Cranagan.
To the Central Command Center.
Roger!
Let’s go, Storm Raider.
Okay.
Take off, standby.
Nanoha!
Shari!
In the Devices I just returned to you are chips used to record data.
So be a little careful when you use them, okay?
And also, our mechanic, Shari, would like a word with you.
I’m the mechanical designer and head of communications for Riot Force 6,
Specialist Shario Finieno.
Everyone calls me Shari, so feel free to do the same.
I will be in charge of modifying and adjusting everyone’s Devices,
so every now and then I’ll be observing your training.
If you have any questions concerning your Devices, don’t hesitate to ask me.
Yes, ma’am!
Well then, shall we start this training session?
Sure...
But, we’re going to train here?
Shari?
Okay!
This training space is Riot Force 6’s pride and joy.
It’s a battle and area simulator that was made so Nanoha can observe your training.
Stage set!
Amazing!
Vita. So this is where you were.
Signum.
So the new recruits have already started their training.
Yup.
You’re not going to participate?
The four of them are still hatchlings learning to walk.
It’ll be a while before I help with instructing them.
I see.
Anyway, I want to make use of this time to train myself.
We’re in the same unit after all.
I have to be able to protect Nanoha in the sky.
I’ll leave that to you.
Oh yeah, where’s Shamal?
In her fortress.
This is a great clinic.
With this, I should be able to perform pretty good check-ups and healing.
Though the equipment we’re using was discarded by the main hospital,
There shouldn’t be any problems with them whatsoever!
Everyone’s healing and check-ups are in your hands, Dr. Shamal!
Okay!
All right, can everyone hear me?
Yes, ma’am!
’Kay, let’s deploy the targets.
First, we’ll warm up with a set of eight.
How do movement level C and attack level D sound?
Sounds good.
Our job is to search for, protect, and escort the Lost Logia.
In order to complete our mission, we’ll have to fight our enemies who are...
...these!
Autonomic Magical Machines.
This type of enemy will attack when you approach.
Their attacks are pretty painful!
And so, it’s Mock Battle Training Number One.
Mission objective:
Destroy or capture the eight escaping targets.
You have fifteen minutes.
Yes, ma’am!
Now then,
Mission...
...start!
Time-Space Administrative Bureau
Midchilda Surface Headquarters, Central Command Center
Regarding the search for
antiquities known as Lost Logia,
I’m sure everyone already knows about them.
The advanced technologies crafted by various ancient civilizations,
which have been discovered on once highly-advanced, derelict worlds,
are extremely dangerous artifacts.
Lost Logia require immediate attention as they are capable of
causing large-scale destruction and devastation.
However, it has been confirmed that some of these critical items have gone missing.
Now then, one of the main reasons we’ve requested the formation of Riot Force 6
was to search for these first-class Lost Logia, codenamed “Relics”.
Relics look like any other gem on the outside,
but research tells us that they were created by an ancient civilization.
Though we’ve yet to find out what their purpose is,
they have an extremely high crystalline energy capacity.
Relics have been discovered four times in the past.
On three of these occasions,
they caused great devastation to the surrounding areas.
Also, from investigating two of the incidents,
we have discovered these...
Extremely advanced magical energy R&D facilities.
They have all been discovered on undeveloped worlds.
Such research is prohibited within these sectors,
and the debris we found suggests they were trying to erase the evidence.
They appear to be up to no good.
At the very least,
it is not intended to benefit the public
Someone is gathering Relics so they can use them for their own benefit.
The chance of rhem committing a dimensional crime is high.
And also, this someone is using highly dangerous magical machines to find them.
They are called Gadget Drones.
Since the discovery of the Relics,
they’ve searched for specific Lost Logia responses and have tried to retrieve them.
They are self-powered, autonomic machines.
What the hell? They move too fast!
It’s no use... they dodged all my attacks!
I can’t hit them!
You two up front, you’re all over the place!
Think a little about what you’ll do next!
Okay!
Sorry!
Kid, could you give me a magical boost?
Okay.
Kerykeion!
Boost Up: Barret Power
Shoot!
A barrier?
That’s not it... it’s a field!
The magic was dispelled?
That’s right.
The Gadget Drones have a troublesome special feature.
They can dispel any magic that enters
their anti-magilink field, or A.M.F.
Conventional magic attacks will have no effect.
Dammit!
Why you!
Subaru!
Idiot, that’s dangerous!
Furthermore, when the AMF has been fully expanded,
flight, aerial pathways, and teleportation magic will all be dispelled within the field.
Subaru, are you all right?
Somehow.
Well, in practice, we tweak everyone’s Devices a little to obtain a similar result.
But the data is real, so the result is something very similar to the real thing.
There are several ways to defeat them though.
Whatever you do, carefully plan it,
and carefully carry it out!
Kid, what did you say your name was again?
I’m Caro.
Caro, do you think you can do anything with binding magic and that tiny dragon’s ability?
There are a few things I’d like to try.
I have some too.
Subaru!
Okay! Erio, can you get ahead of those guys and block their escape?
Tia seems to have an idea...
we need to buy them time!
I’ll try!
Everyone sure can run fast.
It’s kind of dangerous and makes your heart race though.
Can you record the data from their Devices?
I’m getting some really good recordings.
Their four Devices are all performing well.
Raising Heart, I’ll need your cooperation as well.
All right.
Let’s do this, Strada!
Cartridge Load
Explosion
Go to the scrapyard!
Just as I thought, if my magic gets dispelled,
I can’t output enough strength.
In that case!
I’ll cut off their escape.
Fried.
Blast Flare
Fire!
Please heed me, things that bind,
constricting things.
Now hear my call, restrain my foes with steel.
Summoning wrought iron!
Alchemic Chain
So summoning magic can do that.
The ability to combine inorganic substances... she’s quite skillful.
I’m a ranged specialist.
If I give up because my attacks have no effect on it,
there’s no point in my being here!
Subaru, I’ll attack from above.
Make sure you get them!
Got it!
A magical attack?
Even though they have an A.M.F.?
Yes. There is an available passing method.
If I put a barrier around my shot,
it should make it into the field.
As long as the barrier isn’t totally dispelled when it hits,
the shot should be able to hit the target!
You can place a barrier around
a shot so it can break through a field,
but it’s usually a skill for AA rank mages.
AA?
Combine
Combine!
Variable Shoot
Tia!
Nice!
That was nice, Tia! You did it, as expected!
Subaru, shut up!
Of course I’d be able to do it!
Hayate.
Vita! Is everyone eating together?
Yes, a lot happened today.
Hayate, have you had dinner yet?
I didn’t even have lunch.
I could eat a horse right now.
We can’t have that.
I’ll quickly fix something for you.
I’ll bring some tea!
Thanks a lot!
Where’s Rein?
Here.
As usual, that girl’s fast asleep.
Well, she was hard at work all day.
How did everything go at Central Command?
Well, although we’re a new unit,
they’ve decided to give us their full support.
There don’t seem to be any problems.
We’ve been supported by Admiral Lindy, Admiral Laty,
and Chrono—Admiral Chrono Harlaown.
And also, our greatest supporter is
the Church of the Holy King and the leader of the Church Knights, Knight Carim.
In any case, no one seems to be against us.
How’s the current situation?
Nanoha and the forward squads are going through some hard training through the night.
The newbies are probably exhausted by now.
Well, they’re determined and pretty energetic.
They’ll make it through somehow.
The support team also has no problems.
Everyone is full of vim and vigor.
Griffith is working as hard as ever too.
There don’t seem to be any problems.
I see. It’s been ten years since we signed up.
After all of our hardships and hard work,
we finally have it:
The unit of our dreams.
We’ll do our best to solve this Relic case and finish what Carim entrusted us with.
Let’s do our best together, okay?
Yeah, I’ll work hard!
Of course!
We guardian knights will always be with you.
Something smells good.
You woke up because of the smell?
You’re such a glutton.
We’re all eating dinner now.
Rein, do you want some too?
I want some too!
Here, wash your face.
I’ll give you some of mine.
Vita, could you get a small plate?
Sure.
Looks yummy!
What do you think of the new recruits?
Everyone is very energetic.
I’ve got a good vibe about them.
Really?
It’d be great if they can learn a lot from you.
I’ll train them well,
until those kids are able to fight down their own individual paths.
Without end, the dreams continue to weave
Surpassing thousands of nights
Like a prayer, the journey continues
Be my guide any day, oh small jewel
Spica among the stars
I engrave beyond the horizon
The faint footsteps that are connected to everywhere
The reflection of your eyes casts away the loop of anxiety
The midnight sun
The Orion of Midsummer
Just now from somewhere, I heard your voice
This heart without darkness
Illumine it, o distant blue star
No matter what the time, I will be able to start walking
Sparkling far and near
Watching over me
The thing inside my heart, overflowing
More than tears, I want to be loved
Like a prayer, the journey continues
Be my guide anyday, oh small jewel
Spica among the stars
Next
Episode
Preview
Next
Episode
Preview
To be prepared to
sortie at any time,
the forward members
are continuously training.
You are about to meet your partner,
who will fight with you.
Your Device is only for you and is customized for your use.
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS:
Episode 4: First Alert
Episode 4
First Alert
Take off!