Our first deployment went well, but
that’s all you could say about it.
Even though we train every day,
I haven’t had much time to get stronger.
In my hands is a partner who is too good for me.
And the only people around me are
either geniuses or heroes with long service records.
Now I can’t help but ask myself, “Why am I here?”
Why did she choose me to be her subordinate?
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS
will now begin.
The hot comet dwelling within my heart beats towards the beginning.
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
My fingers tremble, grasping upon a silent wish
I cower, wanting to flee from the inescapable past
Even if it is merely a faint light fading
I want to chase after it, just like that star
And accept everything, no matter how high it is
An angel’s whisper dancing throughout the galaxy
Pursuing these certain memories
The door to the truth will surely be born now
No matter what kind of cold darkness binds me
Because I want to know
I won’t be stopped
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Midchilda’s Capital, Southeastern District
Now then, I’ll go over the events leading up to now, as well as today’s mission.
The mysterious creator of the Gadget Drones,
as well as the person collecting Relics, is currently believed to be this man.
He’s an interdimensional criminal with
a wide-area arrest warrant for his illegal research.
We’ll conduct our investigation around Jail Scaglietti.
Even though I’m the primary investigator in our division,
I still want everyone to take note of him.
Yes, ma’am!
So today we’re heading here, Hotel Augusta!
We’ll be guarding an antiques auction as well as securing the premises.
That’s today’s mission, okay?
Due to the trade of legal Lost Logia,
there’s a good chance their presence
may attract Gadget Drones mistaking them for Relics.
For that reason, we were called in as security for today.
With a large auction such as this one,
there may be some secret deals
and smuggling involved in the shadows.
So make sure you don’t let your guard down.
Since last night, Lt. Signum and Lt. Vita, as well as a number of clerks, have been at the scene.
We will handle the security within the building,
so the front-line troops should act in accordance with the lieutenants’ instructions, okay?
Yes, ma’am!
Er... Dr. Shamal?
I’ve been wondering for a while now... what’s in that box?
This?
They’re the captains’ “work clothes.”
Episode 7
Hotel Augusta
It’s a pleasure to have you.
Welcome.
Good afternoon, we’re from Riot Force 6.
The assembly hall’s security is as tight as you’d expect.
If there’s any general trouble,
they’re probably enough to deal with it, I suppose.
Riot Force 6’s youngsters are fortifying the outside,
and there are also emergency shutters around the premises.
It doesn’t seem like the Gadgets would be able to make it in this far.
We can’t be complacent, but that’s a relief.
Well, whatever happens, we won’t get our turn unless there’s a real emergency.
How long until the auction starts?
Three hours and 27 minutes.
Is that...?
Doc, is something wrong?
Uh... no.
But today, Commander Yagami has gathered all her guardian knights.
It seems so. You seem pretty well-informed about them.
Commander Yagami and the lieutenants, that is.
I’ve heard things from Dad and Ginny, though.
The device Commander Yagami uses is a tome-type,
and they said its name is the Book of the Night Sky.
The lieutenants, Dr. Shamal, and Zafira are
Commander Yagami’s personal special forces from what I’ve heard.
And if you include Command Sergeant Major Rein, the six of them make an invincible force in battle.
Well, specific information about the capabilities of Commander Yagami and the others is top secret,
so I don’t know all the details either, but...
It seems like everyone has Rare Skills, right?
Tia, is something
bothering you?
Not really.
I see.
Well, see you later then.
Riot Force 6’s combat strength is more than just “invincible”: it’s utterly abnormal.
I don’t know what trick Commander Yagami used, but
the captains are all S+ rank,
and even the lieutenants are at least AA rank.
All of the other soldiers,
from the front-line troops to the control operators,
are nothing but future elites.
Then there’s Erio, who’s already B rank,
and Caro, who’s a rare and powerful dragon summoner...
Both of them are Fate’s protégés.
Though Subaru may be dangerous at times, she’s full of potential and latent talent,
and she has a kind family backing her up.
I knew it! The only average person in our unit is me.
But that doesn’t matter.
I can’t let that stop me.
So that’s the place.
The thing you’re looking for, it’s not here, is it?
Is something bothering you?
The doctor’s toys seem to be getting closer.
Klarwind’s sensor is reacting.
Shari!
Right!
They’re coming! They’re here!
Gadget Drones: Type 1 land models sighted, 30... 35!
Type 3 land models, 2... 3... 4!
Erio, Caro, head back up.
Teana’s team will create
the defensive line in front of the hotel.
Yes, ma’am!
Zafira will go and intercept them with me.
Understood.
Zafira, you can talk?
You scared me!
The center of our defensive net will be you guys.
We’re counting on you.
U-Understood!
I’ll do my best.
All front-line soldiers,
we’re using a wide-area defensive setup,
together with Long Arch 1’s general surveillance.
I, Shamal, will take command of the scene.
Stars 3, roger!
Lightning F, roger!
Stars 4, roger!
Dr. Shamal, I’d like to see the situation as well.
Can you let me look at the front-line monitors?
Roger, I’ll connect Cross Mirage to the monitors.
Klarwind, can you please?
Yes.
Ja.
Signum, Vita?
Stars 2 and Lightning 2, heading out!
Device locks released.
Graf Eisen, Lævateinn, approved for level 2 maneuvers.
Graf Eisen!
Lævateinn!
Start up.
Anfang.
We can’t let any units make it to the newbies’ defensive line.
We’ll smash them to bits there.
You’re surprisingly protective.
Shut up!
Fate, what did the chairman say?
We’ve told him about the situation outside,
but evacuating and interrupting the auction would be a problem.
They’ll delay the opening a bit
and see how things are from there.
I see.
I’ll smash the big one.
Can you take the small ones?
Of course.
Let’s go, Eisen!
Roger!
Jawohl!
Smash them all
to pieces!
Lævateinn.
Explosion
Glittering...
...Swordflash
You shall not pass!
The lieutenants and Zafira—they’re amazing!
This is with an ability limiter?
Good day, Knight Zest, Lutecia.
Good day.
What do you want?
How cold! You’re watching
the situation from nearby, aren’t you?
It doesn’t seem like a Relic is at that hotel,
but there is one thing that is of great interest to my experiments.
I don’t suppose I could ask for your cooperation for a little while?
For you, it’s really something very simple, but...
I refuse.
As long as it doesn’t concern a Relic,
we agreed to not get involved with each other.
How about you, Lutecia?
May I ask you to do this for me?
Fine.
You’re so kind.
Thanks.
This time for certain, I’ll treat you to tea and treats.
I’ve sent your Device, Asclepius,
the data on what I want.
Well, good day, Doctor.
Indeed, good day.
I’ll be waiting for the good news.
Are you sure?
Zest, although you and Agito hate the doctor,
I don’t dislike him that much.
I see.
What I seek...
Caro, what’s wrong?
Someone’s using a summoning spell nearby.
Klarwind’s sensor also reacted to it.
But this mana signautre...
I-It’s big!
O small ones, ones that flap their wings,
answer my words and heed my command.
Summoning
Insect Platoon
Insektzug
Mission: object control.
Have a nice trip. Be careful, okay?
W-What the?
What?
They’re suddenly moving better.
Those aren’t the movements of automated machines.
They completely changed their allies’ abilities!
Is it that summoner’s magic from before?
Vita, fall back to the defensive line.
If that summoner is over there,
the new recruits might be in danger.
U-Understood.
Zafira, meet up
with Signum.
Understood.
It’s as amazing as I thought...
That girl’s power.
Control of autonomic machines with
her small summons, “object controllers.”
That’s only a tiny fragment of her power.
Matter translocation: eleven objects.
Teleport.
Incoming summon!
It’s coming!
Is that...
...a summoning circle?
Summoning can even do things like this?
A great summoner can also be a master of teleportation magic.
What does it matter? Let’s go and intercept them!
Let’s do it!
It’s the same as it has been up until now.
It’ll be okay if I can show results.
I’ll prove my skill and bravery,
just like I’ve always done before.
Such a powerful summoner!
Even if I can’t defeat them myself, at least I need to see who they are.
Silver-colored bugs?
Command Sergeant
Major Rein,
lots of those bugs are
appearing from
the direction
of the summoner.
It’s dangerous for you
to go alone.
Evade them and join up
with the new recruits.
Okie-doke!
I’ve found what the doctor was looking for.
Galue, could you do me a little favor?
The children in our way are being distracted by the Insects.
Use this chance to secure the object.
Be careful.
Barret F
Tia!
Defensive line, hold out
for a bit longer, okay?
Yes, ma’am!
Lt. Vita will be back soon!
Just defending won’t solve anything.
I’ll be sure to take them out!
Wai—Teana, are you okay?
Don’t do anything rash!
Psh. I’m fine.
This is why I’ve been practicing every day: morning, noon, and night.
Erio, fall back to the center.
Subaru and I will go two-top.
O-Okay!
Subaru, Cross Shift A! Let’s go!
Right!
I’ll prove it.
Even without special talents or
an impressive amount of magical power,
even in a unit with first-class leadership,
no matter how dangerous the battle,
I, the bullet of the Lansters,
will definitively strike down any enemy.
Teana, it’s reckless to load so many.
Both for you and for Cross Mirage!
I’ll be able to fire.
Yes.
Crossfire...
...Shoot
Lt. Vita!
Teana, you stupid idiot!
You were reckless and almost hit an ally,
what were you thinking!?
Uh, Lt. Vita, we were doing a combination attack, and...
What’s wrong with you?
That would have been a direct hit!
That’s not it! It was my fault, I—
Shut up, morons!
That’s enough.
I’ll do the rest myself.
Both of you, get your asses out of the way!
Is someone there?
This place is dangerous!
What’s this?
Galue, mission clear. Good boy.
Now, take it to the doctor.
What was the object he wanted?
I don’t know. It wasn’t something
being auctioned, so probably smuggled goods.
I see.
The battle’s almost over.
The front-line knights fought quite well.
Well then, let’s continue searching for what you were looking for.
Sorry to have kept you waiting, the auction will begin shortly.
Thanks to the front-line troops, the Gadgets were all intercepted,
but unfortunately we couldn’t chase after the summoner.
There haven’t been any injuries to our members,
and the mission itself was a success.
I’d say job well done.
I have sent an inquiry to nearby observation units.
I think we’ll at least be able to find their transportation route.
Young lady over there,
the auction has already started, you know.
Are you sure you don’t need to go inside?
Thank you for your kindness.
But unfortunately, I’m actually here as a part of my work.
Unlike a certain casual Inspector, I’m pretty busy.
Did you ditch your work and go playing around again, Inspector Acous?
How mean! I’m also in the middle of work, Hayate.
Now then, for an expert opinion and analysis on the items,
I’d like to introduce our young archaeologist.
A native Midchildan scholar and Chief Librarian of the Infinity Library,
Dr. Yuuno Scrya!
Thank you and good afternoon.
Yuuno!
Finally, they’re all destroyed.
Same here. We couldn’t find the summoner though.
However, now that we know they’re there,
we can devise countermeasures.
True.
Do you know where Teana is?
Yes, ma’am. She’s guarding the back of the building.
Subaru’s with her.
Tia, it seems everything’s over on the other side.
I’ll stay on guard here. You go on ahead.
You know, Tia...
It’s okay, go on.
Tia, that wasn’t your fault at all!
If I’d been paying more—
Didn’t I tell you to go!?
Sorry. I’ll see you later then, Tia.
I... I...
Without end, the dreams continue to weave
Surpassing thousands of nights
Like a prayer, the journey continues
Be my guide any day, oh small jewel
Spica among the stars
I engrave beyond the horizon
The faint footsteps that are connected to everywhere
The reflection of your eyes casts away the loop of anxiety
The midnight sun
The Orion of Midsummer
Just now from somewhere, I heard your voice
This heart without darkness
Illumine it, o distant blue star
No matter what the time, I will be able to start walking
Sparkling far and near
Watching over me
The thing inside my heart, overflowing
More than tears, I want to be loved
Like a prayer, the journey continues
Be my guide anyday, oh small jewel
Spica among the stars
Next
Episode
Preview
Next
Episode
Preview
Regret and sadness
can be turned into
the power to stand up.
We had always walked together like that.
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS:
Episode 8: A Wish for the Pair
Episode 8
A Wish for the Pair
Because I’m Tia’s partner!