After the last battle with the combat cyborgs,
we haven’t been sent out
on any more emergency deployments for some reason.
Along with Ginny who transferred to Riot Force 6,
we’ve been training, training and training some more.
Vivio’s started to smile a lot,
and Nanoha seems somewhat happy as well.
The forward team and
the lieutenants are also doing really well.
I kind of feel like we’ll be invincible no matter what comes at us.
So, Dad, we’re doing fine.
I’ll write you again.
Love, Subaru.
The hot comet dwelling within my heart beats towards the beginning.
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
My fingers tremble, grasping upon a silent wish
I cower, wanting to flee from the inescapable past
Even if it is merely a faint light fading
I want to chase after it, just like that star
And accept everything, no matter how high it is
An angel’s whisper dancing throughout the galaxy
Pursuing these certain memories
The door to the truth will surely be born now
No matter what kind of cold darkness binds me
Because I want to know
I won’t be stopped
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Episode 16
That Day, Riot Force 6
(part 1)
September 11, Riot Force 6 HQ, 7:14 PM
So, tomorrow the public press conference finally begins.
The area’s already been locked down in preparation for the conference at 1400 hours tomorrow.
Captain Nanoha and Lieutenant Vita,
along with Command Sergeant Major Rein
and the four forwards, will be heading out now.
They’ll start guard on a night shift.
Everyone, have you rested up well?
Yes, ma’am!
Captain Fate, Lt. Signum, and I shall step in early in the morning.
Until then, I’ll leave it up to you.
Yes, ma’am.
Oh, Marie’s coming as well?
I’m doing something else.
I have a bit of business in the central region.
Eh? Vivio, what’s wrong?
It’s dangerous here.
Sorry, Captain Nanoha, she said she wanted to see you off no matter what.
You can’t do that, Vivio.
Dragging Aina out here was very selfish of you.
I’m sorry.
Nanoha, it’s her first time seeing you go out on night shift. I’m sure she’s nervous.
Oh, I see.
Mama Nanoha will be staying out tonight, but I’ll be back tomorrow night for sure.
You will?
I definitely will.
If you wait like a good girl, Vivio,
I’ll make you the caramel milk you like.
Promise Mama, okay?
Well, let’s go back, Vivio.
We’re also departing in nine hours.
Let’s clean up what we were working on and hurry to bed.
Yes, I’ll give the orders to the unit on shift.
If you would.
Even so, Vivio’s become really attached to you.
Honestly.
You’re right.
I’ve tried to be pretty strict with her, but...
I’m sure she understands that you’re really nice, Nanoha.
Well, you might as well officially accept her as your child, Nanoha.
We’re still looking for a household who will take her in.
If we find a nice place,
and Vivio is all right with going there...
I have a feeling she won’t be.
Ditto.
Well, I’d be happy if I was with her forever,
but if we do find a good place for her, I’ll convince her.
She’s a good girl, after all.
Because I want her to be happy.
Well... um...
Until we find a home for her, I’ll continue to protect her and be her guardian.
And that’s definitely for sure.
You’re right.
Yes.
And we’re done.
Huh?
It’s my mom.
Director-General, Time-Space Administrative Bureau Main Office
Lindy Harlaown
Hi! Have you been doing well?
Yes. Good evening, Mom.
Vivio, you too, good evening!
Good evening!
Is something going on?
About tomorrow’s press conference,
I was wondering if I should show my face.
Oh, I think it’ll be okay.
Chrono is in the middle of another mission.
Others from the Main Office won’t really be there.
Well, you see, I’d like to see my daughter’s face again, and I’d like to meet Vivio.
You know, Mom, I’ll be on security detail,
and Vivio will be at the dorms.
Oh, I see. You’re right.
We haven’t been able to see
each other for a while, so it’s been lonely.
You’ll be all right.
Mama Lindy is Mama Fate’s mama.
This mama is also Mama Fate’s mama.
That’s right.
In the Testarossa family,
there’s my mother Presea and my big sister Alicia.
In the Harlaown family, there’s my mother Lindy,
my big brother Chrono, and all the rest.
Presea gave life to me,
and Lindy is still raising me even now.
I’m sorry, that was confusing, wasn’t it?
In other words, I have two mothers.
Just like me?
Yep, just like you.
September 12, Central Bureau Surface HQ, 2:35 AM
Oh, what’s up?
I got some tea from the other security forces,
so I thought I’d bring you some.
Oh, how nice, thanks.
Here you go.
How’s everyone else doing?
They’re at the far end of the security line.
They’re just relaxing, taking turns in shifts.
Can I stand here with you?
Go ahead.
I think this might have been a bit rude, but...
I looked into you a bit.
You were supposedly an ace-tier mage some years back.
What? An ace?
My magical point values were only half yours.
Even so, you were an expert at
outrange shooting, an outstanding sniper.
The past is the past. I’m Riot Force 6’s helicopter pilot now.
It’s not a story which will be of any use to you.
Besides, now is not the time to
be thinking about worthless stuff.
If you space out, you’ll screw up
another shot and start crying about it, idiot.
I’m sorry. I’ll be careful.
If you understand, that’s fine. Go.
I’m going.
It’s an old story. Isn’t that right, Storm Raider?
I think so.
In any event, it’s time for me to head inside.
Yes, ma’am.
And it seems while we’re guarding the inside,
we can’t bring our Devices.
So Subaru, can I leave Raising Heart to you?
Y-Yes, ma’am!
The rest of you front-line soldiers should hang on
to the Devices for the rest of the captains.
Yes, ma’am!
September 12, 11:55 AM
There’s only three hours left until
the Public Conference on Opinions begins.
The purpose of this conference is the exchange of ideas
in regards to the management of
the Bureau on Midchilda’s surface
between representatives for the HQ and the Main Office, as well as other worlds.
And many people will be paying close attention to the announcements by Surface HQ,
which is a frequent subject of heated controversy.
In particular, there has long been dispute over the use of the G.A.S.’s Defense Interception System,
Einherjar, and it is believed that this issue will be discussed.
Until the conference starts, we will continue with our live feed, as well as updates on the situation.
Oh, it’s started, hasn’t it?
Yeah.
At this point, it doesn’t seem like anything’s going to happen.
Don’t let your guard down.
Do your job and keep watch.
Yes, ma’am!
Even so...
I don’t really get it.
If things happen according to the prophecy, the chances of an internal coup d’état are low.
It’s not possible based on the data Inspector Acous acquired for us.
So, then, it’ll be external terrorism.
If so, what are they after?
The culprit before was that loser
who was collecting the Relics, Scaglietti, right?
Yeah.
If it’s the same dude and his crew this time,
we definitely don’t know what they’re after.
Just how do they benefit by attacking this base?
If he’s a weapon developer,
he might want to prove the might of his creations.
If he can prove that he has the firepower or weaponry to destroy the HQ, there are many that would want such a thing.
But if he wants to prove his power,
then there are many other places where he could do it.
This would be too risky.
You’re right.
So I have no clue.
Well, there’s no use thinking about it too much.
We are given orders from superiors we trust.
Let’s just follow that.
Sounds good.
It’s been a little over fours hours since it’s started.
It should almost be over inside.
Let’s do our best until the end!
Right!
Where did Ginga go?
She went to the north entrance to give a report.
I don’t feel so great relying on the others.
Even so, it’s a valuable opportunity.
If we’re able to clean everything up today,
that would be for the best.
I guess.
Actually, I’m worried about Lulu.
I wonder if she’ll be okay.
If you’re worried about Lutecia, then you can just go to her.
But this time I’m concerned about you, sir!
Lulu still has her bugs and Galue with her,
but you’re alone, sir.
Your target is this beardo, right?
I’m just going to follow until then.
I’ll protect you, sir.
It’s up to you.
Do as you wish.
And I will.
You are my savior, after all, sir.
The Numbers from Number III, Tre,
to Number XII, Deed, are all in position.
The young lady and Zest are in position as well.
All preparations for attack are complete.
Only thing that’s left is to wait for the signal.
Yes.
Seems like you’re having fun.
I am.
It’s the moment I change
this planet’s history with these hands.
As a researcher and engineer,
it’s obvious I’d be overflowing with joy.
Isn’t that right, Uno?
We’ll show something special to our sponsor.
The result of our feelings, research, and development.
Well, let us begin!
Yes, sir.
Mission start!
Asclepius, release limiter.
An energy signature?
What? That can’t be right.
There’s an abnormality in
the communication control system.
It’s being hacked? Someone’s breaking in!
This can’t be!
Quattro’s I.S.: Silver Curtain.
Lies and illusions woven from electricity.
Enjoy the play on my silver screen!
It’s not just our transmitter?
There’s something wrong with the transmission system itself!
Deploy the emergency defenses!
Hurry and start up the backup search system!
To think that they would really target HQ!
Execute I.S.: Rumble Detonator
Output power of the defensive barrier is falling.
Miss Lu, if you would please.
Initiating remote summon.
I.S.: Heavy Barrel
Barret Image: Aerosol Shell
Fire!
Evacuate! Evacuate! Evacuate!
What’s going on?
We’re taking fire.
We won’t stop the conference.
Take action as quickly as possible.
Sir!
Surface HQ’s defenses are perfect.
There isn’t anyone who can get past them.
There’s no real need to get all the way inside
if we just surround you and keep you powerless.
So we’ve been locked in?
There’s a highly dense A.M.F.
Magic can’t be concentrated.
Transmissions won’t get through either.
We’ve been had.
Sette, this is your first battle.
There’s no need for worry.
I wasn’t born late for no reason.
Execute I.S.
Slaughter Arms
Ride Impulse
Action!
The gas isn’t a lethal type, but rather a paralyzing one.
I’m sending the defense data to you now.
The jamming’s strong.
Long Arch!
The situation outside has stopped for the time being,
but the situation inside is unknown.
Lieutenant, we’ll head inside.
We have to rescue Nanoha and everyone else.
There are aerial units heading toward HQ.
They’re fast!
Ranks are estimated to be S+.
Rein!
Righty-o!
Rein and I will head up.
These guys will handle Surface HQ.
I’ll leave these to you as well.
Make sure it gets to them.
Ma’am!
Rein, it’s Unison time!
Yes indeedy!
Unison in!
Please calm down!
Everything is okay over here.
There’s no need to worry!
The bulkheads to the meeting room
and the emergency exits are all completely sealed.
There’s no way to contact our allies either.
The elevator’s down as well.
There’s no way to get in contact with those trapped inside either.
In any event, we can’t just sit here.
It might get kind of messy, but want to come with me, Fate?
Of course.
Oh yeah, this should do.
We haven’t done this since
the G.A.S. Training Course.
It sure helps to do a lot of different training.
You’re right.
Orders were given on how to move if an emergency occurs.
Our goal is to meet up at the designated location in the underground passageways, the Rotary Hall.
On it.
This is the Bureau.
Permission for your flight has not been granted,
and your I.F.F is not recognized.
This voice is...
Please stop immediately.
If you proceed any further, we will intercept.
You ass!
Blazing Spheres
Brennenkugel
Physical shots?
Giant Hammer
Giganthammer
We missed. Their counterattack and defenses blocked it.
But the damage made it through.
Let’s go and smash them up.
Dammit.
They hit us as hard as they could.
Sorry, Agito. You saved me.
Not at all.
They’re a Unison-type.
The same as us, eh?
This is Lieutenant Vita
of the Bureau’s Riot Force 6 Stars Squad.
Zest.
Mach Caliber!
Protection
Subaru!
Nove, you didn’t forget anything we had to do?
Shut up, I didn’t forget anything.
Our capture targets were those three. We are to bring all of them back alive.
Even if they are old, can a Type-0 really be taken down this easily?
Combat cyborgs.
We’re all done here, right?
We’ll head to the next one.
Yes, young lady, the place where the unconfirmed Relic
and the Vessel of the Holy King is believed to be held.
Riot Force 6.
This can’t be! Two large energy signatures
approaching us at high speed!
Standby unit, prepare to intercept.
Send a notice for support to the nearby units.
Yes, sir!
All hands, highest alert status.
Support staff, please hurry with your evacuation.
Etched into this amulet, these precious times
In my precious days
“The bluebird ran away”
I cried, embracing the empty cage
I still remember the color of the high-rising sky
That I looked up at that day
Rewinding
Inside my memories
In painful times, in happy times
You were always there at important times
The thing which I looked for to the ends of the labyrinth
Is deep within my heart
Etched into this amulet, these precious times
Soft and secret pieces of my memory
No matter what type of tomorrow it is, I can walk towards it
In my precious days
Next
Episode
Preview
Next
Episode
Preview
Things I wanted to protect,
and things I had to protect.
Things that are starting to crack, and things that will disappear.
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS:
Episode 17: That Day, Riot Force 6 (part 2)
Episode 17
That Day, Riot Force 6
(part 2)
Take off!