The Gadgets and combat cyborgs launched an attack on Surface HQ.
The attack was brilliantly executed, paralyzing HQ within minutes.
It was as if they knew everything about the facility and its defenses.
During the battle with the combat cyborgs, Ginga was kidnapped, and Subaru was badly wounded.
And with its forces deployed,
the defenseless Riot Force 6 HQ was destroyed,
with the remaining members left gravely wounded.
Erio and Caro were shot down, and Vivio was kidnapped.
It’s the worst possible situation. What’s going to happen to us?
And what about Subaru?
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
The things that I can do for you and no one else
I honestly feel and wish for those
I am frozen by uncertainties
By the rules I have been relying on
My past embellished with excuses
I want to get over it
Staining the stars in heaven scarlet
Gather the grains of miracles
Before the still, unseen night
I want to tell you that I am escaping from illusions
The twilight moon calls out to me
Removing my veil of delusions
My hidden, deceitful self
And took all of my weaknesses
I don’t want words that seem passionate
The fact that I’m here right now is my truth
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
We’re on the scene above
the Time-Space Administrative Bureau’s
Midchilda Surface HQ,
which was attacked by terrorists yesterday.
There’s been no announcement from
the Bureau regarding the details of the incident,
the damage to the facility, or the number of casualties.
There seems to have been a message from
the responsible group immediately after the incident,
But the Public Relations Department has said that it’ll only release it after detailed analysis.
Why?
Why in the ever-loving hell is this happening?
Have you been able to contact that son of a bitch?
The line’s been changed,
and the research facility is empty.
We’ve given him more than enough funding up until now, so why?
Where the hell did Auris get to!?
She’s working on a counterplan.
She’s discussing matters with the security division and the other parties involved.
Lt. Colonel Yagami, a pleasure to see you.
Major Auris, may I speak to you for a moment later on?
There’s something I want to ask you.
I have a conference now. I’ll contact you when I’m free.
Very well.
Episode 18
Wings Anew
It’s a mess.
Lt. Signum, how were things at the hospital?
All the wounded members have made it through the worst.
Is that so?
I’m glad.
Where’s Captain Takamachi?
Inside.
How is she?
The same as always.
She’s performing her work well.
Once she’d confirmed that Vivio was kidnapped
and that the wounded members were taken care of,
she hasn’t even taken a break.
Really?
I’ll take care of this.
You get to the hospital too.
B-But...
Go see her.
Yes, ma’am.
Nanoha, it’s Teana.
Ah. What is it?
Lt. Signum has taken over for me.
I’m going to the hospital for a while.
Okay.
Captain Fate should be heading there as well.
All right.
Um... may I tell Subaru and Shari what you told me earlier?
Sure.
If you think it’ll cheer them up, tell them.
I’ll leave the choice to you.
Understood. I’ll be back later.
Okay. Take care.
I’m sorry. I’m so sorry.
I was in charge while you were gone, and I still couldn’t protect them.
It’s not your fault, Shari.
Don’t cry.
About Vivio, how am I going to apologize to Nanoha and everyone?
Don’t force yourself.
You were hurt really badly.
I’m fine.
Compared to Zafira, my wounds were light.
Zafira shielded me from the worst of it.
Me too.
Rein protected me.
If I hadn’t been in Unison with Rein, I’d be worm food now.
I heard from Marie.
Rein will wake up tonight.
But Zafira will take a while to fully recover.
And Vice...
Even if he’s through the worst, for a long time he’ll...
Tia.
I brought you some snacks.
None of you have really eaten, right?
Thank you so much.
Thanks, Tia.
You can move your arm now...
The nerve cables got fried, so I can’t move it well yet.
They say it’ll be back to normal in a few days.
I see.
How much have you told the kids?
About how Ginny and I were born, stuff like that...
Sorry to keep it from you.
I’m the one who told her not to tell you, that she should keep the truth about her body a secret for a while.
Not at all.
Erio.
Oh. Right.
Subaru, do you want some hot soup?
They’re selling it at the cafeteria. I’ll get some.
We’ll be back.
Tia, I’m sorry.
What are you sorry for?
For running ahead instead of listening to Nanoha and me?
Or that you got yourself
badly hurt and made everyone worry?
All of it.
You better apologize to Mach Caliber later too.
She’s in pretty bad shape.
Yeah...
Hey, Ginga’s still alive, right?
I think she can come back from that level of damage.
They were talking about recovering the Type-0s, so I don’t think they’ll...
...kill her, right?
Then you’ve got a chance to save her.
Nanoha was saying that she thinks that after this,
we’ll be changing our mission from
looking for the Relics to chasing after Scaglietti.
What happened to Ginga bothers me too.
But if Riot Force 6 is going to act, then we can save her as a team.
Erio, Caro, the captains,
and the Long Arch are upset too
that they lost what was important
to them and that they couldn’t protect it.
So this time we won’t fail them.
We’ll protect them and take back what was stolen.
We’ll save her.
We’ll save everyone.
So what did you want to ask me?
About Lt. General Regius Gaiz’s work.
A large portion of that information is classified.
There’s very little I can tell you as an individual.
Can I just ask?
Well, where I should begin?
Start with the Combat Cyborg Incident
that you were in charge of.
Including Ginga and Subaru if you can, and their mom.
The basic idea behind the combat cyborgs was to produce a humanoid combat machine.
This research has been around for a long time.
And by a long time,
I mean since the old calendar was in use.
A mechanical weapon created in the form of a human.
The idea’s been developed
on many worlds and in many forms,
but there aren’t many examples of it actually working.
Then the research underwent a dramatic evolution.
It was only 25 years ago.
The combination of machinery
and biotechnology is nothing special.
Artificial organs and bones
have been around for a long time.
But...
The function of those is to compensate for lost ability,
which is very different from strengthening that ability.
There are also problems with rejection and maintenance during long use.
But the combat cyborgs were different, you see.
Those bastards got around that problem by
screwing around with the genetic code of their subjects.
During birth, they would become the base for the combat cyborgs.
They are children, but modified
able to accept mechanical body parts.
He created technology to allow that to happen.
That would be Jail Scaglietti.
Eleven years ago, back before I knew that the man named Scaglietti was involved,
my wife was investigating the incident as a G.A.S. mage.
She managed to shut down an illegal research facility and capture some of the test units that had gone out of control.
Subaru and Ginga were experimental combat cyborgs that my wife saved while she was following the incident.
We couldn’t have kids.
She said that their faces and the color of their hair and eyes were like hers somehow.
Anyway, she said that she was going to raise them as our daughters, as humans.
There were some issues with maintenance,
cooperation with research, and the technology involved,
but they were both raised as normal girls.
They were both older when she died.
They said that she died during a secret mission.
The truth about the way she died is still classified.
I think she saw something she shouldn’t have and went somewhere she shouldn’t have been.
I’m glad she died the way she wanted, investigating a crime.
But I promised her that I’d raise Ginga and Subaru well.
Well, I kept looking into it. I figured one day I’d have a chance to charge those responsible.
Yagami figured that the combat cyborgs would
get involved with the matter she was dealing with,
and she asked me to help with it.
That’s one smart little girl!
Well, that’s about all there is to say about my wife and kids.
All that’s left is the joint investigation.
Ma’am?
Yes, sir.
Combat cyborgs, artificial mages...
Both of them are technologies that
Lt. General Regius tried to develop for the Bureau to use.
That was a long time ago.
A power that could be mass-produced in a stable environment.
If you could avoid having it shut down
for ethical violations and decrease the cost via mass production, it’s actually a very feasible plan.
Was Lt. General Regius continuing that project in secret somewhere?
Scaglietti was the ideal person to entrust that job to.
If he wasn’t an illegal researcher, there’s no doubt he’d go down in history as one of the greatest geniuses of all time.
I suspect that he arranged for Scaglietti to be offered a plea bargain and then waited for the right time.
It’s possible to set up a situation where Scaglietti would mass-produce artificial mages and combat cyborgs,
and Surface HQ would discover this and make it public.
If that were the case, upon being discovered,
it would also be simple enough to incorporate whatever was left into experimental usage.
Somewhere in there,
it’s also possible for an investigator who got
too close to discovering the truth to have an accident,
which would also cause several excellent artificial mage samples to be acquired.
I’ll ask you to refrain from telling me any more of your foolish delusions.
I’m merely interested in your opinion.
You’ve been in the Bureau for ten years, right?
That’s right.
The Lt. General has been here forty years.
And ten years ago, when you were causing
your knights to commit crimes out of fear for your life,
and when that source of the power that has raised you up to a lieutenant colonel at your age,
the Book of Darkness, that Lost Logia
that fused with you, was taking many lives,
the Lt. General was working to keep the peace.
I won’t deny the crimes I have committed, nor those of the Book of Darkness.
But if there’s a hidden truth here, I will bring it to light.
That’s my job now.
If you wish to investigate us, then either bring an investigative permit or a warrant.
Then we can talk.
I will, definitely.
There was a message from the Council earlier.
An emergency hearing will be held
concerning your conduct, Lieutenant General.
Einherjar’s operations are to be suspended as well.
It’s an emergency! Continue the operation!
Have the hearing put off!
I’m not going to be his puppet!
I’m the one who was controlling him!
If he’s going to go against us, then I’ll destroy him!
I’ll attend to it immediately.
Also, there’s something I’d like you to confirm immediately.
What?
This is an image of the U.F.O.
that was heading towards HQ yesterday.
An aerial mage stopped him, but this man...
Lt. General.
Lt. General!
Sir!
Sir.
I’m okay now.
Sorry
for scaring you.
I’m sorry, sir. It’s my fault for not being useful.
You did well.
That red knight was a good one,
including her use of her Unight.
You’re stronger than her, sir!
If you’d been at your best, sir,
and if I’d been more useful, she’d be no match!
This is my best now.
And you did your best as well.
Hey, Agito?
Can I have another glass of that medicine you made for me?
Yes!
Knight Zest, it’s Uno.
You seem unwell.
Don’t worry about me.
You don’t need me or the Relics anymore, do you?
That’s not true.
There are a few things I have left to do, that’s all.
Then I’ll die.
I don’t think I’ll interfere with your plans.
That’s very sad.
Even if there’s a difference between
you artificial mages and us combat cyborgs,
we should be friends.
I’m different from even you.
I’ve died once, and now I’m just a dead man living for a short time before he returns to the land once again.
Miss Lutecia finished her examination and tuning earlier.
She should be able to return to you soon.
I see.
Get well soon.
Sir, I brought your medicine.
Sein.
How’s Cinques?
Her basic frame has been badly damaged, it seems.
That girl—the second 0’s I.S., Oscillating Breaker,
is extremely effective against the electrical components in our bodies and frames.
Of course, I’m sure it’s pretty strong against normal objects or people as well.
A direct hit from that would be the end of any of us.
Nove, your right arm is going to need a lot of surgery too.
I see.
I’m fine, but Cinques got hit with a bunch of them.
Our original was born in a different way than us.
There’s no doubt that she’s made from the Doctor’s technology, but we don’t even know who made her.
I don’t really care about that, and it doesn’t really matter.
I’m going to demolish that girl with the hair ribbon
who did this to Cinques!
Don’t demolish her! We need to recover her.
And the ginger illusionist too.
If I hadn’t been so busy dealing with her...
We know, we know.
Let’s get her next time.
Quattro, the Doctor is calling.
Okay! Sein, keep an eye on Cinque, okay?
On it!
Oh, hey Miss Lu!
I’m XI, Wendi!
This is VIII, Otto, and XII, Deed!
So this is your mom, huh?
So it seems.
Seems?
I don’t remember her.
Uh, well... once we find the appropriate Relic core, she’ll come back to life, right?
That’s what the Doctor says.
If we find Serial XI, she’ll wake up.
And that if she awakens and becomes my mom,
then I’ll finally have a heart.
Hayate.
Verossa!
I’m sorry to keep you waiting.
I bet even you are a little down, huh, Hayate?
Well, I guess so.
It was a major failure,
with Ginga and Vivio getting kidnapped.
Several of my soldiers were hurt.
But we’ll take back what was stolen.
And this time I’ll protect them.
So even if she’s down, she’s still up for the job.
Pretty nice.
As Mistress of the Night Sky
and as the head of Riot Force 6, it’s natural.
But are you sure about this?
Since you and Chrono asked for it, Hayate,
I managed to get permission.
We need an HQ so that the staff will have somewhere to live.
And considering what’s coming, a mobile HQ is better.
Arthra, we’ll need you to do your best for us for just a little while longer before you go to sleep.
Nanoha?
Fate.
What are you doing out here?
Thinking about Vivio?
Yeah, I couldn’t keep my promise.
I said I’d be her mother, that I’d protect her.
But I couldn’t be by her side.
I couldn’t protect her.
I’m sure she’s crying now.
Nanoha.
When I think about Vivio crying alone,
and that maybe she’s sad or hurt,
my body shakes and I feel like I’m about to go crazy.
I want to go save her right now!
But I...
It’s okay.
Vivio is definitely okay.
Let’s save her together.
Okay, there we go.
Don’t be scared.
Vitals are fine.
Mana output stabilized.
Transplant preparations complete.
Perfect timing.
No! No!
The princess knows what’s about to happen to her.
Mama! Mama!
You can cry all you want,
but nobody’s going to come save you!
Now then, let’s begin.
We shall now bestow the royal mark
upon the Vessel of the Holy King.
Vivio, you shall be my masterpiece!
Mama!
Etched into this amulet, these precious times
In my precious days
“The bluebird ran away”
I cried, embracing the empty cage
I still remember the color of the high-rising sky
That I looked up at that day
Rewinding
Inside my memories
In painful times, in happy times
You were always there at important times
The thing which I looked for to the ends of the labyrinth
Is deep within my heart
Etched into this amulet, these precious times
Soft and secret pieces of my memory
No matter what type of tomorrow it is, I can walk towards it
In my precious days
Next
Episode
Preview
Next
Episode
Preview
With new wings,
Riot Force 6 rises again.
With resolve in their hearts,
they head for the sky and what appears there.
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS:
Episode 19: Cradle
Episode 19
Cradle
Take off.