It was only by chance,
but I found a place where I belong.
But even here, I know there will be days where we’ll be fighting, watching the sky.
Still, my hero is here.
And my closest friend is here with me too.
We’ve had many new encounters.
Eventually our feelings will reach the open sky.
Though the wall we must climb is far and tall,
our hearts are set on facing it.
All of us together.
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS
will now begin.
The hot comet dwelling within my heart beats towards the beginning.
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
My fingers tremble, grasping upon a silent wish
I cower, wanting to flee from the inescapable past
Even if it is merely a faint light fading
I want to chase after it, just like that star
And accept everything, no matter how high it is
An angel’s whisper dancing throughout the galaxy
Pursuing these certain memories
The door to the truth will surely be born now
No matter what kind of cold darkness binds me
Because I want to know
I won’t be stopped
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
Magical Girl
Lyrical
Nanoha
May 0075, 5:45 AM
Time-Space Administrative Bureau Antiquities Department
Riot Force 6 Headquarters
May 0075, 5:45 AM
Time-Space Administrative Bureau Antiquities Department
Riot Force 6 Headquarters
Dad, Ginny, how have you been? This is Subaru.
Barracks of same
Tia and I have been here at Riot Force 6
for two weeks already.
Good morning.
Mornin’.
We haven’t fully assembled yet,
so we four forwards are in the same class,
Training from breakfast all the way until dinner.
Not to mention we’re still on the lowest level of training.
Good morning, Fried.
The training provided by the unit’s instructor,
Nanoha, is rather difficult.
But if I can keep up,
I feel like I can become stronger and stronger.
As I’m on duty twenty-four hours a day now, I won’t be able to occasionally return home like I used to.
But I’m still planning on asking for leave, so I can return home on Mom’s anniversary.
Let’s go all out again today!
See ya! I’ll send another letter later.
Love, Subaru.
Episode 4
First Alert
Okay, fall in!
Yes, ma’am!
We’ll do one last exercise before we wrap up this morning’s training.
Does everyone feel up to it?
Yes, ma’am!
In that case, we’ll practice our shooting evasion.
Raising Heart!
All right.
Accel Shooter
I’ll be attacking for five minutes.
If you can avoid all of my attacks and get a clean hit on me, you’ll clear the exercise.
If any one of you are hit,
then all of you will have to start over.
Give it your best!
Yes, ma’am!
In this worn-out state, and with Nanoha attacking for five minutes,
Do you have any confidence you can evade her attacks?
None!
Same here.
In that case, let’s aim to get a hit in somehow.
Okay!
All right! Let’s go, Erio!
Okay, Subaru!
You’re all ready, right?
In that case...
Ready...
Go!
Everyone, be sure to evade!
We’ll beat her in two minutes!
Right!
Accelerate!
Snipe Shot
Silhouettes.
Not bad, Teana.
Good reaction time.
Subaru, you idiot!
That’s dangerous, you know!
Sorry!
Wait a sec, I’ll shoot them down for you.
Tia, a little help here!
Why now of all times!?
Here they come!
Please hear my wish, wings that ride the storm.
Anoint this knight with power to break through.
Boost Up: Acceleration
By the way, the acceleration is really sudden. Be careful!
No problem! Speed is my specialty.
Let’s go, Strada!
Erio! Now!
Here goes!
Spear Assault
Speerangriff
Erio!
He missed?
Mission complete.
Well done! Mission complete.
Really?
Look, you broke through the barrier
and even reached my Jacket.
Well, that’s all for this morning. Let’s clean up.
Yes, ma’am!
Now then, everyone seems to be getting used to working as a team.
Thank you very much!
Teana’s tactics are becoming more and more reliable.
Would you like to take squad leader training?
Not really. I’m already fully occupied with combat training.
Fried, what’s wrong?
Something smells burnt.
Subaru, your blades!
Wha?
O-oh crap! Aw man...
Now I’ve done it! I pushed them too hard.
Did they overheat?
Have the maintenance staff look at them later.
Yes, ma’am.
Teana, your Anchor Gun has been having problems too?
Yes. I’m using every trick I’ve got.
Everyone’s been using the training equipment.
I guess it’s time to switch to the new Devices for active combat.
New...
...Devices?
Okay, use the facility’s shower,
change your clothes, and meet up in the lobby.
Yes, ma’am!
That car is...
Fate, Commander Yagami!
Incredible!
So this is Captain Fate’s car?
That’s right. I use it for getting around while on the ground.
How’s everyone’s training coming along?
We’re doing our best.
Erio, Caro, I’m sorry. I’m your captain, but I haven’t been looking after you two.
No, not at all.
We’re doing fine.
The four of them are all looking good
and getting the hang of it.
They should be good to deploy at any time.
Is that so? That’s reassuring to hear.
Are you two going out somewhere?
Yeah, just to Port Six.
I’m going to talk to Carim at the Cathedral.
I’ll be back before evening.
I’ll be back before lunch.
Would everyone like to eat lunch together?
Yes, ma’am!
See you then!
A mage-knight with the Church of the Holy King’s Knights,
and a board member of the Bureau’s Main Office, Carim Gracia, huh?
I’ve never met her before.
I guess you haven’t, huh?
How long have you known her, Hayate?
When I was first summoned to work with the Church Knights, Rein was only just born, so...
...around eight years.
I see.
Carim and I usually have completely different beliefs, positions, and tasks that we undertake.
But this time our objectives are the same.
Carim was actually the one responsible for getting Riot Force 6 off the ground.
Is that so?
Thanks to her I’m able to concentrate on gathering personnel.
So she feels like a trustworthy superior?
Her job and abilities are really impressive,
but she doesn’t feel much like a superior.
If I had to choose, I’d say she’s more like a big sister.
I see.
Well, after we take care of the Relic Incident, I’ll make sure to introduce you to her.
I’m sure you two will get along well with her, both you and Nanoha.
Sure. I’ll be looking forward to it.
Hey, Subaru, your rollerblades,
and your gun, Tia, are both homemade, right?
That’s right.
In training school and my last unit, we were only provided staves.
I use Belkan magic...
it suits my fighting style better.
Tia said she wanted to use a Cartridge System also.
So we had no choice but to make them ourselves.
The training school didn’t have original Device users, so we kind of stood out.
Ohhh.... is that how you became friends?
It was the start of my days of agony and
our inseparable relationship that I never wanted.
Now then Caro, want me to wash your hair?
Please do!
I’m heading out first.
Okay!
Is everyone done yet?
Northern Midchilda
Belkan Autonomous Territory
Grand Cathedral, Church of the Holy King
Northern Midchilda
Belkan Autonomous Territory
Grand Cathedral, Church of the Holy King
Knight Carim, Knight Hayate has arrived.
She arrived rather quickly, didn’t she?
Please send her to my office.
Yes, ma’am.
Also, bring some of tea, please. A nice brew of first leaf with milk and sugar, please.
Certainly, Milady.
All right.
Please come in.
Carim! Long time no see.
Hayate, welcome.
Sorry it’s been so long since I last visited.
Don’t worry about it.
Looks like the unit is progressing well.
Thanks to you, Carim.
If you say that, then it’ll be easier to ask you for a favor.
What’s that? Today’s appointment was to request a favor?
Gadgets? New models?
Besides the one we already know,
there are two new models.
Their combat abilities are still unknown, but the third type here is rather large.
I haven’t formally reported this to the Main Office yet.
I want to at least let Admiral Chrono know about this problem.
This is...!
This is why I arranged for us to meet today.
We discovered it the day before last,
being transported to Midchilda.
That’s a Relic, isn’t it?
There’s a very good chance it is.
Types II and III were discovered yesterday as well.
How long do you think we have until the Gadgets find the Relic?
From our reports, it could be as soon as today or tomorrow.
You’re right, but it’s strange. It seems way too soon for a Relic to appear again.
That’s why I wanted to talk to you:
to figure out how to judge and react to this.
We can’t afford to botch the Relic Incident—or any of the incidents that are bound to follow.
Hayate?
Well, no matter what happens, everything will work out.
Because you’ve lent us your strength, Carim, the unit is now ready to deploy at any time.
Of course, the captains were ready from the start, but the new forwards are also combat ready.
If unexpected situations or emergencies arise,
we’ll be able to deal with them.
That’s why it’ll all work out!
Ah, these are...
Are these our new Devices?
That’s right!
I’m the designer, with help from Nanoha, Fate, Raising Heart, and Command Sergeant Major Rein.
Strada and Kerykeion don’t seem to be any different though.
I’m not sure about that.
Bzzzt!
Only the outside appearance is unchanged.
Rein!
Yes indeedy!
Because you two haven’t had any real experience with Devices before,
we used only the basic frame and provided only minimal functions to let you get used to the feeling.
T-Those had minimal functions?
Really?
The four Devices that you will be using are
the latest creations by Riot Force 6’s front-line troops
and the mechanics team, after combining their experience and expertise,
to meet this unit’s objectives.
Also, Erio and Caro, Subaru and Tia, to meet your needs,
we’ve made the best Devices we could come up with!
These children have only just been born,
but they’ve been entrusted with a lot of people’s hopes and dreams.
After a really long time, they are finally complete.
Don’t just think of them as just tools or weapons.
Treat them as if they were precious.
But please, use them at their full potential!
I’m sure they’d want you to do that as well.
Sorry, sorry. Thank you for waiting.
Nanoha!
Nice timing. I was just about to explain how to use them.
Really? They’ll soon be in usable condition, right?
Yep!
First, they all have several stages of power limiters installed in them.
The first stage won’t be so powerful as to surprise you. So get used to using that first.
And when you’re able to handle the current power efficiently,
depending on my, Captain Fate, Rein,
or Shari’s judgment, we’ll release a limiter.
You can think of it as levelling up together.
Just curious... these power limiters... you and the others have them too, right, Nanoha?
Yes, but in our case, it’s not just for our Devices but for us physically as well.
With a limiter?
They’re called ability limiters.
All of our captains and lieutenants have one.
Captain Fate and I, Lieutenants Signum and Vita...
Hayate too.
Right.
You know! To prevent jealously between units,
the brass balances the mage ranks of each unit evenly.
Oh, yeah! That’s right.
In cases where many excellent mages are in one unit,
ability limiters are used to keep the peace.
Well, there are still some that play dirty.
In our case, Commander Hayate
is four ranks down,
and we captains are something like two ranks down.
Four? Commander Yagami should be SS rank, so...
She was dropped to A rank?
Hayate-chan has it tough with many things too.
What about you, Nanoha?
I’m normally S+. So two ranks down, and I’m AA.
So I might have a tough time alone against all of you soon.
The captains require Hayate’s permission,
but Hayate needs permission from her direct superior Carim,
or from the unit’s inspector, Admiral Chrono. Otherwise, we can’t remove the limiters.
And it doesn’t seem that easy to get approval either.
Is that so?
Well, you can keep the talk about
the captains in a corner of your mind.
Right now, it’s about your Devices.
Okay.
Yes, ma’am.
The new Devices are tuned using your training data,
So even if you jump into using them, they shouldn’t feel out of place.
Let’s use this afternoon’s training for testing and re-adjusting.
They can do self-adjustments,
so it should be mostly taken care of.
The latest ones sure are convenient.
Convenient they are!
In Subaru’s case, Revolver Knuckle’s synchro function has been set.
Really?
To make it easier to carry, a storage and instant boot function were installed.
Thank you!
Yeah, Hayate should have already arrived.
Okay, thanks for your hard work.
After this I’m planning on going to visit Public Safety’s investigation office.
Do you have any urgent tasks or anything?
No, we’re fine over here.
The lieutenants have deployed with the reserve forces, but Nanoha is here in the office.
I see.
This alert is...
First alert warning!
Griffith!
Ma’am! It’s a deployment request from Church headquarters.
Captain Nanoha, Captain Fate,
Griffith, this is Hayate.
What’s the situation?
The item the Church investigators were after,
a Relic-like object, has been found.
It’s located in the Mountain District.
The item is moving along the Third Linear Rail.
Moving?
It can’t be!
Yes, it can. The intruding Gadgets have caused the vehicle to go out of control.
In the worst-case scenario, there could be thirty machines other than the Linear Rail ones.
Two new types might appear as well: a large type and an unknown type.
It’ll be a difficult mission for starters, but Nanoha, Fate, can you do it?
I can go any time.
Me too.
Subaru, Teana, Erio, Caro!
Is everyone else ready as well?
Yes, ma’am!
Yes, good reply.
Shift A-3, Griffith will take command.
Rein will observe the situation.
Yes, ma’am!
Nanoha and Fate will take command at the scene.
Right!
In that case,
Riot Force 6 forward squads:
Move out!
Yes ma’am!
Roger! Everyone go on ahead. I’ll catch up soon.
Got it!
Schach, take Hayate all the way to
Riot Force 6’s headquarters as quickly as possible.
Acknowledged, Knight Carim.
Go to the church’s back door.
Schach will be waiting.
OK.
Thanks a lot, Carim. Today’s tea was delicious.
Well then, I’m off.
Even though we’re using the new Devices without testing,
they should be just like the ones from training.
Okay.
We’ll do our best.
Erio, Caro, and Fried, hang in there!
Yes, ma’am!
If it gets dangerous, make sure you follow what Captain Fate, Rein, or I say.
Keep your wits about you,
and see this all the way through!
Yes, ma’am!
Are you okay?
Sorry, I’m okay.
Nice to meet you!
Although it may be a bit sudden,
let’s do our best together, buddy!
Without end, the dreams continue to weave
Surpassing thousands of nights
Like a prayer, the journey continues
Be my guide any day, oh small jewel
Spica among the stars
I engrave beyond the horizon
The faint footsteps that are connected to everywhere
The reflection of your eyes casts away the loop of anxiety
The midnight sun
The Orion of Midsummer
Just now from somewhere, I heard your voice
This heart without darkness
Illumine it, o distant blue star
No matter what the time, I will be able to start walking
Sparkling far and near
Watching over me
The thing inside my heart, overflowing
More than tears, I want to be loved
Like a prayer, the journey continues
Be my guide anyday, oh small jewel
Spica among the stars
Next
Episode
Preview
Next
Episode
Preview
Our first deployment
and our first real combat.
I feel butterflies in my chest.
With the feelings and new power
I’ve been entrusted with, I’ll face it straight on.
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS:
Episode 5: Stars and Lightning
Episode 5
Stars and Lightning
Take off!