Hello everyone! It's been a while.
This is Disaster Prevention Leader Subaru Nakajima
from the Harbor Special Rescue Unit!
Long time no see.
I'm Teana Lanster, an Enforcer with the Main Office.
Now then, we'll be in charge of the
commentary just like in The Movie 1st.
We've gotten a real boost in our members and
hope to deliver a fun and sometimes serious commentary.
Right!
So then, Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha the Movie 2nd A's...
...brought to you by the former Riot Force 6
members plus extras, the audio commentary...
...will now begin!
Wow! Clap! Clap!
And with that, the movie's moved on
from Chief of Staff Rein's prologue to the real start.
But this is still kinda part of the prologue, right?
It's about half a year before the rest of the movie.
And here we see Commander Yagami's first appearance.
Commander Yagami sure was small, huh?
She was still using a wheelchair back then.
It must've been tough to get around by herself.
Commander Yagami said that the bus drivers and
townspeople were really nice so it wasn't too bad.
Uminari Univ. Hospital Dr. Ishida
But isn't it sort of dangerous for such
a small girl to be out this late by herself?
Well, Japan is just about as peaceful as Mid's cities.
Wait, what was Commander Yagami
even doing out so late by herself?
Apparently she was reading at a big library
in the next town over and lost track of time.
Oh, I see. Commander Yagami does love books, after all.
She liked them even more back then,
so she was always reading.
Ah, okay.
And here's a missed call from her primary care physician.
She didn't pick up on the bus
because it would've been rude, right?
Yeah, and she didn't call back right away
since it would've been hard to turn her down her offer
to throw a birthday party over the phone.
Ah, that's so...
Huh?
Hey, wait, how come you know so much
about Commander Yagami from back then?
Naturally, I came prepared!
While we were watching the movie's sample disc at the
commander's house, I asked her about all sorts of things!
I can't believe you're so casual with your superiors...
Oh my god, a truck!
Commander Yagami's in trouble!
Speeding in an urban area and falling asleep at the wheel...
That's horrible.
Maybe the driver was having a tough time
at work and couldn't take a break...
But still, if he ends up causing an accident...
But he notices her and hits the brake!
That must have been a shock to the driver.
But there wasn't an impact
or any trace of the girl he thought he'd hit.
I wonder if he thought he was
hallucinating from sleep deprivation.
Hopefully that woke him up
and he drove more carefully from then on.
That's right! Be more careful on the road!
And as he's leaving, Commander Yagami
has a mysterious encounter in the sky.
Her book suddenly starts floating and beating like a heart.
"Did this strange-yet-precious book
save me from that accident?"
Well, it's not really the sort of situation
where you'd think things like that.
Well, it was more or less like that, but
we'll hear more about it
from Commander Yagami herself later.
Right.
And not just from Commander Yagami...
We'll hear a lot more about the mysteries and secrets
behind this incident through our young tele-porters.
Starting in the next chapter,
our reporters will be interviewing
the young aces who are the protagonists of this movie.
So then, Vivio, over to you!
Right! Hello everyone!
This is field reporter Vivio Takamachi!
Today, we have an on-scene report
from the Takamachi residence.
The two we'll be hearing from are, of course, these two.
Hello, I'm Nanoha Takamachi.
Hello, I'm Fate Testarossa-Harlaown.
Right! It's my two mamas! Thank you very much!
Yep, thank you.
We'll be in your care.
And also with us today are our special guest reporters...
Hello! I'm Vivio's classmate
from the fourth grade at the St. Hilde Academy of Magic.
My charm point is my black hair! I'm Rio Wesley!
I'm also a fourth-grader from the same magic academy, and I've been friends with Vivio since first grade.
I'm Corona Timil.
F-From the same academy, in seventh grade...
I'm Einhard Stratos.
I-I'll be in your care.
Okay! These members will be providing
commentary on my mamas' most famous scenes.
Here, everyone. There's cookies so eat up.
Okay!
We've got hot drinks too.
Thank you very much.
Then I'll have some.
Yep.
And I'll have some too!
It's so good!
U-Um, everyone?
This is a commentary,
so please don't just act all like you're at home.
Eh? But Subaru and the other organizers
said to just relax and reminisce.
I have to be responsible as a reporter,
so I have to be tough about this!
Eh? Let's just have fun!
Here, Vivio. Have a cookie.
It's delicious!
I made them myself, after all.
Hey, wait! The movie's moving forward!
We're already at the important reunion scene.
Vivio! As your senior, I'll support you.
Einhard!
Based on the materials we got from Subaru,
the two of you hadn't seen each other
for about half a year before this, right?
Right.
We parted in May and met again in December, so it was a little over half a year.
In the movie, and like Nanoha said just now,
after the Jewel Seed Incident, I spent most of my time
either at the Main Office or aboard the Arthra.
You were still in contact during that time, right?
We were, through letters and video mail.
It showed a little of that earlier, right?
Yeah.
What sort of things did you talk about in your letters?
Let's see...
Just lots of unimportant things...
...like how we were doing
and stuff we had planned.
Back then, I still didn't know much about Earth,
so I learned a lot about how Nanoha and
everyone else lived and what school was like.
Right!
I was always thinking, "That's so nice",
and "That sounds like a lot of fun."
I see.
You heard a lot from Alisa and Suzuka too, right?
Yep, like about how they spent their holidays
and what was popular at the time.
Alisa's really good at showing
how fun and interesting things are.
Seishō University Magnet Elementary School
Yep.
There are people like that.
Then you must've been really happy to move
and become a student at their school.
I was! Really happy!
Oh, we're at the scene of her first day at school.
Fate was embarrassed. It was so cute!
It was my first time ever going to school,
and the uniform was too cute so it made me nervous...
But everyone is really welcoming you.
Yeah, I guess they were excited.
Now the scene's changed to Lindy's residence.
Arf was still big back then, huh?
We've only ever seen Arf in her small form,
so this is sort of strange.
Wait, Rio and Einhard,
do you know about Arf?
I heard about her from Erio and Caro!
She's Fate's familiar, right?
I've only heard her name.
Oh right, Arf doesn't come over much.
She still stays at the Harlaown family's house to
look after it so that Mama Fate can always return.
Yep. She said to say hi to everyone for her.
Um, is it okay if I ask a dumb question?
Sure. What is it?
The two of you could obviously
understand each other in a conversation,
but what language did you write your letters in?
Huh?
Oh, Einhard wouldn't know what you're talking about.
The main administrated worlds and Earth
have quite different languages and cultures.
They're just as different as ancient
Belkan writing and modern Mid writing.
Oh, I see. That's quite a big difference.
So if you just wrote normally,
the other person wouldn't understand, huh?
Actually, Amy wrote some translation software for us.
At first, we used that to scan our letters
and would include the translation.
But it's a bit sad to just rely on that,
so I did my best to learn how to write in Japanese.
And I learned to write in Administrative Basic.
So in the end, I was writing my letters in Japanese...
And I was writing mine in Administrative Basic.
Dear Fate
Nanoha
Suzuka
Dear Fate
Nanoha
Suzuka
Dear Fate
Nanoha
Suzuka
That's pretty amazing.
Learning a non-administrated world's language
is a high-school elective for us, right?
Yeah.
Could it have been the power of friendship?
Well, they were letters between children,
so there wasn't any difficult writing in them.
And I had Raising Heart to help me too.
Oh, it's about time for Admiral Chrono's appearance.
Back then, he was still Enforcer Chrono, though.
Chrono, Amy, and Commodore Laty...
Corona, you've met Admiral Chrono before, right?
Yeah, when I went to the Main Office with Vivio.
I was running an errand for my mamas
and asked her to come along.
He treated us to snacks in the cafeteria.
Whoa! That's so nice...
Admiral Chrono is a really nice guy, isn't he?
He seems cool and aloof so it's easy to misjudge him.
When he's off work, he's funny and easy to talk to.
He's really nice to kids too.
Oh, but back then, he was still
quite distant and really serious.
Could it have been because that incident
hadn't been resolved yet?
I think so.
The Book of Darkness Incidents had
a major impact on Chrono's life, after all.
So this story is also about Admiral Chrono, huh?
Yeah, it's the story of everyone who
was affected by the Book of Darkness.
And now we see the four happy friends
returning home from school.
Alisa and Suzuka go home by car?
Their homes are close to each other,
so they often ride together in Alisa's car.
Suzuka's house is on the way
between school and Alisa's place.
And Nanoha's and Fate's homes
were in the same neighborhood, right?
Yep, close enough that I could see Nanoha's house
from the front of my apartment.
That's really close!
Ah, it looks like you two can't help but be happy
about being able to see each other again after so long.
I was! I'd been wanting to see her that whole time!
Me too!
Right?
The two of you still get along so well.
They sure do.
Since Fate came to Earth, we could practice magic
and do lots of fun things together!
We couldn't help but be really happy!
Huh? By this time, had Chief Yuuno already...
Yuuno had to be a witness at the trial
and had other things to attend to.
He came to the Arthra a little bit after the previous incident.
Before he left, he checked that I could make a stable connection with the Arthra,
left me a magic training schedule, gave me some advice,
and did some other things for me too.
In his ferret form?
Yep, in ferret mode!
Does he practice magic like that?
No, whenever we did battle training,
he changed back to human form.
That's good.
But I was able to talk with him a lot back then, so it was fun.
And the fundamentals of magic he taught me are still
an important basis for everything I do even today,
especially defensive and binding magic.
And through you, Mama, it's been
passed down to my generation too.
Yuuno's really amazing!
Oh, it's time for that cute part!
Cute part?
Arf's puppy form!
She's so cute!
Right?
She's wagging her tail.
My older sister really liked her too.
Hm? What's that sound?
It must be a message from hosting headquarters.
Yes, this is Vivio at the Takamachi residence.
Hey there! This is Subaru at hosting headquarters!
Subaru!
Hello!
Vivio, thanks for the field report!
No problem!
They've finished preparations at the second location,
so we'll be connecting to them for now.
Okay!
You guys listen in too, okay?
Okay, we're cutting to the next location!
H-Hello. This is the second location.
I'm field reporter Miura Rinaldi, and...
Long time no see. I'm Lutecia Alpine.
The second location is the Yagami residence.
And we'll, of course, be interviewing these four.
Hello, I'm Shamal!
I'm Signum.
And me, Vita, with...
Me.
Um, Coach, your name...
It's Zafira.
Right, so the commentators here
are the four guardian knights.
Everyone, we'll be in your care.
Us too.
Yeah.
Miura, Lutecia, shouldn't you two
say a bit more about yourselves?
Oh, that's right.
Um... I'm Lutecia, 14 years old, and a good friend
of Agito who's the youngest of the Yagami family.
Because of some circumstances,
I've known the Yagami family for several years.
Lucy here used to be really quiet,
but she's gotten peppier lately.
I don't really think that I've changed too much.
Your friends have probably been an influence.
All of them are lively kids.
That might be it.
So then, Miura...
Right. I'm Miura Rinaldi, seventh-grader.
I go to the Yagami dojo and practice Strike Arts.
Everyone in the Yagami family is always helping me.
You're a friend and rival of Vivio's group too, right?
Yep, we get along well.
The two of us are the reporters for this part.
We'll be in your care.
While we were busy talking about that,
Vita is getting into her first spot of trouble.
Nanoha's going to attack Vita with her Buster!
There was no trouble! I dodged it just fine!
Eh? But didn't Nanoha just miss?
I dodged it!
With my great reflexes and mid-air maneuvers!
Well, we'll leave it at that.
She still got your hat though.
Crap... even in the movie, my Doombunny hat gets it.
Oh, here's Graf Eisen's Rocket Form.
Raketenform
Well, I guess it looks flashy... and terrifying.
My payback is gonna be a hundred times worse.
Alright! Here I go, Nanoha!
My attack of rage! Rockets, blast!
Sissy charges in, Nanoha flees...
But Vita accelerates and is hot on her heels!
She corners her as they clash.
Take this! This is for my Doombunny!
This time, Nanoha's the one in trouble!
Nanoha's blown away and crashes into the ground!
If this was an official match,
that would count as a down but...
In a real battle, you follow through after they're down.
So take one more!
This final blow is my payback!
Sissy's excessively merciless attack
drives Nanoha into a corner!
Nanoha's equipment was quite fragile back then.
Vita's attacks were really strong!
That's right, Miura! Praise me more!
Nanoha is defeated.
Here comes the Book of Darkness's collection.
This part's a little different from what actually happened.
Fate's supposed to come save her right about now.
In this, Testarossa's still on her way there.
During the real event, Vita ended up
fighting Fate and Arf too, right?
Yuuno was there, too.
After Signum and the rest arrived,
I fought with Yuuno.
The real thing was a pretty chaotic battle.
I didn't actually get to speak much with Testarossa.
Signum only got hit by Fate once, right?
Well, it wasn't a direct hit,
but she did a little bit of damage.
Fate was really strong even
when she was that young, huh?
Speaking of strong, Nanoha managed to pull off a collection
bombardment spell to break the barrier, didn't she?
Really?
As a collection-type practitioner,
I'd really like to see that footage!
Wow, back then Sissy made some really scary expressions.
She looked so gloomy.
That's pretty sad coming from you.
Back then, we were really desperate.
We knew that what we were doing was bad.
Signum and Dr. Shamal
were both really serious too.
We were.
But there was something that we absolutely had to do.
Looking back now, I do think that we
should have tried other methods too.
We just didn't know enough about the world at the time.
We weren't confident that the organizations or people
in charge would understand our circumstances
or hold any regard for Mistress Hayate's life.
If our freedom had been taken away, there would've been
nothing that we could do as our mistress's life slipped away.
Of course, that's just a criminal's excuse.
Right...
Meanwhile, Fate sees
Nanoha in trouble and cries out!
She rushes there immediately, but...
...my scary sister gets in her way.
At the time, I had to protect
Vita and the Book of Darkness.
I had no choice.
Well, I do understand, but...
Ah! The mid-air swordplay here is short,
but I learned a lot from it!
The team made sure to check all the action scenes.
For this part, I hear they had a mock battle with Testarossa
as herself and Nanoha playing my part for reference.
Sissy was there for the checking too, right?
Which part did you do?
I checked all of my own spells
and also the Belkan stuff in general.
Other people can't really do your magic, huh, Vita?
Like her Rocket Form spins.
Raketenform
I tried to do it in the garden with Agito helping,
but it just made me really dizzy.
Of course it would!
I can do it because I practice.
I tried it for about half a day but still couldn't do it.
Looks like I'm not too good with spinning magic.
It's impressive that you even kept trying for half a day.
Lu, you shouldn't play around recklessly.
Fine...
And now Fate tears up.
Yeah...
And here, Signum mercilessly yanks out her Linker Core.
You're being pretty merciless yourself.
Fate expression and voice
make it sound really painful.
Fate gets taken out, and Arf is also defeated.
Somehow, it seems like a really sad scene.
The skirmish ends, and the stage calms down.
Ah, this ringtone is...
Hi! This is hosting headquarters.
Tia!
Lutecia, Miura, thanks for the report.
No problem.
Looks like Commander Yagami and the other
two with her have finished their preparations.
We'll be switching over to their audio for now.
Right!
Geez, Teana's really getting into this job.
As long as she's enjoying it.
Uh, we'll be coming back to everyone in
the guardian knights later, so please continue then.
Got it.
Right.
So then, location change...
Switch on!
Ah, hello there. I'm Agito.
And I'm Rein.
We'll be doing this from a studio in the Main Office.
And our main guest is, of course...
Hello, I'm Hayate Yagami.
I'll be in your care.
Right!
But compared to the other groups,
we're a bit lacking in numbers, aren't we?
But Meister, if more people were here,
you wouldn't get a chance to talk.
We discussed it with Subaru and the others
and agreed that all you need is
Agito and I to listen to whatever you have to say.
Th-That's a bit... please be gentle.
Oh, we'll be gentle, but we'll also be going at it with a bang!
Subaru and Teana will also be joining us later,
but first, we'll just be hearing from Hayate.
Right. Let's get started then, shall we?
This movie's the story of
the Meister and our family's past, right?
Yes, it is.
It's also the story of Nanoha
becoming a real warrior of the sky
and of Fate taking another step forward in her life.
December was really quite eventful that year.
It really was.
Oh, the movie's showing the Yagami residence on Earth.
It is. It really takes me back!
It sure is!
That's so nice. I've only ever seen it in pictures.
The house itself is still there.
It's being rented out at the moment.
Right now, a family of six is living there.
Ah... oh, right! I think I've heard
something like that before.
It's time for little me and Vita to get up.
Sissy's so cute!
Now the scene's changed to Nanoha's school day morning.
Little Nanoha and the others are just so cute.
They really are.
But for me, seeing Nanoha and the others
when they were so little feels a little strange.
But they were still small around
the time you were born, right?
Well, that's true.
But when I was born, in addition to Hayate, Nanoha
and Fate were already like really big sisters to me.
Nanoha and Fate both really grew up, after all.
So much so that by junior high,
you could barely recognize them.
Especially the way Fate grew
so tall that it surprised everyone.
Fate was actually pretty bothered about it.
She said she was happy to get taller,
but was worried that she'd get too tall.
Ah, I heard about that from Sissy.
Signum would say to Fate when she was worried,
"If you get taller, your arms and legs will also get longer,
which will be good for your swordplay."
and other weird words of encouragement.
That really does sound like Signum.
But everyone grew up nicely in the end, right?
Well, I guess you're right.
Fate has a very nice figure.
And Nanoha's really pretty too!
And then there's me who gets called
a little raccoon since I'm so short.
No, no, no, no...
I look the most similar to my younger self from back then.
If I tried, I could still fit into some of my clothes from then.
No, it's okay! You're really cute, Meister! You're beautiful!
Hayate, you're perfect like this!
I still wish I was a little bit taller.
You have heels to hide it at work, though.
And my face, too!
Out of all my childhood friends, I'm the only one
who still gets mistaken for being underage.
Uh... well... that's...
But that's what makes you so nice and familiar.
I like you just the way you are.
Me too!
Thank you, Rein, Agito.
There, there.
While we were talking about that,
there's Marie who doesn't look her age either.
Marie was fifteen at the time, right?
Yeah.
She was part of the Main Office's logistics department then.
She's been a big help to me too.
She takes care of all of the Yagami family's Devices,
and Subaru's family's too.
She went to O.C.S. like Admiral Chrono, but isn't it
pretty rare to go into a tech department after that?
Oh, haven't you heard?
Marie initially wanted to become an Enforcer.
Eh?! Really?
But after entering O.C.S.,
she realized that might be too hard,
so she changed focus to the technical things
that she'd always enjoyed.
So that's it.
So in her second year, she chose tech-related electives.
And after she finished, she went to Commodore Laty
and started working in the logistics department.
You didn't know even though
she's done so much for us, Agito?
I-It's not my fault!
My normal maintenance is done at the
Air Armed Service tech department by Shari.
And my Unison tuning is done by my Meister.
Well, that's true.
Marie taught me all of my Device-related skills.
So our whole family owes a lot to her.
We're very grateful. Amen, amen.
Hey, don't do that. It's ominous.
While we were talking about Marie,
Suzuka appeared.
Suzuka!
Little Suzuka is so cute.
Right?
This is the scene where you two first met, right?
Yep, it was an important first meeting.
If Suzuka hadn't gotten that book for me,
we might not have ever become friends.
Then you wouldn't have had the chance to
meet Nanoha, Fate, or Alisa.
Uminari University Hospital
Oh, then you might not have met on Christmas Eve!
Then no one would have been there to stop us.
The Book of the Night Sky would've stayed the
Book of Darkness and respawned with a new master.
Waah! That's bad! That can't be allowed!
In a way, it's thanks to Suzuka
that the Yagami family exists today.
It really is.
And another very important person to me is Dr. Ishida.
She was your primary care physician, right, Meister?
Yeah, she's Dr. Sachie Ishida, a neurologist.
But you didn't really like Dr. Ishida back then, right?
I didn't really dislike her.
I just felt bad because she tried so hard to help me,
but I just wasn't getting better at all.
So that was it.
They called it an "'unknown sickness",
but somehow I understood the situation.
I knew that my legs wouldn't heal even with treatment
and that I wouldn't live much longer.
That's so...
But I wanted to do my best with the time I had.
And after everyone in the family arrived,
I wanted to keep living
for as long as I could and stay optimistic.
Now, now, let's try to move on.
Look! It's Raising Heart's and Bardiche's famous scene.
Oh, you're right!
It's where the two swear to recover and show their resolve.
They're like, "We can't just let it end like this!"
Who'd've thought they'd go through that sort of power up?
Back then, it wasn't a good idea to put
cartridge systems in Mid-style Devices, right?
There had been research into it.
But it was only at an experimental level, so it was quite
reckless to suddenly use them in an actual battle.
I see.
Ancient Belka's cartridge systems
were like a lost technology.
Marie said that being able to analyze actual Belkan Devices
like Lævateinn and Eisen after the incident
helped her make a safer cartridge system.
So Lævateinn and the others were useful to society, too.
Of course! Raising Heart and Bardiche's
operational data were used as well.
Oh, I've heard about that, and how data
from the Instructor Corps was also used.
And it's thanks to that research that the system is available
not just to Modern Belkan-types like Subaru and Erio
but also to many Mid-types.
Teana also uses it.
Hey there! This is Subaru, still at hosting headquarters.
Thank you!
Rein, Agito, great work!
Commander Yagami, thank you for your commentary.
Sure!
Another commentary team's finished their preparations,
so we'll be handing the main mic over to them.
Okay!
Right! This is the fourth commentary team.
Seishō University Magnet Elementary School
The reporters are me, Erio Mondial, and...
...Caro Ru Lushe from Lightning.
And our main commentators are...
Hello, I'm Yuuno Scrya,
Chief Librarian of the Infinity Library.
And I'm Admiral Chrono Harlaown with the Main Office.
These two have finally made their appearance!
Applause!
But what's with this combination?
You're one of the key figures in the incident, right?
And Chief Yuuno also played an
important role behind the scenes.
So we really want to hear about the events from you.
Really? Well, I'll do my best.
Please do!
Now then, the movie's at the part where
Commodore Lindy and Admiral Chrono talk.
It's the scene where Commodore Lindy realizes that
Chrono is working on the Book of Darkness Incident.
Commodore Lindy's always been a sharp person,
so I didn't think that I could hide it forever.
But I didn't expect her to find out this quickly.
She sort of found out through
the grapevine from Commodore Laty.
I should've asked Commodore Laty to keep quiet about it.
But it probably would have come out sooner or later.
Yeah.
Why did you keep it a secret in the first place?
I didn't intend to keep it a secret forever.
Once I'd confirmed the situation,
I planned to explain everything.
And if the need arose, I would have asked her
to return to duty even if she was on leave.
But events unfolded more quickly than anyone expected.
Worst of all, Fate and Nanoha got dragged into it.
And there was also the risk of
the Commodore herself being attacked.
So there was no way around it.
Erio and I have heard about
Admiral Chrono's father, Commodore Clyde.
We heard that he was a very cheerful person.
He was.
My memories of him are a bit blurry,
but I do remember that my father was always smiling.
I see...
Commodore Lindy told us that you've become more and more like your father as you've grown older.
Well, he is my father.
When Commodore Clyde passed away,
he was in his mid-twenties, right?
About your current age?
Yeah.
Please be careful with your health.
Though right now,
it's almost surprising how healthy you are.
I don't drink, and I watch my diet at home and on duty.
And as an Enforcer,
you'd be training your body and magic every day.
There's probably nothing to worry about
with my health... compared to others.
Why are you looking at me?
I'm watching my health too.
Are you sure?
You're in the Infinity Library all day,
so you don't get much exercise.
And even when I invite you to train,
you turn me down half the time.
Well, I'm busy too, you know.
But that means you do go the other half of the time, right?
Seriously, you can't expect a librarian to go along
with the same training as an Enforcer.
But you keep up anyway, right?
And my team says it's more fun when you're there.
Oh, while we were talking about training,
something's started happening in the movie.
Looks like an emergency—a mana signature
in downtown Uminari.
I'm not a field operative,
but I still get tense when I hear these alerts.
When we were in Riot Force 6, we were always
nervous that the alert would be sounded.
We'd have to sortie right away once it rang.
But we have to do our best so that civilians
never have to hear things like emergency sirens or evacuation announcements.
Yeah, Subaru also told us the same thing.
Ah, she does work in a department where
she hears these alerts almost every day.
That's right.
On the screen, the knights all sortie starting with Vita.
It's pretty intimidating being attacked by these four.
Signum is really scary!
It's sort of unusual to see
Commodore Lindy in a battle, though.
She wasn't really a field work sort of person.
She only ever enters the fray in real emergencies.
It's also quite strange to see Commodore Lindy using Durandal.
That's true.
It's a bit strange for me too.
Are you still using Durandal?
Yeah, I still have it.
Freezing magic is pretty useful in the field,
so there's times where I need to use it.
People think of you as an ice mage now,
right, Admiral Chrono?
Something like that.
Ice mages are pretty rare, after all.
Freezing magic is hard to use.
It's mostly because I have Durandal.
Oh, while we were talking,
Instructor Vita's started attacking!
Her Claymore cracks the ground!
But Commodore Lindy barely dodges it!
She changes her position and activates Durandal.
It's about time for the battle to start in earnest, but...
The knights sure closed in quickly.
Four-on-one is tough even for Commodore Lindy.
This could be bad.
Or it would've been...
Here they come! Her saviors!
Outside of the barrier, flying in from
the sky are, of course, those two.
Yep.
They're here!
Nanoha and an upgraded Raising Heart!
And...!
It's Fate and Bardiche!
Yeah, the scene after this is a bit difficult
for us to be commentating on,
so let's switch back to the Takamachi residence.
It's their transformation scene, right?
Aw... but I wanted to say "Set up!"
Maybe another time.
So, Vivio!
Right! This is the Takamachi residence.
We're finally at the transformation scene!
It's really exciting!
Yeah.
Ah, this feels really embarrassing for some reason!
Yeah...
We'll be looking at your transformations
very carefully while we commentate!
Whaaa?!
First, her clothes come off above the magic circle.
Each piece gets stripped off one by one.
Raising Heart sets up first.
Sparks fly as the parts appear.
This sort of construction transformation is the nice thing
about staves and weapon-type Devices.
Right? They go clonk and click!
It really gives off a sense of strength.
And there goes the cartridge unit!
It combines...
And finishes with a chunk! Cartridge loaded!
It looks powerful!
Oh, what's that magical pattern on screen now?
It's finalizing the surface coating.
Normally that'd be done during testing, but...
We went straight into battle.
I see.
Now the Jacket parts appear
one after another on her naked body!
Um, please don't look too closely!
Mama's getting embarrassed!
But it's really pretty!
The way the hard parts assemble is really cool!
Especially the screw spinning in!
It's beautiful and strong. It looks really tough.
There's her shoes and ribbons.
Pling!
She catches Raising Heart in her hand.
Sacred Mode's about to complete!
The final touch...
Emblem, opened!
Raising Heart spins around, and Mama spins too...
Complete!
Yep.
And without any break,
it's time for Mama Fate's transformation!
P-Please be gentle.
Fate's transformation is different from mine.
It's really cool.
Yes, it's very elegant.
She takes Bardiche in her hand...
The way she spins here is so cool!
Especially how she makes her hair spin like that.
Now it's time for her clothes to come off.
It's just a movie, but it's still really embarrassing.
It's pretty how Fate's hair comes undone too.
I also changed where it gets tied up.
Eh? Really?
Only slightly.
And Bardiche's transformation begins too!
The black parts steadily assemble!
He also looks very strong.
The revolver unit sets in.
I sort of want a cartridge Device, too.
Bardiche's been finished, and now
we move on to equipping Mama Fate's Jacket!
This undersuit looks really easy to move in.
It sure does.
The undersuit guards her body,
and the outer coat helps fortify her defenses.
It's a two-layer defense, right?
Right!
That, on top of some new physical defenses,
is her new powered-up Jacket!
Her skirt has defensive properties, too.
Yep, it's a magic defense coat with a reactive purge function added.
I see.
So, her arm guards get finished up...
And her hair's done back up in her fighting style...
And she spins Bardiche around elegantly...
And her cape gets put on with a flourish...
And there's some more spinning...
Complete!
It's completed!
And the two arrive on the scene from the sky!
They pierced the barrier magnificently!
The battle begins here, right?
That's why we'll be opening up a line
to the Knights of the Night Sky to speak with them as well.
Yagami residence reporters, Lu, Miura?
Hey there!
This is the Yagami residence.
Lulu, Miura, we're counting on you!
Right, Vivio.
Signum, Vita, and everyone,
we're counting on you too.
Yeah.
Sounds lively over there too.
Are Corona and Vivio in charge?
I'm here too!
Um... and also me.
Huh? Rio and Einhard,
have you met the Yagami family?
Vivio has introduced them to us before.
And I visit them every once in a while
for Teo's maintenance, too.
Ah, I see.
And Corona has trained with them before, right?
Right! Thank you very much for that time.
Dr. Shamal too, go ahead!
Right, leave it to us.
Now, the first battle is between Nanoha and Vita.
I went straight in to smash her.
Nanoha, how did you feel when the fight started?
I guess I felt like I definitely didn't want to lose.
You were up against an opponent you'd lost to once before,
so were you nervous?
Strangely, no. I did all I could to prepare for it,
and Fate and Raising Heart were there for me.
I see.
Vita's scary but a bit cute in this scene
when she says "break a few bones."
Yeah, I thought so too!
Not "I'll kill you!" or something like that?
Well, I did think they were getting in our way,
but it's not like I was out for revenge or anything.
I see.
Oh, Competitor Nanoha has deployed her shield!
She's completely stopped Instructor Vita's charge attack.
The shape of the shield is different too.
It's Excelion Shield.
It uses a direct link to the cartridge system to form
a hardshell-type shield for stopping attacks.
That one-handed counterattack shoot was nice.
The new Nanoha fights a lot like a knight.
She's a mage but doesn't know how to act like one at all.
It was the result of plenty of forethought.
I considered my own skill,
Raising Heart's new abilities, and things like that.
And now we have a barrage counterattack.
Accel Shooter fires off!
All of Vita's Flights are being
shot down one after another!
Fliegen
Boom! A big explosion!
It's amazing that she could shoot down
all those shots like that!
Technically, she'd seen me fire it and knew the trajectory,
so a decent ranged mage should be able to lock on to them.
There was some distance between us too.
But it's still impressive.
Ah, this is where what Nanoha says makes Sissy angry.
She says, "So, please, be a good girl"...
W-Well, I thought she was younger than me.
Vita actually is smaller than you.
Shut it.
And now, the camera's changed to show
Fate and Signum's battle!
Competitor Fate's doing her best!
Signum's going all out against such a small child.
What an immature way to fight.
There's no point holding back!
But Fate is really amazing when she's serious!
Zooming all around like that!
Fate, had you trained in aerial swordplay by then?
I didn't really know the concept of aerial swordplay,
but I'd been taught about clashing in mid-air.
By Lynith!
Yup.
Then Signum sheathes Lævateinn...
...and lashes out with a chain attack!
She's attacking Fate!
But she keeps dodging!
And now she charges Signum...
An all-out strike!
But Signum blocks with her sheath!
Which one is better?!
Competitor Signum kicks!
Competitor Fate's been blown away!
Competitor Signum charges in...
Clash!
Boom!
You two were so showy!
Well, uh...
It was a head-on collision, after all.
And the result of the clash is an even match,
and they acknowledge each other.
Signum, how were you feeling back then?
Well, I remember thinking that it was unusual
to encounter a mage who could use a blade.
Right.
So I was expecting her to put up a good fight at least.
It's sort of embarrassing.
And you tell each other your names.
You hadn't known them before this point, right?
Giving your name is a knightly sort of thing, right?
I guess so.
I wanted to know her name since she was
the first worthy opponent I'd fought in a long time.
Ah! This part's cool, isn't it?
"I can't guarantee that I won't kill you.
Will you forgive my childish immaturity?"
And also Fate's proclamation that
"I'll be the one who wins."
I want to be able to say something like that, too.
I know, right?
This is so awkward.
Isn't it?
And now it's time for Zafira and Arf's battle.
Zaffy, it's your turn!
Right.
Zafira got to talk quite a bit with Arf, huh?
They're discussing some serious matters.
I wonder why I did.
Maybe I sensed that they were opponents
who could understand our situation.
I wonder if some of it managed to get through.
Oh, speaking of Arf, I can imitate her voice from back then!
Eh? Really?
Should I give it a try?
"Here I go! Eat this punch!"
That's pretty good.
It really is similar!
Our voices are pretty similar to begin with.
Lu, what about little Arf?
Hmm... uh...
"Hey, Corona! Are you eating dinner?"
That one's even closer!
Right?
Hey! While Lu was doing her imitation,
my scene passed by!
Ah, sorry.
It's okay! You still haven't executed Clear Howl yet!
Klargeheul
Vita also gives her name...
...and then just retreats!
I didn't really want to.
And here's Dr. Shamal's Clear Howl!
Klargeheul
Okay! Here I go!
Flashbang spell, Clear Howl!
Klargeheul
One, two...
Boom!
The flash covers the battlefield!
The spell's a huge success!
As expected of Dr. Shamal! Nice work!
Ahem!
In team battles, these sorts of spells are important, too.
Hm?
Aren't they banned in magical battle matches?
Flashbangs that blind the opponent
aren't allowed in the Intermiddle.
Since the ring is so small, it would make it hard
for the audience and the referee to see.
I see.
But in the aerial competitions and open field battles,
there's no specific rule against it.
Right?
It's not banned in events like the Tactics Festival, right?
Because anything goes in that.
There's going to be a Tactics Festival after the
administration's live fire exercise this year, right?
I'm definitely going!
I wanna see a live match between
Signum and Nanoha!
Um...
I don't really want that.
The PR department's not going to let you off though, Captain Takamachi.
They'll ask people to get you to participate.
I don't want to! Signum's too scary!
You're one to talk. How many times do
you think you've nearly shot me down?
The two of you are sort of like rivals, huh?
They're both in the Armed Services,
so they sometimes have competitive matches.
Fate, why don't you participate in this one?
M-Me?!
But I'm not even in the Armed Services...
I don't mind going against the two of you.
In that case, I'll bring Vita.
Eh?
The legendary two-on-two revived again!
This is getting exciting!
That's great! Miura should come watch with us, too!
I'd love to!
Let's invite Harry's group, too!
I'll do my best to learn from it.
Um... well, it's not decided or anything.
It probably won't actually happen.
I have a hunch it won't.
I'll make it happen. Come prepared.
Huh?!
But while we were chatting about battles,
the scene's shifted to the Yagami residence.
Now it's the Yagami family's turn, right?
Then the Takamachi family group will be taking a break
and leaving it to the Yagami family group, okay?
Thank you very much.
Then, uh, where's Hayate's group?
Hey there! This is headquarters.
Hi, this is the Yagami residence.
While everyone was talking, we met up with
Commander Yagami in the Main Office studio.
Oh, so it'll be a commentary with us and headquarters?
That's what I'd like!
So then, direct link, high quality audio mode start!
Commander Yagami, go ahead.
Ah, thank you.
Hayate, thank you for your time.
Sure.
Right now, we're at Commander Yagami's flashback.
Oh, you're right.
Lulu, Miura, we're here too.
Good work.
Agito and Rein, thank you for your time.
Now then, we're in main office's studio with
Commander Yagami, Rein, and Agito.
It's been a little while since we've spoken,
so I'm Teana Lanster...
...and I'm Subaru Nakajima.
We'll be hosting the commentary
about the Yagami family's past.
But it's really impressive that we can get such good
audio and video even though we're this far away.
The advancement of technology is always surprising.
Right?
Well then, the movie's at the scene of the first meeting.
Vita's so cute!
Hayate's eyes are spinning!
And then finally we get to this part...
It's the important scene where
Hayate encounters that person.
At this point, she was still just the Will of the Book of Darkness, but she later becomes the first Reinforce, right?
Is this scene the same as how you met her in reality?
Yeah. I didn't remember it until later, though.
Later?
Eins says it in this scene too, but I don't remember
most of the things that happen in those dreams.
Before the tome's completion, the system prevents
the Unight and master from communicating.
And even if they do, the system reorganizes
memories to keep them from getting left behind.
That's just one of the cruel alterations
to the Book of the Night Sky.
That's...
Ah, we'll be talking about the origin of the Book of Darkness
more later with Chief Yuuno and Admiral Chrono.
For now, let's focus on the everyday life of their family.
We'll talk more about Eins later, too.
Okay.
It's about time for my movie self
to wake up from the dream.
It's right where you hear Eins's message, right?
But when I look closely, Eins and Rein
don't really look that similar.
Eh? Really? I thought we looked pretty similar...
That's true.
Rein's face might be closer
to Hayate's than Eins's.
Oh, I get told that occasionally.
But Rein will probably look more like Eins
when she grows older since she's naturally pretty.
I hope I grow up fast!
I guess you do grow up a bit each year... subtlety.
There's a system that makes sure you look
like an adult by the time you're twenty, you know.
So about another six years...
I hope I become a mature-looking lady like Eins.
I'm gonna grow, too!
But I sort of hope Rein will stay the way she is.
Yeah, I kind of know how you feel.
Oh, while we were talking about that,
here's a scene with Instructor Vita and Zafira.
They're talking about the past, huh?
It's a little bit scary.
Well, we'd just woken up, so our memories were hazy.
Yeah, and it was a long sleep too.
And now, we have little Commander Yagami's
first conversation with the knights.
The Book of Darkness is following along, too.
Commander Yagami, weren't you surprised
by such a strange development?
Well, I was surprised, which is why I fainted at first.
That's true.
But I wasn't frightened.
They'd come from the book that
I thought of as my important treasure.
And I felt a sense of responsibility as their mistress
after hearing their explanation.
Commander Yagami is way too quick to adapt.
But it's thanks to that flexibility that
we weren't kicked out of the house.
That way we didn't attract the police's attention
for being weird homeless foreigners either.
If you think of it like that, it's actually pretty scary.
It really is.
It was a first for us to be able to live normally in a house,
so we were quite hesitant but happy.
Oh, it's Vita and Hayate's bath scene!
It's Hayate's soap bubble attack!
Sissy's reaction sure is cute.
It sure is!
It's from when I was a kid,
so of course I was like that.
Now they're drying laundry.
It looks so peaceful.
Ah! It's Hayate's homemade dinner!
So Dr. Shamal couldn't use chopsticks.
Because they didn't have chopsticks on Belka!
Instructor Vita's using a spoon.
And she's gripping it with her fist.
Well, I used to be like that...
The hamburger looks really good.
Just looking at it makes me happy.
Right?
So why is Zaffy eating on the floor?
I was curious about that, too.
Zafira said he preferred it like that.
I tried to convince him otherwise at first.
I decided that in a house,
a guardian beast should live as a companion.
Unless I had errands, I didn't take a human form.
So a "companion" is another word for a pet, right?
Right.
So it has to do with your position in the family?
My human form is big and takes up a lot of space.
And of course, it stands out.
Hmm... I feel like that's not too
different from your wolf form.
Well, he did stick out at first,
but people got used to him quickly.
Ah! Here's Vita's fateful encounter!
Oh, it's her Doombunny.
So that's how you got it!
Yeah, we were just walking around and it caught my eye.
You have somewhat strange tastes, huh, Instructor Vita?
When Vita heard that it was okay to open it,
she immediately hugged it really happily.
She sure looks happy.
Yeah, it made me happy, too.
It's a nostalgic memory from my childhood.
Looking back like this is a little embarrassing though.
And after getting home,
Signum and Hayate stargaze romantically.
This should be such a happy scene,
but I can't help but start tearing up here.
I know...
Hayate and Signum are so kind
and don't want to cause trouble for anyone.
The only thing they want is to
be happy alongside everyone else.
We already know how the coming incident unfolds, so it's sad.
Right. Why can't such people who are
trying so hard to live become happy?
Events and accidents can happen
due to many different reasons,
but it's sad when reality doesn't
reward kindness and hard work.
Ah! This part is bad for me, too!
Vita is... Vita is...!
Oh, when she asks if she can have ice cream?
How can such an innocent and cute child
be made to go through something so sad?
It's too horrible! It's heart-breaking!
I get how you feel, but it's kind of complicated.
Commander Yagami is pretty easy
on the youngest child of the family.
I made sure I wasn't too lenient
and taught her a bunch of things.
The etiquette lessons were pretty strict, weren't they?
I went through the Yagami family education, too!
Me too.
It's a really happy family,
but soon, the fateful day arrives.
Please don't!
And here we are at the hospital in Uminari
where a shocking truth is about to be revealed.
Oh no, it's here!
Dr. Ishida always put on a smile
around Hayate and Vita.
She only discussed medical issues with me or Shamal.
But considering how you guys just suddenly appeared,
Dr. Ishida seems to trust you quite a bit.
Well, some things happened.
I actually asked Dr. Ishida about it myself.
At first she thought, "They're definitely suspicious!
Is Hayate being tricked by these strange people?"
So it seems she did some investigating in her own time.
She used a detective agency and stuff.
Wow, Dr. Ishida's impressive!
But as she investigated, she could see
that they were just living together normally.
Signum became a teacher at the local kendo dojo,
and Shamal joined the neighborhood association.
And Vita became really popular
in the neighborhood croquet team.
And our Meister also very adamantly insisted
that they were her relatives and family, right?
Yeah.
And most importantly, after seeing that Hayate
was laughing a lot more, she trusted them.
I see.
So they managed to connect through their sincerity.
Oh, it's their sortieing scene.
It really feels quite tragic.
And at that point, no one had realized
the Book of Darkness's fate.
That's true.
We thought if we completed the Book of Darkness,
we could save Hayate.
We knew that it was a crime.
But you still did your best to avoid
causing trouble for others, right?
Even while stealing Cores, you tried to not hurt people.
And if they got wounded, you'd heal them.
Even so, it was definitely a crime.
But back then, we didn't think there was any other way.
Now that we've discussed that,
isn't it about time to hand over to the next team?
Oh, you're right! Um... Team 4!
Right, this is Caro from Team 4!
And Erio!
Hm? Is it our turn again?
Right when Chrono showed up.
It's where Commodore Lindy, Nanoha, and Fate
join the investigation and Admiral Chrono accepts it.
Chief Yuuno still did field work back then, huh?
Mister Enforcer here was a real slave driver,
so I was usually researching cases,
but in emergencies, I'd sortie.
Talented individuals should work
where they're most useful.
And we're back at the Yagami residence
with Dr. Shamal returning in a panic.
Commander Yagami got tired from waiting and fell asleep.
The hot pot set sitting on the table
seems kind of sad.
The knights kept giving us the slip around that time.
The teleportation technique they were using
wasn't in the Bureau's database, either.
Oh, really?
If it were, we would've caught them much more quickly.
The research on Ancient Belka
was still in its infancy at the time.
In addition to the cartridge system,
there was a lot of technology that we hadn't analyzed yet.
Erio, you're a knight, so you should know this stuff!
Uh, no, I'm a Modern Belka-type,
but, well, I'll study up on it.
Good luck.
After this incident, we learned a lot about Ancient Belka
thanks to Hayate and the knights' full cooperation.
Their contributions towards historical research
and redeveloping technology have been huge.
I see.
And while we were talking about Belka,
the movie's at Commodore Lindy's and Fate's scene.
It's the story of how Admiral Chrono's father,
Commodore Clyde, passed away.
That's right.
So Commodore Lindy and Commodore Clyde
were stationed on the same ship?
I don't think they were always together
since they belonged to different departments.
Oh, did they?
My dad was a director for the Enforcers, and my mom was an investigator.
Commodore Lindy worked as a barrier mage, right?
During the Presea Incident, it was thanks to
Commodore Lindy's distortion shield that we survived.
But now I'm making sure she stays
off the scene on dangerous cases.
She has a nice, quiet desk job now.
This part is the story of little Admiral Chrono's past.
We find out why Admiral Chrono began aiming to work
at the Bureau and see his meeting with Amy.
When you say it like that,
it's embarrassing for some reason.
You've gotten along with Amy
since your school days, right?
Well, she mostly just treated me like a little brother.
What started off the friendship?
I was the youngest and the smallest in our grade.
I think I may have stuck out a little, too.
We were in the same class, and our grades in magic
were pretty close, so we had plenty of chances to talk.
And when did that relationship first start to change?
What's with you, Caro? You seem eager.
She's at the age where she likes to hear love stories.
I wanna hear it!
You can ask Amy when you go to Uminari.
Fate knows about it, too.
Roger that!
It's more about Fate than us in the movie right now.
It looks like she still hasn't sorted out
her feelings about Presea.
It's still stuck somewhere in her heart even ten years later.
And it'd only been half a year, so it was even harder.
Had there already been talk of adoption by this point?
I think my mom had spoken to Fate about it.
But rather than a direct question, I think it was more like,
"If you'd want to, please think about it."
Lindy is so sweet.
It reminds me of our past, too.
Which one? Fate or Lindy?
A bit of both.
In addition to Fate, Commodore Lindy also treated us kindly.
For my mom, you two are like her grandchildren.
Ah, the chapter's about to end.
Right, then let's pass things on to the next team.
In that case, all of our headquarters hosts!
Right, this is hosting headquarters!
We were connected to the Yagami residence,
but now we're here!
Location 2, Takamachi residence?
Yes! This is the Takamachi residence!
Vivio!
Hayate!
Oh, Einhard's group is here, too.
Yes, Agito.
Rio and Corona too!
Yep!
So for a little while, we'll be commentating with the hosts
at headquarters and the Takamachi residence group.
And we'll occasionally call in guests from other groups.
Let's have the first one join now.
I'm Miura joining from the Yagami residence group.
Thanks for having me.
Thank you!
Uminari University Hospital
But while we were chatting cheerfully,
something terrible's happened to Hayate!
It's okay, I survived.
It'd be terrible if you hadn't!
It's the scene where Commander Yagami
is hospitalized, huh?
Who here has been in the hospital long-term?
Me!
Huh? Was it just me and Hayate?
I've been in for two or three days at a time.
I haven't been in long-term, either.
And the kids like Vivio and
Corona wouldn't have, either.
I've been fine.
I've only gone for small injuries.
Einhard, you too?
Apart from health checkups,
I've never had to go to the hospital.
Me too.
You're all athletes, so of course you're healthy.
Huh? What about your long-term hospitalization, Nanoha?
It was a long time ago,
but I had bit of an accident during work.
I was in the hospital for about two months.
Ah...
I wanted to do a little group corner with the hospital-stayers, but if there's only two, there's not much we can do.
To talk about rehab and stuff, huh?
Um... let's talk about that some other time.
Okay.
Oh, this! It's the scene where
Dr. Shamal is making cartridges.
Can you really make cartridges on your own like that?
Oh, a generation gap!
Back then, it was normal to have to charge them by hand.
Whoa...
But ours were charged by machine
at the logistics department.
But it does seem like half the charging was done manually.
Well, we don't really have experience
with cartridge systems.
It's because we don't use them in lessons at school.
Ah, it's Eins!
Looks like Signum's flashback.
It's a somewhat sad scene.
They were fighting their own fates under Belka's gray sky.
Signum resolves to save Hayate and Eins, but...
She's trying so hard to do bad things.
Ahhhh! And this part with Vita in the rain!
Vita's wandering and fighting by herself.
A little while ago, she was just a little girl
living happily with her loving family.
How did things end up like this?
And she didn't even know if her efforts would be rewarded.
Still desperately doing her best while
thinking that she might be hated for it...
I can't take it! I really can't take it!
Ah! Don't cry! Don't cry!
You're right...
I think the only thing that Vita
cared about was saving Hayate.
It's really sad.
Oh no, the kids' sadness is getting to me too.
Let's go to Nanoha!
Sorry, we're at the age where
a child's effort gets to us too.
Yeah...
Even Nanoha's group?!
Um, what should we do?
Let's pass the mic to another team for now!
T-Then for now, let's go to Erio's group!
Admiral Chrono! Help!
Keep it a secret
that I bawled when I first saw this scene, okay?
Yeah, you were crying so much
that the handkerchief got all heavy.
And with that, it's suddenly been passed back to us.
Oh, but we're just in time to see the scene
with Admiral Chrono and Chief Yuuno.
Right, then let's talk.
Yeah, let's.
Um, according to the materials we have, the Infinity Library
didn't function the way it does now back then.
It says that Chief Yuuno led a team to explore
and organize the labyrinth-like archive.
As a result, it was made into a database
that anyone can use now.
Ah, that's a bit of an exaggeration.
I did take charge of the exploration and organization,
but it was accomplished through a team effort.
But it's because of your achievements from then
that you're the Chief Librarian of the Infinity Library now.
I am thankful to be acknowledged.
The Scryas were always more involved in outdoor excavations, but I've gone and become an indoor guy.
When Erio and I first met you,
you were already the Chief Librarian,
so it's hard to imagine you as anything else.
Sometimes I yearn for field work.
Okay, then I'll take you on some field training.
How about a snowy mountain?
A desert sounds good, too.
I think I'll pass on both.
Oh, come to think of it, Chief Yuuno
didn't wear glasses back then, huh?
That's right.
It's not like your vision's that bad, right?
It's not good either, though.
It's about like this.
They really are weak.
Even when I put them on,
my vision doesn't change much.
Ah, Admiral Chrono, please let us see you wear them.
When I put on glasses, I suddenly look really serious.
Oh, you're right!
Now he looks like an office worker.
I'm not happy about it,
but I know glasses don't match this uniform.
N-No, that's not true!
Hey wait, is it okay for us to talk about stuff like this?
Shouldn't we save this for when it's not our turn?
Well, I think this should be fine.
It's okay!
I think the children have calmed down by now.
Let's ask. Hosting headquarters?
We're here!
This is Hayate Yagami at hosting headquarters.
Huh? Commander Yagami?
Erio! Caro! You seem to be doing well.
Thank you very much!
Good work, Chrono and Yuuno.
Sure.
Yeah.
How's everyone doing?
The children talked it over and said they won't cry anymore.
They're finishing up from last time right now.
Um...?
Even if it's a sad scene, we won't cry!
Yeah!
We're going to commentate without getting too sad!
Commentator team, fight!
Yeah!
Fight!
They're doing this huddle like athletes.
They're dealing with the commentary like a match.
I don't think we're looking for quite that much enthusiasm.
Well, they do sound reliable.
Right, kiddies, li'l ol' me will cheer you on
so do a good job with the commentary.
Yeah!
Even Lu?
Oh, while we were talking about that,
it's Christmas Eve in the movie already.
Lu, everyone, is it okay to leave commentary to you?
It's fine!
Please leave it to us!
Then we'll pass things back to headquarters
and the Takamachi residence.
Fate, we're counting on you too.
Yeah, leave it to me, bro.
Please stop calling me that.
Then we'll talk to you later, Team 4.
You too, Yuuno!
Right!
Right! Now we're back to the commentary.
Everyone's come to visit me in the hospital.
It's a cute visit like you'd expect from grade-schoolers.
Alisa really likes doing stuff like this.
Commander Yagami's really happy, too.
Yeah!
Uh oh, but this is where Fate
realizes the grave truth.
The Book of Darkness is sitting right there!
And the people knocking who come in are...
Unbelievably, it's Signum's group.
Mamas, behind you!
We were really shocked then, huh?
Yeah.
I was still out of the loop at the time,
so I didn't get what was happening at all.
For me, seeing them all wearing
normal Earth clothes was a surprise, too.
Oh right, because you'd only
seen them in their knight outfits?
Yeah.
Oh, here, here!
I've kind of been wondering about this part.
Okay, Rio.
Had Alisa met Commander Yagami before that day?
Oh... I'm not sure.
I think this was the first time we'd met in person.
Hadn't you spoken with her on the phone and stuff?
That's right. And I knew her face from pictures Suzuka showed me.
And we'd talked before,
so it didn't feel like our first meeting.
I see.
And now Vita looks really threatening.
She really glared at me.
But it's cute how she says "I'm not glaring!"
It's Vita's special "polite" speak.
She got scolded by Hayate too,
so she's in all kinds of trouble.
I also made sure to follow up.
Uminari University Hospital
And now the hospital visit ends.
In this uncomfortable tension, the story advances.
Ah, now for a while, it develops things
between Nanoha and Vita's group.
What should we do?
Should we switch members?
Vivio, Miura, and the others probably want to
have fun with the battles, so I'll swap out.
Then I will too.
I'll wait and charge up for Eins's arrival.
Then the members will be...
Ah, Erio and Caro haven't spoken
with the other main members...
...so let's leave the EriCaro pair in charge
and let them pick out members to talk to.
Yeah, let's do that.
Let's have some fun commentating by ourselves too.
Okie-doke!
Okay, Erio, here you go.
Erio here.
First, we'll be hearing from
select members about these events.
First up is Signum!
Please tell us how you felt at this moment.
I did curse our bad luck, but mostly,
I was thinking that we only had one way forward.
How about Instructor Vita?
Just like what I say in the movie.
We were desperately trying our best, so I didn't want people
who didn't understand the situation to keep interfering.
So you didn't believe that they were
genuinely reaching out to help?
Hayate was already in a state where she might have dropped dead at any moment,
so we didn't have any time to think.
Then Nanoha, what were you feeling at this moment?
I was sad. Not being able to convey
your feelings through words is very sad.
Hey, I was feeling a bit of despair, too.
You just shook off the attack that I'd put
everything I had into like it was nothing.
Enough to make you want to brand her as a devil?
I actually meant it back then.
I thought she was a devil that was trying to
get in our way and get Hayate killed.
And yet Nanoha didn't back down.
We hadn't gotten a chance to talk properly.
I thought that if we could communicate,
then they'd surely understand.
I see.
And by the way, you said I shook it off
like it was nothing, but it actually hurt a lot.
I thought you might have broken some bones.
I was trying to kill you!
Um, we're trying to be serious, so could
our two instructors please leave this for later.
What about you, Dr. Shamal?
Well, I also thought that there was no turning back.
But somewhere in my heart, I might've been
thinking that there must be another way.
What do you mean by another way?
Like if we could somehow get
Nanoha's group to keep quiet about this.
But we didn't have any sort of magic like that.
Right.
How did you feel, Fate?
I guess I felt similar to Nanoha.
We were telling the truth,
and they definitely heard us,
but the most important parts weren't getting through,
so it was scary and frustrating.
This is where Fate activates her Sonic Form.
Captain Signum and Fate take up their stances.
It's a really dangerous situation!
It really makes you tense.
But this fight sort of ended halfway through.
I wonder who would've won if you'd finished it.
I think I would have.
It would've been me.
Wait, why would you have won?
Because if I'd lost, in addition to Signum,
Hayate and the others would've been in a terrible situation.
That may be true, but...
I don't know about a proper match, but under
those circumstances, I definitely wouldn't lose!
Feelings alone aren't enough to win.
But... I wouldn't have lost!
Ah, Fate is sulking.
Instructor Vita, don't egg them on like that.
This is the serious interview block.
The movie's at a serious scene,
but it's exhausting to be so straight-laced.
Well, the battles are starting now.
Battle commentating group?
We've been waiting for this!
Vita sends a big ball her way.
She's attacking with Flying Comet!
Kometfliegen
Nanoha moves to engage!
While deploying her shield, she also prepares some binds!
But she's forcefully pushed back and falls down.
That sure was powerful, huh, Einhard?
Normally, that'd be enough damage to slow her down...
But Competitor Nanoha controls
her angle of descent and avoids a down!
And now she readies a long-range barrage!
The binds she prepared activate!
Looks like she can't dodge this.
Competitor Vita's doing her best
to destroy the rings by force!
But then Competitor Nanoha loads two cartridges!
It's a Divine Buster!
Shoot!
Competitor Vita is in trouble!
After that big explosion, Competitor Nanoha
assesses the situation, but...
Uh oh! Looks like Competitor Vita is fine!
When Competitor Vita looks up, right in front of her is...
It's the Book of Darkness! It should've been
by its owner's side, but it's come here for some reason!
So has the Book of Darkness come to protect Vita?
It doesn't look like it came only to protect her.
Nanoha is confused by the sudden turn of events!
And the book's owner, Hayate, appears to be in agony!
A new challenger appears: NachtWal!
It's twisting all around! So scary!
It's supposed to be an autonomous protection system, but...
Can you explain, Lu?
Sure.
According to the materials, this is the true form
of the Book of Darkness's curse.
It's NachtWal's activated form.
So because of these snakes,
the Book of Darkness can't operate correctly
and endangers whoever becomes its master.
As soon as NachtWal appeared,
the battles all completely stopped.
Even though they were battles of
intense desperation, that stopped them.
I guess it's just that dangerous and intimidating.
Ah! It's caught everyone!
Even Hayate and Fate...
And now NachtWal starts absorbing their Cores.
How could this have happened?
Nacht, stop it!
Everyone's Cores are being taken out!
So the reason Nanoha and Fate are fine here is...
The two of them already had their Cores absorbed by
Signum's group before, so Nacht can't absorb theirs again.
It's more that there's nothing to gain
from absorbing their Cores again, though.
This is where my coach arrives on the scene!
Zafira, save everyone!
Please!
But Nacht barely even reacts
and just starts absorbing his Core.
But Coach is trying so hard!
Even his last, desperate attack doesn't reach it.
The battle stops for a little bit here.
Argh! I don't want it to end at this weird part!
There's another hot-blooded battle later,
so let's have fun then.
Yeah.
So with that, we'll be returning
to the normal commentary now.
Erio, Caro, if you please.
Got it!
The scene is now showing the hospital roof.
It's when Nacht and Commander Yagami first meet.
It's another painful part.
Let's hear from Dr. Shamal and Zafira.
The reason the guardian knights
don't remember the Book of Darkness's curse is...
The alteration to the program meant that anything negative related to the Book was erased from our memories.
Even if we tried to remember, it would lock them down.
If we knew that the only thing awaiting
us and our master was destruction,
then there would be no reason to collect Cores.
The master's access to the Book's will
was probably blocked for the same reason.
What I don't understand is why that sort of
alteration was made to the program.
This is just a theory, but I think the system was slowly
put together by many masters over a long period
with good intentions to improve the Book
or more effectively use its power.
But each of those users changed the Book
in different ways to different ends, and this is the result.
So it just ended up creating new problems.
Right.
There wasn't much documentation left
related to any alterations, either.
Ah! And now, this is where Commander Yagami finally...
Her scream of anguish is ringing out.
Ah! Hayate is...!
Nanoha and Fate have
escaped from their prison, but...
The Book of Darkness has already
been completed and activated.
Hayate!
It's no use! I know it's just a movie, but I can't watch!
It seems like she's not conscious anymore.
But if she was conscious,
then it might just be even sadder.
Th-That's true.
And now that the Unison is complete,
the one who appears out of the shock wave is...
...Eins.
She didn't have a name then,
so she was just the Will of the Book of Darkness
She's in tears.
In the time she was together with us,
she made sure to never let us see her tears.
She had a strong sense of responsibility.
Right now, she has an expression of sorrow and anger,
but she was originally someone
who looked and sounded very kind, right?
She was really cute when she laughed.
If only we had more memories of her smiling
apart from those final moments.
That way, we could've told Rein and Agito about it, too.
Yeah.
The time she was able to spend with us
in her human form was really short,
but I sort of thought of her as a little sister.
I can imagine you two being great sisters.
Yeah.
It's going to get more exciting from this point onward.
Who should we call to commentate?
Hmm, hosting headquarters?
Hey there!
It's the main scene with the first Reinforce,
so we've obviously got this person!
I'm the second.
And also her partner...
Agito!
Well, I'm not really her partner though.
And we'll have the two main characters with us, too.
We'll be in your care!
We'll do our best!
So then, Nacht's moving about in a foreboding way,
so it's about time for the battle to start.
This thing's scary in its snake form and its weapon form.
Is the weapon form supposed to be
something like a shield or a spear?
It's a mechanism used to shoot spears called a strafing gun.
It's an old Belkan infantry weapon.
Even on Belka, it wasn't really a widely used weapon.
Originally, it was a weapon made
to shoot spears over long distances.
You put the unit on your arm, stand like this, and... bam!
Rein, it's a commentary
so they can't see you even if you pose.
U-Um...
Ah, here. You point the arm it's on in front of you
at an angle and support the back of it with your chest.
Then you line up the trajectory
with your target and thunnnnnnnk!
The ranged infantry are supposed
to shoot it out in a line formation.
I see. That sounds quite effective for large battles.
A good ranged user can shoot while running
and enchant the spear tip to give it
an explosive, incendiary, or other effect.
That sounds a lot like a modern weapon.
Yeah, but the one Eins has isn't the ranged type, right?
That one's made for melee combat.
The idea is to use explosives or a cartridge to push the spear with massive force.
It's for piercing armor or other defensive layers,
and some units can freely adjust the length of the spear.
You can also make it shoot out repeatedly.
Oh, that's sort of romantic!
It's like a prototype that led to stuff like your Knuckle.
Oh, and I heard about this from Einhard, but
smaller units can also be used in hand-to-hand combat,
so you can attach it to your hands or your feet.
Th-That sounds pretty scary.
Thank goodness Eins didn't use them like that, huh?
How scary! I'm so glad it wasn't like that!
And now in this scene,
Fate and Nanoha are in trouble.
Eins is attacking Nanoha.
This is the melee-type strafing gun's terrifying attack!
Oh, I see. Even if your attack is stopped,
you can get in another one.
You get into an opening in their defense, then bam!
And now we have Fate's prudent counterattack.
She reloads her cartridge,
then shoots out a Crescent Saber, but...
It's unbelievably thrown back at her!
I have seen Einhard do that, though.
There are quite a few Belkan-style users who can do that.
But as expected, these two are a really good combo.
They've locked her down and are doing their Buster Shift.
It's a really beautiful crossfire.
And of course, we've made sure to offset our aim a little
so we don't end up hitting each other.
Friendly fire is serious, after all.
Ugh...
What's wrong?
No, it's nothing.
I just remembered one of my past mistakes.
We've accidentally shot each other in practice, too.
Right?
But Eins is barely affected by the binds and bombardment
and actually catches the two in a chain of her own.
She's using the spells she gathered through her collection.
Being able to use any of the gathered spells
at full power feels a lot like cheating.
Commander Yagami obviously can,
but Rein can use them too, right?
That's right. But as you'd expect,
mine aren't quite as irregular as Eins's.
Yours generally come out weaker.
I know, right? The effects are pretty dependent on compatibility, too.
She was an amazing person, Eins.
I wish we could have spoken with her more.
And now, we have Nanoha's
emotional outcry of "It's not over yet!"
Her earnest persuasion continues, but...
She wouldn't listen to me.
Or more like she just fired on you.
We do understand why she might not listen, though.
Compared to us who'd only lived a short while, she'd endured an immense, unimaginable amount of sadness.
But if she refused to listen,
everyone would be placed in danger...
So to get our message through,
we had to make her listen.
Words alone weren't getting through,
but force alone won't communicate anything.
It's a difficult situation.
Oh! It's Fate's Jacket purge!
So you can use modular Jackets
for stuff like this too, huh?
My Jacket didn't use much mana in the first place,
so it's pretty easy to change the parts.
I've also learned about purging part of my Jacket
as a technique to escape from binds.
A bind break that only purges the parts of the Jacket
that are trapped by binds! Right?
That's so cool!
Don't you change up your Jackets, Nanoha?
I used to do it in the past, but not so much now.
Exceed Mode's become your standard, huh?
The mana consumption and stability of that one's the best.
Nanoha's Exceed Jacket is really cool!
It makes me want a coat on mine too.
Good idea! I think it'd look cute.
Oh! Fate charges forward in anger!
It's a really amazing Drive!
Whoa!
Uh, I don't think my Drive's as impressive as in the movie.
And especially at that age,
it would've been a lot clumsier.
But nowadays, it does look like that.
We've often been taken down by this Drive.
She comes straight at you, but it's still unavoidable.
But I got caught by Eins.
Ah, Fate's disappearing!
She's been swallowed by the book!
Nanoha, you must have been pretty shocked by this.
I was! I thought that Fate had really disappeared!
Yeah.
And this is where Fate's dream world starts.
There's no such thing as eternity,
but it's a world where it feels like there is.
And now it's started... the world inside my dream.
The commentators are myself and...
...Vivio's group, the grade school trio, and...
...Erio and Caro!
Let's do a good job.
Right!
So this is where Fate lived before, right?
Yeah, this is the Garden of Time in Artesaim.
Alicia and Arf make their appearance as well.
And Lynith's debut.
Everyone from the last movie's back again, huh?
Yep, they're my precious family.
It looks just like an ordinary, everyday morning.
It's unbelievable after that heated battle just now.
It is inside a dream after all.
It's a dream of the time that I wished for most.
Alicia and Arf are both really cute!
She's a little big sister.
Alicia's appearance here probably comes from
the impression of her that remains inside me.
But the two of you make a really cute pair
of sisters when you're together like this!
The way she goes "Yep" is really lovely!
Right?
Ah, which reminds me, Vivio, didn't we talk
about that thing in the last commentary?
"That thing?"
About magic colors determining personalities.
Ah! Yeah, we did!
We started it off with Alicia's light blue, right?
Something like that.
That's where you can tell your personality
from the color of your magic, right?
I don't know much about that.
Corona's pretty familiar with it.
Yeah, Lu told me about it, so I looked it up.
It sounds really interesting!
Uh, what are all your magic colors?
Mine's yellow. It's a pale, tea-ish hue, though.
Einhard's is a sort of bluish green,
and Miura's is pink.
And Lu's is purple with a little black.
Rio has double colors, right?
It's orange and pink. If I had to pick one,
then I guess the main color is orange.
And mine's colored like a rainbow, Kaiserfarbe.
And I think I have a rare gold color.
Th-Those are pretty rare cases,
so it might not be too accurate.
Let's take this chance to get our divination master
to look at those who didn't get one last time!
Subaru!
The divination master is here!
Okay, master, please tell us about our new members!
Got it. You there with the yellow magic!
Yes?
You're a gentle and polite girl, aren't you?
Additionally, the white shows your abundant natural talent,
and the tea-like part means you're a simple and calm person.
It's right on!
It's really accurate!
With dual colors, the main color shows your main traits
and the sub-color shows some other minor traits, so...
The suspense is killing me!
Your orange means you're passionate,
and the pink represents your innocence and sincerity.
It's right again!
Yeah!
Th-That's sort of embarrassing.
Wait, but if it's like that, doesn't a really mixed color
mean someone with a really mixed-up personality?
Oh? Does it really?
It's okay! The master has looked into it since last time!
Apparently people with many
bright colors are lively and active.
So you weren't too far off when you made up
"bright and happy little girl" last time.
Master, what about Fate's gold color?
Right, it's supposed to be the traits of yellow
plus a strong sense of pride.
Th-That doesn't seem quite right.
The sparks from your magic are purple,
so maybe it's a double color.
Purple means that they're deeply affectionate, right?
Sounds about right.
Ah, the pride in gold is more about being proud of the things
you've accomplished and inherited from others.
Things I've inherited?
Like your ancestry or lineage.
I see.
My family is important to me,
and I am really proud of it,
so I guess it does fit.
Yeah!
But while the dream world team
has been having fun with divinations...
...over here is the battle scene.
Myself and Einhard are the junior high pair, plus...
...Rein and Agito will be joining in!
Let's do it.
We've also called over Signum and Vita for analysis.
Yup.
We're in your care.
Right.
The heated aerial battle's already begun.
Eins isn't flinching at all against Nanoha's attacks.
Her defense is on a different level.
Nanoha's ranged attacks
can't pierce her defensive layers.
Yes, Nanoha searches for a good shooting position
as she breaks off from the scissor exchange, but...
Getting blasted through the debris stops that!
And then she pursues her.
This is an intense attack.
Nanoha crashes straight into the sea.
She couldn't correct her angle of descent, either.
Solid ground would've been very damaging.
But she manages to avoid taking damage
and moves under the water without being seen.
She has a line of sight,
but the distance is a little too great.
The difference in strength is too great.
Normally, this would be a good time to withdraw...
But it's not like Nanoha to give up or retreat.
Nanoha, determined, decides to use her trump card.
What's Nanoha's Excelion Mode?
It's a Full Drive mode that pushes right to the limit—a self-boost system that enhances your power.
It might be easier to call it
an extension of the boost system.
It raises the limit of your attack and defense power.
And for very short intervals, it can push these
two or three times higher than normal.
That's very impressive, but...
As you might expect, the mana consumption
and burden on your body is nothing to laugh at.
It's not something that such a small child
should normally be using.
But this is the only way to even have a chance of winning
against such a clearly superior opponent.
Right.
Nanoha's tactics were all formed while assuming
that her opponent would be stronger.
That includes her mana-collection bombardment
and this self-boosting system.
It's a clumsy style with no room for second chances
for winning when push comes to shove.
I get it.
Nanoha's Excelion Mode is really dignified
with a new black part on her Jacket.
Yeah, it adds a gallant ambiance.
Now here comes Eins's Genocide Shift!
It's an altered version of Fate's spell.
That's a really amazing number of bullets!
Nanoha, I hope you make it through this.
And now we've returned from the battle outside
to the peaceful world inside the dream.
The two sisters are relaxing outside.
Alicia is in the middle of reading...
...but then the weather...
Could it be raining in the dream world because of
stuff like Mama Fate's uncertainty or uneasiness?
Yeah, I think that may be it.
Alicia's saying to go home, but...
Fate says she wants to stay for a bit longer,
so they're both taking shelter from the rain there.
"We're taking shelter from the rain!"
As expected of sisters, even speaking the same way.
Alicia's really nice, isn't she?
Oh, come to think of it,
does everyone here have siblings?
I have an older sister.
She's quite a bit older than me, though.
About ten years difference, right?
Yeah, so she feels more like
a second mother than an older sister.
I'm an only child, but I have
quite a few relatives who are my age.
So visiting home is always fun!
We're technically both only children, but...
We've got family and close friends in many different places,
and we're almost always together, so it doesn't feel that way.
Me too!
I've got Erio and Caro, so I don't feel like an only child.
We do get in touch pretty often.
We're always at each other's birthdays.
I've been thinking a lot recently about how things
would have been if Alicia could have been with us, too.
Like what sort of an adult Alicia would have grown into,
or if I'd be treating her as my big sister or my little sister.
I feel like she would have enjoyed being treated as a big sister.
It'd be okay to treat her as a ltitle sister normally,
but when it's important, she'd be the big sister.
Yeah, I think that's how it would have been, too.
Since Alicia's a big sis who loves her little sister.
And now, Commander Yagami's also in a dream.
She looks sleepy.
Oh, the part after this is Nanoha's scene.
Do you guys want to go commentate?
I'm going!
We'll go!
We'll meet up with Miura and Einhard and cut loose!
Erio and Caro too!
Yeah!
Then we'll be out for a bit.
Okay!
And here we are, Nanoha's excellent battle scene!
Everyone, are you all ready?
Yeah!
Nanoha fires first.
She shoots off a Short Buster!
But Eins easily dodges it!
What an amazing reaction speed!
A punch sends Nanoha flying!
She tumbles and tumbles and tumbles!
But somehow lands!
Now Eins is telling her to surrender, but...
Hold on! My mama won't back down!
She's still got a sure-hit finishing move!
Excelion Mode, overdrive!
It's really pretty!
It's getting more and more tense!
Here we go, the finisher...
Strike Flame
The crimson spearhead has appeared!
Her heart's engine has passed the redline!
Excelion Buster A.C.S.
Drive!
She's off!
She's heading straight at her target!
But Eins puts up her shield!
It's a rock-solid defense!
She can't pierce it!
But she's pushing her back by force!
They break through the debris!
Eins is enduring!
Nanoha pushes back!
Hayate looks like she's going to
be woken by the violent shaking!
Hayate, wake up!
It's no use. She's gone back to sleep.
The one who holds the key to her fate is Nanoha!
Nanoha keeps forcing her back!
They crash into a rock pillar!
But Eins is still holding on!
But the spearhead has dug into her shield,
so she can't parry the attack!
Cartridge, quadruple load!
The wings are spreading wider!
She's pushing even harder!
The blade's cut into the heart of her defense!
Break...
...shoot!
Has she finished it?
That was enough power to
completely smash that stone pillar.
It's venting the exhaust.
But Nanoha has taken some damage, too.
It was a risky close-range bombardment.
The recoil on powerful attacks isn't anything to laugh at.
But despite that desperate all-out attack from Nanoha...
Eins comes out of it with barely a scratch.
It's shocking how she's completely uninjured!
It must be disheartening,
but Nanoha sure doesn't waver at all.
Raising Heart is still raring to go!
Nanoha's continuing to give her all in the battle.
The impacts from the battle are also affecting
Hayate who's sleeping inside Eins.
What's going to happen?
They sure were having fun with the commentary.
Right?
They really were.
From here, it's going to be another scene
between me and Alicia.
Fate's resolved to put an end to the dream.
This is sort of weird coming from me, but Fate,
did you think about remaining in that dream forever?
To be honest, I did.
I was really torn.
Right.
But even though it was only for a short while, I got to see Alicia and Lynith, and my mother was also kind to me.
I'd already gotten everything out
of the dream that I could've wanted.
Right.
My heart didn't break completely
after I was abandoned by my mother,
and I was able to take Nanoha's hand
when she reached out for me,
not so that I could go to sleep in a comforting dream,
but so I could live my own life even if it was painful and sad.
That's how I felt.
I see.
But in reality, there weren't really any painful or sad things,
and I ended up living a very fulfilling everyday life.
There must have been tough things too,
but it's all part of being alive.
Yeah.
Alicia is such a good girl.
Yeah. I wish I could've met her.
Yeah.
This scene really makes you emotional.
Yeah, even though we've seen it so many times.
This light that Alicia is bathed in...
Is it the color of her magic?
Yep. It's an light blue, tinged with green.
What would the divination
have said about her personality?
Master!
Yes, did you call for me?
Her partner's here, too.
Okay!
Rehydration complete!
We're done with our restroom breaks too!
Let's keep doing our best!
Right!
Everyone's back!
You're just in time! We were about to
resume magic color divination.
Ah, really?
Who're we doing this time?
Alicia's.
She's light blue with a greenish tinge,
so what would she be?
A light blue base means positive and bright.
That's right! Mine's light blue too.
Yeah, it is.
And green is kind and gentle.
It's right on.
Oh, Einhard's was green, too.
Yes.
It's green, tinged with blue, right?
Blues are serious, so that means she has
a kind, gentle, and serious personality.
That one's right.
Magic color divination is impressively accurate!
Well, there's still no scientific basis for it.
It's fine! Divinations are
something you do for fun anyway.
Oh, speaking of which, the magic color here...
Look, the sparks from Fate's magic are light blue!
It's light blue, tinged with green.
You're right! I'd never noticed!
I guess it's because Alicia
was lending me her strength.
I'm sure that's it.
And going by the double color divination,
this adds both positiveness and brightness!
Th-That's really amazing!
I'm pretty shocked.
That must be a pretty great feeling.
And while that was going on, I've woken up.
And I'm fighting with Eins.
Nanoha's being swung around! She's in trouble!
You've really been tied up.
And she finishes it off with a loop.
Eins's last spell is really amazing, too.
It's one of the spells that was in the Book of the Night Sky.
I haven't used it in a real battle before,
but do you want to try taking one later?
N-No, that's...
It's okay! I'm sure Einhard can
just throw that black spear back!
I think it'd be a bit too much...
It's only a little short of being the size of a tower.
Even I look in despair there.
Like "Oh no! I'm done for!"
Yeah, I couldn't even move
so it wasn't like I could shoot it down.
And the one who comes to the rescue
is, of course, Fate.
Her pure white cape is pretty!
The part around her skirt is different, too.
Yep.
Ah, Fate, when you get upgrades,
your Jacket gets more white parts, right?
And when Nanoha powers up,
hers get more black parts, so...
Maybe they'll eventually swap colors?
A black-clad Nanoha and a pure white Fate.
I want to see that!
Well, I don't think it'll go that far.
And mine's pretty much black apart from the overcoat.
And as the two best friends have finally reunited...
It's the insert song part!
Oh, you're right.
Let's leave this part to Commander Yagami!
Got it! Rein, Agito, come on!
Okay!
From here, it'll be the Yagami trio
at headquarters and...
...Miura and...
...Lucy doing the commentary!
I've been worried about whether
to call you Lucy or Lulu recently.
I like both.
Vita and Rein both call her Lucy, right?
And Vivio and I call her Lulu.
And the other one I get called is Lu.
Wait, let's leave what to call me aside for now.
Right, this is the Meister and Eins's really important scene.
Eins is crying a lot.
The precious mistress that she'd tried to protect
for so long is going to die because of her.
That thought alone must be too much to bear.
But the Meister saves her, right?
Hayate, how were you able to do complicated things
like access the administrative rights back then?
Had you already learn about Device engineering
and systems software back then?
Not at all! A lot had happened,
but the Tome was actually complete.
At that point, the way to activate the administrative rights
and how to use them all entered my mind.
And so that's how you knew how to revive the knights.
Yeah.
If the previous masters hadn't all lost consciousness as it
was completed, they could've used the admin rights, too.
But most of the previous masters lost their sense of self
or died when they tried to use the power.
And even if you wake up, if there's no one outside to suppress the Book of Darkness's power,
then you can't do anything.
And even if you manage to cut out the berserk part early on,
it'll change into the Darkness of the Book of Darkness.
Sounds like some sort of impossible game.
But many coincidences
and pieces of good fortune came together,
and we were able to do the impossible.
It's really thanks to everyone that we were saved.
Hayate did her best, too!
Thank you.
Ah, this is where Hayate grants her a name!
"Reinforce"
It's a beautiful name.
The first was also...
Wait, no, the first is just "Reinforce", right?
That's right, and I'm Reinforce Zwei.
We refer to her as Eins a lot now, but when we say "Reinforce", we're usually talking about the first.
And this one's pretty much officially called Rein.
I can't deny that.
Oh, while we were talking about that,
something dreadful is happening on screen.
It's Nanoha and Fate's Blast Calamity!
I don't know whether to call this frightful or chilling.
Even the Book of Darkness's curse
would be sent flying by this.
W-What an amazing barrage!
Nacht's being blown to bits.
If those two hadn't been there at the time,
I don't know what would have happened.
Really.
Looks like the explosion's died down.
Oh, we're going off on a tangent again,
but we were talking about Reinforce's name, right?
Yeah.
Well, I think it doesn't matter if you call her
Reinforce Eins, just Reinforce, or just Eins.
No matter which one you choose, she'll smile and respond.
I think so too.
In my imagination, she'd get all shy
if you just called her Eins.
It's sort of like calling her my big sister.
Oh, I think I get it.
On screen, they've suppressed the first part of the berserk Book and succeeded in cutting away its Darkness.
Commander Yagami seems really mature here.
Oh? Really?
Eins seems to have calmed down a lot.
I think she's just overwhelmed by emotions.
Being called by the name given to her by her beloved master...
And being able to use her power
for her master—for her loved one.
She looks really happy when she gets called by her name.
It's her smile when she responds with "Yes, my mistress."
It sort of makes me feel happy, too.
Now then, it's about time for the insert song to end.
And my knights are finally revived.
Let's call everyone in!
Okay then, Yagami family knights!
Everyone, gather!
Come forth, my knights.
Okay!
We're coming now.
I'm here.
Looks like we're all here.
Well then, everyone, here we go!
Yeah!
They're completely in sync.
Yup.
Right, now everyone's getting revived!
Feels like we were gone for quite a while.
Wasn't it for about one or two hours?
I think it was about that much. Maybe a bit less.
Whoa! Everyone's been revived!
Little pieces of everyone's magic are floating around.
It's great that everyone's fine.
Welcome back, Coach!
Yeah.
Vita's revived, too!
My Doombunny hat is also back.
And Hayate's putting on her Knight Armor.
Schwertkreuz has appeared, too.
Yep.
The first time I saw this, I thought that was
Hayate's full Knight Armor in her younger days.
Well, this does look cute and easy to move in.
That's just the undersuit.
The final pieces are coming now.
It's a "Unison in!" with Eins.
It's Hayate's transformation scene.
I've seen Nanoha's and Fate's plenty of times,
but it's kind of embarrassing to watch my own.
You start with the undersuit, so it's a bit disappointing
that there's no part where you take off what you had on.
Right?
But instead, we get a double set-up with Eins.
It's what makes us Unights so great, huh?
Eins's knight clothing is great, too!
It sort of matches my undersuit.
It's a lot like my knight outfit too.
But your proportions are so different
that it's hard to tell what's similar.
What'd you say?
Well, if you change the color, it is pretty similar.
With their hearts joined as one,
the Unison completes!
You both look great!
Hayate's Knight Armor is really cool!
Yes indeedy!
Hey, this is hosting headquarters.
It's the moment before the final battle.
The battle commentary will be with everyone, so we'll take
this chance to ask these two some questions before then.
Hello.
Since the Book of Darkness Incident, I've grown
quite a bit, and my voice is different. I'm Chrono.
Yes, hello.
I've grown taller too, but I pretty much
sound the same. I'm Yuuno.
Thank you very much!
Right.
Thank you too.
When people talk about the Book of Darkness Incident, the spotlight naturally falls on our two aces and the Yagamis,
but Admiral Chrono's investigation and Yuuno's research and front-line contributions
were both very important to the case.
The materials have me down as the one in charge of the case, but I was just doing a normal investigation.
It was really all thanks to the many talented
field operatives, contractors, and backup crew.
Admiral Chrono's just arrived on the scene in the movie.
Yeah.
In reality, there was actually another hidden faction
who played a part in the events leading up to this, too.
Some things happened at the Bureau.
The documents and information for that have since been made publicly available,
so if anyone is interested, you can look it up.
I've had a look at those files.
There was a lot going on.
Be that as it may, it was thanks to them
that there were no deaths or serious injuries.
And we gained an opportunity to put an end
to the persistent threat of the Book of Darkness.
Gaining the cooperation of the knights and the mistress
who were freed from the book was also a large factor.
Plus you had Durandal, the Staff of Freezing...
And also the Arc-en-Ciel, right?
It's a good thing we had everyone together like this.
It'd be pretty amazing to see this team together again, too.
Although Nanoha, Fate, and the knights
were all together at Riot Force 6.
But Arf and I don't do field work
unless it's an absolutely terrible situation.
And I don't get many chances
to be on the front line any more.
I wish we could see you all together in a battle, though.
I see. If that's what you want, should we participate
in the Tactics Festival or live-fire exercise?
Oooh!
How about having a team of everyone from that time
versus the ex-Riot Force 6 Forwards?
Wait! Those odds are way too stacked!
We'll be crushed in ten seconds!
Think so?
We'd die.
But thanks to this movie, we've had
another chance to remember the past.
It's kind of nice.
That's true.
It'd be nice if we could see our memories
brought together like this some day.
That would be nice, but even if it did happen,
it's way too early to be talking about it.
I'd love to see the achievements of Riot Force 6's strikers again.
Yes. Someday, definitely.
We'll do our best!
Oh, I think the battle commentary team is just about ready.
Ah, I think you're right.
So let's pass the main mic over to
the final battle commentary team.
Although we're in it, too.
We'll be counting on you too, Admiral Chrono and Chief Librarian.
We've got it.
I hope we'll be okay.
Well then, commentary team, Vivio?
Right! Here we are! The final battle!
For this last battle, the commentary will be done by
the kids team along with the people who were there!
We'll do our best!
The four from the Forward team are here, too.
Yep!
We'll be in your care.
Right!
Excuse us!
The beginning of the insert song's started playing.
Everyone, here we go!
Yeah!
The thing that arrives with a roar is the final enemy,
the Darkness of the Book of Darkness.
It's huge! Whoa!
It's a really intimidating size.
Those tentacles are writhing all around.
Moving in to surround it are Zafira, Chief Yuuno, and Arf.
They're restraining it with bind magic.
Chief Yuuno's large-scale bind is very powerful.
I gave it everything I had.
Arf's bind also catches the joints, one by one.
My coach's signature spell joins the fray, too!
Steel Yoke
It impales stuff to stop its movement.
It's a spell used to stop large creatures or machines.
But the Darkness of the Book of Darkness's resistance is fierce. Arf's binds are shattered, one after another.
It lets loose a wild black barrage with a roar!
Even a single shot of that packs
some crazy destructive power.
They're tearing those massive stone pillars to bits.
It'd be bad to get shot down, so everyone spreads out.
I'm delivering the position and attack timing orders.
And here, Nanoha and Vita's partnership is formed!
It's our first co-op exercise, right Vita?
More like the start of a long, unwanted association.
Still?
Graf Eisen's changed into Giant Form.
Gigantform
Eisen's so cool!
Isn't it? But the coolest part has yet to come!
And here's my mama's Accel Shooter, Vanishing Shift!
It's a barrage of locked-on guided shots.
They avoid Vita beautifully and spread out!
They hit the main tentacles one after another.
What amazingly high accuracy!
Not just the accuracy, the power is amazing too!
Sissy's also maneuvering through the skies perfectly.
It's the Center Guard's job support the entire team.
Okay everyone, here we go!
Thundering explosion!
The Giant head grows larger!
Gigant
Giant Smash
Gigantschlag
Boom!
The first barrier's been smashed to pieces!
The second barrier is being pushed into the sea!
Next up is Signum and Fate.
The two are charging forward
while dodging each shot in the air.
This pairing is also the first of a partnership, right?
Yep.
She cuts cleanly through the water with Zanber
as she shoots out a Blade Impulse!
All the tentacles in the way are taken out
with one slash which damages the barrier too.
Everyone clears out from Captain Signum's line of fire
as she and Fate move to their positions.
It's Captain Signum's Bow Form!
Bogenform
Fate also expands her magic circle!
Since the days of old Belka, the bow and arrow
have been a skilled knight's most deadly weapon!
The flashing blade which cuts through the darkness and...
The flaming falcon which races the skies.
Fire and lightning. The attacks of a mage and a knight...
Explode!
It punches through with incredible force!
And then the slash! A huge explosion!
We did our best.
Yeah.
If it were a normal opponent,
that would've ended it.
The legs are breaking and falling off.
Chief Yuuno and the others are
cautiously observing the situation.
It's not over yet!
It's a wild barrage!
With a great roar, it rises into the sky!
It's a shell-type multi-layer defense!
It won't be easy to get through this.
Coach!
Hurrrrrrrrrrrrgh!
Zafira's attack penetrates the barrier!
The follow up with his left fist
completely shatters the layered barrier!
That's amazing, Zafira!
Yeah.
Now that its defense is down,
the finisher's down to Hayate and Eins.
The inner space is a beautiful sky blue.
The spell I shot together with Eins, a long ranged attack!
Okay, here I go!
Spears of petrification!
Mistilteinn
The bright, petrifying spears
pierce the Darkness of the Book of Darkness!
The Darkness of the Book of Darkness is turned to stone in the blink of an eye!
Now it's over! Or so I'd like to think.
Everyone is watching with tense looks.
The insert song has ended, too.
Now, what's going to happen?
And the final touch goes to Chrono. Here you go.
Yeah, leave it to me.
Durandal, the Staff of Freezing, is in Full Drive.
The Reflectors deploy around the immobilized Darkness of the Book of Darkness!
Take this! Eternal Coffin!
The beam turns the sea to ice
as it flies over the water!
The reflectors each activate and start a flash freeze!
The Darkness of the Book of Darkness is getting frozen!
The head part's finally been frozen, too.
And now the finisher!
First up, Nanoha Takamachi!
At maximum power, Starlight Breaker!
Here it comes!
Second up, Fate Testarossa.
Lightning flash, Jet Zanber!
Here I go!
And third, Hayate Yagami.
The Darkness of the Book of Darkness evokes many different emotions, but I'll sound the horn of its end!
Here I go, Ragnarök!
One, two!
Breaker
Their three ultimate spells are coming down!
Nanoha's Starlight Breaker,
Fate's Jet Zanber, and Hayate's Ragnarök!
And the three together make a Triple Breaker!
It's turned into something crazy!
Miura, you use mana-gathering techniques too,
so you should be able to do this.
Yeah, you should.
I-I'll do my best to work towards that.
Fight!
Ah, Dr. Shamal's secured the core!
I somehow managed to find it.
Chief Yuuno and Arf are in charge of translocating it.
Yuuno was doing the control for it back then, right?
It was thanks to Arf helping out
that I could focus on the spell.
And now the core flies far away, straight into orbit!
The next part is up to Commodore Lindy!
But it's rapidly regenerating from just the core!
It's getting pretty disgusting.
The exit coordinates are perfect.
Now for the Arc-en-Ciel.
As soon as Commodore Lindy fires...
It goes flying out!
Big!
Just how much can it regenerate?
There's no beating this thing with normal methods.
With many emotions in her heart,
Commodore Lindy fires the Arc-en-Ciel!
It flies straight into the Darkness of the Book of Darkness!
The shot itself is only that big, huh?
Then everyone watches the sky silently.
And we're watching tensely, too.
The Arc-en-Ciel's activating!
The Darkness of the Book of Darkness is destroyed from the inside out.
There's a flash of light and then a huge explosion.
It's bright enough to see from the surface.
Everything within range of the explosion was annihilated.
Commodore Lindy and Amy confirm the destruction
of the Darkness of the Book of Darkness.
The situation is safely resolved!
This was the moment when the curse
of the Book of Darkness finally ended.
Everyone, good work on the commentary.
Thank you very much!
But from now on, there's going to be more sad scenes.
Yagami family team, is it okay
if we ask you some questions for this?
Sure.
Yeah.
Then we'll shift the main mic over to the Yagami residence.
Okay, it's been switched over.
We want to hear a lot more
about things like Eins's farewell.
Right.
Wait, where's Hayate?
She said she's stepping out for a moment.
She said it'd probably be easier for everyone else
to talk about their feelings for Eins if she's not here.
I don't think that's necessary.
It's just like Hayate to be so considerate.
Should Lutecia and I step outside, too?
No, you guys are fine.
Really?
We've also discussed it many times at home.
It might even be easier if you two are here.
Indeed.
Then we'll be listening quietly.
Miura, Lutecia, we'll leave it to you.
Ask us whatever.
Okay.
Roger that.
The barrier Eins put up has come down,
and the city's been returned to the way it was.
The peaceful Christmas Eve has returned.
But...
The atmosphere aboard the Arthra is a sad one.
Commander Yagami is sleeping in bed.
It's the sad farewell with Eins soon after this,
so what was everyone's relationship
with her like up to this point?
Dr. Shamal said she was like a little sister.
Yes, I like to think that she relied on me a little as well.
I'm pretty sure she did.
Yeah, I hope so.
Zafira and I don't talk much as it is,
so we didn't speak with her much.
We only have memories of her from after the Tome
became known as the Book of Darkness.
She seemed incredibly lonely
and was always apologizing.
She said she was truly sorry in the movie too.
Vita was always acting rebellious toward Eins.
I wasn't really rebellious...
I was just irritated about our fates and stuff like that.
Right.
Why couldn't we just live normally?
Why did we always have to listen to the orders of strangers
and do these things that we don't even want to?
We were adults, so we'd come to accept it.
I think that's probably why she was soft on me.
And when she was, I'd snap at her in anger
and say some pretty nasty things.
No matter what you said to her,
she always worried about you the most.
The only times she'd show one of
her rare smiles was to Vita, too.
I still remember it well, her reserved smile.
Did she express herself a little better before the farewell?
Just a little. We had a talk.
What about?
A bunch of things.
I apologized a bit for not being nicer to her and stuff.
What did Eins say?
She smiled, patted me on the head, and said
"I'm glad you'll remain by our mistress's side."
It was in her book form, but she had always
been watching over us and Hayate.
Whenever we talk about her,
it just always gets sort of sad.
It's fine. It's a wonderful story.
I only know Eins from hearing stories about her,
but I'm sure that she treasured you all
and loved you very much.
She'd lived with and watched over you
for all that time, after all.
That's why we wish we could have let her
live happily for even a little while.
That's right.
I'm sure our Meister feels the same way.
Yeah.
This is bad! It's getting too sad!
Hey, you two!
Yes?
If she saw her successor and her partner looking down from talking about her,
she'd definitely feel responsible and get sad!
Ah! That's right!
We can't just talk about sad things!
Miura, Lucy, you two as well!
Right.
Yeah.
Eins, are you watching?
Vita is actually acting like an older sister!
She's our Sissy!
And an instructor to boot!
Stop, it's a bit embarrassing.
Um, excuse us.
This is hosting headquarters.
Do you mind if we intrude?
No, you're not intruding.
It's okay.
Thank you for reminiscing about Eins.
Is it okay if we go on to the scene of the farewell
with Nanoha, Fate, and Commander Yagami?
Yep!
Go ahead.
Excuse us!
Me too.
Ah, everyone who was at this scene is here too.
Guess so. It's the second Reinforce, though.
And the Nanoha trio have all grown up, too.
Do you two remember this time?
Of course!
We can't possibly forget.
And of course, Hayate too.
Yeah.
But I can remember the time she was together with us,
as well as the times she was still a book, even more clearly.
I see.
After we removed the Darkness from the Book,
she was always smiling.
All of the expressions I can remember of her are her smiling.
It was a shy, reserved little smile,
but a really kind and warm one.
Farewells are sad.
If I said that this farewell wasn't still
left deep inside my heart, I'd be lying.
But rather than regret the parting and being sad,
I think it's more important to take what she left me—what she gave me—treasure it, and live on.
Right.
Heh, maybe I'm just making stuff up.
Not at all!
Yeah.
Luckily, my family are all doing well,
and I'm happy with my job.
The one carrying on her name and wishes is also very lively.
I am!
Our family's grown and has made
many new friends who come over and play.
Yeah!
So that Reinforce won't have to worry
about us on the other side of the sky...
So that she can keep smiling until the day I go see her,
we'll do our best and live together as a family.
Right.
Well, Vita said it too, but let's not be gloomy.
That's right.
Then what should we do?
Talk more about what we remember of Eins?
It seems like the only memory
you'd have of her is the fight.
W-Well, that's true for me.
But when you see Eins with such a peaceful expression,
you can't tell that she's actually really strong.
She was initially strong even without Nacht's power.
Her specialties were hand-to-hand and magical combat,
but she could use spears, swords, and bows too.
She could pretty much use all our weapons perfectly.
Eh? She could?
Did Eins use your attacks like
Thundering Explosion or Glittering Swordflash too?
She wouldn't call them out like that,
but she'd used each of them before.
When she uses Eisen or Lævateinn, their colors change.
They turn black and purple.
That might be pretty cool.
Lutecia also likes black and purple, right?
My magic's purple, after all.
Oh, if we go by the magic color divination,
what would Eins's black have meant?
Let's ask.
Divination master?
Yes, master here!
The color black or gray means that
they're knowledgeable and intelligent.
It sounds right.
It really does.
Eins also has a bit of purple, which stands for a strong sense of responsibility and deep affection for their loved ones.
So she's knowledgeable, intelligent,
responsible, and deeply affectionate.
It's completely right.
Yeah.
That would mean I'm like that too!
All your cruel reactions have broken my maiden heart!
Well, Lutecia's main color is purple,
so she's an affectionate child.
It's sort of reddish, so you're passionate too.
Let's forget knowledgeable for now.
You are clever, though.
So it's not too far off.
You girls sure do love divinations.
Really.
That's coming from our positive and kind Dr. Shamal
and responsible and passionate Captain Signum.
Huh? Did we just have ours done?
It feels a bit strange.
And now the farewell scene moves
to its most beautiful moment.
Eins has a really happy expression on her face.
But it's a bit painful when she turns away
from the crying Hayate.
She still walks on without turning back.
It's the Tome of the Night Sky's final journey.
We had to send her off.
The snowy landscape is really pretty.
Yeah, it truly is.
Eins's voice is really gentle.
The farewell's really sad, but in the time that she
was with you, she left behind many things, right?
That's true.
I haven't experienced a parting like this before,
but I think I understand a bit how sad it is and how it feels
to remember how precious they were once they're not there.
Just like Nanoha said,
there's no such thing as eternity.
Everything changes little by little, and eventually, it'll end.
But the memories we shared and the feelings passed on
will be there forever in our hearts.
Yeah.
In order to face our precious ones proudly,
the ones who inherit their wishes have to do their best!
I feel like I've learned something really important.
We've had many things passed on
to us from our loved ones, too.
Yeah!
And some day, you'll be the ones to pass on what you have.
Until then, make sure to experience many things
and mature into good adults.
Right!
We'll do our best!
Well then, there's only a short while before
this over-two-hour-long commentary will end.
We'll have the members who appeared in the movie
do their farewells in the next chapter,
so we've gathered our reporter team first!
So everyone, how'd you find being reporters?
Let's start with the Takamachi residence team, Vivio's group.
Vivio here!
After the first movie, this is my second time doing this,
but I was a lot more confident with
Rio, Corona, and Einhard alongside me.
Rio here!
I got to hear about a lot of things and got to talk
with everyone in other places, too, so it was fun!
Corona here.
I don't know if I did a good job as a reporter, but I had fun!
Einhard Stratos here.
I got to hear about many valuable experiences,
so it was very enlightening.
And now our veterans, Erio and Caro!
It was fun, just like usual.
We got to talk with Admiral Chrono and
Chief Yuuno together, so it was a bit new and fresh.
I wonder if we'll ever get to be the
main commentators for our own movie.
Let's believe we will!
I'm sure we will someday.
Well, let's not get too hyped while we wait, okay?
So then, Rein and Agito?
I heard many things that took me back
and many new things too.
I'm sure Eins is also watching over us
from above the sky and laughing.
Right, Agito?
Yeah.
I feel like going around to see the people who've helped us
and visiting the graves of the ones we owe so much to.
Let's go together.
We'll be heading to the same places anyway.
Yeah!
Thank you very much.
One of them is flying right here, though.
Teehee.
And following them are Lutecia and Miura.
I'm only here now because of many people
who reached out to save me in similar ways,
so I've been reflecting on that a lot.
Well, I'll just pretend to be bright like normal for now.
Ah, Miura here.
Um, I haven't been as involved as everyone else, but I'm
happy that you invited me and told me all sorts of stories.
I definitely won't forget what everyone has told me today!
Um, thank you very much.
There's still some time left in this chapter.
Everyone, which parts did you like the most?
Me, me! The battle commentary parts were really fun!
I thought so too!
I liked that part too, but I guess
it was the divination corner for me.
We had a lot of fun with that one last time too.
We sure did.
Oh? What color was Miura again?
Mine's pink.
Her color is pretty close to my mama's.
I feel like mine might be a little redder than Nanoha's.
The light of Nanoha's magic is really pretty.
Reddish pink would be innocent and passionate, right?
It's a bullseye!
Yep.
Ah! No, no!
Seems like there's quite a few reddish hues
among you athlete girls.
Oh, I think you're right.
Oh, here comes another famous scene in the movie.
It's Hayate's last tearful scene.
It's a little tragic.
I wonder if Hayate is as kind and gentle as she is today
because she's been through those tearful moments.
I'm sure that's it.
Nanoha and Fate are really kind, too.
Yeah.
Just like Hayate, Nanoha and Fate
resolve to continue walking towards the future.
And then they return home
where their families are waiting.
Right.
And that means it's about time for this chapter to end.
The organizers for this commentary were me, Subaru Nakajima,
who appeared more as a divination master, along with...
Teana Lanster, who probably appeared more as a mediator and a comedic straight man than an organizer.
In the last chapter, we'll be getting a final message
from each of our main commentators.
Everyone stay with us till the end, okay?
Okay!
Right, so the movie's skipped forward two years.
It's the last scene.
Great work sticking with it, everyone.
We'll be doing our parting words in order.
Right! We're at the last part,
and I finally get an actual organizer task.
We'll be calling each of you up in order.
First up is Instructor Vita.
Yeah, I got to talk about a lot of old memories.
I talked a bunch with Vivio, Miura,
and Lucy's group, so it was fun.
Vita doesn't really get embarrassed even
when she watches footage from her childhood.
At least not out of the house.
I know, right?
I'd rather not.
Thank you very much.
How about Dr. Shamal?
I had a lot of fun!
I didn't get to appear that much in the movie,
but it's great to enjoy it with everyone.
Dr. Shamal is everyone's doctor, after all.
Well then, Captain Signum, go ahead.
I reflected on many things thanks to this like my past,
a dearly departed friend, and the blessings I now have.
It was a nice opportunity.
Thank you very much.
How about you, Zafira?
It was a good discussion.
It's great that the kids had fun, too.
Oh, uh, thank you very much!
Coach, that's too short!
At the very least, you should, um...
It's not good to talk too much.
Right?
Well, the ending theme's prelude is starting.
Admiral Chrono, how was it for you?
I didn't think you'd have me
do the battle commentary too.
I feel like I've gone back to being a kid again.
Thank you.
It was fun.
Thank you very much.
What about Chief Yuuno?
Ah, I don't show up much in this one,
but I'm happy to have been invited.
You contributed a lot both
with the investigation and on scene.
I'm glad we got to hear from you!
And now someone else who played
a large role in these events, Fate.
I had fun the whole time, but I was especially
happy to talk about Alicia with everyone.
It'd be nice if Alicia—if my sister—was laughing with us from the other side of the sky.
Thank you very much.
Nanoha, go ahead.
Okay.
It was another good opportunity to reminisce.
My appearances were mostly in the aerial battles,
but I'm an air combat instructor, so I'm okay with that.
You had plenty of appearances apart from the battles!
That's right!
Right?
Thank you.
And finally, Commander Yagami!
Right.
I had a really great time.
The Book of Darkness Incident ends here, but it'd be nice
if we had another chance to do something like this.
I know, right?
Oh, and...
Reinforce? Are you watching?
Everyone's still here and doing well!
And our families and circle of friends have both grown a lot!
Your successor and her partner are both doing well!
Yep!
Thank you very much.
So then, let's finish up with the ending theme.
Everyone, thank you so very much!
One, two...
See you later!