The hot comet dwelling within my heart beats towards the beginning.
My fingers tremble, grasping upon a silent wish
I cower, wanting to flee from the inescapable past
Even if it is merely a faint light fading
I want to chase after it, just like that star
And accept everything, no matter how high it is
Dancing throughout the galaxy is the angel's whisper
Pursuing these certain memories
The door to the truth will surely be born now
No matter what kind of cold darkness binds me
Because I want to know
I won't be stopped
Episode 1
Wings to the Sky
April 29, 0071
Northern Midchilda, 8th Coastal Airport
When I was little, I was really weak—a crybaby.
I always cowered from sad or difficult things.
Anyway, all I could do was cry.
It's no use! We can't put it out!
But there's a kid up ahead!
Can't you do anything about it?
They just reported a mage from the Main Office broke in. Search for other survivors instead!
Dad?
Sis?
It hurts... and it's hot...
I don't like this... I want to go home!
Help...
Somebody, save me!
Good, I made it. I've come to save you.
You've done your best, right? That's impressive!
Everything is okay now. I'll take you to a safe place.
Upward clearance confirmation.
A firing lock is cancelled.
Let's pierce through to the surface with one shot.
All right. Load Cartridge.
Buster set.
Divine...
...Buster
This is Rescue Unit 01.
I've rescued a girl from the entrance hall.
Thank you very much...
as expected from the flying ace of aces!
After dropping her off with the medical team on the west bank, I'll resume with the rescue effort.
Yes, please!
I was rescued from the inferno...
and brought into the expansive sky.
The cold wind was gentle...
and the arm embracing me was warm.
The person who saved me was strong, kind, and cool.
I was ashamed of myself for only crying and being unable to do anything.
Since that time, for the first time in my life, I firmly believed in my heart.
April 0075, Midchilda
8th Coastal Airport Abandoned Highway
Being able to only cry and to do nothing...
I won't be like that anymore...
Because I will become stronger.
Subaru, if you move around too much,
those cheap rollerblades are going to fall apart during the exam.
Tia, don't jinx it! I oiled them before I came.
Good morning.
Now then, are the two mages who will be taking this exam here?
Yes, ma'am!
I'm going to confirm your identity, all right?
Is Private First Class Subaru Nakajima of
the Time-Space Administrative Bureau's
386th Battalion present?
Yes, ma'am!
And Private First Class Teana Lanster?
You two are currently C rank mages.
Today you will be taking the qualifying
mage exam for B rank. I'm not mistaken, am I?
Yes, ma'am!
You're not mistaken.
Okay! I will be your proctor today, Command Sergeant Major Reinforce Zwei.
Pleased to meet you!
The pleasure is ours!
Ah, they're already getting started.
Rein is really being a proper examiner, too.
Lt. Colonel, Time-Space Administrative Bureau
Hayate Yagami
Hayate, it's dangerous to watch from the door.
Enforcer, Time-Space Administrative Bureau Main Office
Fate T. Harlaown
You can see it on the monitor anyway.
Okay.
So these two are the ones you picked out?
Yes, and both of them have some pretty interesting grades.
Depending on the results of today's exam—if they make it—will they be officially assigned?
The final decision is in Nanoha's hands.
I see.
If they make it onto the squad,
They'll be under Nanoha's direct command
and training under her.
There is no life response within the range.
There is no dangerous object, either.
Check of the course was finished.
Thank you, Raising Heart.
The surveillence searchers and the Auto-Spheres's obstruction field calibrations are done.
Shall we just sit back and watch the show?
Yes, my master.
You two will start here.
Your objective is to destroy the point targets.
Oh, and of course, there are dummy targets which you mustn't destroy, understand?
Be careful of incoming attacks, and destroy all the targets.
Also be sure to reach the goal before the timer runs out.
Are there any questions?
Hmm...
No.
None.
Well then, we'll be starting in just a bit.
I'll seeya at the goal!
Ready...
...go!
It's starting!
Let's see what they've got.
Subaru...
I'll take the targets inside!
I am letting you go...
Okay!
Load Cartridge
Revolver...
...Shoot
Calm down...
It's a beginner's skill.
Nice timing!
Of course!
They make a good pair.
They are, but the hard part is yet to come.
Especially when this makes its appearance,
That last challenge at which more than half of all examinees are defeated,
The Large-Scale Auto-Sphere.
Looking at that pair's skill now, it would normally be hard to defend against or evade it.
The Sphere uses medium and long range attacks, making it a difficult opponent.
How will they get past it?
They'll have to show their experience and courage.
Let's go!
Subaru, shut up!
Good! All clear.
What's up next?
If we keep heading up, we'll come under more concentrated fire.
Utilizing Optic Hide, we'll sneak up and destroy the spheres with Cross Shift.
Let's do it!
Roger!
Five...
Four...
Three...
Two...
One...
Zero!
Crossfire...
Revolver...
...Shoot
I see! They certainly do look promising.
I knew they would.
Now all that's left is the final challenge.
Yay! Nice one, Tia! We finished it in one blow!
Well, that's because we've got so much time.
These enemies don't seem all that difficult...
Tia, you must be strong after all!
Shut it! Hurry up and finish this
so we can move on—
Subaru, get down!
Tia!
What happened?
It seems the searcher was hit by a stray bullet.
I wonder if they're in trouble?
Rein, I'm going to take a look, just in case, all right?
Yes indeedy, please go ahead.
Am I set up?
I suppose. Just to be sure, please.
All right. Barrier Jacket standing up.
Tia!
Don't make a fuss! It's nothing.
Don't lie!
You tripped! It's sprained, isn't it?
I told you it's noth—
Tia, I'm sorry. I let my guard down.
It was because of my carelessness.
If you apologize, I'll be mad when we get back.
It looks like I can't run anymore.
I won't be able to pass the last test.
Tia...
I'll keep my distance and support you. That way...
You can make it to the goal by yourself.
Tia!
Shut up!
I'm telling you that at the next exam I will pass by myself!
The next one?
That's more than a half a year away!
Rather than being a bother and dragging you down, I feel more comfortable doing it this way.
If you understand that, then hurr—
Look, just hurry up!
Tia, I told you before, didn't I?
How I hated myself for being weak, useless, and always wanting help from others?
That's why I enlisted in the Bureau's Ground Armed Service.
Aiming to become a mage...
Studying magic and Shooting Arts...
And finally working to save people.
I know that. Even though I didn't want to hear it,
You told me many times over anyway.
Because we've always been together, Tia.
What you dream to become, and why you're working so hard to raise your mage rank,
Your anxiety and your hard work...
I know them too well!
That's why, in a place like this, right in front of me,
To see you fail to achieve your dream when it's so close to you...
I don't want that!
And I definitely don't want to finish this alone!
Then what are you going to do?
Trying to cover for someone who can't even run,
in the short amount of time we have left, how are you going to reach the goal?
We'll use that trick. It might be against the rules if we get caught,
And I'm not sure if I can do it properly;
But if it goes well, we can both reach the goal.
Really?
It might be a little hard, and it'll require you to push yourself a little bit.
When I think about it, it might be a bit too reckless...
How do I say it? But if you're okay with it, then...
This is so annoying!
No matter what you're going to say, you'll still follow your selfish decision, right?
You're going to make me go along with your selfishness anyway, right?
If so, then just say it clearly!
If we do it together, we will succeed.
Believe in me, Tia.
3 minutes and 40 seconds remaining.
What's the plan?
Right on!
She came out!
Yes... well, that's odd..
However...
A direct hit!
No, not quite.
High-speed evasion? No, that's not it...
That Tia is a decoy.
Then that means...
Fake Silhouette
This uses up an excessive amount of mana.
I can't hold it for too long.
Finish it with a single blow, so we'll both have it easier.
Right.
I can't fly in the sky, and I'm not as skillful as Tia.
I don't have any decently ranged attacks, either.
The only thing I can do is to run full-speed and finish it with one shot at close range.
After all, I've decided to be like that person...
To be strong!
To be able to protect someone or something by myself!
Wingroad
Let's do it!
Here I go!
With a single blow!
Divine Buster
You did it!
Somehow...
There's only about a minute remaining, Subaru!
Got it!
Here they come!
How many seconds left?
Sixteen seconds. We can still make it!
Okay, all targets cleared!
Magic at full power!
Subaru, you are thinking about how we're going to stop, right?
Huh?
Oh no!
Ah, this doesn't look good.
An Active Guard with a Holding Net should do it.
Active Guard with Holding Net
Grrr...
You two! Minus points for dangerous maneuvers!
You should try your best, but not if you get hurt!
Because of that, you'll be no good as mages!
Tiny...
Honestly!
Now, now...
That was a little surprising, but it's good to know you're safe.
For the time being, the exam is over.
Thanks for the hard work.
Rein, thanks for the hard work also.
You've become a real proctor.
Yaaaaay! Thank you so much, Nanoha!
Well, let's leave the details for later.
Private First Class Lanster.
Yes, ma'am?
You injured your foot, didn't you?
I'll treat it. Can you take off your boot?
If she needs treatment, I'll do it!
Thanks... sorry to trouble you.
Nanoha?
I mean, Instructor Takamachi...
No, Captain!
Nanoha is fine. That's what everyone else calls me.
It's been four years, right?
You've really gotten taller, Subaru.
Well.. uh... ah...
I'm happy to see you again.
Well then, how well did those two do in Nanoha's eyes? I wonder if they passed.
I wonder...
Without end, the dreams continue to weave
Surpassing thousands of nights
Like a prayer, the journey continues
Be my guide any day, oh small jewel
Spica among the stars
I engrave beyond the horizon
The faint footsteps that are connected to everywhere
The reflection of your eyes casts away the loop of anxiety
The midnight sun
The Orion of Midsummer
Just now from somewhere, I heard your voice
This heart without darkness
Illumine it, o distant blue star
No matter what the time, I will be able to start walking
Sparkling far and near
Watching over me
The thing inside my heart, overflowing
More than tears, I want to be loved
Like a prayer, the journey continues
Be my guide anyday, oh small jewel
Spica among the stars
Next
Episode
Preview
Next
Episode
Preview
The incident at the airport
four years ago started it all.
Inside the burning flames, there were many encounters,
And it was the beginning of many determinations.
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS:
Episode 2
Riot Force 6
Episode 2: Riot Force 6
Take off!