Pain from the past, and stubborn pride, as well as mistakes...
The small wings that stumbled managed to spread out on their own.
I'm watching over you, so that all your failures and hesitation will help you tomorrow.
So that your stumbles and regrets may someday be treasures.
When we train our hardest every day,
sometimes we need a rest.
Sometimes you need to take a nice break.
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS
will now begin.
The hot comet dwelling within my heart beats towards the beginning.
My fingers tremble, grasping upon a silent wish
I cower, wanting to flee from the inescapable past
Even if it is merely a faint light fading
I want to chase after it, just like that star
And accept everything, no matter how high it is
Dancing throughout the galaxy is the angel's whisper
Pursuing these certain memories
The door to the truth will surely be born now
No matter what kind of cold darkness binds me
Because I want to know
I won't be stopped
Dear Ginny,
It's been two weeks since that little incident.
Tia.
It's morning!
It's time to get up!
Tia.
Get up!
Hey, Tia!
It's our turn to set up the practice field today.
Get moving!
So you're up?
Why you! I let my guard down for just a second, and you sexually harass me!
It's just to get us a little closer.
Tia is completely back to normal.
Morning, Caro.
Morning.
And after what happened, I've been able to discuss a lot more things in depth with Erio and Caro.
It's kind of nice.
Okay, that's the morning training and the mock battle.
Good work.
And just so you know, this was the test to see if you've all cleared the second stage.
What do you think?
Pass.
That was fast!
Well, after all the practice they've done,
it would be a serious issue if they still sucked.
I think you're all doing well.
Okay then, you've cleared the second stage.
Yes!
We'll take off a stage of your device limiters
so go see Shari later, okay?
Tomorrow we'll have you start training with the basic form of your Devices' second modes.
Yes, ma'am!
Wait... tomorrow?
Yeah, we'll start training again tomorrow.
We're supposed to stay on standby at HQ today.
Everyone has been training every day since you've joined.
So you see...
You all have the rest of the day off.
Go out to the city and have fun!
Okay!
Episode 10
Riot Force 6's Day Off
(part 1)
That was your entertainment news for the day.
And now for political and economic news.
Yesterday at the Bureau's Ground Central HQ on Midchilda,
a budgetary conference for next year was held.
This is the third budget that has been submitted,
and every planet is watching carefully due to concerns about taxation issues.
The Capital Defense Corps representative,
Lt. General Regius Gaiz,
made an announcement concerning the Bureau's defensive policies.
The advancement and evolution of magic and technology is a wonderful thing.
However!
This means that the dangers and disasters that face us
are of a scale far greater than they were ten years ago!
Strengthening our weapons is a method to protecting an evolving society!
We do not yet have enough people to adequately defend the capital.
If our proposed budget passes,
with a 20% increase in the crime rate,
we can expect a 35% increase in the arrest rate from the very first year!
Is that alter Knacker still rambling on about that?
Lt. General Regius has been a hawk for a long time now.
Oh, that's Admiral Midget.
Granny Midget?
...become a hotbed of smuggling
and other serious crimes!
Main Office Chief of Staff
Midget Crowbel
No, it is already in that process.
Honorary Field Marshal
Largo Kiel
Marshal Kiel and
Judicial Advisor
Leone Phils
Judicial Advisor Phils are there too.
All three of the legendary admirals are there.
But if you look at them now,
they just look like a bunch of alter Knacker.
You can't say that, Vita!
They're an important group of people!
They're the ones who took the Bureau from its beginnings to what it is today.
Hey, I like this bunch of alter Knacker.
We once accepted a mission to guard them.
Admiral Midget seems to like Mistress Hayate and Vita.
I see.
That makes sense.
I don't mind loaning it to you, but don't blow it out.
What kind of protector are you using?
My own autobarrier.
But you know, I watch your training sometimes,
and you've changed the way you work lately.
Yes.
Up until now your movements were the same
whether you were in a team,
on your own, or in a pair.
Lately you've become a lot more adaptable.
You've started to act more like a center.
It's thanks to everybody's help.
Okay, it's looking good.
Here.
Thanks.
I'm sorry if I shouldn't ask this, but...
You were a mage once, right, Sgt. Vice?
Well, I am from the Armed Services.
I have just enough experience to give lectures to complete amateurs.
But even so, I've always loved helicopters,
so now I'm a pilot.
Your partner's waiting. Get going.
Thank you!
You have your handkerchief, right?
Did you remember your ID card?
I'm all set.
Do you have enough money?
I don't want you to run out, so...
Fate, I'm getting paid, you know.
Oh... I see.
I'm fine. Thank you.
Well, you're a boy and two months older than Caro.
So make sure you escort her properly.
I will.
Sorry to have kept you waiting.
You look very pretty, Caro. How cute!
Thank you.
Are those the right size?
Yes, they're perfect!
Very nice.
Well then, make sure you don't crash.
It's all right.
We rode every day in my old squad.
Tia is a good rider.
Okay.
I'll buy you a present, like cookies or something.
Thanks, but don't worry about it.
You two go have fun.
We will.
We're off!
Is the Lightning Squad heading out together?
We're going now.
Okay. Be careful.
Come back before dark.
The town is dangerous at night.
Okay!
Signum.
Vita.
Are you heading out?
Yes, to the 108th Battalion and the Church of the Heiliger Kaiser.
Major Nakajima is going to make us a Joint Investigation HQ, so we're meeting about that.
You too, Vita?
I'll be teaching tactics to their mages.
I never should've gotten this teaching credential.
If it has to do with the investigation, I should go too.
Making preparations is my job.
You're the squad leader, and I'm your assistant.
Thank you. Are you sure about this?
Do what you want.
I'm glad the removing of the first limiters went well.
Yes.
Starting tomorrow, we'll be busy adjusting them,
so finishing the adjustments on Nanoha's and Raising Heart's unlimited mode,
Exceed Mode, is what I want to work on right now, okay?
And Bardiche's Zanber Mode too.
We'll be busy.
This is fun!
We should give you a complete check-up while we're at it, Command Sergeant Major Rein.
That's right.
If you please.
Roger that.
You haven't needed to enter Unison with anybody lately, right?
No. Neither Hayate, Signum, nor Vita has needed to use me.
That's a good thing in and of itself, right?
But I need to be ready to live up to my name,
Reinforce, the Wind of Blessing,
so take care of my check-up, and check the Buch der blauer Himmel, Shari.
Okay.
This is fun!
Hold on tight!
I'm fine!
The weather's nice.
This is a great day for riding a motorcycle.
Yeah, I just want to keep going on forever.
We can do something else if you want,
but we're having fun in town first, right?
For now, let's go to town, get some ice cream, and then decide what else.
Sure, sure.
Okay, I'm going to gun it!
The plan for today that Shari made for us...
starts with going to Third Avenue via railway,
walking around the city together,
and enjoying window shopping and conversation.
Then we're to eat in a place with an atmosphere conducive to conversation.
I pray for your success.
This seems kind of hard.
For now, let's just go with what she planned.
By the way, Caro, you have another dragon besides Fried, right?
Yes, Voltaire. He's an immense black dragon.
I raised Fried from an egg, but Voltaire is an ancient guardian dragon of the world of Alzus.
So it's more that I'm Voltaire's priestess and that he's lending me power than he's my dragon.
It's something like that.
I see. It would be nice if you could introduce him to me like Fried.
But if he's that important of a dragon,
then I guess you can't just bring him here for me to say hello to him.
He's very large, and I can only borrow his power when I really need it.
But I'll be sure to introduce you to him someday.
And it seems that Fried thinks of you as a real friend, Erio.
That's good.
I'm sure Voltaire will like you.
Third Avenue South Exit.
To get to Outer Gateway, please use platforms 9 to 12.
To get to the Fairway, please use platforms 7 and 8.
The ice cream here looks really awesome!
Thanks.
You really like ice cream!
'Cause it's so yummy! Mmm... ice cream!
Okay then.
Cheers!
Once we eat our ice cream, let's go to the arcade.
Good idea! We haven't been there in a long time.
This is really nice once in a while, isn't it?
It is!
Hayate, look who's back!
Welcome back.
Did you get a maintenance check?
Yes indeedy,
A full check of me and the Buch der blauer Himmel.
I see.
Shari is going to come and take your
Buch der Nachthimmel and Schwertkreuz later.
Roger.
I hope we can spend the day resting.
Yes indeedy.
We really are taking it easy.
Don't do that.
Caro, did you spend your breaks like this before you came to Riot Force 6?
Actually, not really.
But Fate took me to amusement parks and aquariums sometimes.
Really? Me too!
The first time she took me to an amusement park, it was really fun.
Too fun.
When the sun went down and my funtime was over, I was so sad.
I cried just a bit.
I can understand that.
The day before you're looking forward to it so much you can't sleep,
and when it's over you're just so sad.
Yes! That's exactly it!
I understand that. But Fate was really busy
and still found time to look after me.
Yes.
This is Lightning 3.
Hi! This is Stars 3.
How's your day off?
Having fun?
Yes,
even though we just got started.
We were wondering if you were having any problems.
Thank you!
Anyway, we're fine.
What are you doing?
We're at the park as planned,
and then we're going to a department store.
That's what we're doing.
After that, we'll eat and see a movie,
And then we'll go to the coastline and watch the sunset this evening.
That's the plan they made for us.
We're going to clear them all in order.
Clear? Those kids!
Well, it's healthy.
No, don't worry about it.
Okay, if anything comes up,
Give us a call.
We're senior to you in terms of playing in town too.
Great!
Thank you!
Later.
Subaru and Tia are nice.
But it really has been a long time since we've relaxed this much.
Hasn't it.
Here.
I hope there aren't any crimes or accidents or anything.
Yeah.
Sergeant Ginga Nakajima, with the Ground Armed Service's 108th Battalion
I've come to help investigate the scene.
Thank you.
I heard that it was a rollover accident.
Yes, but the circumstances of the rollover were strange.
Furthermore, the driver is in a state of total shock.
It seems he was attacked by something,
and then his cargo blew up.
All he was carrying were bottled drinks and canned goods.
Nothing that explodes.
And there is something strange down there.
Is this a life pod?
The six Type 1 Drones that were following the Relic signal have all been destroyed.
Oh my. Was it a Bureau mage who took them out?
Or did we get lucky?
I can't say for sure, but it seems to be the latter.
Splendid.
I'll chase after it immediately.
Hey, Doctor,
I'd like to go, then.
Nove, you would?
No, Nove.
Your weapons are still being adjusted.
If we did get lucky this time,
then I want to see for myself.
There's no need to hurry.
It will certainly come here sometime.
For now, I'd like you to just wait.
Understood?
I understand.
Let's launch the Drones once we get a better handle on the situation.
I'll find somebody suitable from my younger sisters.
Sure, and while I'm at it, I'll ask my dear friend.
My sweet Lutecia, can you hear me?
This has to do with a Relic.
Can you help me out a bit?
I have to go.
Erio?
Caro, did you hear something?
Like what?
It was like grinding or something.
An alert to everyone from Caro?
What is it, I wonder.
This is Lightning 4!
We have an emergency situation. I will report.
We've found a case believed to be a Relic
in a back alley at F23 Third Avenue.
There is a girl who we believe was carrying the case.
The girl is unconscious.
Give us orders, please.
Subaru, Teana, I'm sorry,
but your break is cancelled.
Yes, ma'am!
It's okay.
We'll get medical assistance ready.
You two secure the girl and the case.
Give her first aid.
Yes, ma'am!
All staff on standby.
Anybody who isn't at their post, return to it.
Yes, ma'am!
Recover the girl and the Relic safely and securely.
Roger.
Without end, the dreams continue to weave
Surpassing thousands of nights
Like a prayer, the journey continues
Be my guide any day, oh small jewel
Spica among the stars
I engrave beyond the horizon
The faint footsteps that are connected to everywhere
The reflection of your eyes casts away the loop of anxiety
The midnight sun
The Orion of Midsummer
Just now from somewhere, I heard your voice
This heart without darkness
Illumine it, o distant blue star
No matter what the time, I will be able to start walking
Sparkling far and near
Watching over me
The thing inside my heart, overflowing
More than tears, I want to be loved
Like a prayer, the journey continues
Be my guide anyday, oh small jewel
Spica among the stars
Next
Episode
Preview
Next
Episode
Preview
A girl
brought a Relic to us.
An incident
began to take shape.
Battles will be fought on the ground and in the sky.
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS:
Episode 11: Riot Force 6's Day Off (part 2)
Episode 11
Riot Force 6's Day Off
(part 2)
Toward the sky, I too will take off!