In the vast ocean of worlds,
this is a story that took place in a small country
on a small planet.
I didn’t see it with my own eyes,
but my family and my dear friends told me all about it.
It all started in June two years ago.
Uminari Univ. Hospital Dr. Ishida
Thank you.
You have one new message.
Hello, this is Dr. Ishida with Uminari University Hospital.
Well, it’s your birthday tomorrow, Hayate.
How about we go out to lunch after your checkup tomorrow?
Could you get back to me before you come tomorrow?
Okay, bye.
End of message.
I’m disengaging the seal.
Ich hebe das Siegel auf.
Booting.
Anfang.
December 2, City of Uminari
Good morning, master.
Good morning to you too, Raising Heart.
This spring,
I had a few important encounters.
I met Yuuno, my teacher in magic,
and I learned about the existence of magical powers.
There’s also my dear partner, Raising Heart.
And then... there was Fate.
I first met Fate half a year ago.
We didn’t always see eye to eye.
We clashed and fought because of our misunderstandings.
There was a lot of pain and sorrow.
A lot happened in a short time.
And I mean a lot.
But Fate returned my feelings,
and we became friends.
We went our separate ways,
only to meet again.
Fate...
Nanoha...
Fate!
Welcome back, Fate.
I’m back, Nanoha.
Time-Space Administrative Bureau Main Office
You think Fate’s in tears after seeing Nanoha again?
Probably.
You want this mattress upstairs, ma’am?
Yes, please!
Hey, careful.
Yeah.
Seishō University Magnet Elementary School
Today, we have a new friend joining this class.
A transfer student?
A boy? A girl?
Fate, come in.
E-Excuse me.
I’m Fate Testarossa.
Pleased to meet you.
Yeah, we’re pretty much done moving in.
Really?
Arf was a great help.
No, not at all.
You can relax a bit now, Captain.
You’re right.
I’ll use my break wisely.
We’ll contact you again.
Arf, say hi to Fate for me.
Sure.
All right.
We can take a short break, then go shopping.
Oh, okay.
I still don’t know much about this world,
so I’m counting on you.
I’ll do my best.
Well, um...
Commodore Lindy?
Thanks for taking Fate under your wing.
Where’d that come from?
I’m grateful to you, Chrono, and Amy
for all your help with Fate’s magic test and trial.
You’ve been so kind.
You really went out of your way for Fate and Nanoha.
I’m Fate’s and your legal guardian. It’s my job.
But to move to and go to school in this world...
I’m glad Fate came around.
When Fate first heard about it,
she cried the whole night.
Now she’s so happy and excited.
Dear Fate
Nanoha
Suzuka
Dear Fate
Nanoha
Suzuka
Dear Fate
Nanoha
Suzuka
Both you and Fate went through a lot.
But from now, you get to choose your own future.
Yeah.
You and Fate are both so sweet. I love you two.
I’d be happy if you’d stay with me forever.
Thank you.
Chrono, Amy, how have you been?
Commodore Laty, it’s been a while.
Hello, ma’am.
Fate left already?
Yes, she should be at school by now.
I see.
Lindy’s with her, so she can rest for a while.
Yes, ma’am.
Now about the case I want you to handle, Chrono.
Track and arrest the trespassers.
Their main violations are poaching of large animals and plundering of mages.
Plundering?
They are attacking to extract
the power source of a mage,
the Linker Core.
Fate, Nanoha, bye!
See you tomorrow!
See ya!
Nanoha and Fate both seemed so happy.
You’re right. I haven’t seen Nanoha that happy in a while.
Yeah.
Fate, what’d you think of school?
Our teacher and classmates are all kind,
so I think I’ll be fine.
Good to hear!
Oh yeah, I have a lot of things from Yuuno and Chrono for you.
Like study materials on magic and a new training program.
We can work on them together, Nanoha.
Yeah! We can practice magic together from now!
Yeah.
I feel a bit bad keeping Alisa and Suzuka in the dark though.
We shouldn’t make them worry. Plus, it’s not for us to decide.
Listen, Nanoha.
Yeah?
There are so many things I don’t know about
school or this world in general.
I may cause trouble for you and make you worry, but...
It’s fine.
I’d do the same thing in your shoes.
Well, I’ll...
I’ll do my best.
I’ll be in your care from now on, Nanoha.
And I’ll be in yours, Fate!
Did you get to catch up with Fate?
Yep!
Yuuno, are you busy with work?
Yeah, I guess so.
The Infinity Library is massive, after all.
Ah.
Fate, I’m ready!
Oh my, Arf! Why have you become so small?
Because a wolf stands out too much.
We’re playing it smart.
I see.
We’re going on a walk.
Okay, just be careful.
I’ve detected a large mana signature.
Ich habe eine große magische Reaktion entdeckt.
Alright.
Let’s do this, Graf Eisen.
Indeed.
Einverstanden.
Magical Prison
Gefängnis der Magie
Caution. Emergency.
A barrier?!
Communications down.
Something is approaching.
Arf!
Gotcha!
Incoming.
Homing bullet.
Deadly Smash
Tödlichschlag
Raising Heart, please!
Standby, ready. Set up.
Swallow’s Flight
Schwalbenflug
Go!
Crap...
An aerial-combat mage!
Why’d you try to ambush me?
Who are you? What do you want?
I won’t understand if you don’t tell me!
Kiss my ass!
Cannon Mode
Listen...
Divine...
...to me!
...Buster
Graf Eisen, load cartridge!
Explosion
Rocket Form
Raketenform
Rocket...
Raketen...
...Hammer
Protection
Smash through!
Roger.
Jawohl.
Book of Darkness, collect.
Nanoha!
Nanoha, answer me!
Decline in mana energy reading.
Raising Heart is not responding.
What’s this unsettling feeling?
Yes, from Fate and Arf.
Confirmed. A seal-type capturing barrier.
Enemy E.T.A. is 16 seconds.
Noch sechzehn Sekunden, bis die Feinde nähern.
Crap, I need more time here.
No problem. The general is coming.
Kein Problem. Der General kommt.
Signum... Shamal and Zafira, too...
You shall not pass.
I’m sorry, dear.
But...
Keep still.
Hm...
Not bad swordplay for a mage.
Roger!
Jawohl!
Nanoha!
Lævateinn.
Explosion
Glittering...
...Swordflash
Collection complete.
Die Sammlung ist fertig.
Vita, I took out a mage.
Pass me the Book of Darkness.
Here.
Let’s go, Eisen.
Indeed.
Einverstanden.
Impressive.
Still moving?
Is she family or something?
My friend.
We’ve been apart. I finally got to see her.
She’s my best friend!
I see. Sorry about that.
But like you,
we have our own reasons.
Let’s go back now.
December 2, 8:34 PM
Same time: Medical Section
They’re not injured.
They’re just asleep.
We have two problems.
There’s been a temporary decline in their magical output due to the draining of their Linker Cores,
and all three have sustained serious injuries,
but they’ve been treated at least.
As you all know, this is an emergency!
This team will investigate the trespassers case.
Yes, sir!
Let’s aim for a swift arrest!
Yes, ma’am!
The cores and the basic frames are unharmed.
Don’t worry. I’ll have you fixed in no time.
Photos from the scene?
Valuable data Raising Heart and Bardiche recorded for us.
Chrono?
You recognize that book?
A Lost Logia, the Book of Darkness.
A first-class dangerous relic from Ancient Belka.
The Book of Darkness?! You mean...
December 3, 6:30 AM
Yagami residence
Good morning, Book of Darkness.
December 3, 7:45 AM
Nanoha!
Oh! Fate...
Good morning, Nanoha.
How are you feeling?
I can’t use magic, but I’m fine physically.
I see. Same for Arf and me.
I see.
Oh, Fate.
You came to save me, right?
I’m sorry, and thank you.
No...
I was useless in the end.
That’s not true! Thank you, Fate.
But who were they?
Well, I was just ambushed, so...
But Chrono’s investigating the case, so it should be fine.
Yeah, you’re right.
Yeah.
Oh!
Fate, do you have time after school today?
Huh?
I wanna check up on Raising Heart and Bardiche.
Sorry, did I wake you?
Oh, not at all.
You should sleep in a bed, or you’ll catch a cold.
Oh... sorry...
Were you up late?
Yes, a little.
I see.
I’m sorry! I slept through my alarm!
Good morning, Shamal.
Good morning.
Good morning, Vita.
Yeah.
Come on, Vita. Go wash up.
1:35 PM
Engineering Section, Bureau Main Office
Hello.
Oh, hi, Fate.
And you must be...
Nanoha?
Yes, ma’am.
I’m Mariel Atenza with Engineering.
I’m junior to Chrono and Amy.
I’m Nanoha Takamachi.
You came to check in on your Devices?
They’re running system checks,
so you can’t talk with them, but go ahead.
Yes, ma’am.
It’ll take time, but we’ll get them fixed.
So don’t worry.
They must’ve been incredibly powerful
to have damaged your Devices to this extent.
They were different. I’ve never seen a magic circle like that.
That was Belkan magic.
The authentic kind.
Ancient Belka...
A pure offensive magic from ancient times.
A mage of this style is called a knight.
Then what was exploding inside their Devices?
The magic cartridge system.
They load shells filled with
compressed mana into their Devices,
which gives them explosive destructive power.
You need a powerful Device and a talented mage.
Without both, you end up with
a weapon that blows up in your face.
It’s a dangerous and unsafe system, but...
This one?
Yes!
Thank you so much.
Wow, we’re the same age?
Yeah.
I’ve seen you around here and thought maybe you were my age.
Me too.
Um, I’m Suzuka Tsukimura.
Suzuka, huh?
I’m Hayate Yagami.
Hayate...
Uminari University Hospital
Oh, hi there.
Dr. Ishida.
Thank you for your time.
Of course.
Hayate, how have you been?
Um...
Same as usual.
Well, here are the test results from the other day.
The current treatment hasn’t been that effective.
But we want to continue it to be completely sure.
What do you think, Hayate?
Um...
I’ll leave it up to you, Doctor.
Are the tests and medication causing any pain?
Are you okay?
I’ll stay strong.
I have this feeling that we’ll meet them again.
Yeah.
We didn’t get to talk to them.
But next time...
Yeah.
You wanna start now?
Sure.
Let’s practice.
Let’s get stronger.
So we won’t overlook the sad reality.
So not to hurt anyone anymore.
Systems check damages......
All clear
Functions diagnostics................
Problem detected
You came?
Yeah.
The Bureau’s really on our case now,
so we better be more careful.
We must start collecting from worlds away from here.
How many pages have we filled?
We’re on page 290.
Those two girls contributed a lot.
So we’re almost halfway there.
Let’s not waste any time.
We’ll complete it quickly,
so we can live in peace.
With Hayate.
Ready?
Yeah.
That’s right.
I’ve been put in charge of repairing you.
A serious problem has arisen in Functions.
Please insert Systems including the
“CVK792” component
to eliminate problem.
A serious problem has arisen in Functions.
Please insert Systems including the
“CVK792” component
to eliminate problem.
But that’s too...
CVK792, the Belkan cartridge system.
Are you sure?
Please
Seishō University Magnet Elementary School
December 12, 1:23 PM
Problem 1.
The figure on the right has two circles of the same size
inside a bigger circle with a circumference of 8 cm.
Question 1.
What is the radius of the bigger circle?
The perpetrators can absorb
a Linker Core’s energy only once per mage.
I see.
That means Nanoha and Fate
won’t be attacked again?
No, ma’am.
But you might, Captain.
You’re right, but don’t worry.
I can protect myself.
Should I cut my break short and come help you?
No, ma’am. We’ll handle this.
All right.
Enjoy your time with Fate, ma’am.
Will do.
Laty, do you have a moment?
Oh Lindy, how can I help?
We go way back, don’t we?
Sure, way back.
Why do you ask?
Is Chrono investigating a case related to the Book of Darkness?
We weren’t aware of it at first.
Many things were different from the Book of Darkness Incident we know.
I told Chrono I could have another team take over, but...
He refused?
Yeah.
He told me not to tell you he’s handling this case.
I see.
Now...
Time to prepare dinner.
I’m so glad I made it in time.
Thank you very much.
Are you okay, Marie?
I’m all right. How about you two?
Great.
Our mana ia back up to normal.
Very impressive.
They’re ready, so go see them.
It’s been a while, master.
Raising Heart, your shape...
Pretty chic, isn’t it?
It’s cute!
Bardiche, you too!
Yes, sir.
Check with them what modifications have been made.
Yes, ma’am.
Thank you very much.
Oh, Fate!
Arf, what’s wrong?
Well, today, I was
meeting up with Commodore Lindy, but
I can’t get a hold of her.
Have you heard anything, Fate?
There’s a barrier in the monitored area.
Detecting Ancient Belkan magic!
Four on-site operatives have surrounded the barrier.
We’re attempting to destroy it, but...
It’s really tough!
Of course. It’s a barrier Klarwind and I made.
The Bureau’s mages will come soon.
Get a move on!
Alright!
I’d rather stay away from here,
but we can’t have mages around Hayate while we’re out.
So, you’re their leader?
Care for a chat?
A chat?
Part of the Book of Darkness’s system,
eternally regenerating programs with their own minds and bodies...
The guardian knights known as the Wolkenritter.
Cloud Knights
What are you after with the Book of Darkness?
We have our own mission and reasons.
I don’t need to answer you.
What if I told you I had family who was killed by the Book of Darkness when it went out of control eleven years ago?
Flying Swallow Claymore
Schwalbefliegen Claymore
Signum, get it together!
Right, sorry.
This looks rather bad.
No, ma’am.
Teleport signature above!
I’m sorry, Raising Heart. I know you just came back!
All right. That’s what I’m here for.
Bardiche, you too!
No problem.
This is the first launch of a new system.
Requesting a renewed activation code.
Okay!
Raising Heart Excelion
Bardiche Assault
Set up!
Activation...
...normal.
Cartridge unit, functioning normally.
They’re...
Commodore Lindy, are you okay?
Yes, for now.
Thank goodness.
Their mana is fully recovered already.
That’s amazingly fast.
Plus those Devices...
It doesn’t matter! I’ll destroy everything that gets in my way!
Fate...
Right.
We’re not here to fight! We came here to talk!
Yeah, right! You can’t shake hands with a clenched fist!
Look who’s talking! You attacked us first!
You’ve outlived your usefulness!
Explosion
How about I break a few bones and cut you down to size?!
Raising Heart!
Commencing cartridge load.
So persistent!
I won’t go down so easily!
You...
Smasher!
Rest in pieces!
Accel Shooter
Accel Shoot
I just want you to talk to me.
I also wanted to apologize about your hat.
So please, be a good girl.
Shut up, you witch!
Outta my way or I’ll smash you!
Snakebite...
Schlangebeißen...
...Assault
...Angriff
Hmm...
You’ve improved a lot.
You must’ve trained quite a bit.
Or did you just lose your head last time?
Thank you.
I did train more, and I’m prepared this time.
I am Signum, general of the Wolkenritter.
Cloud Knights
You?
Fate Testarossa.
Testarossa, eh?
Under different circumstances,
my soul would have leapt with joy from this battle.
But I’ve not the time.
I can’t guarantee that I won’t kill you.
Will you forgive my childish immaturity?
That doesn’t matter, because I’ll be the one who wins.
You bonehead! You’re someone’s familiar, too!
You’re supposed to stop your master if they’re doing something wrong!
My mistress knows nothing of our deeds.
The four of us are taking this upon ourselves.
Bureau reinforcements.
An armed squad and multiple barrier mages.
They’re fast!
They’ll close in on us!
Everyone, retreat now!
Fine.
Understood.
Once I fire the flashbang, that’ll be your cue.
That’s...
Sorry, Testarossa.
We’ll settle this next time.
Signum!
I’m Vita, the Wolkenritter’s Knight of the Steel Hammer.
Cloud Knights
I’ll talk with you if you insist.
But stay out of our way for now!
Clear Howl
Klargeheul
The barrier disappeared.
A flashbang’s obstructing our view,
and something’s jamming our signal!
Track the signal!
Right away!
Amy, are you tracking them?
Yeah, we have them marked!
Sending coordinates to all tracking units!
No matter where they hide, we’ll find them!
Thanks!
Chrono’s after an ancient Lost Logia, the Book of Darkness.
Along with its four guardian knights,
the Book has been through multiple masters
since the Ancient Belkan era.
But the data I have on the Book of Darkness
doesn’t match those four.
Fate, you were speaking with your opponent?
Yeah.
She said they have a mission for them and their mistress.
Fate, Arf, I’m sorry.
Is it okay if I put my break on hold and go back to work?
Of course it’s okay.
Yes, but if possible...
We’d like to help out, too!
Can we?
Let’s all go ask.
Yes, ma’am!
Oh really?
It’s so late.
Yeah, I should let you go now.
Okay.
I’ll call you next time.
Yeah.
Well, good night.
Good night.
You’re back, Book of Darkness.
Didn’t you go out with Shamal?
Oh well.
I prepared a hot pot for dinner, but no one’s back yet.
I was chatting with Suzuka.
Don’t worry.
Even if they’re not here, we’re still family,
so I’m not lonely.
But you know what?
It’s just us two again, Book of Darkness, like before.
Confirmed startup of the Book of Darkness.
We are the guardian knights who will collect for the Book of Darkness and protect its mistress.
Clouds that gather under the Mistress of the Night Sky.
The Wolkenritter...
Cloud Knights
Hey, hold on.
Vita, shh!
Stay quiet. Discourtesy in front of your mistress is forbidden.
Discourtesy, or whatever,
she looks like she’s passed out.
What?
You’re kidding!
Good morning.
This is my first time meeting you.
I’m the this book’s—the Tome of the Night Sky’s—Unight.
You’ve officially become our mistress just now.
The Tome of the Night Sky and its four guardian knights
will offer you wisdom and power.
We serve at your pleasure.
U-Um... okay...
There’s much more I’d like to tell you.
But once you wake from this slumber,
you shall forget most of what I’ve told you.
I will?
Actually, it feels so strange.
I feel like I’ve known you.
In the form of this book,
I’ve been by your side since you were little.
Oh, I see.
Huh? What’s this?
You’re waking up now.
I may never be able to see you again,
so may I ask something of you?
Those dear, sweet knights have been
fighting against their will.
Please show them kindness.
But most importantly,
more than anything else, I wish for your happiness.
No, wait.
Wait!
What a crummy town. Not a hint of magic.
At least it’s not a warzone or a charnel house.
But what of us guardian knights?
We’re stuck with a randomly-chosen mistress,
and we must fight to fill the pages of the Book of Darkness.
That’s our fate.
At least until we die.
Vita, Zafira, come back.
Our new mistress has risen.
So...
This is a magic book from an ancient world called Belka,
known as the Book of Darkness.
You’re its guardian knights.
Yes.
And I’m your mistress.
Has the Book of Darkness spoken to you before?
In your dreams, perhaps?
It may have, but I’m not sure.
Ah, that’s it!
But I know one thing.
As the mistress of the Book of Darkness,
I have to provide clothing, food, and shelter
for all the guardian knights.
Fortunately, I have a place to live.
Plus, I’m quite the cook!
That leaves clothes!
To be honest, I don’t know
what I should do as the mistress of the Book of Darkness.
I just want to live in peace with all of you.
Knight Armor?
Yes, we each have a weapon,
but we need our mistress to grant us armor.
We can make them out of our own mana,
so all you have to do is come up with the design.
I see.
But I’m not going to make you fight or anything like that.
How about clothes? Clothes that look like knights!
Yes, that will be fine.
Mistress Hayate, are you sure about this?
About what?
As soon as you wish it so,
we can fill the pages of the Book of Darkness,
and you would gain immense power.
I’m sure your legs would heal as well.
No way.
To fill the pages of the Book of Darkness,
you’d have to inconvenience many people, right?
That’s wrong.
I’m plenty happy as I am right now.
Dad and Mom are up in heaven already,
but they left me this house and a fortune.
Besides, I have all of you with me now.
Hayate! Hayate!
What is it, Vita?
Can I have some strawberry ice cream, Hayate?
You ate that much dinner, yet you’re going to eat more?
Shut up! I’m on a growth spurt!
Hayate’s food is giga-delicious, too!
Oh, all right...
Just a little bit. Got it?
Yeah!
Signum?
Yes?
I don’t want any power from the Book of Darkness.
As long as I am your master, forget about filling its pages.
Can you promise me that?
I so pledge, on my sword as a knight.
Hayate, I need a few words with Signum and Shamal.
Yes, Doc.
Vita, stay with Hayate.
Okay.
It’s life-threatening?
What’s wrong with Hayate?
Yes...
Hayate’s neuroparalysis is progressing.
We’re doing our best,
but at this rate, it may spread to her organs.
It wasn’t an illness.
It was a malfunction in the Book of Darkness’s
autonomous protection system.
The magical power that had long been suppressed
ate away at Hayate’s premature body.
And our mistress is silently, but surely
being killed by the curse of the Book of Darkness.
We have to save her...
We have to save Hayate!
Signum, what do you say?
There’s only one way.
Our mistress’ body is being poisoned by the spell
of the Book of Darkness’s autonomous protection system!
If Hayate were to truly awaken
as the mistress of the Book of Darkness...
...our mistress’ affliction will vanish.
At the least, it would stop progressing.
I don’t want to tarnish Hayate’s future with blood,
so I won’t kill anyone.
But I’ll stop at nothing else!
Please forgive us, mistress.
Just this once, we will break the vow we have made to you.
It’s great that we have more support
with the Captain back, but...
I’m sorry for being selfish.
Sorry, Chrono.
Sorry.
Captain, please start tomorrow.
Nanoha and Fate, as part-time mages with us,
we’ll request your assistance as needed.
All right.
Thanks, Chrono.
December 12, 10:15 PM
Hayate, I’m sorry we’re so late!
Mistress Hayate was waiting,
but she’s fallen asleep by now.
I see.
We’ll apologize to her tomorrow.
Yeah.
By the way...
What were you talking about?
She asked about the Book of Darkness.
What we know about the Book of Darkness
and what we’re after.
We’re the Book of Darkness’s knights.
We just fill pages for our mistress.
That’s right.
But something’s bugging me.
Commodore Clyde Harlaown.
He died eleven years ago
in the last Book of Darkness Incident.
My husband.
When transporting the culprit and the Book of Darkness,
the Book of Darkness went out of control
when it was supposed to be sealed by four mages.
To get the Book of Darkness off our ship,
my husband flew out on a pod with the transport container.
That was it...
Um, when Commodore Clyde died, was Chrono...?
Chrono was three.
At the funeral, he didn’t cry,
nor did he accuse me of not being able to save his father.
Not even once since that day.
So I worry about him sometimes.
But Amy, his friend from school, told me
what Chrono said at school.
“I’m proud of my parents more than anyone,
so I want to pursue the same career as them.”
I’m sorry. I was being a little too sentimental.
No, not at all.
Well, your turn. Tell me about yourself, Fate.
Yes, ma’am.
You told me a little,
but how are you feeling about your mother, Presea?
It’s still hard to put it into words.
Nanoha saved me. You and Chrono
have been so kind, too, Commodore Lindy.
I’m physically here, but...
...a part of me can’t move on from that day.
I’m so naïve.
That’s not true. You’re doing great.
Let’s talk more from now on, okay?
About the past and the future.
Yes, ma’am.
Thank you.
In transformations, Bardiche and I each have three forms.
Bardiche’s Bullova and Crescent
and my Accel and Buster cannon are standard forms.
And the third...
Your Full Drive, Excelion Mode.
Exactly.
December 13, 6:54 AM
Welcome back.
Yeah.
You were out all night?
We collected more.
We’ll add it to the Book of Darkness later.
Okay.
Hayate!
Uminari University Hospital
Hayate...
Vita?
Everyone...
You went into shock but seem stable now.
Guys, you shouldn’t’ve panicked.
Sorry for troubling you.
Hold on, Hayate.
I guess I’m stuck here for a while.
And that means I can’t cook for you guys.
Well, that’s...
We’ll manage. Don’t worry.
I’ll come visit every day!
You’re such a good girl.
But don’t worry about it.
Shamal will stay here
to take care of and guard our mistress.
We’ll fill pages when we’re not visiting.
All right.
The active area of the guardian knights has expanded.
They’ve changed their pattern.
We’ll contact you when we require your assistance.
Okay.
All right.
The pace at which the Book of Darkness
is infiltrating into Hayate seems to be steadily increasing.
At this rate, she’ll only last a month at most.
Or maybe even less than that.
Don’t worry.
We’ll save her.
I have no clue who added this on.
I just cannot free myself from this cursed chain.
I’ll sometimes put our master and you all in danger,
and I’ll respawn forever against my will.
I’m terribly sorry.
Mistress Hayate...
I won’t let you kill our kind mistress.
It doesn’t hurt.
This doesn’t hurt at all!
Hayate must be in much more pain.
Hayate must be suffering so much more!
I don’t know if Hayate will be happy
with becoming the true mistress of the Book of Darkness.
She might get upset.
She might despise us.
But...
To see sweet Hayate suffering like that...
I can’t stand it.
I can’t stand losing Hayate!
So, Eisen!
I know.
Ich weiß.
Rest in pieces!
December 18
Uminari University Hospital
Okay, here’s what I’ve found so far.
Book of Darkness is not its original name.
Its real name is Tome of the Night Sky.
It was a tome that travelled with its master, originally created to gather great magical technology from each land.
It’s probably exhibiting destructive powers because someone in its line of masters hacked its program.
Because of that corruption, the travel function and the automatic repair of corrupted data went haywire.
The worst part of it all is
the changes to its owner’s condition.
If mana isn’t collected often enough,
it’ll feed on that of its master.
And when it’s complete, the owner’s mana will be used without limits for indiscriminate destruction.
The cause?
The autonomous protection system that’s been added.
NachtWal.
That’s what infects its master
and causes it to run out of control.
The Book of Darkness has a main Unison system,
a unit called the Will of the Book of Darkness.
But after the Book of Darkness is completed,
the autonomous protection system,
NachtWal, takes over after a certain period.
So all the incidents so far were caused by...
Probably.
By using the energy it collected and taking the life of its master,
the Book of Darkness will respawn
in search of a new master.
That is why, right after the completion of the Book,
all the owners until now have...
Anything on how to stop or seal it?
Unfortunately, nothing.
But I’ll keep searching.
Thanks.
Amy, what about our last resort?
The Captain’s working on it.
The Arthra should have had it equipped already.
Last resort?
An anti-matériel annihilation cannon, the Arc-en-Ciel.
Your friend is in the hospital?!
Yeah, it happened suddenly last week.
You mean Hayate from the library, Suzuka?
Yeah. She’ll be spending Christmas in the hospital.
Aw.
Let’s go visit her.
Really?
You’re in, right?
Yep.
Yeah.
Let’s go there on Christmas Eve with presents in hand.
Sounds good.
Zafira’s back, so I’ll switch with him.
All right.
By the way, Hayate’s friends’ll be visiting her.
Suzuka and her group.
I see.
Hayate got permission to go out on Christmas Eve.
She wants to have dinner with us.
Sounds good.
We’ll be back by then.
Okay. I’ll check in again later.
160 pages left...
December 24, 4:50 PM
City of Uminari
Come in!
Good evening, Hayate.
Good evening.
Welcome!
How are you feeling?
I’m so bored, I might pick up another disease.
Let me introduce you.
I’m Nanoha Takamachi.
Fate Testarossa.
Hayate Yagami.
It’s nice to meet you.
Oh, these are for you.
We brought Christmas presents!
We got so lost on our way here.
Oh, it must be them.
Come in!
Coming in.
Good evening!
Suzuka, Alisa, good ev—
Stop it, Vita!
That’s not how you should treat my guests.
B-But Hayate...
U-Um... nice to meet you, Vita.
We mean no harm.
So don’t worry.
Fine.
I’ll take your coats.
Enjoy.
Thank you!
I can’t use telepathy. Are you jamming communications?
Shamal’s support skills are amazing.
She finds it quite simple at this distance.
Um... please don’t glare at me.
I’m not glaring!
Come on, Vita. Be a good girl.
Um... well, we...
It was pure coincidence.
May we chat with Hayate?
Sure.
Uminari University Hospital
See ya!
Later!
Hayate is the mistress of the Book of Darkness.
Our wish will soon come true.
Even if you’re Hayate’s friends, if you interfere...
Hold on. Hear us out, too.
You can’t do this! If you finish
the Book of Darkness, Hayate will—
Nanoha!
Signum!
We can’t let you inform the Bureau about our mistress.
We can’t let you out of my jamming area.
Vita...
Stay out of our way.
Soon, Hayate’s going to get better and come back to us!
We’ve tried so hard.
We’re almost there...
So stay out of our way!
You devil...
Then I’ll be the devil.
If we can see eye to eye, I’ll be the devil for you!
Shamal, stand back and focus on jamming communications.
The Book of Darkness is broken.
It’s been corrupted by a malicious actor.
If you complete it as it is now, Hayate will...
It doesn’t matter how much you judge or criticize us.
We won’t listen!
That’s not it! It’s not—
I said, we won’t listen!
If you stand in my way,
I’ll cut you down!
Barrier Jacket: Sonic Form
Crescent
You made your thin armor even thinner.
I can move that much faster.
You’ll die if even a weak attack lands a direct hit.
It’s so that I can win against you.
If we hadn’t met in this manner,
you and I may have been great friends.
It’s not too late!
We can’t stop!
If it’s so our mistress can smile,
we guardian knights will even give up our knightly honor!
We’ll give up our lives for hers!
So we can’t stop here!
You’ll be stopped, by Bardiche and I!
I can’t get through to anyone.
What in the worlds has happened?
Restrict Lock, activated.
You...
Divine Buster Extension
Shoot!
Book of Darkness?
That’s...
NachtWal... but why?
No!
Autonomous protection system, NachtWal, activated.
Das Anwendungssystem für automatische Verteidigung „NachtWal“ lässt an.
Wait! Not yet! We can still fight!
You...
That’s right. It’s all your...
Shutting down the guardian knight system.
Erhaltung des Schutzrittersystems vernichten.
Prioritizing filling the pages of the Book of Darkness.
Vollendung der Schrift der Dunkelheit hat die oberste Priorität.
Eliminating the guardian knight system.
Das Schutzrittersystem eliminieren.
How dare you?
How frickin’ dare you?!
Vita!
Destroying enemy forces.
Die Kräfte des Feindes wegschaffen.
Collecting Cores from collection targets.
Den Kern aus den Sammlungsobjekten sammeln.
Initiate.
Anfangen.
Shamal! Signum!
One part of the system remains.
Ein zurückbleibendes System bestätigen.
Collecting.
Sammeln.
The Cores of the guardian knight system have been reclaimed.
Den Kern aus dem Schutzrittersystem beschlagnahmen.
All pages have been filled.
Die Sammlung der Seiten ist fertig.
What’s that?
Who are you?
It’s time to rise, master.
Es ist die Zeit der Erweckung, mein Herr.
Forget that.
What have you done to Signum and everyone else?
Give them back to me! Now!
...Einverstanden...
...I shall...
When the guardian knight system has completely terminated,
Das Schutzrittersystem ist völlig ausgestrichen,
it will be returned to the master in Core mode.
und wird mit dem Kernmodus für meinen Herrn wiederhergestellt.
No, stop! That’s not what I want!
No!
Stop!
Don’t do it!
Terminating.
Ausstreichen.
It’s time to rise.
Es ist die Zeit der Erweckung.
Hayate!
Control unit,
Verwaltungseinheit,
begin Unison.
verschmelzen
Once again, everything has come to an end.
Hayate!
I am the Tome. All of my powers will be used...
Diabolic Emission
...to destroy my distasteful enemies!
A spatial attack!
Sink into darkness.
Excelion Shield
Anomaly detected!
We’ve got a visual, but no audio!
But this is...
The Book of Darkness’s Unight.
Where’s Chrono?
On his way already!
Cease automatic protection.
I will protect my mistress for a while now.
Nacht...
I will not blame you, a mere protection program.
All responsibility lies with me.
So be still if only for a while longer.
Mistress, please rest.
Please rest inside me for a while.
Nanoha, I’m sorry. And thank you.
Don’t worry. I had a good shield.
Bardiche.
Lightning Form
Who is she?
A Belkan Unight.
A control unit that fuses with its master and fights.
If she’s out here, Hayate’s probably unconscious.
How do we save her?
I’m not sure, but...
Let’s try talking to her.
Sure.
Um, Ms. Book of Darkness?
We are Hayate and Vita’s...
My knights...
They swore to beat you and break Nacht’s curse
to save my mistress.
My mistress wished
the despair she faced to be but a bad dream.
I’m here to grant her that wish.
I just want my mistress to find an eternal and peaceful rest.
As for those who stand in our way,
endless darkness awaits!
Nanoha!
Crescent Saber
Combination 2: Buster Shift
Lock!
Shoot!
Penetrate.
These are...
...our spells.
The spells my knights collected at the cost of their lives.
Ms. Book of Darkness?
It’s not like I don’t know that this isn’t your fault.
Had you two not interfered, my knights and mistress would’ve been able to spend this holy night in peace.
They would’ve been able to spend
our mistress’s remaining days in peace.
Hayate’s still alive. So are your knights!
It’s too late.
The fates of those who become the masters of the Book of Darkness are sealed.
It’s not over yet!
We won’t let it end like this!
You’re crying because you’re sad!
Because you don’t want to give up!
If not, it doesn’t make sense!
If you’ve given up already, you wouldn’t be crying!
Barrier Jacket, purge!
We’ll keep telling you until you get it.
We want to save you. And Hayate, too!
It’s here.
The destruction has already begun.
My consciousness will soon fade.
Then Nacht will go on a rampage.
But before I go, I want to grant
the wishes of my mistress and her knights.
Sleep.
Don’t be selfish!
Sonic Drive
You must have some darkness in your heart.
Fate?!
Absorption
Fate!
My mistress and that girl
shall lie in an endless dream, never to rise again.
A dream between life and death.
That is eternity.
There’s no such thing as eternity!
This is...
Fate, Alicia, Arf, rise and shine.
This can’t be.
Good morning, Fate.
Are you all up?
I am!
I’m sleepy.
You two were up late, I bet.
Just a little, right?
Be more like Fate. Sleep early and wake up early.
You’re her big sister, Alicia.
Um... Lynith?
Yes?
What is it, Fate?
Alicia?
Yep.
Bardiche! Where’s Bardiche?
Who’s that?
What? He’s my...
I may have spoken too soon. Fate’s a sleepyhead today.
Get changed and have breakfast.
Presea is waiting at the garden table already.
Okay!
Mom...
Good morning, Mommy!
Good morning.
Good morning!
Good morning, Arf.
Presea, did you hear that we might get a storm tomorrow?
What’s wrong, Fate?
She must’ve had a nightmare.
She thinks this is a dream or an illusion.
Studying too much?
That’s possible.
Fate, come here.
Did you have a nightmare?
But you’ll be okay now.
Your mother, Lynith, and Alicia are all beside you.
Presea, me too!
Yes, Arf, you too!
She should forget about her bad dream over breakfast.
Come on, sit down. Let’s eat.
No...
This is the dream.
My mother never smiled at me like that, not even once.
Alicia and Lynith are both gone now.
But...
This is...
Shall we all go into town today?
That sounds great.
We should buy Fate new clothes.
Only Fate again? That’s not fair!
It’s a reward for getting 100 on her magic test.
Alicia, you need to try harder.
That’s right!
Fate!
Tutor me for the next test, please!
Sure.
Fate?
This is the life I always wanted.
The life I dreamed of, over and over...
What’s wrong, Fate?
Are you okay?
Fate?
I’m so sleepy.
Stay asleep, just like that, my mistress.
I will grant all of your wishes.
Nacht, penetrate.
Three magazines and eighteen cartridges left!
Reload
I need a killer shot.
Let’s go, Raising Heart.
Let us go, master.
What did I...
What did I wish for?
To erase this depressing reality.
You should sleep too.
I will, sooner or later.
But not now.
Raising Heart!
Excelion Mode
Drive...
...Ignition
We’ll put a stop to all the sadness and nightmares!
Photon Lancer: Genocide Shift
Huh?
Fate, let’s go home.
Hey, Fate?
Sorry, Alicia. I’d like to stay here a little longer.
You will? Then I’ll keep you company.
We’re taking shelter from the rain together!
Hey, Alicia.
This is a dream, right?
Don’t be silly, Fate.
Of course it’s not a dream.
You and I can’t exist at the same time.
If you were still alive, Alicia,
then I wouldn’t have been born.
And our mother never...
She was a kind person,
but she tried a little too hard...
...to bring me back from the dead.
I know.
Hey, Fate. Who cares if it’s a dream?
Let’s stay here. Together forever.
I’ll be your big sister forever if you stay here.
Mommy and Lynith, too...
They’ll really love you.
We can do a lot of fun things as a family.
We’ll give you all the happiness you ever wanted, Fate.
The happiness I wanted?
A healthy body.
A life always together with your loved ones.
Please sleep.
And you’ll get all of that in your dream.
No one will hurt you.
A world without pain or sorrow.
That would be nice.
The only attack you know.
You think that will work?
I’ll make it work.
A.C.S., standby.
Raising Heart is giving me the power to save the crying girl!
Strike Flame
Excelion Buster A.C.S.
Drive!
Make it through!
Break...
No way!
...shoot!
At point-blank range,
a direct hit from the Buster through her barrier...
If that didn’t work...
Master!
I guess we’ll have to give it a little more.
Yes.
Right...
I still...
Thank you.
Alicia.
Sorry.
But I...
I have to go.
I should be the one apologizing.
I actually knew.
But even for a little while... even in a dream...
I wanted to be with you.
I’m sorry.
I’m so sorry, Alicia.
It’s fine.
I am your big sister, after all, Fate.
You need to go back to your friends and loved ones.
Yeah.
Then go ahead, Fate.
Thank you.
Sis.
I love you.
Me too.
Fate.
Forever and ever.
Take care.
I wish it was like this in reality too.
If you...
If you people weren’t here!
Let’s get out of here, Bardiche.
Yes, sir.
Zanber Form
Mom...
Lynith...
Sis...
I’m glad I got to see you.
I’m going to where I’m needed now.
With lightning speed!
Sleep!
I remember now.
I remember it all.
I remember why all this happened.
I’m begging you.
Please go back to sleep, mistress!
In a mere few minutes, with my own curse,
I will kill you.
So I at least wanted you to find peace in your dream.
I know you’re only thinking about me,
but I can’t accept that.
We finally reached the place we met
We’re alike, you and I.
We were all so lonely, so sad.
Powerless as individuals.
But I mustn’t forget any of that.
I’m your current master, and you’re my dear child.
But Nacht won’t stop!
It’s beyond control!
Buried in the fragments of time
Stop.
With the stars disappearing
in the distance
Whoever’s fighting out there,
please help!
In the height of
long-standing suffering
Hayate?
The black thing coiling around her...
The wishes seem to freeze
Nanoha! Fate!
Yuuno!
With a wounded heart and teary eyes
Fate, can you hear me?
Arf!
While the mistress is conscious within Unison,
You still found your way to me
we may be able to decouple
the protection system from the Unight.
Really?
But how?
How can we?
Blast that black thing head-on
with your pure magical cannons!
At the edge of the world far into the distance
Hit it with all the power you’ve got!
The color of miracles that I touched
Clear as crystal, Yuuno!
Loud and clear!
Indeed.
Like the white of snow
I’ll give you a name.
I won’t let people call you
the Book of Darkness or the cursed tome anymore.
We softly feel each other
I won’t let them!
You and I melt into each other
I have a perfect name for you.
One who uses her strength to support others.
You are a wind of fortune, a shout of blessing.
And we finally become our true selves
Reinforce.
The snow melts and glitters in the night
N&F, mid-range wipeout combination!
It brings about the wind that signals our parting
Blast calamity!
The wish of the Wind of Blessing
Fire!
Becomes the unbreakable bond
Decoupling of the protection program
from the Unight, confirmed.
Great!
It’s not over yet.
Arc-en-Ciel, stand by!
Yes, ma’am!
Durandal, lend me your power.
Everyone leaves on a journey someday
The Tome of the Night Sky and its Unight, Reinforce,
will protect you with our lives.
While bearing scars of their sorrows
But...
NachtWal cannot be stopped.
In search of an answer at the end of the journey
The immense energy that’s been detached will quickly wreak havoc.
Well, let’s do something about it.
The snow melts and glitters in the night
Let’s go, Reinforce.
Yes, mistress.
It brings about the wind that signals our parting
And the Wind of Blessing
Carries us away with a smile.
Enable admistrator rights.
Linker Cores, reactivated.
Guardian knight system, recovered.
Come forth, my knights.
Hayate!
With the blessing of the light of the Night Sky!
Reinforce, Unison in!
Hayate...
I’m sorry.
Um... Hayate, we...
It’s okay. I know all about it.
Reinforce told me.
We’ll talk more later.
But for now...
Welcome back, everybody.
Hayate! Hayate!
I’m sorry to break the mood, but...
Enforcer Chrono Harlaown with
the Time-Space Administrative Bureau.
We don’t have time, so let me cut to the chase. It’s about that black mass.
That is the Book of Darkness’s protection program
that will go out of control soon.
Am I correct?
Yes. It’s the autonomous protection system, NachtWal.
Nacht will swallow the objects around itself and keep growing.
Unless it reaches its limit, it could swallow this planet whole.
I have a plan to shut it down.
I wish I could say “we’ll take care of it”, but...
We need all the help we can get.
The guardian knights must end the curse of the Book of Darkness.
Nanoha and Fate must protect this city and this world.
Will you cooperate?
Yes.
Yeah.
First, breach Nacht’s multiple defenses.
Next, damage its body and expose its core.
Then with Yuuno and their teleport spells,
send it before the Arthra!
We’ll obliterate it with Arc-en-Ciel, and it’ll be finished!
Yes.
Start charging the Arc-en-Ciel!
Yes, ma’am!
Nanoha, Fate.
Shamal.
Yes?
Shall I treat them?
Klarwind.
Show them your power.
Yes.
Ja.
Dear zephyr, please deliver a boon of healing.
Shamal, Knight of the Lake,
and Klarwind, the Rings of Wind.
Healing and support is our specialty.
Amazing!
Thank you so much!
We’ll provide support
until its core is exposed.
We’ll pin it down.
Yeah!
Got it.
It’s beginning.
The program that caused the Tome of the Night Sky
to be called the cursed Book of Darkness.
NachtWal’s infective destructive form.
The Darkness of the Book of Darkness.
Caging Circle
Chain Bind
A bell rings for the Holy Night
Testing courage from Heaven to Earth
Chain it!
Steel Yoke
Once you raise the star, brandish the flare of the future
Even if that which was entrusted to your small hands is heavy
Hold tightly this connected love, and let’s go confirm the truth
I won’t give up carrying anything, be it sorrow or joy
Forward team coming in!
Nanoha, Vita! I’ll leave it to you!
I know what it means to be weak so I can be strong
Alright!
Back me up, Nanoha Takamachi.
I swear to protect it with bonds in my heart, the Sacred Force
Sure!
Let’s go, Eisen!
Giant
Gigant
Accel Shooter: Vanishing Shift
Be it justice or your dreams
They only turn real once you believe in them
Lock on.
It is darkness that always lies underneath the shadow of doubt
Shoot!
We’ll stand up as many times as it takes
To clear up the skies
It’s time to take the first step of many
Ah...
Let’s unleash this power now
Thundering explosion!
I want to create a legend
Together with you
Giant Smash
Gigantschlag
With your hand in mine
I’ll believe that our precious star will surely shine
Signum, Fate!
Let’s go, Testarossa.
Yes, Signum.
Bow Form
Bogenform
Race the skies, falcon!
Storm Falcon
Sturmfalken
Break through, Thunder God!
Jet Zanber
Did we do it?
Not quite!
Thus we find something precious
A resonating concerto
Hayate!
Come from far in the distance, twigs of mistletoe.
And see the truth for ourselves
Become the spears of the silver moon,
and smite this creature!
Be it happiness or sorrow
I will not abandon anything
Spears of petrification!
I find my strength because I know my weakness
Mistilteinn
I promise to protect you
With our bond firmly in my heart, and with a smile on my face
Let me embrace you, my sacred force
And take you to where it all begins
Chrono, finish it!
Freeze!
Eternal Coffin
Nanoha, Fate, Hayate!
Starlight Breaker
Maximum power!
Starlight...
Plasma Zanber
Lightning flash!
Plasma Zanber...
I’m sorry.
Rest well.
Resound, horn of the end times.
Ragnarök...
...Breaker
There!
Got you!
Long-distance translocation!
Target in orbit!
Teleport!
Core teleport underway!
As it’s being translocated, it’s reparing itself.
I-It’s fast!
Arc-en-Ciel, deploy barrel!
Firing lock system, open.
Arc-en-Ciel...
Fire!
The object within the space
has been completely annihilated!
Scanning for regenerative response...
Not found!
Maintain our current guard position.
We’ll observe the response area for a while.
Roger!
Mission complete.
Thanks for your help.
Mistress...?
Please maintain Unison.
Mistress!
Hayate!
Hayate...
The damage I...
The damage the Book of the Night Sky inflicted is severe.
Nacht has been killed, but its twisted base remains.
I, the operating system of the Tome of the Night Sky,
will invariably create a new NachtWal, paving the way for destruction once more.
What’ll happen to Mistress Hayate?
You don’t have to worry about her.
Nacht’s infection has stopped, and her Linker Core is stable.
Her legs will heal with time.
Her first mission was so demanding.
She just needs some rest.
Oh. She’s going to make a full recovery?
Well, we have no regrets.
Now that Nacht’s been killed,
the Book of the Night Sky can be easily destroyed.
If it’s destroyed, it can never hurt anyone ever again.
But we’ll disappear with it.
Vita...
I don’t mind.
We all knew this might happen.
You’re wrong.
You four will remain.
I’m the only one who will go.
Destroy the Book of the Night Sky?
Why?
I thought we already killed the protection program!
NachtWal has been killed,
but the Book of the Night Sky quickly relaunches its processes.
Hayate or one of the knights might be possessed next time.
The threat remains so long as the Book of the Night Sky exists.
So Reinforce has suggested
that we destroy her while we can.
But that’s...
Then Signum and the rest of the knights will—
No. We will remain.
Just like NachtWal, we guardian knights
have been decoupled from the operating system.
Reinforce is asking for a favor from you two.
A favor?
General, I’ve known you for such a long time now,
but we never spoke like this.
Indeed.
Sorry.
I’m at a loss for words.
Don’t apologize.
Stand proud with your chin up.
Take good care of our mistress.
We will.
I see you came.
Reinforce?
You would call me by that name?
Yeah.
Are you sure you want us to return you to the sky?
I wanted to ask it of you two.
Don’t you have to say goodbye to Hayate?
I don’t want to upset Mistress Hayate.
But that’s just too sad!
You’ll understand one day,
when you meet someone for whom your love is
as deep as the sea and whose happiness you wish to protect.
Shall we begin soon?
The end of the Tome of the Night Sky.
Reinforce?
Ready to set.
Stand by.
Ah...
We didn’t know each other long,
but I give thanks to you two as well.
Don’t worry.
Have a good journey.
I shall.
Reinforce!
Everyone!
Hayate!
Don’t move!
Please stay back.
You’ll disrupt the ritual.
No! Stop! Stop, Reinforce!
You don’t need to! I’ll control the Book!
It’s okay. You don’t have to do this!
Mistress Hayate...
It’s for the best.
No, it’s not! It isn’t for the best at all!
I have lived a long time,
but at the very end of my life,
you gave me a beautiful name and a soul.
Even though our time was brief,
I was able to fly with you and support you.
The knights will be by your side.
I have no regrets.
I don’t care about regrets.
That’s why I can go out with a smile.
Don’t go! I’ll figure something out!
I promised you I wouldn’t let you go out of control!
You’ve kept that promise magnificently.
Reinforce!
My duty as a magical vessel is
to protect my mistress from danger.
Please let me choose the best way to protect you.
But...
But you were always so sad,
and we... we finally saved you!
My will shall remain in
your magic and the souls of the knights.
I shall always be by your side.
That’s not true. That’s not true!
Your friends don’t like selfish people.
Please understand, mistress.
Reinforce!
Why? Everything was going to begin now.
I was going to make you happy.
It’s okay.
I am the happiest magic book in all the worlds.
Reinforce...
Mistress, I have one favor to ask.
When I disappear, a powerless fragment will remain.
If you like, can you give my name not to that,
but to the next magical vessel you will obtain someday?
Reinforce, the Wind of Blessing.
My wishes shall live on that way.
Reinforce...
Yes, mistress.
Mistress Hayate...
Guardian knights...
And you young heroes.
Thank you.
We’ll be leaving the guardian knights with you.
They’ll be on probation during their interrogation and trial.
But considering Hayate’s situation,
we’re not planning to keep the four here
as long as they wear their magic limiters and GPS locators.
Thank you.
Now you can tell your husband, right?
Going soon?
Yeah, maybe next week.
With Chrono, Fate, and Arf.
What are you planning to say?
Well, probably the same as usual.
I’ll say that it’s as busy as ever, but I’m doing fine.
I see.
And so, the incident was resolved.
Many things happened as the days flew by,
bringing the end of December.
Hayate was discharged.
The four knights were interrogated at the Main Office.
They’re busy deciding where they’ll go from here.
We’ll be heading to the Main Office now.
See you in the evening.
Okay, I’ll have dinner ready for you.
Is tea okay? Make yourself at home.
I’ll help you.
Me too.
Don’t worry. Have a seat.
So you’ll be on probation too, Hayate?
Yes. And I want to learn to control and use magic.
I’m a rather new mage compared to you two.
I’m glad Signum and the others won’t be getting any severe punishments.
Me too.
But I still can’t forgive myself.
I should’ve realized all the things about my body, Nacht,
and their actions much sooner.
I shouldn’t regret what’s done,
but we should own up to our mistakes,
and I should lead them to a bright future.
Oh, sorry. Was I rambling too much?
No.
You just sounded so mature, Hayate.
Oh...
Maybe that’s because of Reinforce.
I see.
Reinforce’s will and power merged with you, right?
Hayate?
Sorry, it’s nothing. Nothing at all.
Ever since she passed, my tears won’t stop
Maybe she drew out my inner crybaby.
Nanoha? Fate?
I think you can cry.
Goodbyes are always sad,
so you can take all the time you need.
It’s just us here now.
The knights you want to protect aren’t watching.
We’re with you.
Reinforce won’t be worried, either.
Undoubtedly, it was a very small wish.
A wish that couldn’t be granted.
The future’s in our hands now.
However much we may cry, what’s past is past.
But with the strong will to shape the future,
and the wings to fly in the boundless sky,
we can make it.
This is all I know about the Book of Darkness Incident.
Two years later...
The kind mages and the young mistress
all lived their days to the fullest.
And the knights repented for their past mistakes by
protecting and serving the people.
They were allowed to live with their mistress.
And the will of the Wind of Blessing who crossed the winter night
was inherited by a breeze born in the spring
with the same name.
Reinforce...
Are you watching from the sky?
Hey!
Let’s go, Rein.
Yes, Meister Hayate!
We’re always smiling now!
And doing great!
It’s time to say goodbye
But this moment doesn’t say a word
I’m sure that’s because it wants to
Tell the story of the days that won’t return
Every path in life leads somewhere
A parting is by no means the end
Giving wings
(I won’t ever)
To my smile
(Forget you)
Lets me see a sky through my tears
This sorrow
(I won’t ever)
Will make me stronger
(Forget you)
And you’re the one who made me capable of that
Always
You’re a big part
And forever
Of my memories
Until the end of time
This will never change
I’ll always be with you
That’s right
A rainbow
(I won’t ever)
Spans across this dream
(Forget you)
That I have always pursued
This sorrow
(I won’t ever)
Will make me stronger
(Forget you)
And you’re the one who made me capable of that
Raising Heart.
Yes, my master.
Bardiche.
Yes, sir.
Reinforce.
Yes indeedy!
Standby, ready.
Set up!
I look at you, wondering what you’re staring at
A solitary stream of light shining
in the darkness of my world
Showing even my wounded heart
the way to compassion
Your pure brightness unravels everything
Don’t be afraid
I’m always at your side
I can hear your voice
echo around my night sky
In search of hope, these white wings of mine
Guide me through the countless nights
While I embrace my own, secret grief
I believe I will grow stronger
For all the tears I’ve shed
I’ll hold my head up high
because you’re with me
My mind reels as you look at me
As you gave me warmth,
you brought me fear
All the things I wanted
that I couldn’t reach
Have made me forget
what it meant to be honest
I want to stay here with you
Always and forever
But I’m afraid I’ll lose the chance
if I say my wish out loud
Seeking freedom, an honest dream
Writes the story of an endless future
Destroying this frozen clock
in the process
I want to be the first to tell you
That the door to the truth is opening
And I will hold fast until the very end
I found myself smiling more
Wanting to see your smile
You taught me that
the most ordinary of days
Could be this precious
In the search of hope,
these white wings of mine
Guide me through the countless nights
While I embrace my own, secret grief
I believe I will grow stronger
For all the tears I’ve shed
I’ll hold my head up high
because you’re with me
So let’s fly to where it will all begin