A quiet and peaceful Christmas Eve.
A coincidental encounter led to a sad battle.
The blurred truth.
The dancing shadows.
The unreachable desire.
The tears that hold the key to destiny
revive the deep darkness.
A long and cold night quietly raises its curtains.
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha A's
will now begin.
Prayers echoing in the vast skies turn to miracles
Teardrops melt and flow into the blue of the middle of the night
I met a warmth that engulfs all without hesitation
Just like the pure white snow
Words that are honest no matter how far you go
It moves me as I wear wings of steel
Each time I am hurt,
I can become kinder
My only wish is to protect that smile of yours to the end
Memories of sadness engraved across the ages
You are an angel of light, catching them straight on
An eternal blaze that stopped in my heart that day
Releasing the deep darkness
It opens the door of freedom
Towards the strong, boundless future
Hurry! Hurry!
Not good!
Take shelter!
This is the second block of the Hestia.
The Buch der Dunkelheit is out of control!
We've lost the bridge and the reactor.
Even the operating system and Arc-en-Ciel control.
The Hestia is charging its Arc-en-Ciel!
It's currently bearing on the main fleet!
Commodore Clyde, escape immediately!
We'll destroy the Hestia.
I just confirmed the evacuation of all the crew.
Charging of our Arc-en-Ciel will be complete in one minute.
I will show you our countdown.
Please shoot it down before the launch.
The communication was...
68 seconds until the Hestia's charge is complete.
The charge is complete here.
We can fire at any time.
Father!
Deploy the Arc-en-Ciel's barrel!
Fire on the Hestia before the count hits zero.
It was my mistake.
I didn't expect the Buch der Dunkelheit to go out of control
to the point of taking over the ship.
I could not have anticipated it.
Destiny
Targeted area's communication interference has been eliminated.
Receiving visuals.
What about Chrono?
He has already left for the location.
Good. I was able to put up a barrier.
Is Durandal ready?
It's ready.
Diabolic Emission.
A dimensional attack!
Blend into darkness.
Round Shield
I wonder if they can handle it.
It'd be nice if they could hold on
until it goes out of control.
Struggle Bind.
It binds the target and dispels magical effects.
It's magic of limited utility,
but at times like this,
it comes in handy...
...for forcefully dispelling transformation magic.
Chrono... how dare you...
I didn't teach you that magic.
You two were the ones who taught me to devote myself to magic.
Aria, Lotte!
They're hiding?
I'm sorry, Nanoha.
Thanks. Are you okay?
Yeah. I'm okay.
She's using wide-area attacks.
It might be hard to dodge them.
Bardiche.
Yes, sir.
Barrier Jacket: Lightning Form
Here.
Hayate...
Nanoha!
Fate!
Yuuno, Miss Arf!
Meister...
I shall grant your desire.
Our dear guardians...
Those who injured them...
I shall destroy them now.
Gefängnis der Magie
Magical Prison
What is it?
It's the same barrier
the Ritter used to trap us!
She's really after us.
Chrono is searching for the way to solve this.
Support is on its way,
but it will take time.
So until then, it's up to us
to do something?
Nanoha...
I'm okay.
Sleipnir, take wing.
Sleipnir
You gave the Liese their orders, right?
Admiral Graham.
No, he didn't, Chrono!
It was our decision.
Father was not involved.
Lotte, Aria, it's okay.
Chrono already knows a great deal.
Am I wrong?
Ever since the Buch der Dunkelheit Incident eleven years ago,
Admiral, you've been trying to find where the Buch respawned.
And then you discovered the
Buch der Dunkelheit's location,
and its present Meister,
Hayate Yagami.
But though you found the Meister and the incomplete Buch der Dunkelheit,
that itself didn't matter.
Even if you captured the Meister or destroyed the Buch der Dunkelheit,
it would respawn right away.
Therefore, you kept a close eye on it
and waited for the completion of the Buch der Dunkelheit.
You've found it, haven't you?
A way to seal the Buch der Dunkelheit forever.
When I saw her,
in poor health and orphaned,
My heart bled for her,
but I also thought it was destiny.
Lonely as she was,
there would be none to grieve for her.
You acted as her father's friend,
and were financially supporting her too, right, Admiral?
At the least, before she would be put to sleep eternally,
I wanted her to have happiness.
Hypocrisy, isn't it?
The way to seal the Buch is
to freeze it along with the Meister,
and trap them between dimensions in a frozen world.
That's about it, right?
It is.
If that is done, the Buch der Dunkelheit cannot respawn.
The past Meisters of the Buch der Dunkelheit
were annihilated with the power of the Arc-en-Ciel,
so it amounts to the same thing!
Chrono, it's still not too late.
Release us.
The only time we can freeze it
is within a few minutes after it goes out of control!
Until that happens, the Buch der Dunkelheit's Meister
is not yet a criminal who deserves to be frozen forever.
It's illegal.
Because of that!
Because of the law,
this tragedy keeps being repeated!
Clyde too...
Even your father was—
Lotte...
The law aside,
there is a problem with your plan, Admiral.
First of all, removing the freeze would not prove too difficult.
No matter where you hide it
or how well you protect it,
someone, someday,
will try to find and use it.
Anger and sadness,
greed and despair.
Those kinds of wishes can lead one to the sealed power.
I'm worried about what's going on out there.
I'm sorry, but I'll take my leave.
Chrono!
Yes?
Aria, give him Durandal.
Father!
No way!
We don't have another chance.
We can't put it to good use.
I'll leave how to use it up to you.
This is Durandal, the Staff of Freezing.
Break.
Break up.
Plasma Smasher
Fire!
Divine Buster Extension
Shoot!
Shield.
Panzerschild
Armored Shield
Launch the fangs. Dye them in blood.
Blutiger Dolch
Bloody Dagger
Pierce it. Bloody Dagger.
Shine the light of destruction on the murderers.
No way!
That's...
Gather, o stars.
Become a light that penetrates everything.
Starlight Breaker?
Arf! Yuuno!
Got it.
Penetrate, o beam.
How dare she use Nanoha's magic!
Nanoha was already absorbed.
She copied it then.
Fate, we don't have to get too far.
If we're hit at that range,
it can penetrate our shields.
We have to get far away.
Sir, there are noncombatants
on the left at 300 yards.
There really isn't anybody here!
They just disappeared all of a sudden.
Then it got dark, and something is shining.
What the heck is going on?
Yeah...
For now, let's run far away.
Yes.
Distance 70...
60...
Nanoha, I'll leave you here.
50...
20...
18...
Huh?
Um, excuse me!
It's dangerous, so please stay right there!
That voice is...
Nanoha?
Fate...
Starlight Breaker.
Fate, take care of them.
Stay right there, you two.
Defenser Plus
Raising Heart!
Wide Area Protection
Nanoha! Nanoha, are you okay?
Fate!
I'm fine, but...
Alisa and Suzuka are trapped within the barrier.
What the hell?!
Amy!
As soon as the interference dies down, I'll evacuate them.
Hang in there somehow!
Okay!
It's all right now.
I'll have them take you to a safe place,
so stay still a little longer, okay?
Um... Nanoha, Fate...
Hey, hold on...
They saw us.
Yeah.
Yuuno, sorry, but can you protect them?
Arf, please, you too.
But Fate...
Let's go.
But...
They can't fight if they have people to look out for.
Oh.
Nanoha, Fate, there's
a message from Chrono.
He's saying to convince the
Buch der Dunkelheit's Meister,
Hayate, to stop and surrender!
Right!
Hayate and Ms. Buch der Dunkelheit, please stop!
We're not the ones who hurt
Vita and the others!
Signum and we are...
My Meister wishes for this world,
the world that took away her loved ones,
to become a bad dream.
All I need to do is grant that wish.
An endless sleep in a peaceful dream to the Meister...
And...
To those who took away her Ritter,
endless darkness.
Ms. Buch der Dunkelheit!
You call me by that name as well...
That doesn't matter.
All I do is grant the Meister's wish.
Just grant her wish?
If you grant that wish,
is that really going to make Hayate happy?
Simply being a machine with an empty soul,
that just grants its Meister's wish...
Are you all right with that?
I'm a magic book.
Just a machine.
But you can talk, right?!
You have a soul, right?!
It'd be messed up if you didn't!
If you really didn't have a soul, then you wouldn't be crying!
These tears are the Meister's tears.
I'm a machine.
I don't feel sadness.
Barrier Jacket, purge!
Sonic Form
You don't feel sadness?!
When you say such sad words
with such a sad face,
who would believe you?!
You have a soul too!
It's okay to say you're sad!
Your master, Hayate, is a nice girl who can answer you!
So release Hayate.
Put down your weapon!
Please!
So fast...
Already the destruction has begun.
I'll soon lose consciousness.
If that happens, then I will go out of control.
I want to grant the Meister's wish while I'm still conscious.
Blutiger Dolch
Bloody Dagger
Sink into darkness.
You whiny...!
Sonic Drive
Listen to...
Ignition
...us!
You too shall sleep within me.
Fate!
Absorption
Everyone is in a peaceful sleep.
I won't forget even when I grow up
My love, the day that we came across each other
In this place, where flowers bloom intensely
I kept you in tears
I remember the promise
My love, the smile that I love so much
That day, when the secret door opened
I was chasing after a small white butterfly
I got lost, and I wanted to cry
My true wishes, my true feelings
Maybe you taught those to me
Guarded by such kind feelings
I'm sure I was spoiled for all this time
How you thought dear of me
My love, I won't forget all of you
Fate got trapped in the Buch der Dunkelheit.
Hayate remains asleep in the Buch der Dunkelheit.
Past memories and sadness revive on a holy night.
And a small present.
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha A's:
Episode 11: A Gift for Christmas Eve
A Gift for Christmas Eve
A wish will come true.