It was only a small wish.
Everyday life where nothing happens...
Each day gently continuing on to the next.
I'm not going to wish for anything.
I'm not going to seek any power.
I'm just glad that it's at my side.
That way, I will be able to protect everyone.
There are times when
the feelings cross each other.
But even then...
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha A's
will now begin.
Prayers echoing in the vast skies turn to miracles
Teardrops melt and flow into the blue of the middle of the night
I met a warmth that engulfs all without hesitation
Just like the pure white snow
Words that are honest no matter how far you go
It moves me as I wear wings of steel
Each time I am hurt,
I can become kinder
My only wish is to protect that smile of yours to the end
Memories of sadness engraved across the ages
You are an angel of light,
catching them straight on
An eternal blaze that stopped
in my heart that day
Releasing the deep darkness
It opens the door of freedom
Towards the strong, boundless future
Welcome, customers!
Welcome to Mikuniya Supermarket!
Today's sale items are ingredients for a hot pot,
full of stamina to overcome the cold winter!
In the store's special corner,
we have all sorts of items on sale!
Also, the meat department is holding a pork fair.
Pork is a healthy meat that is very nutritious!
In our time-limited sale, some items are half price!
Everyone, please buy them today!
But lately, you guys are hardly ever home.
Well, um, you know... I wonder why?
Oh, I don't mind at all.
If all of you have things you want to do outside, that's fine with me.
Hayate...
I'm used to being all alone.
Hayate, it's all right.
Lately, everyone has been busy,
but I'm sure that soon enough,
they'll once again...
I see.
If you say so, Shamal, it must be true.
Suzuka is going to come by tonight too,
so I guess we need about this much meat?
Sure.
It's cold outside, so we should have a nice hot pot tonight!
Yes...
I wonder if everyone else is feeling cold outside.
It Was Only a Small Wish
(part 1)
A fortified entrapment barrier...
Looks like Vita's group has been trapped inside.
Select your action!
Wählen sie Aktion!
Lævateinn...
Has your mistress been a Ritter who would pull back in a situation like this?
No.
Nein.
That's right, Lævateinn. You and I
have always done it this way.
We are not here to fight against you!
At least let us hear you out.
The reason you're aiming to complete the Buch der Dunkelheit...
Y'know, there's an old Belkan proverb.
Messengers of peace don't carry spears.
It means, only a Dummkopf is gonna bring a weapon
when they want to just talk things out!
Dummkopf!
This from the girl who suddenly attacked us without a word?!
By the way, that's not a proverb,
but the punch line in a short story.
Halt die Klappe! Don't sweat the details!
Signum!
Yuuno, Chrono,
don't get involved in this!
I'm going to fight one-on-one with that girl!
Is she serious?
She's serious, all right.
Arf...
Me too.
Against her...
Right.
I have some talking to do with that guy myself.
Yuuno, this makes matters easy.
We should split up and search for the Meister of the Buch der Dunkelheit.
The Buch der Dunkelheit?
Those guys don't have it,
which means that they have one more comrade
or the Meister somewhere around here.
I'll search outside the barrier, so you should search inside.
Got it.
Master.
Please call me "Cartridge Load".
Raising Heart!
Cartridge Load
Load Cartridge
Sir.
I'll do the same.
Bardiche, Cartridge Load!
Load Cartridge
They have strengthened their Devices.
Be careful, Vita.
Like I don't know that!
So you're going to fight after all!
If I win, I'm going to have you tell me your story! Got that?!
If you can, you're welcome to try!
Schwalbefliegen
Flying Swallow
Accel Fin
Eisen!
Explosion
Raketenform
Rocket Form
Protection Powered
Hard as a rock!
No kidding.
Barrier Burst
Let's shoot it. Accel Shooter!
Accel Shooter
Shoot!
Control, please.
Are you a moron? There's no way you can control this many bullets.
It can be done, as for my master.
It's a promise. If we win, you'll tell us your situation!
Accel...
Panzerhindernis
Armored Barrier
...Shoot
Oh, you've got to be...
Plasma Lancer
Fire!
Turn!
Lævateinn!
Sturmwinde
Storm Winds
Blitz Rush
Haken Form
Schlangenform
Snake Form
Testarossa, you're strong.
Schwertform
Sword Form
You, and your Bardiche.
Thank you.
You and Lævateinn too, Signum.
Danke.
Thanks.
If there was nothing that
my body needed to accomplish,
then my soul would have danced with joy from this battle.
However, for my friends and for my Meister,
I can't say that for the time being.
I'm not confident that I
can win without killing you.
Will you forgive me for my immaturity?
That doesn't matter.
Because I'll be the one who wins.
Hey, you big lug, are you someone's familiar too?
On Belka, beasts who serve Ritter
are not called familiars!
I am my mistress' fang and her shield...
her guardian beast!
It's like the same thing!
The situation doesn't look that good.
I don't think Signum or Vita would lose,
but we should pull back.
Shamal, can you do anything?
I'd like to do something,
but the Bureau's operatives are maintaining a barrier from outside.
I don't have enough mana
to break through!
You'd need power like Signum's Falken
or Vita's Gigant form for that.
Neither of them have a free hand right now.
There's no choice. Use it.
I know that, but...
Shamal?! What's wrong, Shamal?!
You are under arrest for suspicion
of posessing and using
a Lost Logia registered on the search list.
Alright! Chrono, good job!
If you don't resist, you have
the right to speak in your defense.
If you're willing to cooperate,
disarm yourself.
Another ally?
Amy, what was that?!
I don't know! There was nothing in the searcher results over here!
Why? What's going on?!
And you are?
Use it.
Use the power of the Buch der Dunkelheit
to destroy the barrier.
But that's...
The pages that will be used up
can be added again.
If your comrades are defeated first,
it will be too late.
Everyone! I'm going to fire
a blast to destroy the barrier!
Avoid it as best as you can, and retreat!
Right!
Who in the worlds are you?
Are you another one of them?
Answer me!
O Buch der Dunkelheit...
Your guardian Shamal commands you.
Give me the power to destroy
the enemies that lie before my eyes!
Do not move for now!
Wait for the time.
It will be revealed in due time that I'm doing the right thing.
What?!
Rain down the thunder of destruction!
Geschrieben.
Let it be written.
Not good!
Individual defenses!
I'm sorry, Testarossa.
We'll finish this duel another time.
Signum!
Vita, the Wolkenritter's Ritter of the Steel Hammer.
What's your name?
Nanoha.
Nanoha Takamachi!
Nanu... Takamati...
Nano...
Ach, I can't pronounce this Mist!
She suddenly snapped?
Whatever. We'll settle the score later!
Kill ya later! I mean it!
Uh, Vita?
Protect your friends!
A direct hit can be dangerous!
What?!
Okay...
Sitrep, please!
A magical explosion.
There's no physical damage!
But they're jamming the airwaves, so the searchers and the radar...
Nanoha, Fate, Arf, are you all right?
Yeah. Thanks, Yuuno, Arf...
Over here, over here!
Your kitties are all
good babies, Suzuka!
But I'm really sorry for barging in so suddenly.
No, not at all.
I'm happy that you came out here.
Oh, I'll get it.
Hello, it's me, Shamal.
Hayate, I'm really, really sorry!
I had thought that it would end soon enough,
but I couldn't quite meet up with the others,
and that took up our time...
Yes, well...
I left my cell phone behind...
Yes... I just came home...
Yes, yes...
Everyone is together... of course...
How can I apologize?
I'm really glad, then.
I'm not mad at all!
I'm fine, so there's
no need to apologize.
It was too lonely for Suzuka and I to poke at pots by ourselves,
so Suzuka invited me to her place.
Yeah, that's all.
I was treated to dinner at Suzuka's house!
It's a big helping...
Dessert is in
the fridge!
—Hayate
I have all the ingredients cut up in the fridge,
It's a big helping...
Dessert is in
the fridge!
—Hayate
and the broth is already in the pot,
so it should be ready to eat.
It's a big helping...
Dessert is in
the fridge!
—Hayate
It's a big helping...
Dessert is in
the fridge!
—Hayate
You guys should eat up!
Yes... I'm really sorry about this!
Yes. Yes. Then, I'll give it to Vita.
Hayate
cell
Hayate...
Hello?
We've really made her feel lonely.
Yeah...
But anyway, who in the worlds was that man who saved you?
I don't know,
but he doesn't seem to be
one of our enemies, at the least.
Those guys from the Bureau
will put out an even bigger effort from now on.
And that blast used up quite a few pages too.
But we don't have much time left.
Right...
As soon as possible...
we must make Meister Hayate
into the true owner of the Buch der Dunkelheit.
You're right.
Signum!
Hayate wants to talk to you.
Right.
Hello, this is Signum.
The Cartridge System is very difficult to handle.
It's usually not something that gets integrated
into delicate Intelligent Devices
like those two.
I said that it would be dangerous,
since it has a high risk
of destroying their main bodies.
But both of them insisted that we just had to do it.
They must have been really frustrated
that they weren't able to protect their masters,
that they couldn't answer the trust their masters have shown them.
Thank you, Raising Heart.
All right.
Bardiche.
Yes, sir.
There are three modes each.
Raising Heart has the mid-range shooting Accel, the Buster cannon,
and the Full Drive, Excelion Mode.
Bardiche has the default Assault,
Haken the scythe,
and the Full Drive, Zanber Form.
There's a risk of complete destruction,
so try not to use the
Full Drive if possible.
Especially you, Nanoha.
Yeah?
Until we can fortify the frames, never boot up Excelion Mode.
Okay.
The problem is their objective.
Yes... something really doesn't quite fit.
It even feels like they themselves are the ones wishing
for the completion of the Buch der Dunkelheit.
Is there something strange about that?
The Buch der Dunkelheit is something like a Jewel Seed,
and people who want lots of power go after it, right?
Then it's not so weird for those guys to
do their best for the sake of
the person who wants that power.
In the first place, the power of the Buch der Dunkelheit
isn't something that can be freely controlled like the Jewel Seeds.
Both before and after its completion,
the power can only be used for pure destruction.
At the least, there aren't any records of anyone using it for anything else.
I see.
That, and one other thing.
Those Ritter... they are the guardians of the Buch der Dunkelheit.
They are neither humans
nor familiars.
They are quasi-humans created by
magical technology that accompanies the Buch der Dunkelheit.
They act upon receiving orders from the Meister.
They should be mere programs that do nothing more than that.
I won't forget even when I grow up
My love, the day that we came across each other
In this place, where flowers bloom intensely
I kept you in tears
I remember the promise
My love, the smile that I love so much
That day, when the secret door opened
I was chasing after a small white butterfly
I got lost, and I wanted to cry
My true wishes, my true feelings
Maybe you taught those to me
Guarded by such kind feelings
I'm sure I was spoiled for all this time
How you thought dear of me
My love, I won't forget all of you
Next Episode Preview
Somehow, things are getting
more and more complicated.
Artificial lives, destiny that has been determined...
Where can you find the truth?
That can be found in the past of the Ritter.
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha A's:
Episode 6: It Was Only a Small Wish
(part 2)
It Was Only a Small Wish
Drive Ignition!