It was only a small pain.
Feelings that were supposed to have connected were blocked,
unable to reach the other side.
Wishes get tangled up,
hearts and hopes melt together...
We almost lose sight of the truth.
Now matter how sad the past,
no matter how dark the future.
Still, we have to stand up against it.
Because I'm sure that everyone is fighting at the same time.
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha A's
will now begin.
Prayers echoing in the vast skies turn to miracles
Teardrops melt and flow into the blue of the middle of the night
I met a warmth that engulfs all without hesitation
Just like the pure white snow
Words that are honest no matter how far you go
It moves me as I wear wings of steel
Each time I am hurt,
I can become kinder
My only wish is to protect that smile of yours to the end
Memories of sadness engraved across the ages
You are an angel of light, catching them straight on
An eternal blaze that stopped in my heart that day
Releasing the deep darkness
It opens the door of freedom
Towards the strong, boundless future
Though Fate's Linker Core
is severely damaged,
her life is not in danger.
Just like what happened to me...
The Buch der Dunkelheit absorbed it all up.
I'm glad it was while the Arthra was running.
We were able to help her out much faster than in your case, Nanoha.
Right.
A while after the two of you departed,
the security systems at headquarters were hacked and taken down.
That was why I couldn't give commands or even contact you.
I'm sorry, it's my responsibility...
It's not like that.
Because you got the system back up quickly, Amy,
you were able to contact the Arthra.
And we were able to grab
clear footage of that masked man.
But it's strange.
Their equipment is of the same system as used by the Bureau.
Is there anyone out there that can crack into it from the outside?
That's exactly it.
Getting past all firewalls and alarms to take the system down so suddenly...
It's just unthinkable.
I'm shifting the units around right now,
but I have to think of a stronger way of blocking them out.
Does that mean that they have that good an engineer over there?
Perhaps they have
an organization to do so.
What I also heard from you...
The conditions, and how they interact with each other, are still unclear.
Yeah...
By the time I got there,
the masked man was already nowhere in sight.
But she...
Signum was holding on to Fate...
She said she had no excuse, but she wanted to relay that she was sorry.
Allex, any problem with the Arthra cruising about?
No problems.
Then, this is a bit earlier than scheduled,
but we will return to
command HQ aboard the Arthra.
All hands, back to your regular positions!
Yes, ma'am!
Miss Nanoha, you need to go back home.
Oh, yes... but...
If it's about Fate, then it's all right.
We'll take good care of her.
Okay.
The Heartbreaking Decision and the Courageous Choice
So, we can say that we were saved?
At the least, it is certain that
he wants the Buch der Dunkelheit to be completed.
Perhaps he wants to use the Buch der Dunkelheit once it is completed.
That can't be it!
I mean, even if he took the Buch der Dunkelheit after it's completed,
only our master can use it!
At the point of completion, the Meister will have absolute power.
There is no way threats or brainwashing would have any effect.
Well, we have heavy security around the house,
so I don't think there's any chance a threat will come for Hayate.
Just to be on the safe side,
Shamal, stay by our Meister's side as much as possible.
Right.
Hey, when we finish theBuch der Dunkelheit,
and Hayate becomes
our master for real,
it's going to make
Hayate happy, right?
What's this, all of a sudden?
The Meister of the Buch der Dunkelheit
will have grand powers.
We, the guardians, know that better than anyone else, right?
Right...
We do, but...
I think somehow we're forgetting something really important...
Hayate!
Hayate! Hayate!
The hospital... an ambulance!
Right!
Don't move her. Leave her alone.
Okay...
Fate, are you awake now?
Commodore Lindy?
Arf?
Arf has been at your side all night as well.
What? I...
You're aboard the Arthra right now.
You were attacked from behind during your battle in the desert,
and had been unconscious.
Your Linker Core got absorbed a little,
but they say you will be fine soon.
No need to worry.
I was defeated, wasn't I?
Not even Bureau searchers could confirm this ambush beforehand,
so there's nothing you could have done.
Oh, I'm sorry. Did you not like that?
No... It's not that
I didn't like it... um...
You seemed to be having a nightmare, so...
But thank goodness you're okay.
I'm sorry.
Thank you so much.
I contacted the school and told them
that you will be absent due to family matters,
so you should rest a bit more.
Yes...
You're getting hungry, right?
I'll bring a light meal and a drink.
What would you like?
Oh, no, that's not...
It's all right.
Well... I'll leave it up to you.
Fate...
Uminari University Hospital
Yes, you seem to be all right. I'm glad.
Yes... thank you so much!
I'm so relieved.
That's why I said I got a bit dizzy,
and pulled the muscles in my chest and hand...
Geez, everyone is making such a big deal out of it.
But you did hit your head.
Had it been something, it would have been a big deal.
Hayate, thank goodness.
Well, since you came out here,
I would like to do a few tests, so relax here for a bit longer.
Sure.
Now, Ms. Signum and Ms. Shamal...
A word over here?
Yes...
Nothing's showing up in the tests,
but I don't think it's just a pulled muscle.
Yes. She seemed to be in great pain.
Perhaps the paralysis is starting to spread again.
She didn't have symptoms like this in the past, right?
I don't think she did.
But Hayate always hides all of her pain and suffering.
There is no guarantee that she won't have another seizure.
It would be best for her to be hospitalized for a while,
just to be on the safe side.
Is that all right?
Yes.
Hospitalized?
Yes, apparently so.
Oh, but it's just for testing to be on the safe side.
So you have nothing to worry about, right?
Right.
Well, that in itself is fine.
But if I'm here in the hospital, who's going to cook for everyone?
We'll... we'll... manage somehow.
That's right... it will be all right... I think.
I'll come visit every day!
So it'll be okay.
Vita, you're such a good girl!
But it doesn't have to be every day.
There's nothing to do here, so you'd get bored, Vita.
Then I'll relax and spend a vacation
that comes with three meals and an afternoon nap!
Oh, no!
Suzuka might be texting me and stuff!
Oh, I will contact her for you.
Please do.
Then we'll go home and bring you some clothes and a few books.
Do you have any requests?
What should I choose?
Vita?
Yeah...
Okay...
Let me report what
I've figured out so far.
First of all...
Buch der Dunkelheit is not its original name.
According to ancient sources,
its real name is Buch der Nachthimmel.
It was a tome that travelled with its Meister,
originally created to gather great magical technology from each land
for use as research material.
The use of destructive powers
probably began when
the main program was rewritten
by one of the users over the years.
So people who abuse Lost Logia
to recklessly attempt to gain immense power
existed in the past as well as the present.
Because of that corruption,
the travel function
and the automatic repair of corrupted data are running out of control.
Is that the reason behind the reincarnation
and the perpetual respawning?
If it's ancient magic,
that much might be possible.
The worst part of it all
are the changes to its owner's condition.
If there is no gathering of power for a certain period of time,
it starts to eat away at the owner's magical powers and potential.
And when it's complete,
the owner's magical powers will be used without limits,
for indiscriminate destruction.
That is why all the owners until now have,
right after the completion of the Buch...
Right.
What about material on methods for stopping or sealing it?
That's what I'm looking up right now,
but stopping it before it's complete will probably be very difficult.
Why is that?
Only one the Buch der Dunkelheit recognizes as the true Meister
has administrator rights to the system.
In other words, there is no other way to stop or change the program.
Upon forced controls from the outside,
an embedded system will absorb the Meister and respawn.
That's right. That is why they say
that sealing the Buch der Dunkelheit
for good is impossible.
It started out as
a wholesome research book.
You know, well...
I also feel sorry for the Buch der Dunkelheit,
the Buch der Nachthimmel.
Is that all you've researched?
At this point in time.
I'm still looking up all sorts of things.
But as expected from the Infinity Library,
it's amazing that I can find whatever I look up.
Or rather, we think you are amazing.
You're so skilled at searching for stuff!
Then, I'm sorry, but I'd like you to go a bit further.
Yeah.
I'm counting on you as well, Aria.
Sure thing!
Lotte, take over for me in a while.
Okay, Aria!
Good luck!
Yuuno sure is amazing.
Yeah, I was surprised by it myself.
Amy.
The image of that masked man!
Sure thing.
Are you thinking about something?
Yeah.
This man's abilities are amazing...
Or rather, I think it's more like impossible.
These two worlds...
Even with the fastest warps,
it would take about twenty minutes to cover this much distance.
But after blocking a direct hit from Nanoha's new Buster,
and cleanly initiating a long-range bind,
he crept up behind Fate without her noticing
and took her down,
in nine minutes' time.
That means that he's quite adept.
Yeah. Even I couldn't manage that.
What about you, Lotte?
Oh, no way. Impossible.
I'm not that good at long-range magic.
You two clearly divide your duties, with Aria in charge of magic
and you in charge of physical stuff, right, Lotte?
Right, right!
That got me into so much trouble in the past.
It made you all the stronger, right?
You have to thank us for it!
Are you feeling all right?
I'm a bit uneasy about not being able to use magic,
but physically, I'm all better.
For the time being, Nanoha, until we're called out,
they want us to live quietly over here.
I guess it's like we're on standby?
Yeah. They're going to increase the number of armed operatives,
and switch the main focus
to pursuit research.
I see.
Hospitalized?
Hayate is?
Yes...
I received a call late yesterday afternoon.
She didn't seem to be that bad,
but apparently there are a lot of tests, so it will be a while.
I see.
Then how about all of us go together to visit her after school?
Is that all right?
She's your friend, right, Suzuka?
You said you were going to introduce us to her anyway.
Besides, it's better to have a visitation
that's a little on the merry side, right?
Well...
I don't know about the last bit, but...
But I think it's a good idea.
Right?
Yes... thank you!
There we go...
Oh, Suzuka?
Suzuka Tsukimura
How is Hayate doing?
Dear Ms. Shamal,
Greetings, this is Suzuka Tsukimura.
I would like to visit Hayate with my friends after school today,
but is it all right for us to come?
Suzuka is such a good girl...
Suzuka Tsukimura
How is Hayate doing?
Please get better soon
—Suzuka
If it is inconvenient for you,
please show this photograph to Hayate.
What?
What's this about Testarossa
and her group?
I'm saying...
Testarossa and Nanoha,
those two mages from the Bureau,
are going to come visit Hayate today!
Because they're friends with Suzuka!
Oh, what should we do, what should we do?!
No, calm down, Shamal.
It will be all right.
Fortunately, most of
Mistress Hayate's magical potential
is within the Buch der Dunkelheit.
Unless they give her detailed tests,
they can't find out.
That may be true, but...
In other words, we just have to be careful that we don't bump into them!
It was a mistake to let them see my face.
When went to fight them, I should have used transformation magic or something.
There's no use regretting things now.
When her friends are visiting, we can step out of the room.
Yeah...
And we'll ask Meister Hayate and
Dr. Ishida not to mention our names.
Would Hayate think that was weird?
We have no other choice.
I'll leave it to you.
Hayate Yagami
Yes, come in.
Hello!
Hello! Welcome!
Sorry to bother you.
Are you all right, Hayate?
Yeah! I'm all right!
Oh, everyone, sit down, sit down!
Thanks...
The coat rack is over there.
Yeah.
Here, this is a cake from our place!
Really?
It's really tasty!
Ms. Shamal, what are you doing?
Oh, well... I just got a bit worried!
You can just go inside...
Or is that a taboo?
Um, well...
This may be a strange way of putting it,
but as Hayate's primary doctor,
I really am thankful to all of you, Ms. Shamal.
Ever since you all started living with her,
Hayate seems so happy.
Honestly, Hayate's illness is very difficult to deal with.
But we are doing everything we can to combat it.
Yes...
Hayate is the one who is facing the toughest time.
But, with all of you and all her friends supporting her,
I'm sure she will get
some courage and vitality.
So please keep supporting her.
So that Hayate will be able to fight against her illness.
I will...
I hope Hayate gets well soon.
Yes, me too.
How was your friends' visit?
Yeah, all of them were good girls!
It was fun!
They said they'd swing by every so often.
That's good to hear.
But you know, it's almost Christmas!
Christmas Days
This will be my first Christmas together with all of you.
I hope I can get out of here by then
and have a great, fun time together.
That's right... it would be nice if you could.
The speed with which
the Buch der Dunkelheit
is infiltrating into Hayate seems to be steadily increasing.
At this rate, she'll only last a month at most.
No, perhaps not even that long!
Something is strange.
My memory is telling me that this isn't the way it's supposed to be.
But this is the only thing we can do right now.
We'd hate it if Hayate stopped laughing... or even died... right?
Yes.
Ja.
Let's do it, Eisen!
Explosion
Gigant
Giant
Crush it!
Father...
It's not healthy for you to work so hard.
That's right.
Oh, Liese...
How are things going?
It's going bit by bit.
Chrono's group is doing their best,
but they are facing the Buch der Dunkelheit, so it won't be so easy.
I see.
I'm sorry about this,
getting you involved in this as well.
What are you talking about, Father?
We are your familiars, Father.
Your wish is our wish.
It's all right, Father.
Durandal is already complete too.
Sealing the Buch der Dunkelheit...
I'm sure that it will be fine this time.
Well...
I won't forget even when I grow up
My love, the day that we came across each other
In this place, where flowers bloom intensely
I kept you in tears
I remember the promise
My love, the smile that I love so much
That day, when the secret door opened
I was chasing after a small white butterfly
I got lost, and I wanted to cry
My true wishes, my true feelings
Maybe you taught those to me
Guarded by such kind feelings
I'm sure I was spoiled for all this time
How you thought dear of me
My love, I won't forget all of you
Next Episode Preview
The Buch der Dunkelheit
is almost complete,
but then that happened.
Was it coincidence or necessity,
or even destiny?
The time that had stopped is now running out.
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha A's:
Episode 9: Christmas Eve
Christmas Eve
Drive Ignition!