The weight of the truth that I finally understood.
The sad memories that were woven through time
quietly dissolve the pains of the past.
In order to not extinguish the light in my heart,
in order to not disappear into the deep darkness,
in order to protect the bonds we've created,
we now open the door to the future.
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha A's
will now begin.
Prayers echoing in the vast skies turn to miracles
Teardrops melt and flow into the blue of the middle of the night
I met a warmth that engulfs all without hesitation
Just like the pure white snow
Words that are honest no matter how far you go
It moves me as I wear wings of steel
Each time I am hurt,
I can become kinder
My only wish is to protect that smile of yours to the end
Memories of sadness engraved across the ages
You are an angel of light,
catching them straight on
An eternal blaze that stopped
in my heart that day
Releasing the deep darkness
It opens the door of freedom
Towards the strong, boundless future
The Meister of the Buch der Dunkelheit
has completely separated from the protection program.
Right.
Everyone!
The black mass below is where it will go out of control!
Don't close in recklessly until Chrono gets there!
Okay!
Night's End, Journey's End
Exercising administrator rights.
I've interrupted the protection program's progression.
I can delay it from going out of control
for a couple of minutes.
Got it.
That should be enough.
Send back the Linker Cores.
Fix the damage to
das Schutzrittersystem.
Come forth, my Ritter.
Vita!
Signum!
We are the Ritter who gather before the Meister des Nachthimmels.
As long as the Meister exists, our souls will never extinguish.
As long as we have life in our bodies,
we will stand by each other.
We will always exist before the Meister,
Hayate Yagami,
Queen of the Night Sky.
Reinforce, bestow upon me
my staff and armor.
Yes.
Hayate!
Light of the Night Sky,
come to my hand!
Reinforce, the Wind of Blessing!
Set up!
Hayate...
I'm sorry.
Um, Hayate, we...
It's okay. I understand it all.
Reinforce told me.
But let's worry about the details later.
Right now...
Welcome back, everybody.
Hayate! Hayate! Hayate!
Nanoha, Fate, I'm sorry.
My little ones caused you a lot of trouble.
It's nothing.
It's okay.
I'm sorry to break the mood, but...
Enforcer Chrono Harlaown with the
Time-Space Administrative Bureau.
Since there is no time, I will be brief.
That black mass,
which is the Buch der Dunkelheit's
protection program,
is going to go out of control
in a few minutes.
We need to stop that, no matter what.
There are currently two plans to stop it.
Plan A is to stop it by using extremely strong freezing magic.
Plan B is to finish it with
the Arthra's magical cannon,
the Arc-en-Ciel.
Are there any better methods?
I wanted to ask the Meister of the
Buch der Dunkelheit and her Schutzritter.
Um... I think the first plan will be difficult.
The protection program
without a Meister
is just like a ball of magic.
Even if we freeze it,
as long as the core is there,
the regeneration system won't stop.
You absolutely can't use the Arc-en-Ciel!
If you fire the Arc-en-Ciel here,
then Hayate's house will get blown away!
Is it that strong?
It's a magic that will distort space within a radius of 100 kilometers
from its target point,
causing reactive annihilation.
Does that make sense?
I'm totally against that!
Me too. I'm completely against it!
Neither the Captain nor I want to use it.
But if it starts to go out of control,
then that damage will be worse.
If it goes out of control, it'll absorb anything it touches without limit.
Hey, everyone, it's gonna go out of control in less than 15 minutes!
Please make a decision quickly!
Is there any way?
Sorry.
I don't think we can be of much use.
We have hardly ever seen it go out of control.
But we have to stop it somehow!
I don't want Hayate's house to get wrecked!
Well, it's past that point by now.
If only we could move the battlefield further out into the ocean...
It will still distort space
out in the ocean.
Gosh, it's getting all complicated!
Can't everyone just, like, blast it?
A-Arf...
It's not that simple...
Blast it, huh....
If we shoot it here,
then the damage will be huge.
But if it's not here, then...
Chrono!
Can we shoot the Arc-en-Ciel anywhere?
Anywhere? Like where?
Where the Arthra is right now.
In outer space.
Please don't underestimate the technology of the Bureau.
Of course we can shoot it.
In space or anywhere!
Hold on a minute!
D-don't tell me...
The light shrunk.
Yeah.
But there's still that black thing in the ocean.
What's going on?
Don't tell me this is going to keep up.
I have a feeling it will be okay.
I'm sure they are fighting for us.
Nanoha and Fate are?
If you can say it with such
a serious expression, Suzuka,
I kind of get the same feeling.
Either way...
Gosh! What the heck is going on
on a Christmas Eve that's supposed to be fun?!
If this is a dream,
then hurry and wake me up!
Alisa, calm down!
Oh, my...
They're as crazy as ever.
It's scary that it's even possible, according to the calculations.
Chrono, we're standing by here.
Ten minutes until it goes out of control!
It's a high-risk plan that depends on each individual's abilities,
but... well, it's worth trying.
The protection program's barrier
is made from a four-layer
compound of magic and matter.
We'll break that first.
When the main body's barrier is destroyed,
we'll attack all at once and expose the core.
Then with Yuuno's strong translocation magic,
we'll send it in front of the Arthra!
Finally, we'll annihilate it with the Arc-en-Ciel.
If all goes well, then this is the best way.
Admiral, can you see?
Yes, I can see it very well.
The Buch der Dunkelheit
was a cursed tome.
The curse ate away many lives
and ruined the lives of those who got involved.
Because of that, my mother and many victims' families
had to live unfortunate lives like this.
I'm sure it's the same with you and the Liese twins.
We can't change the past we've lost.
Start up.
That's why I'm going to fight now and change the future!
Start charging the Arc-en-Ciel!
Yes, ma'am!
It will go out of control in two minutes!
Oh... Nanoha! Fate!
Shamal!
Yes. I'll treat their wounds.
Klarwind, it's up to you.
Ja.
Yes.
Dear zephyr,
please deliver a boon of healing.
Shamal, Ritter of the Lake, and Klarwind, the Rings of Wind.
Healing and support is our specialty.
It's amazing!
Thank you very much, Shamal.
We're the support team.
We're going to stop
that annoying barricade.
Yeah.
It's beginning.
The program that caused the Buch der Nachthimmel
to be called the cursed
Buch der Dunkelheit.
The Dunkelheit
of the Buch der Dunkelheit.
Chain Bind
Struggle Bind
Chain it!
Steel Yoke
You better keep up with me,
Nanoha Takamachi.
You too, Vita!
The warmth of the hands gives me strength
Vita, Ritter of the Steel Hammer, and Graf Eisen, the Iron Count!
The piled feelings pass through the sky
Gigantform
Giant Form
This wish of the wind dries the tears
Thundering blast!
The released power becomes a sword and pierces through
Gigantschlag
Giant Smash
The end is the song of the beginning
Nanoha Takamachi and
Raising Heart Excelion, ready to go!
The song of the departing bird
Don't lose the meaning of the battle
Load Cartridge
The wishes become stars
Turn today's fire into the light of tomorrow
Excelion Buster
Despite the shivers, look ahead with courage and a sense of miracle
Barrel Shot
Break...
...shoot!
When I realize you're always there
Next, Signum and Testarossa!
How warm it is
The soul of Signum, Ritter of the Sword,
Like a flower, you're always beside me
is Lævateinn, the Magic Sword of Flame.
Its alternate form,
made from connected blades.
I realized what the true treasure was
I'll never hesitate
Bogenform
Bow Form
For you and for me
The tears turn into a rainbow and shine in seven colors
Race the skies, falcon!
Even for a moment, become the bridge deep down in the heart
Sturmfalken
Storm Falcon
Spread great wings and innocently smile like the sun on the hill
Fate Testarossa, Bardiche Zanber.
Here we go!
The sky is waiting for the light, so let's fly
Cut through! Lightning!
Jet Zanber
Even though you cry at night when you mature
Zafira, Guardian Beast of the Shield!
I won't let you shoot!
This irreplaceable time becomes a map for the future
Don't hesitate to go the new way
Hayate!
Come from far in the distance.
Twigs of mistletoe, become the spears
of the silver moon, and smite this creature!
Look up and see the life arise in the horizon
Spears of petrification!
The end is the song of the beginning
Mistilteinn
The song of the departing bird
Don't lose the meaning of the battle
The wishes become stars
I'll never forget the strong bonds we've tied
I am sure we're brighter than dawn
Let's go without looking back and with a smile
It's kind of incredible.
Ordinary attacks don't work after all.
As it gets damaged, it regenerates!
But the attacks are working.
Stick with the plan!
Let's go, Durandal.
Okay, boss.
Permafrost...
Give it eternal sleep within a frozen coffin.
Freeze!
Eternal Coffin
Here we go, Fate! Hayate!
Yeah.
Starlight Breaker
Maximum power!
Starlight...
Lightning flash!
Plasma Zanber...
I'm sorry.
Rest well.
Resound, horn of the end times!
Ragnarök...
...Breaker
Main core exposed.
Got you!
Long distance translocation!
Target in orbit!
Teleport!
Core teleport underway!
As it's translocating, it's repairing itself, at great speed!
Arc-en-Ciel, deploy barrel!
Firing lock system, open.
After confirming the target,
stand by at a safe distance until we get a response!
Get ready!
Roger!
Arc-en-Ciel, firing!
The object within the space
has been completely annihilated.
There is no regenerative response!
Maintain our current guard position.
We'll observe the response area for a while.
Roger!
So, you guys at the scene, great job!
The situation has been resolved successfully!
We still have to collect the wreckage
and restore the city,
but please return to
the Arthra for now and rest.
What about Alisa and Suzuka?
Right.
Since we removed the barrier in areas where the damage wasn't too great,
I had them return to their original location. They're okay.
What the heck is this?!
I see. Thank goodness.
Chrono, great job.
Yeah.
You did really well. Thanks, Fate.
Hayate!
Hayate...
Hayate! Hayate!
Hayate?
I won't forget even when I grow up
My love, the day that we came across each other
In this place, where flowers bloom intensely
I kept you in tears
I remember the promise
My love, the smile that I love so much
That day, when the secret door opened
I was chasing after a small white butterfly
I got lost, and I wanted to cry
My true wishes, my true feelings
Maybe you taught those to me
Guarded by such kind feelings
I'm sure I was spoiled for all this time
How you thought dear of me
My love, I won't forget all of you
Next Episode Preview
And so, the Buch der Dunkelheit Incident
comes to an end.
We give thanks and smiles to all we met.
And then departures and farewells.
A time to start heading in a new direction.
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha A's:
Final episode: Standby, Ready
Standby, Ready
I'm sure it's not the end,
but the beginning.