In order to revitalize her dying planet and save her father
who suffers from a severe illness,
the girl, Kyrie, travelled through the dimensions
with her best friend, Iris.
They sought the key to saving planets,
the Eternity Crystal.
They clashed with the Earth-based operatives
of the Time-Space Administrative Bureau:
Nanoha Takamachi,
Fate Testarossa-Harlaown,
Hayate Yagami, and her guardian knights,
plus Kyrie’s sister, Amitie Florian.
Kyrie was injured in battle and had her spirit broken.
However, she obtained the key to the Eternity Crystal.
By Iris’s hand, the three souls that form the key:
Dearche, Stern, and Levi, were successfully revived.
While the battle in the sky took place,
Kyrie and Iris found the Eternity Crystal.
However, Iris’s real goal was not
to help Kyrie and the planet of Eltria,
but to exact revenge on Yuri,
who remained unawakened within the Eternity Crystal.
Iris’s betrayal and the loss of any hope of recovery
caused Kyrie to sink into despair.
Yuri, controlled by Iris, ravaged the mages of the Bureau with overwhelming power.
That was when Kyrie fell into the deepest despair.
Still, the girls did not give up hope,
so as to not allow this sad story to end in tragedy.
Please wait!
This time...
I’ll definitely save you!
Iris, please come with us!
If you’re in trouble, we will help you out!
Yuri.
I am not in trouble, nor do I want your help.
I will withdraw.
Eliminate them, starting with the most dangerous.
Order received. Preparing elimination process.
Befehl erhalten. Vorbereitung Prozess Vernichtung.
She’s speaking Belkan!?
Setting up armor.
Rüstung formatieren.
Yuri.
Beginning elimination.
Beginn von Vernichtung.
I’ll save you as soon as I can.
Sorry, it might take a bit!
There seems to be regeneration capacity.
Yeah.
Nanoha, Iris is mine!
Thanks, Amita!
If I stop Iris, I can stop her too!
Flaming arrow.
Flammenpfeil.
Shamal!
Yes!
What immense power.
But the girl is crying.
Master, I have good news and bad news.
Let’s hear the good news.
Formula Mode operational.
I am able to perform above expectancy.
And the bad news?
Three minutes remaining until operational limit.
Then let’s do this in three minutes!
Let’s try our best.
Kyrie!
Iris, what exactly are you after?
And what will you do if I tell you?
A younger sister who betrayed her family
and wasted away their remaining time.
A homeworld that will only perish.
A father who will die without accomplishing anything.
A mother who will share her husband’s fate with the same disease.
You didn’t know, did you, Kyrie?
About your mother’s illness.
She can’t be...
What exactly are you?!
I am Iris.
Just like you, I am a life that was born on a dying planet.
I have been waiting for this chance for a long time.
Amitie!
I will not let anyone get in my way.
60 seconds remaining until operational limit.
One shot at full charge. After that, two shots.
55... 54... 53...
It won’t take much. I just need an opening!
Vita!
Stay calm. I have your back!
Thanks!
Claíomh Solais
Exceed...
...Breaker
Count -9. We’ve made it!
Where’s Yuri?
Those are...!
Pages from the Book of the Night Sky!
Let’s go!
Okay!
Yuri.
Hey, Yuri!
Yuri, are you okay?
It can’t be. Dearche?
Stern.
Levi.
And you’re...
Hayate Yagami, Mistress of the Book of the Night Sky.
Hayate! I have a request.
Of Dearche and the others too...
And of that girl, Iris...
Stay your tongue.
I do not wish to hear any more lies.
You!
The plan got a little messed up. I must redo it.
Iris!
What a handy book.
I will use it until its purpose is served.
Yuri.
Yuri!
Time-Space Administrative Bureau Main Office
The mastermind of the incident is still on the run.
Five material witnesses have been secured.
From Eltria, the Florian sisters, Amitie and Kyrie.
It seems that three persons of unknown identity
will also cooperate during the interview and investigation.
Where is our forward base?
I stationed the command ship in Tokyo Bay.
Its main crew members are already there.
Right, we’re here.
Take your time.
Dearche.
Your Majesty!
Hey, you guys.
This way, please.
Thanks.
Stern. Any thoughts on how to proceed from here?
I am positive that Iris summoned us from within the Book.
It was to find the girl named Yuri and to make us fight her.
I am sure we have a strong connection to Yuri.
There is also our objective to find a large source of power.
First, we need to know what Iris’s plan is.
Right.
And what we are.
I still remember the both of you so well!
Your names, personalities, and the time we spent together.
Under a big tree, in a green field.
The three of us were definitely together there.
I remember that too.
Memories of your great kindness to me a long time ago.
You brought us all kinds of things, like food!
Levi and I swore lifelong loyalty to you.
We will work to protect you and fulfill your wishes.
That’s right!
You’re my friend, Sternen.
Yes, we really are close.
I also clearly remember one thing
from when we were together before.
I exist to protect the both of them.
That’s right. Yuri was also there with us.
Thanks for your hard work, guys!
Hihi!
Oh, it’s you.
Yep.
I’m here about this...
Isn’t this the scrap of paper Yuri tried to give us?
It’s been damaged, but the data inside is still fine.
I think Your Majesty and friends can restore it.
Thank you very much!
Take care.
Amita.
Nanoha.
Can you already move about?
Yes, I’m fairly hardy.
I’m sorry I couldn’t stop Iris.
No, you’re fine.
Those crutches...
I twisted my ankle a bit.
But I’m fine!
Nanoha!
Hey, Amita!
Nanoha, did your examination go well?
Yes, it’s all good!
By the way, Amita...
Yes?
It looks like Kyrie just regained consciousness.
Really? What a relief.
Also, I have a personal request.
Go ahead.
The Formula you gave to Nanoha...
Could you give it to me as well?
Fate.
I hate being stuck on the sidelines.
I want to help you,
but you’d need an injection of nanomachines into your bloodstream to operate the Formula.
The nanomachines I was able to bring over
are the few we have left.
Even if I gave you all of them,
it still wouldn’t match the power Nanoha has.
I see...
However, I will help with enhancing your equipment.
You have my support.
Okay!
Yes... I got it! We’re almost there!
Do your best.
Fight!
Sorry to interrupt! You’ve been working hard.
Too much has been going on. You must be tired.
How about a break with tea and snacks?
Snacks!
Food is here.
What should we do?
Both of you may eat.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
I don’t feel like forming an alliance with you people.
But I wish to know something.
About the book you own.
Tell me about the Book of the Night Sky.
Sure.
It’s a magical tome that originated
on an ancient world known as Belka,
which has long since been destroyed.
Even after Belka was destroyed,
the Book was passed to various masters on various worlds.
Ten years ago, it came into my possession.
Within its pages are manifold spells and knowledge.
My powers as the mistress
and the guardian knights came with it.
We four are the guardian knights.
Knights?
Yes.
Actually, there was one more.
That child of mine has since passed away.
The Will of the Book of the Night Sky, a Unight.
In other words,
she was the avatar of the Book of the Night Sky.
I named her Reinforce.
She was such a beautiful and sweet little girl.
I am the second of her name, Reinforce Zwei.
To distignuish us, we call her Eins.
If Eins were alive and well,
she might know who you are.
Sorry to disturb!
How do you feel?
I’m sorry.
This is all my fault.
I caused everyone on this planet to suffer greatly.
How can I ever make up for it?
I wish I’d listened to my sister.
I should have tried harder to tell you.
It was partly my fault too.
But...
But Kyrie, I have not yet given up on
our father, our mother, or our home.
That our father and mother would be well again together,
for our family dream that Eltria
would once again be revived...
And on the day our parents are laid to rest, they can rest in peace in that warm bed in our house on our planet.
And as we fantasized as children,
we will grow our own flowers for decoration.
We are meant to rise above our failures.
Blaming yourself too much
will only diminish the good we’ve done.
We can still do something.
We must put a stop to the damage happening on this planet, stop Yuri, and really listen to Iris.
If you look up at the sky, your spine will also grow.
Now, be sure to get better!
I will.
Chief, call received from
Deputy Director Lindy at the local branch.
Connect us.
Laty, we’re in the skies above Tokyo.
Are the barrier mages in formation?
They’re ready and in position
to cover all of Kanto as instructed.
Do you have enough manpower?
We have plenty.
Yuuno has also joined us.
Don’t worry about ground protection measures.
We will not incur damage to the locals.
I’m counting on you, Lindy.
Yes. Don’t worry.
The equipment for the armed squad has been improved.
Ready for attack any time.
After I run some checks on Durandal,
I’ll join them in the field.
How are your injuries?
All better.
Don’t do anything reckless.
Don’t worry about it.
I just want to catch the one responsible for all this.
I don’t know how much tragedy has taken place,
but those who pretend to justify their wrongs
by putting the blame on others
are ultimately divorced from reality in the end.
I can’t let them get away with it!
That is our stand.
Durandal, time to move out!
Okay, boss.
Want to grab a snack or something?
Yeah, and I have to contact Alisa and Suzuka too.
Hello!
Alisa! Suzuka’s with you too!
Nanoha. I’m so glad! Are you all right?
I was so worried.
Sorry I couldn’t contact you.
How about Fate?
She’s with me. Oh, here she comes!
Hello!
Fate. What a relief!
Are things there still ongoing?
Yeah.
How about with you?
It’s not so bad here.
There was a quick follow-up report
on the runaway trailer accident.
I see. We’re now at the Main Office, but Hayate is in Tokyo.
Yes, I got a text just now.
I will not be raining damage on everyone on Earth.
I’m not at all worried about that.
Just don’t overwork yourself.
It’s fine! I’ll wrap it all up quickly!
I must continue with
the research project too.
Let’s all work hard at our homework
and finish it by July no matter what.
Yes! Then you can play hard in August, right?
Together with everyone, okay?
Yeah!
Yes! It’s done.
Splendid!
Good job!
More praise, please.
Rein, contact the Main Office
Good girl.
so Nanoha and Amita can watch too.
Yes indeedy!
Right, preparations complete. Playback now.
Our resources have been drained,
and desertification has taken place.
Our planet, once full of life,
is already in the process of dying.
That is our homeworld, Eltria.
More and more people are attempting to flee the dying planet and escape to new grounds.
Some of us remain here and
are trying to regenerate the planet.
That would be us,
the Committee to Restore the Planet!
We carry out research on the cause of
the Death Eclipse pollution that ravages the land,
as well as methods of extracting
deep underlying water to ground level.
We also perform research on organisms and livestock
that can survive even in harsh environments.
We employ many different people here.
By the way,
I myself am one of the Committee’s products!
Bio-Type Terraforming Unit,
model IR-S07, nicknamed Iris.
Leave the risky jobs to me!
I have just one request.
Save our home planet,
and make it green again.
Do your best, everyone!
Okay!
Was it really okay?
Of course! It’s just the publicity we need!
I wonder if additional budget will result from this.
The budget will come. For sure.
The level of contamination has worsened, hasn’t it?
Contamination is at concentration level 9.
It is the Death Zone that is
enough to kill microorganisms.
Andy, Jessica. Can you hear me?
Yes, we can hear you.
Everything looks OK.
Okay!
No way!
Iris!
What’s wrong?
There’s someone here.
It’s a child.
Impossible.
Iris, don’t get closer! Just take a photo.
Don’t worry. Wait a moment.
Hey, are you okay?
Where am I... who are you?
Wo bin ich... wer bist du?
What language was that?
Are you okay? Any injuries?
Where did you come from?
Did you fall?
I am fine. Good day.
Was that the correct greeting?
It was.
I wonder who you are. Are you an angel?
An angel?
Shall we get out first?
It’s dangerous here.
Okay, I will start the interview. What is your name?
Yuri Eberwein.
It’s a nice name.
May I call you Yuri?
Yes.
Where were you born,
and where did you come here from, Yuri?
I was born on Belka, and I was on Olsen before I came here.
Where’s that?
Another planet.
A very distant world.
Well then, what’s that book about?
The Book of the Night Sky. She’s a magic tome.
Some parts of her are dangerous,
but she’s a very good girl.
I was born to enable safe control of the Book.
The Book of the Night Sky is a tome that travels.
She journeys all across the worlds to meet her masters.
I watch over and explain
so that no harm comes to her master.
This is what I was born to do.
Yuri, may I ask what that tome can do?
Her master can use her for many purposes.
Such as?
The only things she can’t do
are resurrect the dead and manipulate time.
She can do just about everything else.
Amazing! She’s like a magic ring that grants wishes!
A ring?
Is this for real?
A great energy reaction can be seen.
Unit-wise, it is astronomical.
I see.
Yuri, are you able to control
the power of the book yourself?
Just a little. On top of that,
I can also use magic myself as need be.
Magic? You can do magic, Yuri?
Yes.
Show me!
I will show you my Formula too!
My Formula is the ability to manipulate
the atoms that make up matter
via nanomachines
that have been placed in my body.
Also, we have a Variant System
that manipulates metal and inorganic matter.
When combined...
...I can do something like this.
That’s amazing!
My magic is similar to that Formula.
It also can be used for destruction.
I could go either way.
I like to use it to for growth like this.
Is this a miracle?
Yuri! Yuri! Yuri!
Maybe you really are an angel, Yuri!
The power to touch life! The power to grow!
That’s the power we want the most!
Is that so?
Yuri, we have a request. Please lend us your power.
Yuri, your magic is our best hope!
It is?
Yes, it is, Yuri. Can’t you do it?
It’s not that I can’t, but if there’s something I can help with...
Yes, there is! I know it’s a selfish request.
But, if you have any troubles or difficulties,
we will help you!
So, please lend us your power!
I don’t know how long I can stay here,
and I may cause problems.
But if my magic is useful for everyone...
Yuri!
Thank you! I love you!
Hey, Miss Iris...
You don’t need to say “Miss”. Just call me Iris!
It’s my favorite name... the chairman gave it to me!
Then... Iris!
That’s right, Yuri!
Like a friendship scene from a TV show, huh?
Iris feels like a daughter somewhat.
What do you say to being her dad?
It is still too early to call her my child.
Well, Iris and us are fellow colleagues and friends.
Let us welcome this.
To new colleagues and new possibilities.
With the addition of Yuri to our committee,
the path to Eltria’s restoration is clear.
Using Yuri’s magic, specifically her life-manipulation ability,
has greatly contributed to the revival of vegetation.
In just two years, several plants have regrown
on the facility premises.
Currently, it is a magical technique that can only be used by Yuri,
but if we water it down to an all-purpose technique,
we will be able to see dramatic progress in the reconstruction.
The research team is also working hard to realize this.
Both of you, look over here!
Okay!
And Yuri has grown closer to us by the day.
We are having so much fun every day with the girl and Iris.
Chairman! Chairman! Let’s play!
Please play with us!
Okay, I’ll be right over!
They are doing well, aren’t they?
They grew nicely even without our help.
Yeah.
I want to share this orchard with the whole world!
Yes!
But I wonder if the committee’s budget will allow it.
Money issues?
The chairman is always troubled over this.
Even with a high possibility of revival, they only have just enough funds for everyone to escape to outer space.
I wish I had more money, so I could help all the people.
Let’s do our best!
Everyone will surely understand
as long as the restoration is progressing.
Yeah!
It’s over?
It just stopped here, didn’t it?
That’s funny.
So many surprises, huh?
Is that the Book of the Night Sky with that girl?
I wonder if Eins knew her in their short time together.
She must have.
She should have been awake from time to time
even when she had no master.
But why did Yuri do those things after that?
There’s no way to find out, is there?
The data must be damaged.
Skip to the next point that can be played.
Hurry! Over here!
Here!
Why?
Why, Yuri?!
Amita, what do you know about
the Committee to Restore the Planet?
It was about 40 years ago. This definitely happened.
My grandparents were also there when the incident took place.
Almost all the staff and officers died.
As a result, all the people who tried to save Eltria were gone,
with the exception of our parents,
who were still children at that time.
Well, I guess this is what you’d call an educated guess.
Yuri became immobilized after what happened.
Eins, who was inside the Book of the Night Sky,
was also unconscious.
So, she had no choice but to store herself
in the Book of the Night Sky.
Yuri was asleep within the Book of the Night Sky.
The Book of the Night Sky,
without a master, left Eltria as it was.
It came to me after going through some other masters.
So, Eins didn’t know what had happened to Yuri.
But if that’s the case, then why was Yuri in such a place?
In that crystal in the aquarium?
When the Darkness of the Book of Darkness was severed,
I wonder if Yuri was also cut loose in the process.
Then she went to sleep in
that crystal at the bottom of the sea.
Then it was found during the development
of the Allston Sea theme park
and installed in its aquarium.
And then we were let loose.
That is right.
However, I have some recollection of
the buildings and the committee staff.
If we think hard enough, we could remember Iris too.
Indeed.
Hayate, this is Investigation HQ.
Yes?
We have located our target, Iris.
Now, the nearest armed operatives are heading there.
Make preparations to mobilize everyone.
Roger!
I have been looking for you for a long time.
Why did you do it?
I want to know the truth.
Whatever your reasons were,
I want revenge on you, you traitor.
If you really did kill everyone, I will never forgive you.
I won’t forgive you for lying to me
and vanishing from my sight, either.
Why did you run away without killing me too?
You wouldn’t let me rest in peace together with everyone.
I want to finish the past.
If not, I can neither live nor die.
Three Pile Smashers already deployed in sniper position.
Surround the area. Assault team also deployed.
Keep monitoring and stay on the alert.
Be ready to charge at any time.
Yes, sir.
This planet is too noisy. Annoying, isn’t it?
Fire!
An attack! From where?
Team A and Team B are under sniper attack!
Rush in!
No equipment or vehicles?
My copies are also working hard.
Split up and work.
Yuri, kill the witches.
I would be happy if you killed the king too.
If you want me to return this book,
stay alive and return before me.
Understood?
Understood.
Verstanden.
Let’s go, everyone.
Unit 4 was destroyed in the siege!
The video and report are in!
Is Iris multiplying?
The copies are dispersing
and targeting the barrier’s outer perimeter!
They are leaving the force field.
This is what my dad told me.
The Terraforming Unit produced by the committee
has a self-replication ability
tuned to the local environment and situation.
Originally, its purpose was to restore the entire planet.
Even with few resources,
this was within Eltria’s abilities.
But on this planet,
with an abundance of raw materials and energy...
Deputy Director, can Iris’s primary body be detected?
It has already been identified by a signature marker.
If she is within the barrier, she cannot escape.
Leave the search to me.
I will strike Iris’s dispersed copies,
so that they cannot exit the barrier.
Chrono, Hayate. Take the field.
Roger.
Roger that!
Nanoha, Fate, please lend your support as well.
Yes, ma’am.
When Iris’s army or Yuri emerges,
we’ll leave it to you.
Do you really trust us?
We have the same goals, don’t we?
Save Yuri, capture Iris, and listen to their stories.
It doesn’t matter which force is bigger.
You may pursue your own target here.
If you face the enemy, we will deal with it then.
I see.
Of course, it’s best if we cooperate with each other.
Hayate!
Thanks.
Here, Your Majesty.
This is my custom tome Device.
I believe it will serve you well, Your Majesty.
Shari, Marie.
They’re all ready.
Thank you.
Welcome back, Raising Heart.
I am back.
Thank you for your cooperation, Amita, everybody.
Don’t mention it.
The emergency gate is ready for use!
I will go to the surface as well
and analyze the page Yuri left behind.
Please do.
Well, then. Marie, everyone.
We’re off!
Nanoha, I’m not making you promise anything,
but whatever happens, don’t act recklessly!
Don’t worry!
Kyrie, let’s do our best!
Okay. Thanks, Fate!
You have done terrible things.
So, you can speak.
Some of our bodies can. This is one of them.
In that case, shall we face off with words instead of combat?
That’s impossible. I simply follow orders.
I’ll rip you apart!
I am taking that radio tower
to be the perimeter of the defensive line.
Mama’s orders were to destroy the defenses and go forth.
Destroy it, Excavator!
Tokyo’s newest attraction was just finished!
Should I just stand by and watch it get destroyed?
What a nuisance.
There’s plenty of good iron here.
I will break it down and put it to good use.
Stop destroying the facility and kindly surrender,
then put us in touch with Iris.
All of us will be pleased if I take you down.
Do it, Excavator!
Cannon, shoot!
Yuuno, go for it!
Lock!
Oh, come on!
You little...
Comin’ at ya!
What? Still here?
Why have you come?
You know you can’t do anything alone.
That’s right.
I always depended on Iris.
I relied on the kindness of others
and did nothing but make trouble for everyone.
But I want to change.
I have to change!
It’s not a choice!
Seriously! You guys are too weak.
Be grateful I’m helping you out here!
I mean, aren’t we outnumbered here?!
It’s also because this area is the fulcrum of the barrier!
Fate.
We will intercept!
Everyone from the Armed Services, defend the barrier!
Yes, ma’am!
Levi, why aren’t you going to Yuri?
I dropped in from across the street
because they seemed to be in trouble.
If I selfishly went ahead to Her Majesty...
Huh?
It’s bad if people get killed, right? That’s what you said, Fate.
Someone who’s a stranger to me
may be important to someone else.
And who knows, that person
may become important to me someday.
With that in mind, isn’t it good to help them?
Yes, it is. It was really nice of you!
Enemies are still on the field!
That’s right.
We’re all good here. Go to your king, Levi.
But...
We’re fine. After all, I’m strong!
The barrier still can’t be broken?
The enemy’s fighting force there
is expected to be massive, but...
W-Well, all areas where the large Mobile Shells
were deployed were stopped by a wide-area attack.
Iris, can you hear me?
I understand your situation somewhat
from the information obtained from Yuri.
Please stop the fighting and come on out.
There will surely be something we can work together on.
I’m not interested. I will finish my work myself.
Besides, I’m a Terraforming Unit.
Part of my role is to eliminate anyone
who gets in the way of renovating the world.
Demonstrating this power is also part of my purpose.
Your Majesty! Sternen!
Levi.
Are things there settled already?
Yes. Did you find Yuri?
Yes, just now.
Let’s go!
Okay!
The resonance reaction that revived
Dearche, Stern, and Levi was also to search for you.
A little harassment before settlement.
I want you to kill the little ones you hold so dear.
Accelerator
To regain our past and your present,
please just endure this for a moment.
Let’s end this, Yuri!
Eliminating three hostile elements.
Vernichtung von drei feindlichen Giften.
Arondight
Your stolen smile was locked up without a place to go
Closing your eyes and praying
doesn’t change anything, even now
Come down, lightning!
Let’s wipe away the weakness we fear,
Thor’s Hammer
In order to get it back without fail,
I want to yearn more for strength
Until the day we fight, I want to offer
All the limited time we have to you
I’m sorry!
That has to hurt...
I really feel like this,
I just want you to smile like you used to
Yuri is being
controlled by
the Formula System’s
action force program.
If we keep up
the attacks on her,
As long as there’s an answer, I don’t feel pain
the thread binding
Yuri will burn out!
There’s also no use in worrying anymore
Don’t cry!
It dashed out, my unwavering heart
If Yuri cries, we will also be sad!
I won’t give this up,
let’s make it come true, I’ll keep going after it
You changed the me from that time
who was bursting with weakness
Stern, Levi, Dearche.
The overflowing feeling
that taught me happiness, even now
I will definitely stop Iris! So...!
You’re my beloved person,
these feelings well up my heart
Are you pushing us away?
Don’t do this!
Fool! Who would listen to a child
who only whines and does nothing to better her situation?!
“Do miracles not happen?” And you laughed, “Why don’t you make them happen!”
I don’t want to lose you guys either!
Let’s leave this parched city and fulfill our wishes
That’s right, we can’t go turn back, let’s open our eyes
Wait for us! We’ll definitely save you!
We have no need for regrets,
let’s fight the place the two of us belong
I wish in the moonlight, this time it’s my turn
I won’t lose anymore, I’ll come out to meet it
No matter what happens, I won’t waver
If we take our souls into our arms,
let’s raise them up ahead
Iris’s heart and the three of you
are caught up in this tragedy!
In order to someday return home...
To fulfill my sworn dream!
If you guys die, I will...!
I’m so glad they’re fine now
Yes.
Once again, your magic is amazing.
They were too weak.
It’s unbelievable that they recovered this much.
I did my best!
What are they talking about?
My body cannot move, and I feel cold.
Is the one in the middle saying something?
Maybe she’s cold.
Wait. Let me get a towel.
Don’t worry. You’ll be warm soon enough!
Want to read together?
You little rascals! You have something
against me in this room or what?!
I’m sorry! They all wanted to play.
Grrrrrr!
They always stick together, don’t they?
The one in the middle is like a little king,
always looking after the other two.
They’re so cute when they sleep like this.
The Book of the Night Sky is a child
bound with a chain of hatred and death.
However, the magic the Night Sky and I perform
is something that has the power to save planets and lives.
Those little ones and yourself
serve as a reminder for me, Iris.
The day may come where I have to give up
and face the fact that I can’t do it myself.
What I can’t do on my own,
I can achieve together with everyone.
I learned that from you, Iris.
Stop it, you’re embarrassing me.
Seeing how healthy and happy
the little ones are is proof of that.
You’ve given them names, haven’t you?
What are they?
Stern, Levi, and that one’s Dearche.
I want to be stronger together,
the beating in my chest won’t stop
That’s it.
She gave us life and raised us.
Let’s make a promise,
we’ll make it to a beautiful future
She gave us a warm life
without hunger or thirst.
In order to repay her for that,
I want to become strong.
The day to fight has come,
piercing our determination
That’s why I wanted it.
That’s right, I want to offer
everything to you
Not weak hands and feet,
nor a mouth that can’t speak a word.
We’ll get stronger again
if we make it through the night
I want to protect only you
Not a tail that is only fit for play.
I wish in the moonlight,
this time it’s my turn
So I can protect this sweet girl,
I won’t lose anymore,
I’ll come out to meet it
I will obtain much power
to make her dreams come true.
No matter what happens,
I won’t waver
An infinite amount of power!
If we take our souls into our arms,
let’s raise them up ahead
Dearche!
We must help our owner!
Our precious little girl!
Right!
This should shatter your chains. Prepare for impact!
Juggernaut
Why you... let me go!
Signum, how is it going over there?
The mass production model
was destroyed in its tracks.
What about your side?
Mrs. Lindy and HQ
are currently searching for Iris’s primary body.
We are working hard to eliminate
her copies in various places.
Don’t worry about them escaping the barrier.
Let’s hope the primary body will be found soon.
Yes. What’s left is the king and her retainers
who are fighting Yuri.
Yuri!
Yuri, stay strong!
Levi. Stern. Dearche.
I’m sorry. I...
What a relief. You’re back to the old Yuri.
This is great. It really is!
Levi. Everyone.
I am sorry!
Thank you!
We did it.
Yes.
Stern!
It was by no means easy to get what I wanted.
Yuri, the cats, and the witches.
If all of you go against Iris together,
you may very well overwhelm her.
Accelerator Alter
You cur!
Stern...
I will take her and leave.
All this trouble will be worthwhile
as long as I have the last laugh.
Yuri has lost consciousness.
Dearche’s group is also dying of serious injury.
Some of us may have secured Yuri,
but communications have yet to be established.
What is going on?
Secure the base!
You.
We are shutting down your forces one by one,
as methodically as humanly possible.
Kindly desist and surrender.
Besides, didn’t you suffer an unexpected incident?
Who knows?
One more thing.
After going over various after action reports,
I have a question for you.
Was it truly by your choice that you undertook these actions towards your stated goals?
Yuri let you in on what happened, didn’t she?
I have a grudge against Yuri
due to what she did to me in the past..
Is that what all this is about?
You seized Yuri’s will and took control of her.
Could someone have done the same to you?
Shut up!
Branch Director! Three new groups
of large Mobile Shells have appeared.
Secure them. I will freeze them.
Iris, please think it over carefully.
I am who I am.
I was born to save my planet
and to be raised with love by good people.
Yuri took all of it away!
You may deny everything else.
But, my memories! The times I was happy!
I won’t let anyone gaslight me out of them!
Kyrie?
Why have you come here?
I came to help.
Who are you trying to help now?
I know everything, Iris! About your past and about Yuri!
Iris, listen to me. Yuri told me.
Mama told me too, back home.
You have misunderstood what happened back then.
No, you were actively misled.
By a specific individual.
Right.
Is the pace of production going smoothly?
Yes.
Apart from the diversion force,
we have established a mining and production base.
Also, the barrier will be destroyed in due time.
Fantastic.
It’s all right! Let her through.
It’s you, isn’t it? The one responsible for all of this.
I don’t think I’ve met you before.
But you’ve met me, haven’t you?
Chairman Phill Maxwell of
the Committee to Restore the Planet.
Yuri left the key. The key to connect this world and Eltria.
Also, I was able to communicate with my mom in Eltria.
She looked up everything regarding
the Committee to Restore the Planet and you, Iris.
About what happened on
the day the committee was torn apart.
That is the record of what happened that day.
Vitals stable. Almost there, right?
Indeed.
Good girl. Please hurry up and be born already.
Chairman! Jessica!
Today, I explored as much as I could!
Then for dinner tonight, we’ll have your favorite food, Iris.
Yay!
That’s it.
This is my oldest memory.
Since I was a little girl, the chairman was always at my side.
I met Yuri, and we became friends.
I was happy.
We all were. All the time.
Chairman?
Yes, Iris.
Are you free now?
Yes.
Still discussing the budget?
They announced another budget cut.
Apparently the government has
lost motivation to work on reclaiming the planet.
Rather, they want us to focus on pioneering and developing safety measures for the new immigration destination.
How ridiculous!
Chairman, you’ve been doing
your best along with everyone else.
That is why I will continue negotiations.
We have first-rate technical staff here,
along with Yuri, our new hope.
And you too, Iris.
It will be all right.
I will not allow my children and those under me to suffer.
We extend our humblest apologies.
The Committee to Restore the Planet has been shut down.
The staff will be tasked to work on greenery
and facilities development for the colony.
I see.
But you have an inquiry waiting.
It’s regarding budget discrepancies and ambiguous plans.
Everything needs to be accounted for.
I know we don’t see eye to eye,
but Eltria could not be saved if I saw things your way.
Your methods could not have saved this planet either.
Also, as for the machine developed in your facility, Iris,
it will be considered a government asset,
along with all the technical staff. Transfer them over to us.
Chairman.
Just like that, all our hopes go up in smoke.
It’s too bad.
But it’s fine. As long as we have
the last laugh, all will be well.
I guess our job is over now.
Iris will be sad, won’t she?
After all our efforts...
Where is Iris?
She’s gone out to play with the kids.
The chairman intends to tell her about
the committee’s shutdown when she gets back.
I feel depressed.
Tell me about it.
Here! Hurry over here!
Chairman!
Yes, Yuri?
Was this disaster your doing?
Indeed. It has come to this.
As per the government’s wishes,
the efforts to restore this planet are over.
Those with no results to show
will be transferred to meaningless, leisurely posts.
Do we want to suffer such a fate?
But...
There is an organization
that wants to buy my skills as well as Iris.
Iris and I have decided to branch out into that direction.
Of course, I want you to come with us, Yuri.
Is it a military group?
Even where the people of this planet are heading,
no matter how distant the world, war is everywhere.
My skills and experience
will be useful in such an environment.
Iris design concept is that of
an artificial soldier with unlimited growth.
With the materials and energy you provide,
she can destroy or create at will.
A convenient and useful soldier in any condition.
I am aware that Iris was created for that reason.
But you love Iris and everybody else!
That’s right.
So why did you do this?!
Love is the fuel that inspires the human mind.
Iris received my affection, and as a result,
she performed beyond expectations.
That is why I love Iris.
She is my child...
as well as a very good tool.
Maxwell! You...!
This is...
And you too are a beloved child of mine.
You have wonderful magic powers.
You are also a good friend to Iris.
Let us work together in a new world.
I must tell Iris.
Please hide yourselves for now.
Everyone, wait here. Do not enter, no matter what!
Iris, can you hear me? The committee has been disbanded.
Yuri has gone berserk. I’m not in good shape myself.
Listen to me, Iris. Run!
How... why?
No!
Why?! Yuri, this isn’t true, is it?
He said you did this to him, Yuri.
Answer me, Yuri!
I did it.
But please listen to me, Iris.
It will be hard for you to believe, but...
Why? Why did you kill him?!
It’s not what you think! All this...
Iris!
I’m sorry, Iris!
I will make sure I come back here.
So please wait.
I know I’ll be back!
Yuri went on a journey, and Iris rested at that place.
After time had passed, she met my daughter.
I do not know when you started working on your plan, but...
I will tell you everything.
Even with only one piece of stored data,
Iris can be revived again and again.
My memories and consciousness
were likewise placed within her.
Then I arrived at the new world.
The things I treasured also came back to me.
This planet is a good one.
It’s ideal for a new home base.
Nothing would make me happier
than for us all to work together.
Accelerator
Too slow!
Due to unfamiliarity with dimensional travel,
I have been fighting since I came here.
It’s useless to resist in a body like that.
Like Iris said, you should go home as soon as possible.
Why are you getting involved?
This planet is also home to many people.
There are people desperate to survive here,
as well as those who wish to protect
what’s important to them,
and people who give their all to help others, even strangers.
Because we’re all the same!
On this planet and on our home planet too!
You’re right. You are the same.
The same as in my test environment.
This is a warning. Please drop your weapon and surrender.
It’s the same Accelerator as mine!
It is not the same.
It clearly has higher operating efficiency than yours.
Also...
Yuri!
Iris!
Run away!
You won’t be able to do anything on your own!
Most of all, I don’t want you to pity me like some stooge!
Iris!
If we fight together, nothing can stop us.
Moreover, I don’t see why we should fight each other.
There is no limit to the arms
and mobile weapons we can create.
I can freely control all the forces under my command.
That includes Iris as well as Yuri.
Right. Let’s see what it’s like
having both of you under my control.
Iris! Snap out of it!
Just get out of here already!
Come on!
Iris!
I don’t deserve your sympathy.
I deceived you for a long time
so I could to use you for my own gain.
But you never caught on, and you fell for it all.
This is what I deserve.
Right, I will tell you.
When you first came to where I was,
I saw you only as a small child I could use.
I only thought of ways to trick you.
Every time you depended on me,
every time I told you something dumb,
I thought that once again, I was someone you trusted.
I also took care of you.
We laughed together.
All of it.
I did all of it because I wanted to use you.
So, hurry! Run away!
I will not run away!
The time we spent together was not a lie!
I learned all sorts of things from you, Iris.
We laughed together.
Those were the best times of my life!
I don’t care what your opinion of that Iris is.
To me, she’s a close friend!
My best friend!
My friend who’s crying!
I can’t leave her alone!
Attack, Raising Heart!
All right.
Master!
There are too many of them.
Let’s split up.
I’ll take
the ground.
What about
Yuri?
Leave that to me.
Neutralization will be difficult,
but I can get her attention.
Nanoha, go after
the mastermind!
Right!
Let me go!
No! You’re seriously injured.
Yuri is crying. I must go!
No, you can’t!
Your injuries are severe, and you’re out of mana.
Let me go!
Dearche.
We have a request.
We’re frustrated that we are no longer able to fight.
So, we have decided.
Those kids...
Our mana.
We give all that remains of it to Your Majesty.
Fools.
If you do that, you will lose your current bodies.
They were only temporary bodies to begin with.
It’s a pity that we won’t be able to talk anymore.
But it’ll be all right.
The power we always wanted,
the power to defend the one we care about.
We entrust our wishes to your wings.
We will simply go back to being cats.
We believe that we will once again
be able to live peacefully in our home.
Just wait. I’ll make sure to bring Yuri...
No, I will bring both Yuri and Iris back!
They’re multiplying.
Speed has also increased rapidly.
Use Ouroboros to blast the enemy
once it gets within visual range!
It takes 90 seconds to execute.
Roger that!
Support?
From ground level!
Hayate! Rein! It will be all right now!
Shamal! Zafira!
How about the production plant?
Branch Director Chrono is assuming command and control.
So, as for us...
Let’s clear out the enemies on the ground!
Amita! I will take charge of securing the mastermind.
Let’s do this together!
I’m really sorry to always trouble you!
Same here. Happy to cooperate!
Let’s go, Amita!
Yes, Nanoha!
Accelerator Alter
Goodbye, Amitie.
Accelerator
Nanoha...
Since you showed me so many times,
I thought I could do it.
I pushed myself a little too hard, didn’t I?
The combination of Eltrian Formula and magic,
using Iris and Yuri.
How did that child pull off
what I had been trying to achieve?
Amita, please return to the support team.
But... I still...!
It’s all right. I understand.
Unit set.
Right now, it’s just that
my physical condition is better than yours.
Magnifcent. You were just magnificent!
I want that power.
I want you to be my child too.
Dearche!
Thank you for your trouble. Leave it to me from here.
You can’t do this alone. I’ll join you!
I’m not alone. Stern and Levi are at my side.
From the beginning, our duty has been to save Yuri.
It is Nanoha and the others who need help.
Go to them!
Dearche, you guys too. Take care!
I shall.
Listen here, Yuri!
I shall put the mana I got from Stern and Levi,
joined to all of mine, into this attack!
I will surely rescue you.
Just in a moment. Hang in there!
Dearche. You can’t! If you do this...
If I can wipe away all the tears from the past,
I shall not regret discarding
whatever life and transient power we have gathered.
You gave your life and heart,
and every day we spent with you was truly warm.
We were happy!
So, this time, Yuri, we will open the door to your tomorrow.
Dearche!
We are giving back all our strength as repayment!
Receive it!
What repayment?
I was always the one on the receiving end...
What? What in the blue hell is up with her?
Nanoha is pushing herself, but she’s way past her limit.
I must help.
Move!
Hornet Javelin
Exceed Estrella
Blast Calamity
Fire!
Shoot!
Iris!
Our allies are confirmed to have been cut loose.
Kyrie and others are safe.
Ready to execute Ouroboros.
Selecting exclusion zone. Anti-ballistics set.
Counting down to launch. Six, five, four, three,
two, one,
zero!
Ouroboros has been executed.
All Mobile Shells and mass-production units
within effective range have been annihilated.
Search for any mass-production units
remaining in the aftermath.
Yes, ma’am!
You really overdid yourself!
Chairman Phill Maxwell, you are under arrest.
Arrest?
Branch Director Chrono, this is the Allston Sea search squad.
Go ahead.
Some of the facilities are exhibiting unusual attributes.
Manpower has been increased at the vehicles on the tracks.
The processing team is currently confirming the contents.
I told you I transferred my memories, didn’t I?
Did you not realize there would be a backup
of Iris’s core system and my consciousness?
Stop all this!
He’s still...!
It’s too late to do anything about it.
Look up.
Huh, that’s weird. What a bright star...
Fortunately, this planet also has satellite technology.
When Iris came here, she planted seeds.
The materials Iris needs to recreate herself.
This is...!
It’s a satellite cannon.
Now, it’s aimed right at this city.
Although small, blowing up this city will be a piece of cake.
Don’t mind the launch.
It’s a little gift to my daughter who waits in the sky.
You!
Let’s make a deal, on behalf of Iris, Yuri, and myself.
I want you to let the three of us leave this place.
If so, I will let everyone in this city go.
If you do not agree, I will shoot
the satellite cannon towards this area.
Of course, you will lose your own life.
You also have friends and family here, don’t you?
You’ll die with us!
I will not.
At least, my memories and consciousness will live on.
You have five minutes.
This shouldn’t even be a choice for you.
Everyone, sorry for taking to the skies without permission!
Nanoha! Amita!
We will not let him turn this around for himself!
We’ll put a stop to his schemes!
It’s too dangerous!
Both of you, come back!
There are currently no means
to communicate with the chairman from orbit.
The barrier jams all communication.
So, he was planning to use Iris to escape the barrier!
He can’t send the order to fire.
His deal is a scam!
That small rocket contains backups of the chairman’s memories and the satellite communications stack.
When we finally reach there, like he said,
there will be no room for choice.
Sorry about this, Fate.
But please continue to distract the chairman
so he won’t figure it out!
Now, what is your answer?
We will consider your request after discussing it with HQ.
Nanoha, I’ll take over from here!
Durandal can also function in high-altitude battle—
We can go even higher.
We will work together and shoot it down!
You can count on us to reach orbit
and take out that satellite cannon!
We’re within firing range.
If the Eltrian government
had not given up on fixing the planet forty years ago,
would he still be working for Eltria?
It was all an act, but he always
had a smile for Iris and his colleagues.
He always came off as happy.
Amita!
You’ll be okay.
Go back down slowly and get to the ground rescue squad.
Nanoha.
But...
Please leave this to me.
At the very least, take this...
I’ll take it.
I’ll give it back soon.
See you.
It’s my first time flying this high.
Life support system is working. A pleasant flight indeed.
Nice to meet you.
Could we have a talk without resorting to weapons?
Having to consider so many people
in so many places, with so many factors.
Sometimes, I really don’t get situations like these.
Without compromise, there will be conflict.
Fighting just because you’ve a mind to do it
really isn’t a good thing.
But there are things I can’t protect without fighting!
What I want to protect...
What I failed to protect...
To protect what’s important to me...
That’s what...
...I have magic for!
Nanoha.
Finally, it’s over.
I’m truly sorry.
Yeah, so am I.
I guess I just saved everyone.
Without doubt.
It’s fine then.
I’m satisfied.
Are you really satisfied?
You must not really love yourself, don’t you?
I wonder if you don’t love yourself because you couldn’t do anything to help or support them.
I guess so.
It’s tough, isn’t it?
A little.
But when I was introduced to magic
and met everyone, it took the edge off a bit.
To this day, Yuuno, who introduced me to magic,
is my dear friend and magical teacher.
And I’m learning so much from
Mrs. Lindy, Chrono, and Amy.
When I see Hayate and everyone
in the Yagami family having fun together,
I can almost forget about my troubles and feel happy.
And there’s Alisa and Suzuka,
who always lend me their ears and worry about me.
When I became close with Fate,
just having everyone call my name made me so happy.
You don’t have to love yourself,
but don’t forget about those
who love you and care about you.
Surely you don’t want to make your loved ones cry?
No.
I’m sure that someday, you will come to love yourself.
I guess.
So, here you go.
Someday, for sure.
Fate.
Nanoha.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
We came to get you.
You can’t. It’s too much for you.
Hey, that’s my line.
No kidding.
In my dream, I had a conversation with my younger self.
What did Little Nanoha say?
She told me that I’m truly blessed.
Let’s go. Everyone is waiting.
Okay.
Your attempt to weasel your way out has been thwarted.
You are under arrest for violating interdimensional law.
Continue monitoring the situation.
Send in the investigators.
Yes, ma’am!
It’s time.
Indeed.
The children who gave it their all deserve a rest.
Late July, Shinjuku, Metropolis of Tokyo
Everyone at the Bureau
is up to their necks with post-incident follow up.
Although she had been deceived, Iris was still
the principal offender of the incident.
The Main Office is still interrogating her.
And they have a similar attitude about
my sister and I who came here unbidden.
They said that we can go home as soon as possible.
What a relief.
What are your plans now, Yuri?
I want to return to Eltria,
to mourn those who are no longer with us.
I have to try to make their dreams come true again.
Yes.
And they have entrusted Granz
and Eleanor’s illnesses to my care.
I see. You know Eleanor’s family, don’t you?
When we first met, they were such little kids.
I knew them from conversations with Iris.
I feel as though the time that had ground to a halt
is finally running again.
I have all of you to thank for that.
But I already feel lonely
thinking of being apart from you guys.
I want to hear more about
the Book of the Night Sky’s guardian.
There’s almost nothing more I can tell.
I was a mere chaperone, after all.
I could not make her happy.
But meeting a master like you at the end of
her long journey must have made her truly happy.
Thank you.
Take care on your journey.
We will!
Your Majesty and friends, why have you shrunk?
It’s not as if we wanted to shrink.
This is only temporary until we recover.
I wonder if the cat’s body might be better than this one.
This is much less flexible.
You guys are still cute in those bodies.
Will Your Majesty go to Eltria with Yuri?
Of course.
We promised to stay with her forever.
We are also somewhat interested in restoring the planet.
I see.
Fate, I’ve healed quite a bit already. So, anytime...
No, you can’t. You still need rest.
And when you want to go out, use the wheelchair.
Fate sure is strict.
Well, an ounce of prevention is better than a pound of cure.
There’s still plenty of summer vacation left!
Fine.
Following this, witnesses were questioned,
procedures carried out, things discussed...
So much has happened.
The time has come for us to go home.
Nanoha.
It’s too bad we can’t have a rematch.
We’ll see each other again.
You too, Fate.
As for you too, well, I am much obliged.
Farewells make me feel lonely.
Kyrie, Yuri.
There is one more person.
Iris!
I have my trial and other things going on,
so I will be staying here for the time being.
But I need to address matters after all this is over.
What kind of matters?`
I deceived everyone and caused so much trouble.
I did many things that can never be undone.
Although I will be judged by the law,
I still did a terrible thing to everyone.
To Kyrie and Yuri especially.
I just...
Please just listen to me this time, Iris.
Don’t bear this burden alone.
Moving forward, let us make amends together.
With my sister, Her Majesty’s people, and Yuri too.
Yes!
Look up to the sky and do your best!
We will all be with you.
Everyone, we are truly in your debt.
Likewise.
Take care, all of you.
I imagined coming home would be a gentle ride.
Actually, it was quite rough.
It gave me a shock!
Everyone, welcome home.
We’re home!
It has been a while since then.
The Florian farm is now in harvest season.
My mother’s illness is in remission thanks to Yuri’s treatment and medicine,
and so she remains in good health.
My father lived longer, and in more comfortable health,
than we expected him to.
With the return of Yuri and Iris,
he was truly delighted that the hope of
reviving our planet has been renewed.
In the end, he was able to rest in peace.
How is everyone getting along?
I hope that someday, you can come and visit us.
Then you’ll all get to see what we've been telling you.
That our homeworld is a truly beautiful planet.
The wheel of destiny that pulled us in in an instant
Reflects our dreams on the ever-changing
happiness as if on a glistening lake
It reverberates deeply, almost gently,
almost fleetingly
It digs into my chest
(feel sharply)
Stubbornly yearning
(happy with you)
Erasing the cycle of sadness
that loneliness connected me to
What I wish is
Embracing numerous nights
like the newborn sun
I want to snuggle close to you
and illuminate everything
Even if we get hit by
the grieving, violent rain
This love that never withers will guide us
Keep believing in the promise
we made that day
People always feel sorrow in chasing that
which they let slip through their grasp
They cower while being swept around
by “what ifs” they can’t return to
Their wounds don’t heal,
almost nobly, almost dazzlingly
They only ever searched for
(desired place)
A tomorrow called “eternity”
(seeking answer)
They fear to confront the truth that is today…
What I pledge is
I won’t let the future I’ll paint with you
like a flowing fountain
Be destroyed by the cruel hands of time
That’s my resolution for
protecting the one place we belong
I won’t avert my eyes anymore
From the end of this path I headed for,
no matter what’s waiting for me
Just as the shining stars
are calling out to each other,
Your smiling face always beckons me
What I wish is
Embracing numerous nights
like the newborn sun
I want to snuggle close to you
and illuminate everything
Even if we get hit by
the grieving, violent rain
This love that never withers will guide us
Please never forget the promise
we made that day
I will definitely come to meet you