We’ve always been together,
through hard times, painful times, and fun times.
Supporting and helping each other, we’ve always fought together.
She'd get mad at me if I said she was my beloved friend,
but to me, she's my precious partner with whom I'll walk the road to our dreams.
To stumble, to regret, and to carry failure together.
So let’s face it together.
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS
will now begin.
The hot comet dwelling within my heart beats towards the beginning.
My fingers tremble, grasping upon a silent wish
I cower, wanting to flee from the inescapable past
Even if it is merely a faint light fading
I want to chase after it, just like that star
And accept everything, no matter how high it is
Dancing throughout the galaxy is the angel's whisper
Pursuing these certain memories
The door to the truth will surely be born now
No matter what kind of cold darkness binds me
Because I want to know
I won't be stopped
Episode 8
A Wish for the Pair
I guess that wraps up my report.
The investigation unit will take care of the scene,
but everyone should cooperate with them as well.
We'll be on standby for a while.
If nothing happens, we'll head back.
Yes, ma'am!
As for Teana,
would you like to go for a stroll with me?
Yes, ma'am.
Looks like you’ve messed up.
I'm sorry.
One shot went astray.
I wasn’t at the scene, but Lt. Vita
has already scolded you.
So I think you’ve already reflected on your mistake.
I won't scold you a second time.
But Teana, you try too hard every now and then.
It’s becoming a bit of a problem.
But you know, Teana,
you have to remember that you aren't fighting alone.
Teana, our position in team combat has us surrounded by allies.
That's why you made your mistake today.
Think about it carefully,
and make sure it doesn’t happen again.
Can you promise me you'll do that?
Yes, ma'am.
In that case, I'll leave it at that.
You've promised me, right?
Yes, ma'am.
Understood, then...
Tia!
Subaru.
I’m sorry for everything.
Forget it.
Were you scolded by Nanoha?
A little bit.
I see.
Tia, it’s all right if you want to take a break over there.
I’ll help with the investigation.
After such a big mistake, I don’t want to be slacking off.
Let’s do it together.
Shari?
What's up?
The person with Fate, is that Dr. Yuuno, the archaeologist?
That's right, Dr. Yuuno Scrya.
He manages the Time-Space Administrative Bureau's database
as the Infinity Library's Chief Librarian.
He is also an accomplished archaeologist,
excavating and performing research on ancient ruins.
A Bureau operative and a civilian scholar would be the best way to describe him.
He’s supposedly a childhood friend of Nanoha and Fate.
I see, so the Jewel Seeds were...
They were lent to a facility along the coast from the Bureau’s warehouse.
It seems they were stolen from there.
I see.
Well, we’re investigating their whereabouts.
If I work with Riot Force 6 to pursue them,
we should be able to retrieve them.
Fate, the person you're after, Scaglietti...
But.
When I saw the Jewel Seed, it really took me back.
Even though there was a sad goodbye,
for me,
it was when my life truly began.
Yuuno, Fate!
Nanoha!
Nanoha, perfect timing!
Until Inspector Acous returns,
I was asked to escort Dr. Yuuno.
Can I ask you to switch with me?
Roger.
Erio, Caro, can you come help me observe the scene?
Yes, ma'am!
I'm coming.
Well then, I’ll see you later.
Was today a coincidence?
It seems Inspector Acous knew that
Riot Force 6 would be on guard at the auction.
And well, he asked me to help with the analysis of the objects being auctioned.
Is that so?
It seems your unit is doing well.
It’s thanks to your sister Carim’s protection, Inspector Acous.
It’d be great if I could do anything to help, but...
You're always late or slacking off
but pretty busy generally.
That’s mean!
Carim’s worried, too, about her cute Rossa.
I'm just as worried as she is!
Hayate, you're like a little sister to Carim and me.
Come to think of it, Rossa, are you friends with Yuuno?
When I went to search the Infinity Library one time, he personally showed me around.
It was quite recently.
Right! To all of Riot Force 6's front-line members,
withdrawal preparations are complete.
Please assemble!
Roger!
Good work, everyone.
You can have the afternoon off, okay?
Have something to eat, take a bath, and relax for tomorrow, okay?
Yes, ma'am!
Subaru,
I'm going to go practice on my own for a while.
Self-training? I'll come with you!
Then I'll come too.
Me too!
You were told to take it easy, weren't you?
You two go relax.
And Subaru, sorry, but I want to train by myself.
Fine...
You two, could I have a minute?
Uh, I guess.
Something's been bothering me a bit during training.
Concerning Teana.
I know that all young mages want to get stronger,
and they're usually a bit reckless,
but occasionally she's more than just reckless.
Did something happen to her before she came here?
Tia's older brother?
His ambition was to become an Enforcer. However,
since their parents both died in an accident,
Tia's brother raised her by himself.
But, when he was on a mission...
Did he pass away?
Tia was only ten at the time.
Teana's brother, Tiida Lanster,
a captain in rank,
was part of the Air Armed Service and passed at the age of 21.
He was rather elite, wasn't he?
That's right, he was an elite. That's why,
during the mission where Captain Tiida died,
he managed to injure a wanted mage but
wasn't able to catch him.
Anyway, thanks to a lot of cooperation from the Ground Armed Service,
I heard that he was captured on the same day, but...
After the incident, some heartless superiors made some pretty cruel comments.
It became quite a problem.
Comments such as?
About letting the criminal get away while he was chasing him.
Saying he wasn't worthy of being an Air Armed Service mage, as it was an unacceptable failure.
That he wasted his life by failing to catch the criminal.
Or to be more blunt, saying he was useless for failing the mission. Stuff like that.
Teana was ten at the time.
To lose her only relative,
and to have him deemed worthless and useless
during his final mission,
she was no doubt extremely hurt and saddened.
That's why Tia wants to prove
that the magic her brother taught her isn't useless.
That no matter the place, no matter the mission, she can handle it.
And to realize the dream he left behind,
the dream her brother couldn't realize before he passed,
the dream to become an Enforcer.
That's the reason Tia desperately tries so hard.
You've been at it for four hours already.
You're going to collapse at this rate.
Sergeant Vice.
You were watching?
While I was performing maintenence on the helicopter, I saw something glittering in the scope.
I understand how you're vexed that you missed that shot, but
sharpshooting isn't something
you can become good at with a bit of practice swinging your gun around.
It'd also be bad if you develop bad habits through forced practice.
But hey!
Isn't that what Nanoha was telling you about a while ago?
Nanoha, Siggy, the others, and I all go way back.
Even so, if I don't practice constantly, I won't improve.
I'm just an average person.
An average person, huh?
From my perspective, you're more than good enough.
So much so that I'm jealous.
Well, I don't want to get in your way.
But for people like you, your physical condition is everything.
Take care of yourself, okay?
Thank you very much!
I'll be fine.
Tia!
What, you're still awake?
I'll be getting up at 0400 hours tomorrow.
Sorry if my alarm's noisy.
That's fine, but are you okay?
Tia?
Tia!
Wake up, it's 0400!
Wake up!
Sorry.
I'm up.
Are you going to practice?
I am.
Right! Then here are your training clothes.
Thanks.
Okay then, me too.
Bu—why are you coming too?
You can do more types of training with two people.
I'll come along!
It's okay. I'm fine as it is.
If you come with me, you won't get enough sleep you know.
You should know already.
If it's just our usual routine, I'll be fine even if I don't sleep for four or five days.
This isn't like every day though.
Your training is especially intense. Make sure you get enough sleep.
Don't wanna!
Because we're a team, Tia.
Let's do our best together!
Do what you want!
So, what's this thing you were thinking about, Tia?
For the time being, there's a way to quickly improve our combat abilities.
If we can do it well, our combination attacks will be more versatile and cover a greater area.
Erio and Caro will be able to follow us better too.
That sounds exciting.
Right? First...
Well then, let's keep focusing on individual skills, okay?
It might seem like we're just doing the basics over and over, but you all need to keep at it!
Yes, ma'am!
Teana, Subaru, you two look in a good mood somehow.
Did something happen?
N-no.
Nothing.
Teana! Be more agile!
First, I have to quickly increase the number of skills I can use.
Subaru, perhaps it should move more like this.
Illusion magic can't be my trump card.
And if I can only shoot from mid-range, I won't be able to proceed when that doesn't work.
My main skill will still be sharpshooting. First, last and always.
It's the precision shooting that my brother taught me, but if that's all I can do, then...
I have to keep improving my combat skills and movement.
Sorry for making you do so much work, Cross Mirage.
No problem.
After tomorrow's mock battle is over, I'll ask Shari to give you a full tune-up.
Thank you.
I'm back!
Tia, here.
Thanks.
I wonder if tomorrow's mock battle
will go well.
If it goes well, the success rate is pretty borderline I guess.
If it's that much, I'm sure it'll be fine!
But are you sure you're okay with it?
With what?
In a way, we'll be going against
your hero, Nanoha.
I'm used to being scolded and making other people mad.
Even if it means going against her,
we're doing this to become stronger!
If we fight properly, I'm sure she'll understand.
Because Nanoha is kind.
Well then, tomorrow's early morning special training is our last rehearsal, so go to sleep quickly.
Well then, to conclude the morning, we'll have some 2-on-1 mock battles.
First will be Stars.
Get your Barrier Jackets ready.
Yes, ma'am!
Erio and Caro will be observing with me.
Let's do it, Subaru!
Right!
The mock battle's started already!
Fate!
I thought I was supposed to be helping though.
It's Stars's turn now.
I was going to be in Stars's mock battle.
Nanoha really does try too hard while training sometimes.
If she doesn't get some rest...
Even when Nanoha gets back to our room, she's always looking at the monitors.
Making the training plans, checking everyone's formations on the video...
Nanoha.
All through training, she's always watching out for us.
She really is. Always.
She's using Cross Shift.
Crossfire...
...Shoot
Somehow it doesn't look very refined.
Her control looks good, but...
No, even if that was it...
That's not a fake! It's really her?
Come on, Subaru!
Dangerous maneuvers like that are poor form!
Sorry! But I'll properly defend for it.
Where's Teana?
A bombardment attack? From Teana?
The results of our special training: Cross Shift C!
Let's go, Subaru!
Tia!
The Tia over there is an illusion?
Then where's the real one?
I'll pierce her barrier and then break through her field.
It'll take her out in one hit!
Raising Heart.
Mode release.
All right.
Nanoha!
It's strange.
You two, what happened to you?
I know you're trying your best,
but a mock battle isn't a brawl.
If you're just pretending to listen during practice
and then acting so recklessly during the real thing,
then training has no meaning, does it?
Let's do it properly, like we do in practice.
Okay?
What I'm asking is,
is my training
really that wrong?
Blade erase.
I just don't want anyone to get hurt anymore!
I don't want to lose anyone anymore!
Tia.
That's why I want to get stronger!
Why don't you cool your head a bit?
Crossfire...
Phantom Bla—
...Shoot
Tia!
A bind?
Stay still and watch.
Nanoha!
Tia!
The mock battle ends here.
Today, the two of you have been shot down.
Without end, the dreams continue to weave
Surpassing thousands of nights
Like a prayer, the journey continues
Be my guide any day, oh small jewel
Spica among the stars
I engrave beyond the horizon
The faint footsteps that are connected to everywhere
The reflection of your eyes casts away the loop of anxiety
The midnight sun
The Orion of Midsummer
Just now from somewhere, I heard your voice
This heart without darkness
Illumine it, o distant blue star
No matter what the time, I will be able to start walking
Sparkling far and near
Watching over me
The thing inside my heart, overflowing
More than tears, I want to be loved
Like a prayer, the journey continues
Be my guide anyday, oh small jewel
Spica among the stars
Next
Episode
Preview
Next
Episode
Preview
The things
we want to convey.
The meaning of courage.
Most importantly, the things we should protect.
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS:
Episode 9: A Precious Thing
Episode 9
A Precious Thing
Until the day each can grasp their own sky.