After days and days of training,
I gave them a full day off to take a breather.
Time for them to spend as friends and as partners.
Time to refresh ourselves,
so that we can do our best tomorrow.
But that day off came to a halt due to a sudden emergency.
A small girl appeared, carrying a Relic case.
The case is quietly set in motion.
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS
will now begin.
The hot comet dwelling within my heart beats towards the beginning.
My fingers tremble, grasping upon a silent wish
I cower, wanting to flee from the inescapable past
Even if it is merely a faint light fading
I want to chase after it, just like that star
And accept everything, no matter how high it is
Dancing throughout the galaxy is the angel's whisper
Pursuing these certain memories
The door to the truth will surely be born now
No matter what kind of cold darkness binds me
Because I want to know
I won't be stopped
Episode 11
Riot Force 6's Day Off
(part 2)
Church of the Holy King, Headquarters
But really, it's an interesting sight
seeing you in uniform.
Admiral, Time-Space Administrative Bureau Dimensional Navy
Captain of the flagship Claudia, sponsor of Riot Force 6
Chrono Harlaown
Admiral, Time-Space Administrative Bureau Dimensional Navy
Captain of the flagship Claudia, sponsor of Riot Force 6
Chrono Harlaown
Everyone tells me I look silly in uniform,
even my wife.
Not at all!
You look as good as you do in your armor, Admiral Chrono.
Thank you, Knight Carim.
Excuse me.
Signum. Welcome back.
Is the joint investigation conference over?
Yes. Everything's going splendidly.
We just finished discussing the logistical side of Riot Force 6.
We were just about to discuss the missions for here on out.
You should stay and listen as well, okay?
Yes, ma'am.
A direct call from Hayate?
Erio! Caro!
Subaru! Tia!
Is this her?
She's quite a mess.
I believe she's walked a long distance through the sewers.
But she's so small!
She is.
Did you seal the case?
Caro did.
There's no chance a Gadget will find it, I believe.
And this.
There was another case?
I'm having the Long Arch look into it.
The captains and Dr. Shamal, as well as Command Sergeant Major Rein, are heading here right now.
For now, we need to secure the area and keep an eye on it.
Yes, ma'am!
I see. A Relic.
The fact that a small girl was carrying it worries me.
If that summoner or any Gadgets show up, we'll have an urban battle on our hands.
We need to get this matter settled as quickly as possible.
Have you already contacted the other forces in the area?
Yes. I contacted the City and Coastal Forces.
We may need to get our trump card ready as well.
I pray that doesn't happen.
Signum, you should return.
Yes, ma'am.
If Schach sees you off, you can get back right away.
Thank you very much, Knight Carim.
Her physical condition is stable.
There are no dangerous readings either.
There's no need to worry.
Good.
What a relief!
I'm sorry, everyone, that this happened during your break.
Not at all.
We're all right.
We'll take the case and the girl back via helicopter.
Everyone else, inspect the scene.
Yes, ma'am!
Nanoha, would you carry her to the helicopter?
Sure.
The Gadgets are here!
They're coming through the sewer in small groups. There are 16—no, 20 of them in all!
And over the sea, there are five groups of twelve!
That's a lot.
What should we do?
Let me think.
Stars 2 to Long Arch.
This is Stars 2.
I was practicing over the ocean.
Major Nakajima gave me permission.
I'm heading to the scene now.
Along with one other.
Ginga Nakajima of the 108th Battalion.
I was investigating another incident,
but it may have something to do with what you're investigating.
May I participate?
Yes, please.
Okay, Vita, meet up with Rein.
Cooperate and gain control of the southwest area of the sea.
Southwest area, roger.
Captain Nanoha and Captain Fate,
start with the northeast.
Roger.
Can I leave the helicopter to you and Shamal, Vice?
Leave it to me.
We'll protect it.
Ginga, meet up with Subaru's group underground.
Along the way, tell me about this other incident.
Yes, ma'am.
Now then, everyone, I hope you enjoyed your break.
Time to get to work! Let's go kick ass!
Yes!
Stand by.
Set up!
Have the forwards become a little more reliable?
We need them to become even more reliable.
Let's finish up this incident and give them another day off.
If we all enjoyed ourselves together,
it would be a lot of fun.
Yep.
Be careful, okay?
I totes will!
Sergeant Vice, please take care of things!
Yes!
Storm Raider, keep them safe, okay?
All right, my friend.
My sisters will get the material and the case in the helicopter.
Miss, head underground.
Where are Knight Zest and Agito?
They are elsewhere.
So you're alone?
I am not alone.
I have Garyuu.
Pardon me.
If you need help, contact me.
I'll make it my highest priority.
Let us go, Garyuu.
To find what we're looking for.
Stars 1 and Lightning 1 are heading toward the scene.
They will engage within one minute.
Stars 2 has joined up with Command Sergeant Major Rein.
The forwards are heading toward the Gadgets' destination.
If they keep up this pace,
we'll get the jump on them.
Ginga, it's been a while.
Yeah. So Teana, you're in command here, right?
Would you give me orders?
I will.
For now, head to area F94 in the southwest.
We'll meet up with you along the way.
F94.
Roger.
Ginga is your sister, right, Subaru?
Yes. She taught me shooting arts. She's two years older and two ranks higher than me.
Ginga,
We can keep in touch and coordinate our movements with our Devices.
Are you ready?
Blitz Caliber, I'm counting on you.
Yes, sir.
Stars 1 and Lightning 1 have engaged.
What I found at the scene of the accident that I was called to
was a bunch of destroyed Gadgets and a broken life pod.
One just big enough for a child of five or six.
There were marks nearby as if somebody was dragging something heavy.
I was following them when you contacted me.
Also, I have seen something very similar to this life pod in another case.
Me too.
The primary cultivation body called for in the Artificial Mage Project.
This is just a guess, but that girl was perhaps created as material for an artificial mage.
Artificial mage?
Children fabricated from high-quality genetic material
who receive injections and cybernetic implants,
to produce the possibility of giving them powerful magical abilities.
That's an artificial mage.
Ethics aside, there are many insurmountable problems using current technology,
and the cost just isn't worth it.
But if someone was out of his mind,
he wouldn't bother...
A movement reaction perception,
at the Gadget Drone.
Incoming! Six small Gadgets!
Stars 1 and Lightning 1 have taken out group 2.
It's going well.
Stars 2 and Command Sergeant Major Rein have taken out group 1.
Alright! It's going well.
I'm doing great too!
Let's keep going.
We need to beat them quickly and help the others.
Yes indeedy!
Why, that's...!
Reinforcements?
This signal.
Quattro's Inherent Skill: Silver Curtain.
These lies and illusions are going to make you dance for me.
The signals in the air are multiplying.
This is impossible!
What is this?
Waveform check!
It has to be a computer error, right?
There are no problems in the system.
All checks show them to be real units!
Nanoha's team says they have a visual on them too!
Griffith!
Yes, ma'am.
The formations are composed of illusory and real units.
I'm pretty sure we can keep them from breaking through the defensive line,
but there sure are a lot of them.
If they're going this far, it would mean...
Their main forces are heading for the helicopter or underground.
Nanoha, I'll stay here and take care of them. You go with Vita.
Fate!
Even together, if we fight normally, it'll take too much time.
If I release my limiter, I can use a wide-area spell to destroy all of them.
That's true, but...
I've got a bad feeling about this.
But Fate...
Sorry to intrude.
Lightning 1, this is the Long Arch.
As commander, belay that plan and the release of your limiter.
Hayate!
Hayate, why are you in your Knight's Armor?
I have a bad feeling too.
I've decided to ask Chrono for permission to release my limiter.
I'll take care of these.
Nanoha, Fate, get back to land, and defend the helicopter.
Vita and Rein, you meet up with the forwards.
Help them secure the case.
Roger.
Right now, Knight Carim and I can only grant you permission to release your limiter once apiece.
It's hard to get that renewed.
Are you sure you want to use it?
I don't want to reserve power that I could have used and regret it later.
Considering your location, I cannot grant you permission for SS rank.
I can only release three ranks. Will that suffice?
S rank?
That's more than enough.
Hayate Yagami, limiter release for three ranks has been approved.
Release time, 120 minutes.
Limiter release!
It might be a little easier to get permission renewed since it's not a full release, right?
Not really.
HQ is really strict about its ground forces.
Well, then...
This will be the first time I've used long-range attack magic in a while.
Seems like they're having some trouble above.
We're almost at the case's location.
Ginny!
Ginga!
Let's look for the case together.
I think I've finished off most of the Gadgets on the way here.
Aw yeah!
This is Long Arch 1, Shario, to Long Arch 0, Commander Yagami.
Yes?
The Sighting Support System is ready.
We've finished compensating for Schwertkreuz's synchronization error.
Roger.
Sorry to bother you with this.
Without Rein, I'm a total klutz with long-range sighting and accurate firing.
Leave that to us.
We're all ready.
Thanks.
Come forth, the wind of snow, and become the fletching which falls from the heavens.
Stars 1 and Lightning 1 have both evacuated to a safe area.
Impact area's safety confirmed.
Okay, here comes the first wave!
Hræsvelgr
Hræsvelgr, first wave fired.
Firing arc okay.
About to hit Group E.
Five, four...
Three, two...
One, zero.
Group E destroyed.
Next, Group B. Impact.
Destroyed. And A too!
Second wave fired.
Shari, calculate the discrimination pattern
for the real units and the false ones with the data from their destruction.
If there are any clues, we'll be able to find them.
I'll find them!
Fried!
Subaru, can you finish it with a single blow?
I can!
Are you ready?
Yes.
Okay, follow me.
Right!
Here we go, partner!
Load Cartridge
Tri-Shield
Divine...
...Buster
I found it!
What's that sound?
Erio!
You're in the way.
Caro!
Hey!
Hey, girl!
That's dangerous!
Don't touch that!
Give it here!
Sorry to play rough.
But this really is something dangerous.
Lulu.
Close your eyes on the count of three.
Ready?
One.
Two.
Starling's Howl
Starengeheul
Geez! This is what you get for going out without telling us.
Lulu, you and Garyuu too.
Agito.
I was really worried.
Well, it's okay now, Lulu.
After all, I, Sword Faerie of the Raging Fire,
Agito is finally here!
Come on, all of you, bring it on!
Without end, the dreams continue to weave
Surpassing thousands of nights
Like a prayer, the journey continues
Be my guide any day, oh small jewel
Spica among the stars
I engrave beyond the horizon
The faint footsteps that are connected to everywhere
The reflection of your eyes casts away the loop of anxiety
The midnight sun
The Orion of Midsummer
Just now from somewhere, I heard your voice
This heart without darkness
Illumine it, o distant blue star
No matter what the time, I will be able to start walking
Sparkling far and near
Watching over me
The thing inside my heart, overflowing
More than tears, I want to be loved
Like a prayer, the journey continues
Be my guide anyday, oh small jewel
Spica among the stars
Next
Episode
Preview
Next
Episode
Preview
A new shadow appears, and our uneasiness continues.
No matter what shows up, no matter who comes, I'll get through it and protect everyone.
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS:
Episode 12: Numbers
Episode 12
Numbers
Take off!