A new place where I belong.
A place that has the kind people I love.
But something inside me is still hesitating.
I’m sure it’s because I’m scared of myself.
Together with my combat partners, and my seniors who give it their best,
I’m sure they wish for the same things I do because they're kind.
I can’t hesitate anymore since I have decided on this path that I’ll be walking.
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS
will now begin.
The hot comet dwelling within my heart beats towards the beginning.
My fingers tremble, grasping upon a silent wish
I cower, wanting to flee from the inescapable past
Even if it is merely a faint light fading
I want to chase after it, just like that star
And accept everything, no matter how high it is
Dancing throughout the galaxy is the angel's whisper
Pursuing these certain memories
The door to the truth will surely be born now
No matter what kind of cold darkness binds me
Because I want to know
I won't be stopped
Dragon summoner of Alzus, child of Lushe, Caro!
At only the age of six, to have a Flying Silver Dragon,
You've accepted the fate of the dark energy's swirling current.
You are indeed a wonderful dragon summoner.
However, a power too strong will lead to nothing but conflict and despair.
We are sorry. You can stay in this village no longer.
Dragon summoners hold a dangerous power.
A frightening power
that can hurt people.
Episode 5
Stars and Lightning
The target railcar is travelling at a velocity of 70 units and rising.
It seems they haven't penetrated the important-goods container yet.
It’s just a matter of time.
Alto, Lucino, perform a smart scan!
Search towards the sky!
Gadget responses? From the sky?
Aerial types appear to be coming to aid local units!
This is Fate. Griffith, I’ve just arrived at a parking lot.
I’ll park the car and go to the scene. Please give me flight clearance.
Roger. City airspace has been closed for the rest of the morning: clearance approved.
Vice, I’m going too.
Along with Captain Fate, the two of us will clear the sky.
Okay! Nanoha, please do!
Main hatch, open.
Well then, I’ll be going out for a while.
Everyone, do your best, and beat them decisively!
Yes, ma'am!
Caro.
It’s okay. You don’t need to be so nervous.
Even if we're apart, we are connected through comms. So you're not alone.
If you get into trouble, I’ll save you.
Caro, your magic can protect everyone.
It’s a strong, gentle power, right?
Get set.
Bardiche Assault.
Set up!
Set up.
Barrier Jacket: Impulse Form
Let’s go, Bardiche.
Yes, sir.
Lightning 1, Fate Testarossa-Harlaown,
heading out!
Standby, ready.
Raising Heart.
Set up!
Barrier Jacket: Aggressor Mode
Accel Fin
Stars 1, Nanoha Takamachi, heading out!
There are two objectives: destroy all enemy gadgets to prevent their escape, and safely secure the Relic.
Therefore, Stars Squad and Lightning Squad,
In your pairs, proceed to destroy gadgets from both ends of the railcar
and rendezvous at the center car.
The Relic is here, within the No. 7
important-goods container.
Stars or Lightning, whoever arrives first, will secure the Relic.
Yes, ma'am!
And!
I’ll also be at the scene to observe and give commands.
Stars 1, Lightning 1, engaging.
We’ll cover the airspace here. Please follow the new recruits.
Roger.
It’s been a while since we’ve been in the same sky, hasn’t it, Fate?
Yeah, Nanoha.
Accel Shooter
Haken Form
Well then, newbies!
Thanks to your captains establishing air superiority, we've made it to the drop point safely.
Are you ready?
Yes, sir!
Stars 3, Subaru Nakajima!
Stars 4, Teana Lanster!
Heading out!
Let’s go, Mach Caliber.
I'm counting on you, Cross Mirage.
Set up!
Standby, ready.
Lightning, you're next!
You kids be careful!
Yes, sir!
Do you want to go together?
Yes!
Lightning 3, Erio Mondial!
Lightning 4, Caro Ru Lushe and Friedrich!
Heading out!
Strada!
Kerykeion!
Set up!
Hey, this Jacket is...
Don’t tell me!
Their design and capabilities are modelled after each squad's captain.
They might be a bit uncommon, but they're highly efficient.
Subaru, you can be impressed later!
Drive Ignition
Variable Barret
Shoot!
Absorb Grip
Revolver...
...Shoot
Wingroad
Mach Caliber, you're—are you really that amazing?
Your acceleration and grip control, for example, and even making a Wingroad!
Because I was made to make you
run stronger and faster.
But, Mach Caliber, you have an AI or soul, right?
Then that seems a little wrong.
You were born so you could run together with me.
I feel it the same way.
That's just all kinds of not right!
I’ll think about it.
Teana, how's the situation looking?
It’s looking bad! Destroying the cables has no effect.
Roger. I’ll take over stopping the train.
Teana, please regroup with Subaru.
Roger!
One-Hand Mode
But still, it's as expected of the newest model.
Convenient for many things, you can even support with squad management, can’t you?
Yes. Was it unnecessary?
Relying on someone as good as you doesn't go down well with me,
but it helps in live combat.
Thank you.
Stars F, advancing at car number 4.
Lightning F, currently in combat at car number 10.
Stars 1, Lightning 1 have gained air superiority.
Gadgets Type 2 are scattering.
Commencing support and pursuit.
Sorry for the long wait.
Commander Yagami!
Welcome back.
So far, everything has proceeded smoothly.
Lightning F has infiltrated car number 8.
Encounter! It's the new model!
Fried!
Blast Flare
Fire!
It's tough!
An AMF?
Even this far away?
Don’t worry! Leave it to me.
She certainly does have some tremendous powers,
but she can’t control them very well.
Even with her dragon summoning,
the dragon that’s supposed to protect her has just been running wild.
It’s more than awful:
she honestly can’t work in any units.
At most she can handle solo missions for annihilation.
That’s enough.
Thank you.
Well then.
No, as I already planned, I’ll take her into my care.
Where do I have to go this time?
That depends on where you want to go and what you want to do.
Caro, where do you want to go, and what do you want to do?
I’d never even thought about it.
In front of me were always places I couldn’t go and things I couldn’t do... nothing else.
Erio.
Erio!
Lightning 4 jumped off!
Wait, those two, to jump off and attempt rescue at that height...
No, she's doing that.
I see!
That's right! If you get away from the source, the AMF will weaken.
She can use her magic's full performance!
I want to protect them.
The kind people.
The people who smile at me.
With my own power,
I want to protect them!
Drive Ignition
Fried, sorry for keeping you sealed.
I’ll control you properly.
Let’s go!
Summoning dragon spirit!
White spirit that traverses the blue sky,
become my wings to reach the skies above!
Come forth, my dragon Friedrich. 'Tis the time!
Summoning Dragon Spirit
Summoning successful!
Fried’s consciousness level is blue!
State is completely under control.
This is...!
That’s right, Caro’s dragon summoning, her greatest power.
That's...!
That little dragon’s true form?
Sweet!
S-sorry!
Me too.
Those two won’t need rescuing anymore.
Well then, let’s retrieve the Relic.
Fried!
Blast Ray
Fire!
It’s tough after all.
Because of that field’s source,
bombardment attacks won’t have any effect.
Strada and I will do it.
O sword of justice, heed my faithful cry.
Bestow your blessed light on this knight's lance.
Enchant: Field Invade
O light of prayer, grant strength unto thy arms.
Boost Up: Strike Power
Let’s go, Erio.
Roger, Caro!
Twin Boost: Slash & Strike
Received.
Empfang.
Steel Knife
Stahlmesser
Explosion
Flash Hit
We did it!
No Gadget responses on the train or anywhere else. They’ve all been destroyed!
Stars F, we've safely secured the Relic.
The train is under control as well. Stopping it now!
Well, while you're at it, why don't you and the three Stars board the helicopter,
and then continue to escort the Relic all the way to the central region.
Yes indeedy!
What about Lightning?
Stand by at the scene, and let the operatives deal with the cleanup.
I'll leave it to you.
Serial No. IX has entered the convoy.
Shall we issue a pursuit order?
Let's not. I want the Relic,
but to have been able to just take the girls' data was more than enough.
Even so, these subjects are wonderful, as expected.
On top of being items of great interest for my research,
these children,
living and breathing remnants of Project F,
To have a chance of obtaining them!
Without end, the dreams continue to weave
Surpassing thousands of nights
Like a prayer, the journey continues
Be my guide any day, oh small jewel
Spica among the stars
I engrave beyond the horizon
The faint footsteps that are connected to everywhere
The reflection of your eyes casts away the loop of anxiety
The midnight sun
The Orion of Midsummer
Just now from somewhere, I heard your voice
This heart without darkness
Illumine it, o distant blue star
No matter what the time, I will be able to start walking
Sparkling far and near
Watching over me
The thing inside my heart, overflowing
More than tears, I want to be loved
Like a prayer, the journey continues
Be my guide anyday, oh small jewel
Spica among the stars
Next
Episode
Preview
Next
Episode
Preview
Following our
first deployment,
our daily training
has been kicked up a notch.
And the incident is being unveiled little by little from the battlefield.
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS:
Episode 6
Development
Episode 6: Development
Take off!