I couldn't forgive myself for my failure.
That's why I wanted to become stronger.
But in the end, I wasn't able to do anything.
I was scolded for my mistake,
and I'm sure I've let them down.
I caused trouble for my partner who runs by my side and gave her a painful memory.
The things that I've done, the paths I've chosen...
They all were useless.
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS
will now begin.
The hot comet dwelling within my heart beats towards the beginning.
My fingers tremble, grasping upon a silent wish
I cower, wanting to flee from the inescapable past
Even if it is merely a faint light fading
I want to chase after it, just like that star
And accept everything, no matter how high it is
Dancing throughout the galaxy is the angel's whisper
Pursuing these certain memories
The door to the truth will surely be born now
No matter what kind of cold darkness binds me
Because I want to know
I won't be stopped
What the...?
Oh, Teana, you're awake?
Dr. Shamal.
This is the infirmary.
Do you remember that you were shot down during the mock battle this afternoon?
Yes.
Nanoha's training magic missiles are well made, so they shouldn't have done any damage to your body.
Are you hurt anywhere?
No, I'm all right.
It's past nine!
At night?
You were sleeping very well.
So well that I almost thought you were dead.
You haven't had much sleep lately, have you?
All the stress you've accumulated has caught up with you.
Episode 9
A Precious Thing
Nanoha?
Fate.
Teana woke up a little while ago.
She came to the office with Subaru to apologize.
I see.
I told them you were at the training grounds
and they should talk to you first thing tomorrow morning.
Thank you.
But I'm sorry.
Because of my incompetent supervision, I got you, Fate, and even the two from Lightning involved.
I don't mind.
How did Teana and Subaru look?
They looked like they were still in a bit of a bad mood, as expected.
Well, I'll make sure to talk to them tomorrow morning—to all the forwards.
Type 2 Gadget Drones have appeared over the eastern ocean!
There are twelve units this time.
They're flying in a circular pattern.
Any Relic responses?
At this point, there are no responses in the vicinity.
However, this is...
The targets' speed is a little bit...
no, much faster than the ones before!
My, this is unusual.
I am delighted that you're contacting me.
What happened to Zest and Agito?
They're on a separate operation right now.
It seems some of your toys are flying in the distant sky, Doctor.
Soon, you should be able to see some beautiful fireworks.
Relics?
If there were, I would have reported to you from the start.
This is just a performance test of my toys.
I want to gather some data on how they get destroyed.
They're getting destroyed?
I'm not expecting these scraps of metal to become a force instantly.
They're just junk I'm using as decoys, so that my work can shine more brilliantly.
I see. If it's not a Relic,
then it has nothing to do with me.
However, try your best, Doctor.
Thank you, my sweet Lutecia.
Well then, good day.
My works are indeed well made.
Out of the Type 2 aerial units, there are three groups of four and one group of twelve.
There are no changes since the they were discovered:
each group is flying in its own low, circular pattern.
They're located over the sea in the middle of nowhere.
There are no signs of a Relic, nor of any
maritime facilities or boats, within the vicinity.
It's as if they're asking us to shoot them down.
Indeed. Enforcer Testarossa-Harlaown, what do you make of this?
If the culprit is Scaglietti, then he probably wants to see what move we'll make to test our aerial forces.
In this situation, we can finish them off by throwing an extreme-range attack at them.
One blast would do it!
Yes, but that's precisely why we shouldn't show our hand.
Realistically speaking,
we can't really lift the captains' limiters for something at this level, anyway.
Instructor Takamachi, what about you?
If the intent is to investigate our military forces,
we should prevent them from attaining any new information
and take care of them the way we always have, right?
We'll go with that then.
As it's an aerial fight this time, the three of us, Captain Fate, Lt. Vita, and myself, will sortie.
The rest of you will be on standby in the lobby.
Signum will be taking command there.
Guard the place while we're gone.
Yes, ma'am!
Yes, ma'am.
Oh, and Teana?
Teana, I think I'll dismiss you for the day.
I think that's a good decision. You're dismissed.
After all, your physical condition and magical powers aren't at their best tonight.
Someone who won't listen to you
is someone you can't use, right?
You said it yourself, and you still don't understand?
That much is obvious.
I've been obeying orders at the scene, and I haven't been slacking off during training either.
Even outside of combat and training,
does the amount of effort I put in have to be exactly as you dictate?
I'm not an elite like you and the other officers, Nanoha!
I don't have the same amount of talent as Subaru and Erio, nor do I have a Rare Skill like Caro.
Even if it means I'm going to push myself,
I'm not going to get stronger unless I work like I'm going to die!
Signum?
Signum!
Don't worry, I held back.
Pessimistic fools will only drag you down if you keep putting up with them.
Vice, are you ready to go?
I'm ready as soon as we have you guys on board!
Teana, you seem like you're a bit worked up at the moment, but let's have a talk once I'm back!
I'm telling you to stop spoiling her!
Erio, Caro, sorry, but please look after them.
Yes, ma'am!
We'll try our best.
What an eyesore! Stop behaving like a spoiled child and return to your quarters.
Lt. Signum, I think that's enough.
Subaru, let's head to the lobby for now.
Lt. Signum.
What is it?
I think it's definitely wrong to disobey orders,
and when I think back to how Tia was acting,
I think it was wrong of me to not stop her.
But,
is it really so bad
to try to become stronger by your own means and to try your hardest in a tough situation?
Striving to do your best in your own way—is that also something that shouldn't be done?
Training in your own time is a good thing, and striving to become stronger is also a good thing.
Shari?
Weren't you on duty?
Command Sergeant Major Rein is in charge of operations right now.
It just looked like everyone was being so awkward,
and I couldn't stand seeing you all like this.
Everyone, would you gather in the lobby?
I'll explain everything about Nanoha and the meaning behind her training.
Once upon a time,
there was a girl. She was just an ordinary girl who knew nothing about magic,
and who wasn't the type who would get into a fight.
She went to school with her friends and was living happily with her family.
She was bound to live the rest of her life like that.
However, there was an incident.
She didn't attend any kind of school for magic,
nor did she have special skills.
She obtained magical power from an accidental encounter,
and it just so happened that she had great capacity.
And she was only a nine-year-old girl.
Only a few months after she acquired magic,
she was thrown into real combat that put her life at stake.
Is that...?
Fate?
Fate was going through some complications with her family at the time.
They were fighting each other over a particular Lost Logia.
The central figure in this incident was Testarossa's mother.
The incident, named after her,
is called the Presea Testarossa Incident.
Also known as the Jewel Seed Incident.
A convergent bombardment? That large?
By a nine-year-old?
A massive power bombardment puts a lot of strain on the body.
And then, shortly after that, the battle continued for her.
An incident we were deeply involved in,
the Book of Darkness Incident.
She came close to getting shot down in an assault and was defeated.
What she chose to overcome that
was to use the Cartridge System, even though its safety was still questionable at the time.
The Full Drive mode ignores the strain it puts on the body
and forcefully generates magic that surpasses her limit.
Excelion Mode.
In order to save people and to get her will across,
Nanoha continued to push herself.
704 has arrived in the destination airspace.
Lightning 1, Stars 2, engage.
Okay, Nanoha, take care.
Thanks, Vice.
Let's go, Raising Heart.
All right, my master.
This is Stars 1, assistance with mid-range shots, coming up!
Roger!
However, there was no way that repeating such acts wouldn't take its toll on her body.
There was an accident during the second winter after she entered the Bureau.
It happened while she was returning from an investigation mission
on another world with Vita and some others.
An unidentified object appeared suddenly.
It was an opponent that Nanoha wouldn't have had any problems protecting her allies from
or destroying if she were her usual self.
But the stress that she had been under
and the way she kept pushing herself made Nanoha slightly less capable.
The result was this.
Nanoha apologized to us for pushing herself too far and kept smiling in front of us, but
having been told that she might not be able to walk again, let alone be able to fly...
I can't imagine how she must have felt.
There are battles that must not be lost, even if it means being reckless or even risking your life.
However, the time when you missed that shot,
was that a situation where you had to shoot,
even if it meant risking the safety or life of your comrade?
Using a move like that during training,
just whose sake was that for?
What was it for?
Nanoha doesn't want any of you to go through what she did.
So that you don't have to push yourself,
and to be absolutely, positively sure that you come back safe and sound,
She has been training you with care,
thinking about your safety the whole time.
Vita, take care of that last one!
Of course!
Let's go, Eisen! Form II!
Explosion
Rocket Form
Raketenform
Rocket Hammer
Raketenhammer
Stars 2 shot down the twenty-fourth unit.
All targets have now been destroyed.
No reinforcements detected.
Contact the nearby maritime observation units to collect the remains.
Roger!
It seems there's no need for them to be on standby there, so can we have the three return?
Yes, and we can dismiss the forward unit too.
I-I'm sorry!
Shari, you shouldn't talk about other people's pasts without asking first.
It's not good for women to be too talkative, you know.
Well, you know, I just couldn't stand watching them.
Well, they would have found out about it sooner or later.
Shari, do you know where Teana is right now?
She's probably...
I heard a lot from Shari and Lt. Signum.
A record of Nanoha's failures?
That's not what...!
About how it's dangerous to act so recklessly, right?
I'm really sorry.
Well, now that you understand, I'll comment about it a bit.
You know, Teana, you call yourself mediocre
and say you can't do anything but shooting and illusion spells.
But you know that's not true.
You and the others are like ore right now, Teana.
You have a lot of rough edges,
and it's hard to tell what your true values are.
But as you polish up, you'll start seeing parts that shine.
Erio has his speed.
Caro has her gentle support spells.
Subaru has her explosive power at short range.
And you, Teana, who leads the other three, can protect them with your shooting and illusion spells
and can get through any situation with your courage and wits.
That's an ideal team, and it's slowly starting to form.
During the mock battle,
didn't you notice when you were shot?
When shooting spells are used properly, Teana,
they're incredibly hard to evade and really hurt when they hit.
You ignored your most important aspect and rushed to do something else.
That's why something like that happened.
That's what I wanted to teach you.
Then again, your line of thought wasn't completely wrong either.
System limiter: test mode release.
Yes.
Try commanding him into Mode II.
Mode II
Set up. Dagger Mode.
This is...
Teana, you plan to become an Enforcer, right?
After you leave here and pursue your path to become an Enforcer,
you'll end up fighting one-on-one battles.
I had this prepared, with your future in mind.
I was thinking of training you on both close- and long-range combat for a while now.
But there's always the possibility that we'll sortie anytime, right?
So I wanted to make sure you're confident with the skill you excel at the most now.
But my training is a bit dull,
so you felt you weren't accomplishing much and having a tough time, weren't you?
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry!
Good morning!
Morning.
Good morning.
Were you able to sleep well?
Yes, ma'am.
You're aware that high-level mages with excellent combat skills are referred to as Aces, right?
But do you know of another term used to refer to an excellent mage?
If one of those is present, it's possible to get through even the toughest situation.
It's possible to overcome even the most intense situation.
With that kind of reliance, one is called by this name:
Striker.
Since the start of your training,
Nanoha has been saying,
"The four that we have, all of them should be able to become first-class Strikers."
"So I'll train them very strictly,
but carefully and thoroughly too."
Instructors have a hard time of things, don't they?
Even if you train them during difficult times,
they still end up going their own ways afterwards.
Well, it's a bit sad that we can only spend a short amount of time together.
I can't look after them forever.
So while I can be with them, I want to teach them as many things as I can.
Good morning!
Oh, you guys are here.
Morning.
Did you sleep well?
Yes, ma'am!
All right, I'm gonna train you hard again today!
No matter what happens,
no matter who comes around,
I'm not going to let anyone shoot them down.
Not only while they're around me, but when the time comes for them to fly on their own as well.
Well, let's put everything into our morning training!
Yes, ma'am!
Without end, the dreams continue to weave
Surpassing thousands of nights
Like a prayer, the journey continues
Be my guide any day, oh small jewel
Spica among the stars
I engrave beyond the horizon
The faint footsteps that are connected to everywhere
The reflection of your eyes casts away the loop of anxiety
The midnight sun
The Orion of Midsummer
Just now from somewhere, I heard your voice
This heart without darkness
Illumine it, o distant blue star
No matter what the time, I will be able to start walking
Sparkling far and near
Watching over me
The thing inside my heart, overflowing
More than tears, I want to be loved
Like a prayer, the journey continues
Be my guide anyday, oh small jewel
Spica among the stars
Next
Episode
Preview
Next
Episode
Preview
Ordinary days have returned
with good news
for the forwards.
All four of them are getting a day off!
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS:
Episode 10: Riot Force 6's Day Off (part 1)
Episode 10
Riot Force 6's Day Off
(part 1)
To a fun day off!
Take off!