As expected, the first battle was a series of close calls. However,
the children who have started to walk are running on their own.
For now, they lock their hesitations within their hearts.
From now on, they will continue fighting together as a team.
Together with their partners and their comrades, they’ll face the upcoming battles head-on.
At many different places, they'll fight many different battles.
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS
will now begin.
The hot comet dwelling within my heart beats towards the beginning.
My fingers tremble, grasping upon a silent wish
I cower, wanting to flee from the inescapable past
Even if it is merely a faint light fading
I want to chase after it, just like that star
And accept everything, no matter how high it is
Dancing throughout the galaxy is the angel's whisper
Pursuing these certain memories
The door to the truth will surely be born now
No matter what kind of cold darkness binds me
Because I want to know
I won't be stopped
Episode 6
Development
Our debut was May 13, the unit's first emergency deployment.
A Lost Logia was being transported along a smuggling route.
A Relic was discovered by Gadgets that had attacked the Linear Rail carrying it.
The mission was to obstruct them and recover the Relic.
Due to the actions of each of Riot Force 6’s members at the time, the problem was safely resolved.
The recovered Serial No. IX Relic is now protected and being investigated in the Central Laboratory.
Our first mission was more or less problem-free and a good start,
according to Commander Hayate and Riot Force 6's superiors,
Knight Carim and Admiral Chrono, who seemed to be satisfied...
Command Sergeant Major Rein.
Shari!
Are you on your break?
Half on break, half working.
I was writing my personal service log.
I see.
What about you, Shari?
I just got back from checking the condition of the new Devices at the training grounds.
Is that so? Is everyone doing well?
Yes. The forwards and the Devices couldn't be any better!
All right, here I come!
Mach Caliber!
Protection
That hurts.
I see. Your barrier strength doesn't seem to be that bad after all.
Thank you very much.
My position, like yours, is the front attacker.
Cutting through enemy lines unaided and leading the defensive line is our duty.
With greater defensive and survival capabilities,
you can attack longer and won’t require help from support units.
Nanoha has taught you this, correct?
Yes, Lt. Vita.
Barrier magic to nullify hits,
shield magic to repel them,
and field magic to surround yourself for protection.
Learn to master these three types.
And to avoid being pushed back,
work on your lower body stance and learn to utilize Mach Caliber.
I’ll do my best!
I'll learn.
Attacks that crush defenses are my specialty.
So unless you want to get smashed by Graf Eisen, you'd better defend well.
Yes, ma'am!
Erio and Caro, you aren’t as sturdy as Subaru and Vita.
Therefore, reaction and evasion are most important.
For example.
In this way, like this.
Firstly, move around so they cannot aim.
If you are somewhere exposed to attack,
don’t stay there long.
Got it?
Yes, ma'am!
If you can do this perfectly at a slow pace,
we'll increase the speed.
Something like this, okay?
A-Amazing.
That was a basic move that anyone can do with practice, just done very quickly.
Yes, ma'am!
At faster speeds, relying solely on your intuition while moving becomes dangerous.
Erio, as a guard wing, you should be able to attack and support from any position.
Caro, as a full back, you should be able to move swiftly and aid your comrades.
Make sure you learn the basics of effective evasion.
Yes, ma'am!
That’s good, Teana.
Just like that.
Yes, ma'am!
Shooter-types like you, Teana,
who have to stand upright mustn't dodge and defend against every attack,
or they can’t do their job.
Barret!
Left: V. Right: RF.
Alert!
Look, if you move like that you’ll never be able to stop guarding.
Barret V & RF
Yes, that’s it!
Stand firmly and widen your field of vision.
What’s the essence of being a marksman?
To select the correct bullet for your opponent and strike them down.
Quick judgment and accurate shooting!
Reload
To stand in the middle of the team and engage in mid-to-long-range battles faster than anyone.
Teana, that's the duty of our position, the center guard.
Yes, ma'am!
They're really into it, aren't they?
Their first deployment seems to have been good motivation for them.
Isn’t it nice for the young ones.
They may be young, but they are developing quickly.
It’ll still be a bit dangerous for a while.
That’s for sure.
Siggy, you aren’t going to participate?
It’s because I’m an old-style knight.
Unlike Subaru and Erio who use Mid-style or Modern Belkan, I work differently.
And wielding but a sword, I have nothing to teach rear-line fighters like Teana and Caro.
Not to mention, I’ve never been one to teach others.
The only tactic I could teach them is how to get within range and slice the enemy. That’s about it.
That's an amazing argument you've prepared, you know.
But you’re right, it’s probably a little too early for them.
All right, that’s all for this morning’s training.
Thanks for your hard work.
Individual-skills training is a little bit tough, isn’t it?
I don’t know about a "little."
More like "a lot."
Captain Fate is busy, so she will only be around once in a while.
However, I’ll almost always be around.
T-Thank you very much.
Also, this is mostly for the two Lightning members, but also applies to the two Stars:
As your bodies are still in the midst of developing, please be careful not to overdo it.
Yes, ma'am!
In that case, why don’t we have lunch?
Everyone's been working hard!
Yes, ma'am!
Hayate, Rein, are you going out?
Yes indeedy, Vita!
Yeah, we’re going to the central region to talk with Major Nakajima.
Subaru, do you have anything you want me to tell your father or sister?
No, that’s all right.
Well then, Hayate, Rein, have a safe trip.
Give Major Nakajima and Ginga my regards.
I will!
Off we go!
I understand, Subaru, that your father and sister are with the Ground Armed Service.
Yeah, apparently Commander Yagami trained with Dad's battalion for a while.
But still, our unit has a lot of connections.
The captains were childhood friends, right?
That’s right. Nanoha and Commander Yagami are from the same world.
Fate lived there when she was younger too.
If I remember correctly, it’s Non-Administrated World #97.
That’s right.
This #97 is apparently where my dad's ancestors come from.
Is that right?
That's right! Your name sounds somewhat similar to Nanoha and the rest.
Dad and I have never been to that world. I don’t really know anything about it.
Now that you mention it, Erio, where were you from again?
I was raised at the Main Office.
The Bureau’s Main Office? Like the housing area?
The Main Office’s protection facility for special kids. I was there until I was eight years old.
Jackass!
Please don’t worry about it.
They were nice there.
And I led a normal, happy life.
Oh yeah, that's right! Ever since then, Fate has been your guardian, right, Erio?
Yep! Even since before I can remember, she’s done a lot for me.
Ever since I started learning magic, she’d teach me once in a while.
Honestly, she was always nice to me.
Even now I feel like Fate's still raising me.
When Fate was a child, something happened in her household that made her feel a bit lonely.
Apparently that's why she can’t leave lonely or sad children alone.
Because she was saved by kind, warm hands as well.
108th Battalion, Headquarters
Your new unit seems to be doing rather well.
Same place, commanding officer's room
Indeed, for now at least.
So what’s the matter today?
You wouldn’t have time to come all the way here just to see your old acquaintances.
Your favorite pupil has just a bit of a favor to ask of her teacher.
Enter.
Excuse me.
Ginga!
Lt. Colonel Yagami, long time no see!
What I wanted to ask of you is about the investigation of smuggling routes.
For the Lost Logia in your care?
There are many different routes they could be using.
For the specifics, Rein has brought the data and will give it to you later.
Well, I don’t mind you using our investigation unit,
since investigating smuggling is our main job anyway.
You can ask for a favor, but...
Please, if you would.
You know, Yagami,
Instead of going to another mobile unit or the Main Office's Investigations Unit,
You purposely came all the way here to see me about it.
Is there any reason for that?
I’ve also requested them to investigate the smuggling routes.
But after all, the Ground Armed Service would know the area here the best.
Well, I see your reasoning.
Sure, we’ll take it.
Thank you very much!
The lead investigator is Cartos, and Ginga is his adjutant.
Since you both know each other, you should be able to work with Ginga easily.
Okay, and on our side,
Enforcer Testarossa-Harlaown will be in charge of the investigation,
so Ginga would be able to work with her easily.
I see, so Fate is...
Righty-o!
She’s Riot Force 6’s lead investigator, so you might get to work together on the investigation.
I’ll have to really try my best then!
Yes!
Oh, that’s right!
Since you’re going to help with the investigation, Riot Force 6 will give you a Device as a gift.
A Device?
The same model as the one that was made for Subaru. Of course, we'll tune it for your use.
For that... I’m really happy, but is that okay?
No problem! To make sure you can accompany Fate, we’ll make you an awesome Device!
Thank you very much, Command Sergeant Major Rein!
Having Subaru and now Ginga come over makes me a feel a bit bad.
Why? Subaru decided herself, and Ginga would be happy to work with Miss Harlaown.
Okay.
But anyway, before I knew it, you became my superior.
Provisional assistant mages sure rise up in rank quickly.
A mage’s insignia is simply for decoration.
At the Main Office in the central region, even junior officers treat me like a little girl.
I can see that.
Oh yeah, sorry about that!
I’m treating you like a little girl too.
Major Nakajima, you always were and still are my superior who I respect.
I see.
Excuse me, this is First Lieutenant Lat Cartos.
Lt. Colonel Yagami has a request for our assistance on a mission.
Take Ginga to the conference room, and we’ll hold the meeting there.
Understood, sir.
And so you have it.
All right. Thank you very much.
After the meeting, want to go get something to eat?
Sure, I’ll accompany you.
Time-Space Administrative Bureau
Capital Central/Ground Headquarters
That’s all the data we have on the Relic.
They’ve properly sealed it, right?
Yes, ma'am, and very securely at that.
But still, I don’t really understand the reason Relics exist.
There are too many traits that don’t make any sense for crystallized energy.
And they're too odd to be used as a power generator.
Well, if their use was easily known, then they wouldn’t be Lost Logia.
Is this the data from the Gadget’s remains?
Yes, ma'am.
These are the same as the ones captured by Signum and Vita.
The new models aren’t very different internally.
Something wrong?
Go back a bit! To that picture of the Type 3’s remains.
Okay.
Probably the internal processing unit.
Which would be, around here?
That’s it.
Is this a jewel? An energy crystal of some sort?
A Jewel Seed.
Quite a while ago, Nanoha and I were searching for and collecting them.
Now they should be under the administration of the Bureau as Lost Logia.
Now I get it.
And why are those things there?
Shari, magnify this area. Something’s written there.
Okay.
Is this a name?
J...
Jail Scaglietti.
Dr. Jail Scaglietti.
Starting with incidents relating to Lost Logia, he’s committed an uncountable number of crimes,
and a wide-area arrest warrant has been issued.
He’s a first-class interdimensional criminal.
Interdimensional criminal?
There was a bit of an incident, and I’ve been chasing him for many years.
Why would a criminal like him
go through all the trouble to show that he’s responsible with such easy hints?
If it’s really him, then he’s provoking us. If it’s someone else, then they’re aiming to mislead us.
Either way, they know that Nanoha and I are involved in this case.
But if it is Scaglietti, I believe he would be capable of utilizing Lost Logia to manufacture Gadgets.
And I can think of a couple of reasons he'd go after Relics.
His reasons?
Shari, get this data together, and let’s get back to our base quickly.
I want to gather the captains and hold an emergency meeting.
Yes, ma'am, I’ll do it straightaway.
Okay, roger that. I’ll return immediately,
and we’ll hold a countermeasures meeting.
I’ve just requested some extra help with the investigation too.
In that case, see you later.
Was there a new development?
We might have a clue as to who the culprit is.
And so, I’m sorry, Major Nakajima. I’ll have to take my leave here.
You can't!
Hurry up and get going.
Your subordinates are waiting, right?
Okay. Ginga, either Fate or I will contact you later, all right?
Okay, I’ll be waiting.
Dr. Scaglietti, was it? The criminal with a wide-area arrest warrant?
You said you knew some reasons why he would be searching for the Relics.
Would you name some?
As the title Doctor suggests,
he has abnormal passion and skill with biological research and manipulation.
He even created a vast number of Gadgets to search for the Relics.
Zest and Lutecia have resumed their activities.
What about the client’s instructions?
"Don’t send any help without their authorization if you can help it," that was his message.
Once in their autonomous mode, the Gadget Drones are not under my complete control.
If they gather at a Relic, I wish they would let them pass.
I’ll let them know.
If they are going to move, then I shall take my time observing them.
They are important experimental Relic weapons, after all.
Okay! That’s it for tonight’s training.
Thank you very much.
Thanks for your hard work.
Okay.
Make sure to get a proper sleep.
Yes, ma'am.
But still, you really stay with them from morning to night, huh?
Isn't it tiring?
I am Riot Force 6’s combat instructor after all. It’s a given.
And about that, is it really okay to be so lenient with them?
When we had our initial training, we were strictly trained in everything from walking to greetings.
Anywhere you go, combat training is basically like this.
If there’s time to scold and yell at them for little things,
Then that should be spent in mock battle, teaching them precisely and thoroughly that way.
I was told that a lot while at the instruction squad.
Is that a lesson? Seriously?
What we’re doing isn’t teaching and raising completely new recruits.
We're guiding mages who have the will and determination to become stronger,
and teaching them combat techniques that are higher than their current level,
because we are combat instructors.
Well in any case, it’s pretty tough being an instructor.
But you're doing well too, Vita.
Very well indeed.
Don’t pet me!
What's wrong with you?
Could you organize and store today's combat data in the data room?
All right.
Thanks a lot, Raising Heart.
It’ll probably be a while before these guys realize how fortunate they are.
Even when they’re fighting on their own,
Caro, they’re still on.
they’re fortunate enough to always be protected by Nanoha.
Oops, that’s not good.
It pisses me off hearing that from you.
There, there.
I’m Stars's lieutenant, so I’ll protect you.
What is it?
It’s nothing! Let’s go, Nanoha.
Okay, Vita.
Without end, the dreams continue to weave
Surpassing thousands of nights
Like a prayer, the journey continues
Be my guide any day, oh small jewel
Spica among the stars
I engrave beyond the horizon
The faint footsteps that are connected to everywhere
The reflection of your eyes casts away the loop of anxiety
The midnight sun
The Orion of Midsummer
Just now from somewhere, I heard your voice
This heart without darkness
Illumine it, o distant blue star
No matter what the time, I will be able to start walking
Sparkling far and near
Watching over me
The thing inside my heart, overflowing
More than tears, I want to be loved
Like a prayer, the journey continues
Be my guide anyday, oh small jewel
Spica among the stars
Next
Episode
Preview
Next
Episode
Preview
In the next mission,
we will be acting
as hotel security,
protecting the auction.
Gadgets will be targeting the auction together with a mysterious summoning mage.
Next episode of
Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha StrikerS:
Episode 7: Hotel Augusta
Episode 7
Hotel Augusta
Take off!